<bill session="100" type="h" number="1020" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home Equity Conversion Mortgage Insurance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Housing Act to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to carry out a demonstration program of insurance of home equity conversion mortgages for elderly homeowners.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411901"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="401155" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="401363" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300017" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403476" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403904" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405377" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="406730" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="406790" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407215" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407457" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407519" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="408490" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="408907" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409052" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410084" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400417" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="411178" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Home equity conversion"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1987--Introduced.
Home Equity Conversion Mortgage Insurance Act - Amends the National Housing Act to authorize the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to insure a home equity conversion mortgage and to make commitments for the insurance of such mortgages prior to the date of their execution or disbursement if such mortgages: (1) may improve the financial situation or otherwise meet the needs of elderly homeowners; (2) can be developed to include safeguards for mortgagors to offset the special risks of such mortgages; and (3) have a potential for acceptance in the private market. Includes among insurance eligibility requirements that the mortgage shall: (1) have been made and held by a mortgagee approved by the Secretary; (2) have been executed by an elderly homeowner; (3) be secured by a one-family residential dwelling occupied by the mortgagor; (4) able to be prepaid without penalty; and (5) have a capped interest rate. Sets forth required mortgage disclosure and mortgagor information service provisions, including the provision of alternate home equity conversion options and related tax and financial information. Prohibits the Secretary from insuring a mortgage pursuant to this Act after September 30, 1991. Sets the total number of insurable mortgages under this Act at 2,000. Permits the Secretary to take any action necessary to provide a mortgagor with funds due pursuant to an insured mortgage or ancillary contract which have not been paid by the party responsible and to obtain reimbursement of such payments from any source. Prohibits the Secretary from insuring a home equity conversion mortgage that does not provide specified safeguards to prevent the displacement of the homeowner. Requires the Secretary to provide the Congress with two specified interim program reports.</summary>
</bill>
