<bill session="100" type="h" number="1032" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Micro-Enterprise Credit Promotion Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 to establish a bilateral program to furnish credit assistance for micro-enterprises owned by the poorest people in developing countries, and to encourage multilateral development banks to establish micro-enterprise credit programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401446" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402435" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402833" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403904" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407400" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407967" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Development Institutions and Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA06" subcommittee="International Development Institutions and Finance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1987--Introduced.
Comprehensive Micro-Enterprise Credit Promotion Act of 1987 - Amends the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 to mandate that the President establish a bilateral micro-enterprise credit program, to be administered by the Agency for International Development (AID). Describes the program as one under which foreign currencies generated from certain sales of U.S. agricultural commodities will be used by financial intermediaries in developing countries to provide loans and related technical training and assistance to micro-enterprises, defined in this Act as small enterprises owned by the country 's poorest people, operating within the informal sector economy of a developing country, and lacking access to credit at reasonable costs. Directs the Administrator of AID to issue guidelines to ensure that women are major recipients of such loans and that financial intermediaries making such loans: (1) consult with potential recipients in the interest of designing projects responsive to the credit needs of the recipients; (2) minimize obstacles to credit; and (3) encourage, when appropriate, cooperation among micro-enterprises as a mass means of fostering improved loan repayment rates. Requires that AID seek to use indigenous nongovernmental organizations as financial intermediaries and to develop the long-term capacity of such organizations to provide credit for micro-enterprises. Sets a minimum funding level for micro-enterprise loans under the program for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the Asian Development Bank, the African Development Bank, and the International Development Association (IDA) to support the establishment, within their respective institutions, of a Micro-Enterprise Credit Fund to provide to financial intermediaries capital resources to enable them to provide credit assistance to micro-enterprises. Requires the Secretary to instruct the U.S. Executive Director of the Inter-American Development Bank to: (1) express congressional support for the goals exemplified in that Bank's Program for the Financing of Small Projects; and (2) encourage continued efforts to make credit available to small enterprises through expansion of that program or the establishment of a Micro-Enterprise Credit Fund. Specifies a recommended funding level for the IDA Fund. Directs each institution, through its Fund, to: (1) attempt to ensure that women receive credit assistance; (2) emphasize the use of indigenous nongovernmental organizations as financial intermediaries and consult with such organizations when preparing and implementing plans for Fund allocations; (3) monitor the Fund's activities; (4) engage in research concerning specified features of micro-enterprises; and (5) prepare to facilitate the transfer of financial control of the loan program to specified institutions in developing countries. Provides for negotiations among all participating Banks to provide capitalization for the Fund. Mandates that the Secretary report to the House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs and to the Senate Committee on Foreign Relations on activities related to the establishment of the Fund. Sets forth specific procedures to govern the establishment of a Fund and the encouragement of micro-enterprise lending in the International Bank for Reconstruction and Development (World Bank). Requires that each annual report to the Congress by the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Policies describe specified micro-enterprise credit activities of each participating Bank.</summary>
</bill>
