<bill session="100" type="h" number="1036" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Administrative and Investment Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Social Security Administration as an independent agency, which shall be headed by a Social Security Board, and which shall be responsible for the administration of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program under title II of the Social Security Act and the supplemental security income program under title XVI of such Act and to provide for more prudent and effective management of the social security trust funds.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405939"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400844" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401585" joined="1987-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1987-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402600" joined="1988-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403203" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400115" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403888" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404019" joined="1987-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404163" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1987-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407069" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408506" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408621" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408725" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409237" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409422" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409446" joined="1987-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409651" joined="1988-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300091" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410567" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="410574" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410641" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1987-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Delegation of powers"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1987--Introduced.
Social Security Administrative and Investment Reform Act of 1987 - Title I: Establishment of the Social Security Administration - Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act to establish as an independent executive agency a Social Security Administration, headed by a Social Security Board. Provides that it shall be the duty of the Administration to administer the programs established by titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) of the Social Security Act. Requires the Board to study and make recommendations as to the most effective methods of providing economic security through social insurance and as to legislation and matters of administrative policy. Establishes in the Administration: (1) a Commissioner of Social Security; (2) a Deputy Commissioner of Social Security; (3) a General Counsel; (4) an Inspector General; and (5) an Office of the Beneficiary Ombudsman, to be headed by a Beneficiary Ombudsman who shall represent the interests of beneficiaries under the Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance program and the Supplemental Security Income Program within the Administration. Requires the annual report of the Board to include a description of the activities of the Beneficiary Ombudsman. Requires the Board to make annual budgetary recommendations relating to the Administration. Requires that appropriations requests by the Administration for staffing and personnel be based upon a comprehensive workforce plan as established by the Board. Provides for the apportionment of administrative costs. Requires the annual report of the Board to include a section reflecting the use of budget authority provided to the Administration. Requires that authority for automated data processing procurement and facilities construction be provided in the form of contract authority covering the total cost of such acquisitions. Makes amounts needed for the liquidation of contract authority so provided available from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund to the extent that such amounts are not needed to meet current obligations for benefit payments. Requires the Board and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management to implement demonstration projects relating to personnel matters. Directs the Board and the Administrator of General Services to implement such projects relating to delegations from the Administrator. Specifies the authorities which are to be delegated to the Board from the Administrator and the Director. Requires the Comptroller General to report to specified congressional committees concerning such projects, including an evaluation of the Board's readiness to assume full and permanent authority. Requires the Board to cause a seal of office to be made and judicial notice taken thereof. Provides for the transfer to the Administration of all functions carried out by the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to the programs and activities to be carried out by the Administration under this Act. Abolishes the position of Commissioner of Social Security in the Department of Health and Human Services. Sets forth effective date and transitional rule provisions. Title II: Conforming Amendments and Rules of Construction - Requires the Secretary and the Board to report to the Congress within 120 days after the beginning of each regular session on their administration under this Act. Requires the Secretary to study and make recommendations on the most effective methods of providing economic security and on the administrative policy for the programs. Directs the Board to appoint, quadrennially, an Advisory Council on the Old-Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance Program and an Advisory Council on Health and Supplementary Medical Insurance to review the relation of the trust funds supporting the OASDI program and the Medicare program and the long-term commitments of those programs. Requires each council to submit a report to the Board for transmittal to the Congress and the Board of Trustees of each Trust Fund. Title III: Management of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund - Amends the OASDI and Medicare (title XVIII of the Act) programs to direct the Managing Trustees of the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund, Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund, and Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund (trust funds) to immediately invest that portion of the trust funds which is not required for current withdrawals. Requires the investment of amounts in the OASDI trust funds to be made in accordance with policies established by the Social Security Board. Prohibits the sale and redemption of trust fund assets or the expenditure of trust fund amounts for purposes other than those specified in titles II and XVIII of the Act. Requires members of such trust funds' Boards of Trustees to faithfully execute their duties, but does not impose a fiduciary duty. Requires that, in consideration of the public debt limit, required investment of funds or amounts over which the Secretary of the Treasury has investment authority occur prior to the issuance of other obligations. Directs that tax receipts earmarked for the OASDI program be immediately transferred (currently, monthly transfers are made) from the general fund of the Treasury to the OASDI trust funds. Requires the Boards of Trustees of the trust funds to meet at least twice each year. Sets forth provisions requiring reports by the Board of Trustees and the Managing Trustees to the Congress regarding the operation and status of the trust funds.</summary>
</bill>
