<bill session="100" type="h" number="1059" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to define the circumstances under which construction workers may deduct travel and transportation expenses in computing their taxable incomes for purposes of the Federal income tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400333"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/9/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code with respect to deductions for ordinary and necessary business expenses to provide a special rule for construction workers' travel and transportation expenses. Provides that a job at a site located more than 30 miles from a worker's residence: (1) shall be considered temporary for the first two years of employment at that site; and (2) shall be considered temporary or not temporary after the first two years based on an examination of all the facts and circumstances. Provides that no deduction shall be disallowed solely because a construction worker's employment at a job site is of indefinite duration. Prohibits the application of the "one-year" rule set forth in Revenue Ruling 59-371, which specifies the length of time which automatically or presumptively classifies the job as other than temporary. Defines "construction worker," for purposes of this Act, as any individual employed as a skilled, semiskilled, or unskilled laborer in the building or construction industry.</summary>
</bill>
