<bill session="100" type="h" number="1079" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Gaming Regulatory Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish Federal standards and regulations for the conduct of gaming activities on Indian reservations and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1987-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404002" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410567" joined="1987-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-17">
      <text>For Further Action See S.555.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="555"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Bingo"/>
    <term name="Casinos"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Dog racing"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gambling and Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Withholding tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/10/1987--Introduced.
Indian Gaming Regulatory Act - Establishes Federal standards for gaming activity on Indian lands. Makes gaming class II (bingo or lotto) and class III (all other forms of gaming not covered under class I or II) activities illegal on certain trust lands located outside of an Indian tribe's reservation unless such tribe obtains the concurrence of the Governor of the State, the legislature, and county and municipal governments. Applies provisions of the Internal Revenue Code concerning the taxation, reporting, and withholding of taxes to the operation of such activities. Establishes within the Department of the Interior the National Indian Gaming Commission. Authorizes the Commission to: (1) monitor Indian gaming activities; (2) establish regulations for the assessment and collection of civil fines; and (3) implement such other regulations as it deems appropriate. Exempts class I gaming (social games for prizes of minimal value) activities from the provisions of this Act. Provides that Indian tribes may engage in, or license and regulate, class II gaming activities on Indian lands if the governing body of the Indian tribe adopts an ordinance or resolution which is approved by the Chairman of the Commission. Requires a license for each gaming facility. Requires tribal licensing requirements for class II gaming activities to be at least as restrictive as State law governing similar gaming within the State. Provides that Indian tribes may engage in class III gaming activities on Indian lands if the governing body of the Indian tribe adopts a class III ordinance which meets the requirements of this Act, secures approval from the Chairman of the Commission, and obtains a license from the Commission. Permits an Indian tribe, subject to the approval of the Chairman, to enter into management contracts for the operation and management of class II or class III gaming activities. Sets forth: (1) specified information to be included in such contracts; and (2) procedures relating to the approval of such contracts. Authorizes the Chairman to levy and collect fines (including the permanent closure of gaming operations) for violations of the standards contained in this Act or regulations adopted by the Commission. Sets forth provisions with respect to the power of the Commission to subpoena witnesses and evidence. Requires the Commission to treat such information as confidential. Authorizes the Attorney General to investigate gaming activities which may be in violation of Federal law. Sets forth specified provisions with respect to the Commission's annual budget. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary of the Interior, upon the request of the Miccosukee Tribe of Indians of Florida, to accept in trust all interest of the Tribe in specified Indian lands. Allows class II gaming activities on such lands.</summary>
</bill>
