<bill session="100" type="h" number="1119" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Exclusion and Deportation Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the grounds for exclusion and deportation of aliens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1987-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403695" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404752" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404765" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1987-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406191" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406730" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406765" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406994" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407457" joined="1987-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407471" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407519" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1987-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1987-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408457" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408575" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409446" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1987-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409650" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409954" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411677" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1987-11-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-25">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from HHS, Justice, Labor, State, CIA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-20">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.4427 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3293"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4427"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Immigration law"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/18/1987--Introduced.
Immigration Exclusion and Deportation Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make only the following classes of aliens ineligible to receive visas and be permitted admission into the United States: (1) any alien with a communicable disease of public health significance; (2) any alien with a record of behavior or mental impairment that poses a threat to property or safety; (3) any alien convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude, with specified exceptions; (4) any alien convicted of two or more offenses for which the aggregate sentences actually imposed were five years or more; (5) any alien convicted of specified drug violations; (6) any alien who has engaged in terrorist activity; (7) any alien who participated in Nazi persecutions; (8) any alien deemed by the Attorney General as a probable security risk for certain specified reasons, including terrorist activity; (9) any alien who is likely to become a public economic burden; (10) any alien seeking to enter the United States for the purpose of performing skilled or unskilled labor, with certain qualified exceptions; (11) any alien who is a graduate of a medical school not accredited by a body approved for such purpose by the Secretary of Education, with certain exceptions; (12) any excluded or deported alien who seeks readmission within one year of the event, unless such readmission is consented to by the Attorney General; (13) any alien seeking to enter the United States by fraud or the willful misrepresentation of a material fact; (14) any stowaway alien; (15) any alien who aids any other alien in illegal entry; (16) any immigrant not in possession of a valid immigrant visa and passport at the time of admission; (17) any nonimmigrant not in possession of a valid passport authorizing the alien to return to the country from which he or she came; (18) any alien ineligible for U.S. citizenship, including a person who left or remained outside the United States to avoid U.S. military service in time of war or national emergency; and (19) any alien who is a narcotic drug addict. Repeals the ideological grounds for exclusion. Permits a U.S. citizen or permanent resident denied an opportunity to meet with or hear in person an alien excluded from the United States on security grounds to seek judicial review of such denial in U.S. district court. Repeals provisions dealing with bond and conditions for admission for permanent residence for retarded, tubercular, and mentally ill aliens. Makes deportable by the Attorney General only those aliens within one of the following classes: (1) any alien who at the time of entry was within one or more of the classes of aliens excludable by then existing law; (2) any alien entering the United States without inspection or at a time and place other than as designated by the Attorney General; (3) any alien admitted as a nonimmigrant who has failed to maintain such status; (4) any alien admitted as a temporary agricultural worker (H-2A visa) whose status has been terminated (with family hardship exceptions); (5) any alien who within five years of entry knowingly and for gain has aided another alien to illegally enter the United States; (6) any alien admitted as an additional special agricultural worker who fails to show the necessary number of seasonal work days; (7) any alien convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude committed within five years from the date of entry and who is either sentenced or confined for a term of one year or longer; (8) any alien who at any time after entry is convicted of two or more crimes involving moral turpitude; (9) any alien who at any time after entry is convicted of a violation of certain drug laws; (10) any alien who is a narcotic drug addict; (11) any alien who at any time after entry is convicted under weapons-possession laws; (12) any alien who at any time is convicted on any of various specified loyalty laws (e.g. sabotage, treason and sedition, selective service, etc.); (13) any alien who fails to comply with alien registration laws or foreign agent registration laws; (14) any alien convicted of fraud or misuse of visas or other entry documents; (15) any alien engaging in activity which endangers the public safety or national security, including terrorist activity; (16) any alien who within five years after entry has become a public economic burden; (17) any alien who has engaged in terrorist activity; or (18) any alien who participated in Nazi persecutions.</summary>
</bill>
