<bill session="100" type="h" number="1141" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">High Technology Trade Promotion Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 with respect to the export of goods and technology subject to export controls for national security purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400987"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403695" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404705" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404765" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404996" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405687" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407519" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407564" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407673" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="408190" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408957" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409219" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411677" joined="1987-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1987-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.3.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic industries"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/19/1987--Introduced.
High Technology Trade Promotion Act of 1987 - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to declare that no permission to export may be required for national security reasons for exports of goods or technology to a country which maintains export controls on such goods or technology cooperatively with the United States pursuant to an international agreement. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to require permission to export such goods or technology to certain end users. Authorizes the Secretary to require permission to export such goods or technology to a country if the country is engaging in a pattern of noncompliance with the agreement of the Coordinating Committee on Export Controls or other applicable agreement. Declares that no permission to export may be required under the national security export control provisions for the export to any country (other than a controlled country) of certain low technology items. Declares that no permission to reexport goods may be required under the national security export control provisions for: (1) reexports to or from any country which maintains export controls on such goods cooperatively with the United States pursuant to an international agreement except for reexports to certain end users; (2) reexports of goods that are incorporated in other goods and do not constitute more than 35 percent of the value of the goods in which they are incorporated; and (3) reexports of certain low technology items. Requires the Secretary, when reviewing the foreign availability of items subject to national security export controls, to include sources of such items within a country to which exports are controlled. Grants the Secretary the authority, with specified exceptions, to make a foreign availability determination notwithstanding the approval or disapproval of any other agency. Imposes a timetable for determinations by the Secretary of foreign availability of items subject to national security export controls. Requires the President to begin negotiations to eliminate the foreign availability of items subject to national security export controls whenever the President determines that it is in the national security interest to eliminate such availability. Provides that if such negotiations do not result in the elimination of such foreign availability within six months, the Secretary may not require a validated license for the export of such items. Deletes the provision that authorized an extension of such negotiating period. Provides a 30-day period for submission of data in connection with review of the inclusion of an item on the national security export control list. Repeals the provision providing special procedures for the Secretary of Defense in the processing of export license applications. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to refer export license applications to other agencies under certain circumstances. Requires the Comptroller General to review the effect of the changes in export license review procedures contained in this paragraph and to report to the appropriate congressional committees concerning procedural improvements to ensure the removal of export controls without adversely affecting national security. Requires the President to appoint a person representing the U.S. electronics industry to the U.S. delegation to the Coordinating Committee on Export Controls. Authorizes appropriations for the Office of the Under Secretary of Commerce for Export Administration and for the Office of Export Licensing. Authorizes the issuance of a distribution export license to approve distributors or users of exports in China. Makes certain technical amendments to such Act.</summary>
</bill>
