<bill session="100" type="h" number="1157" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-27">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acreage Diversion Pilot Program Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Farm Disaster Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Farm Disaster Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Farm Disaster Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Farm Disaster Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for an acreage diversion pilot program applicable to the wheat program for the 1987 and 1988 crops.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403873"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1987-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Wheat, Soybeans, and Feed Grains.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-24">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-03-16">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Agriculture. Report No: 100-25.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-16">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 20.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="32" datetime="1987-03-17" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 304 - 100 (Record Vote No: 32).</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-19" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="40">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 40.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Previous action on Pressler amendment no. 148 vitiated.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Previous action on Wirth amendment no. 151 vitiated.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Previous action on Mitchell amendment no. 152 vitiated.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Previous action on Danforth amendment no. 153 vitiated.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1987-04-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>House Disagreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>House Requested a Conference and Speaker Appointed Conferees: de la Garza, Glickman, Huckaby, Marlenee, Roberts, Nowak, Stangeland.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and held at desk: House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Senate agreed to request for conference. Appointed conferees. Leahy; Melcher; Pryor; Boren; Lugar; Dole; Helms; Moynihan; Stafford. (Senators Moynihan and Stafford appointed for areas under the jurisdiction of the Committee on Environment and Public Works.).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Conference Report 100-91 Filed in House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="conference" datetime="1987-05-12" where="s" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>House Agreed to Conference Report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1987-05-27" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-45" type="public" datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-45.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAG08" subcommittee="Wheat, Soybeans, and Feed Grains" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="904"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="341"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Flowers"/>
    <term name="Fruit and fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Maine"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Nuts"/>
    <term name="Oilseeds"/>
    <term name="Payment-in-kind program"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Soil erosion"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Soybeans"/>
    <term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s148"/>
    <amendment number="s149"/>
    <amendment number="s150"/>
    <amendment number="s151"/>
    <amendment number="s152"/>
    <amendment number="s153"/>
    <amendment number="s154"/>
    <amendment number="s155"/>
    <amendment number="s156"/>
    <amendment number="s157"/>
    <amendment number="s158"/>
    <amendment number="s159"/>
    <amendment number="s161"/>
    <amendment number="s162"/>
    <amendment number="s163"/>
    <amendment number="s164"/>
    <amendment number="s165"/>
    <amendment number="s166"/>
    <amendment number="s167"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/12/1987--Conference report filed in House.
(Conference report filed in House, H. Rept. 100-91) Farm Disaster Assistance Act of 1987 - Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to exempt 1987 winter wheat producers from the acreage diversion program (50/92 program) requirement that at least 50 percent of permitted wheat acreage be planted in order to receive deficiency payments. Authorizes all or any part of such acreage to be used for conservation purposes. Provides similar 1987 exemptions for: (1) wheat producers whose farms are eligible for Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act disaster emergency loans as a result of 1986 disaster-prevented plantings; and (2) wheat, rice, feed grain, and upland cotton producers eligible for such loans and subject to flooding on at least 50 percent of their permitted acreage resulting from 1986 flood-damaged levees. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, to the extent provided for by advance appropriations, to make full payment in the form of Commodity Credit Corporation generic negotiable commodity certificates for disaster claims under the Agriculture, Rural Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1987. Directs the Secretary to make supplemental payments to producers who have received partial payments prior to the enactment of this Act. Amends the Agriculture, Rural Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1987 to make the following eligible for crop disaster payments: (1) apples ruined by 1986 freezes; (2) soybeans or peanuts whose planting (including 1985 planting) was prevented by natural disaster or other conditions beyond the farmer's control; (3) hay and straw that was harvested in 1986, stored on fields, and carried off by floods; (4) sugar beets or sugar cane that was not planted due to the 1985 Great Western Sugar Company bankruptcy, according to county committee determinations of eligible acreage; and (5) certain program and nonprogram crops in Maine. Requires assistance applications regarding hay, straw, apples, and Maine program or nonprogram crops to be filed within 30 days of enactment of this Act. Limits aggregate hay and straw payments to: (1) $20,000 for an individual producer; and (2) $1,000,000 for all eligible producers. Limits apple payments to amounts provided in advance by an appropriation Act. Provides, with regard to crop losses in Maine, that: (1) payments shall be made only as provided for in advance by an appropriation Act; (2) aggregate producer payments may not exceed $1,000,000; and (3) assistance applications must be filed within 30 days of enactment of this Act. States that appropriations made pursuant to this Act shall be made in accordance with the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) as amended, so that the FY 1987 deficit shall not be increased. Directs the Chief of Engineers, in deciding whether or not a particular Great Lakes emergency flood protection project is justified, to consider the benefit of protecting against crop losses and residential and commercial losses. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to review the manner in which the Department of Agriculture is implementing the exceptions to the three-year ownership requirement in order to assure that the inclusion of producer-owned land in the conservation reserve program is encouraged. Amends the Agriculture, Rural Development, and Related Agencies Appropriations Act, 1987 to provide emergency disaster assistance to upland cotton producers who suffered crop quality reduction caused by drought, flood, hail, or excessive moisture in 1986. Limits aggregate producer payments to not more than $15,000,000. Directs the Secretary to designate specified flooded areas in South Dakota as "wetlands" under the Water Bank Act. Limits FY 1987 payments to affected owners and operators to a maximum of $1,243,000. Directs the Secretary to appoint a panel to conduct an ethanol cost effectiveness study. Requires a report to the appropriate congressional committees within 90 days of enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary to submit a marketing loan report to the appropriate congressional committees by July 1, 1987, if a marketing loan program is not established for the 1987 crops of wheat, feed grains, and soybeans. Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to establish price supports (at eight and one-half cents per pound) for the 1987 through 1990 sunflower crops.</summary>
</bill>
