<bill session="100" type="h" number="1256" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Native American Programs Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Native American Programs Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1988 through 1990, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from HHS.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>See H.R.1451.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSED07" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1451"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaskan natives"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Hawaiians"/>
    <term name="National growth policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1987--Introduced.
Native American Programs Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Native American Programs Act of 1974 (the Act) to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a formal peer review process to evaluate applications for financial assistance for specified Native American projects and to determine the relative merits of such projects. Requires the Secretary, when making appointments of members to the peer review panels, to give preference to American Indians, Hawaiian Natives, and Alaskan Natives. Sets forth the duties of such panels. Directs the Secretary, upon approval of an application for financial assistance, to send written notice to the House Committee on Education and Labor and the President pro tempore of the Senate. Provides that administrative rulemaking requirements shall apply with respect to the establishment and operation of any program that provides loans, grants, benefits, or contracts authorized under this Act. Exempts the provisions of this Act from Federal law provisions that do not require notice and a hearing (rulemaking) under circumstances where it would be impracticable, unnecessary, or contrary to the public interest. Prohibits any rule (or general policy statement) that is issued pursuant to this Act from taking effect until 30 days after publication in the Federal Register. Requires a copy of such publication to be transmitted to the Speaker of the House and the President pro tempore of the Senate. Sets forth specified requirements with respect to the promulgation of rules pursuant to this Act. Authorizes appropriations through FY 1991 for Native American projects under the Act.</summary>
</bill>
