<bill session="100" type="h" number="1306" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the role of the Foreign Commercial Service in promoting United States exports of goods and services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408575"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.3.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asian and Pacific Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
    <term name="Taiwan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a pilot program in the Foreign Commercial Service to encourage the export of U.S. goods and services to Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan. Sets forth actions the Foreign Commercial Service shall take through such program. Directs the Secretary to report semiannually to specified congressional committees on the progress of such program, including: (1) the goods and services proposed for trade liberalization; (2) the results of any liberalization towards U.S. goods and services; and (3) the increase in U.S. commercial sales in Japan, South Korea, and Taiwan. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY 1987 through 1991. Amends the Export Administration Amendments Act of 1985 to authorize the Secretary of Commerce to establish a Market Development Cooperator Program the purpose of which is to develop, maintain, and expand foreign markets for nonagricultural goods and services produced in the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts with specified organizations (cooperators) to engage in activities in order to carry out the purpose of the Program. Requires the Secretary to establish a partnership program with cooperators under which a cooperator may detail individuals to the Foreign Commercial Service. Sets forth administrative provisions governing such details. Designates the Market Development Cooperator Program an export promotion program under such Act. Amends the Taiwan Relations Act to require the American Institute of Taiwan to employ personnel to perform duties similar to those performed by personnel of the Foreign Commercial Service. Requires the Secretary to submit to the President and to the Congress a list of those U.S. missions abroad which are commercially significant or are located in a geographical area of commercial importance to the United States. Requires the Secretary of State to designate the senior Commercial Officer at any such mission a Minister-Counselor. Requires the Secretary of State to consider filling any vacancy in the Counsel General position of any U.S. consulate with a Commercial Officer under certain circumstances.</summary>
</bill>
