<bill session="100" type="h" number="132" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Maritime Dry Bulk Trade and Revitalization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote orderly and efficient ocean transportation of dry bulk commodities in the foreign commerce of the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403529"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, State, DOT, DOE, USDA, USTR.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Merchant Marine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-10">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From State.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM06" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Shipping agreements"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Maritime Dry Bulk Trade and Revitalization Act - Directs the Secretary of the Department in which the Maritime Administration is operating to negotiate a Governing International Maritime Agreement: (1) with each nation with which the United States traded a specified amount of dry bulk cargo in 1984; and (2) with nations whose U.S. trade was less than the specified amount if such a nation asks to negotiate an agreement. Lists the essential provisions of a Governing International Maritime Agreement. Directs the Secretary to enter into such an agreement with any group of nations which desires to execute the agreement on a regional basis. Prohibits such an agreement from becoming effective until 60 days after it is transmitted to the Congress. Sets forth procedures for congressional review and veto of such an agreement. Prohibits a non-national-flag ship from transporting dry bulk cargo with a trading partner except as authorized by the Governing International Maritime Agreement. Provides that five years after enactment of this Act: (1) non-national-flag ships not documented under the laws of a trading partner are prohibited from transporting dry bulk cargo; and (2) such ships documented under the laws of a trading partner are authorized to transport dry bulk cargo between the United States and any nation not a party to such an agreement. Directs the Secretary and the Secretary of the Treasury to implement procedures to insure that non-national-flag ships do not transport bulk cargo in excess of the authorized amount. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory committee to assist in implementing this Act. Requires such advisory committee to report annually to the Congress on its activities. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress annually on actions taken pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
