<bill session="100" type="h" number="139" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Unfair Foreign Competition Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Unfair Competition Act of 1916 and Clayton Act to provide for the further relief in the event of unfair foreign competition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403888"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Unfair Foreign Competition Act of 1987 - Amends the Clayton Act to include a specified antidumping provision among U.S. antitrust laws. Amends the antidumping provision to allow any person who is injured in her or his property or business by the sale or importation of an article made in a foreign country to bring a civil action against the manufacturer, exporter, or importer of such article if: (1) the article is imported or sold in the United States at less than its foreign market or constructed value; and (2) such sale or importation causes or threatens material injury to U.S. industry or labor or prevents the establishment or modernization of U.S. industry. (Currently, the cause of such an action is predicated on the intent of the importer to injure or prevent the establishment of U.S. industry or to monopolize trade.) Restricts the district court jurisdiction of such an action to the District of Columbia. Entitles a prevailing plaintiff in such an action to recover: (1) compensatory damages (currently, treble damages) or appropriate equitable relief; and (2) legal expenses. Declares that the standard of proof in such an action is a preponderance of the evidence. Places the burden of proof for rebutting a prima facie case on the defendant. Includes within the meaning of prima facie case a finding by the International Trade Commission (ITC) that dumping exists. Authorizes the district court to: (1) issue subpoenas outside its judicial district if necessary; (2) enjoin importation of articles allegedly dumped pending the defendant's compliance with any court order; (3) review, in camera, confidential or privileged material; (4) accept material under seal; and (5) disclose such material. Requires expedited treatment of such actions. Sets a four-year statute of limitations for actions under this Act. Requires the foreign market value or constructed value of an article to include the amount of any subsidy provided to the manufacturer, producer, or exporter of the article. Expresses the sense of the Congress that this Act is consistent with the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade.</summary>
</bill>
