<bill session="100" type="h" number="141" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Criminal Justice Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia, to transfer prosecutorial authority for local offenses and custodial responsibility for prisoners convicted of local offenses to the District of Columbia government, to provide for the local appointment of the judges of the District of Columbia courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404006"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Judiciary and Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSDT03" subcommittee="Judiciary and Education" name="House District of Columbia"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Municipal politics and government"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Public prosecutors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
District of Columbia Criminal Justice Reform Act - Title I: Short Title, Purpose, and Definitions - Declares that it is the purpose of this Act to establish an autonomous judicial system in the government of the District of Columbia. Title II: Office of the Attorney General - Establishes within the District of Columbia government an Office of the Attorney General for the District of Columbia headed by an Attorney General who shall be appointed by the Mayor of the District of Columbia with the advice and consent of the Council of the District of Columbia. Specifies that the Attorney General shall serve for a term of four years coterminous with the term of the office of the Mayor. Sets forth the qualifications for the Office of Attorney General. Declares that the Attorney General for the District of Columbia shall be the chief legal officer for the District. Requires the Attorney General to appoint a Deputy Attorney General, a Solicitor General, a District Attorney for Criminal Prosecutions, a District Attorney for Civil Proceedings, and a Marshal for the District of Columbia. Enumerates the duties of each office. Provides that Assistant District Attorneys appointed pursuant to this Act shall serve at the pleasure of the Attorney General. Directs the Attorney General to establish programs for the professional training and continuing legal education of the staff of the Office of the Attorney General. Authorizes the Attorney General to appoint an Executive Assistant for Training to coordinate such programs. Declares that, except as set forth in this Act, prosecutions for violations of District laws shall be conducted in the name of the District by the Attorney General for the District of Columbia. States that if the United States Attorney General finds that a particular matter or case involves a legitimate and compelling Federal interest which justifies the exercise of exclusive Federal jurisdiction, and such exercise of Federal jurisdiction is in the public interest, the United States Attorney General may file with the Clerk of the Superior Court of the District of Columbia a certification to that effect. Divests the District of Columbia of jurisdiction over a matter or case as to which a certification has been filed. Directs the United States Attorney General to provide assistance and guidance in the training of Assistant District Attorneys, the development of ethical and professional standards for the conduct of criminal prosecutions, and the development of cooperative law enforcement activities. Directs the United States Attorney General and the Attorney General for the District of Columbia to enter into a Memorandum of Understanding specifying points of cooperation. Provides for the continuation of services to the District of Columbia by the United States Marshal. Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act. Sets forth a formula for minimum budget requests by the District government for the Office of the Attorney General. Authorizes the Attorney General to provide for the expenditures of funds as necessary for appropriate purposes related to the responsibilities of the Office of the Attorney General. Title III: Transition Provisions - Abolishes the Office of the Corporation Counsel of the District of Columbia and transfers its functions and positions to the Office of the Attorney General. Transfers officers and employees of the Office of the Corporation Counsel to the Office of the Attorney General. Authorizes the transfer of positions, property, records, and unexpended balances of appropriations, allocations, or other funds, assets, and liabilities which relate primarily to the functions so transferred. States that any statute, regulation, or action with respect to any officer or agency from which any function is transferred by this Act shall, except to the extent modified or made inapplicable by or under authority of law, continue in effect as if such transfer had not been made. Prohibits any prosecution, suit, action, or other judicial proceeding lawfully commenced by or against any officer or agency in any official capacity or in relation to the exercise of official functions from abating by reason of the taking effect of any provision of this Act. Permits the Mayor to appoint, and the Council to confirm, an Attorney General Designate who shall provide for the planning preliminary to the establishment of the Office of the Attorney General. States that the expenses of the Office of the Attorney General during transition years shall be paid from funds deposited to the credit of the District or the United States according to a specified schedule. Title IV: Amendments to Other Laws - Amends the District of Columbia Self-Government and Governmental Reorganization Act to reduce to five the membership of the District of Columbia Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure and the District of Columbia Judicial Nomination Commission. Provides for the nomination and appointment of judges of the District of Columbia courts by the Mayor with advice and consent of the District of Columbia Council. Title V: Effective Dates - Sets forth the effective dates of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
