<bill session="100" type="h" number="1463" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Primary Dealers' Fair Competition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Reserve Bank of New York from designating, or continuing the designation of, any person of a foreign country as a primary dealer in government debt instruments if such foreign country does not allow United States companies equal access in acquiring government debt instruments issued by such country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA03" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA07" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1987--Introduced.
Primary Dealers' Fair Competition Act - Expresses congressional findings, including that U.S. firms seeking to compete in Japan face discriminatory barriers which effectively preclude fair competition for Japanese business. Prohibits the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Reserve Bank of New York from designating, or permitting continued designation of, any person of a foreign country as a primary dealer in Government debt instruments if U.S. companies are denied equal access in the acquisition of government debt instruments issued by such country.</summary>
</bill>
