<bill session="100" type="h" number="1469" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 with respect to the definitions of industry in antidumping and countervailing duty investigations involving certain processed agricultural products.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411166"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403203" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408097" joined="1987-03-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="411119" joined="1987-03-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Produce trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/5/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 with respect to antidumping and countervailing duty investigations to require the producers or growers of agricultural products to be considered part of the industry that produces processed agricultural products if such products are produced from the raw agricultural product through a single continuous line of production, and there is a substantial coincidence of economic interest between the producers of the raw agricultural product and the producers of the processed agricultural product based upon certain economic factors. Sets forth specified factors, for purposes of this Act, to be considered to determine: (1) when a processed agricultural product shall be deemed to be processed from a raw agricultural product through a single continuous line of production; and (2) questions of coincidence of economic interest. Defines "raw agricultural product." Requires the International Trade Commission, with respect to whether imports (or sales for importation) of both a raw agricultural product and a product processed from such raw agricultural product threaten material injury to a U.S. industry, to consider, in addition to other relevant economic factors, the likelihood that an affirmative determination by the Commission with respect to either products (but not both) would result in an increase in the imports of the other agricultural product to an injurious level. Includes U.S. manufacturers, producers, or wholesalers engaged in the production of processed agricultural products as "interested parties" with respect to antidumping and countervailing duty investigations involving such products.</summary>
</bill>
