<bill session="100" type="h" number="1485" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to impose certain requirements with respect to acquisitions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust actions"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Consent decrees"/>
    <term name="Corporate divestiture"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to prohibit final approval of any merger, consolidation, or acquisition of securities before any divestiture of stock or assets required by the Federal Trade Commission or a court has been approved by the Commission or court. Authorizes the Commission or court to rescind any consent agreement, consent decree, or order requiring such a divestiture and to initiate an action to obtain appropriate relief, if the divestiture is not approved within the prescribed period. Provides that no divestiture shall be deemed an acceptable remedy for an acquisition that substantially lessens competition, unless the divestiture fully restores competition lost as a result of the acquisition and there is a substantial likelihood that any buyer of divested assets will be a viable competitor for the foreseeable future. Directs the Commission or court, in approving divestitures, to insure that reasonable steps are taken to protect the interests of affected employees and to preserve employment consistent with the full restoration of competition. Amends the Clayton Act to allow a State's attorney general to intervene as an interested party in a court proceeding to determine whether a consent judgment proposed by the United States in a civil antitrust case is in the public interest, if such judgment provides for divestiture of enterprises employing more than 100 full-time employees in such State. Allows the disclosure to Federal and State law enforcement agencies for official law enforcement purposes of information filed with the Commission or the Assistant Attorney General of the United States pursuant to premerger notification requirements.</summary>
</bill>
