<bill session="100" type="h" number="1492" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to establish certain requirements for the procurement by contract of certain services that are reserved for performance by preference eligibles in the competitive service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403203" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403695" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408180" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="409353" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1987-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB, OPM.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO04" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/1987--Introduced.
Prohibits a Federal agency from procuring by contract any services performed by Federal employees in the competitive service positions of guards, elevator operators, messengers, and custodians if such procurement would: (1) cause the involuntary separation of a preference eligible from any such position; or (2) preclude the performance of any such service by a qualified preference eligible. Provides that neither an involuntary reassignment within the same agency nor an involuntary transfer to another agency shall be considered to be an involuntary separation if such reassignment or transfer is to a vacant position which is the same type, at the same or higher pay, within the same commuting area, and for which the preference eligible is qualified. Allows the procurement of such services by contract: (1) when qualified preference eligibles are not available; and (2) for positions held by employees other than preference eligibles. Requires that any such procurement be conducted in accordance with applicable Federal procurement laws, including specified provisions requiring certain procurements of services from qualified nonprofit agencies for the blind and for other severely handicapped.</summary>
</bill>
