<bill session="100" type="h" number="1498" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Traffic Safety and Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Authorization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1966 and the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406746" joined="1987-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Automobile industry"/>
    <term name="Automobile recalls"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/1987--Introduced.
National Traffic Safety and Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Authorization Act of 1987 - Title I: Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety - Amends the National Traffic and Motor Vehicle Safety Act of 1966 to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to direct the manufacturer of a defective motor vehicle or motor vehicle part to send a second notification if the Secretary determines that the first notification sent by such manufacturer has not resulted in an adequate number of vehicles (or items of equipment) being returned for remedy. Requires any lessor who receives notification of a defective motor vehicle part pertaining to any leased motor vehicle to send a copy of such notice to the lessee. Provides that a dealer may sell or lease a motor vehicle (or motor vehicle item) for which a defect notice has been received only if: (1) the defect or failure to comply has been remedied before delivery under sale or lease; or (2) an enforcement order has been set aside or restrained.</summary>
</bill>
