<bill session="100" type="h" number="152" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Supreme Court Establishment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a District of Columbia Supreme Court.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404006"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Judiciary and Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSDT03" subcommittee="Judiciary and Education" name="House District of Columbia"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
District of Columbia Supreme Court Establishment Act - Amends the District of Columbia Code to establish the District of Columbia Supreme Court (Court) consisting of a chief judge and six associates with jurisdiction over appeals from all final orders and judgments of the District of Columbia Court of Appeals. Provides for the temporary assignment of Court judges to and from other courts of the District of Columbia. Directs each Court judge to submit a monthly written report to the chief judge and the Commission on Judicial Disabilities and Tenure setting forth the judge's attendance record for, and matters disposed of during, the month. Requires the Court to conduct business in accordance with the Federal Rules of Appellate Procedure unless it elects to modify such rules. Directs the chief judge of the Court to annually summon the active judges of the D.C. courts to a conference for the purpose of advising as to means of improving the administration of justice within the District of Columbia.</summary>
</bill>
