<bill session="100" type="h" number="1531" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Pipeline Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Coal Pipeline Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 with respect to the movement of coal over public lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400844" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400882" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401029" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401203" joined="1987-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401526" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401612" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401837" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401874" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="1988-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402710" joined="1987-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="402928" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403476" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403529" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403873" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404002" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404401" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405580" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="405747" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405855" joined="1987-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300055" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="405887" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406148" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406730" joined="1988-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1988-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406992" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407051" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407399" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407967" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408092" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408190" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408457" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="408725" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="408907" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409534" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410574" joined="1988-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1987-03-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-22">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-835 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Eminent domain"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/8/1988--Reported to House amended, Part I.
(Reported to House from the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, amended, H. Rept. 100-835 (Part I)) Coal Pipeline Act of 1987 - Amends the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920 to authorize a person who has secured specified water rights under applicable State law to apply to the Secretary of the Interior for certification that it is in the national interest to construct, operate, maintain, or extend a coal pipeline. Prescribes guidelines under which the Secretary will make such a certification, including the decision to grant rights-of-way across Federal lands upon such pipeline's request. Conditions such certification upon an applicant's reservation of a specified portion of total pipeline capacity for small, independent producers located in the geographic region served by such pipeline. Makes all Federal and State environmental laws applicable to the issuance or denial of such certification. Conditions the issuance of such certification upon the Secretary's receipt of commitments that all manufactured and unmanufactured articles used in such construction have been mined, produced, or manufactured in the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to grant exemptions. Outlines the procedures for granting rights-of-way across Federal lands. Proscribes the granting of any right-of-way through lands: (1) designated as wilderness areas; (2) administered as part of the national park system; or (3) which are part of a historic site (unless there is no reasonable alternative and reasonable planning is made to minimize the harm to such site). Proscribes coal pipeline construction on, over, or through certain alluvial valleys unless the Secretary has determined that the impact is at an absolute minimum or no reasonable alternative exists. Prohibits any person or entity (including the United States) from claiming any right or interest in water within any State for a coal pipeline unless such claim takes place under the law of the affected State. Delegates to the States all power regarding water rights for a coal pipeline regardless of any otherwise impermissible burden which may thereby be imposed upon interstate commerce. States that this Act does not: (1) impair the validity of any State law (or interstate compact) regarding any claim to water rights; (2) alter the rights of any State to its apportioned share of water under past or future allocation or interstate compact; (3) affect any Indian water rights; or (4) preempt or otherwise affect any State or Federal law or interstate compact regarding water quality or disposal. Prohibits any State acting under authority of this Act from restricting the movement through such State of water acquired in another State and within a coal pipeline. Authorizes certain persons who have received a certification from the Secretary that it is in the national interest to operate or extend a coal pipeline to acquire rights-of-way through private lands by the power of eminent domain. States this Act shall not be construed to permit any person (including the United States) to acquire any water rights through the power of eminent domain. Prohibits the acquisition of any right-of-way through the power of eminent domain if such right-of-way is upon land which is part of a historic site of national, State, or local significance, unless there is no prudent alternative and reasonable planning is made to minimize harm to such site. Provides for an antitrust review of applications for certification by the Attorney General. Requires each pipeline carrier for which a certification has been issued to provide service on reasonable request. Prohibits such carriers from unreasonably discriminating or refusing to enter into contracts with coal shippers under similar conditions in a contemporaneous period. Requires the Secretary to publish notice of coal pipeline certifications in the Federal Register. States that this Act shall not be construed to modify or preempt the ratemaking authority of any State utility regulatory agency. Mandates that every certified coal pipeline carrier record a map indicating pipeline location and extension in each State it crosses, within one year following completion of coal pipeline construction. Requires the Secretary to establish uniform Federal standards for coal pipeline safety. Establishes penalties for failure to comply with such safety standards.</summary>
</bill>
