<bill session="100" type="h" number="1548" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-05">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">California Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">California Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">California Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to withdraw certain Federal lands in the State of California for military purposes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402159"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400401" joined="1987-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Military Installations and Facilities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD, Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-332 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-10-05" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-10-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of Defense, Department of the Interior, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Interior Department. Favorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-05">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Defense Department, Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-634.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSAS04" subcommittee="Military Installations and Facilities" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Military training"/>
    <term name="Navy"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Weapons"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) California Military Lands Withdrawal Act of 1987 - Withdraws from appropriation under the public land laws and reserves for military use by the Secretary of the Navy specified lands in California known as the China Lake Naval Weapons Center in Inyo, Kern, and San Bernardino Counties and Chocolate Mountain in Imperial County. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to manage such lands' nonmilitary uses, subject to closure by the Secretary of the Navy for security or safety purposes. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to develop, within three years, a management plan for such lands. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to prevent and suppress brush and range fires with reimbursable assistance from the Bureau of Land Management. Requires the Secretaries to enter into a memorandum of understanding concerning the management plan which includes the provision of fire control assistance upon request. Requires the Secretary of Defense to notify the Secretary of the Interior whenever withdrawn lands are being used for defense-related purposes other than those specified, including the effect of such different use. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to delegate management responsibilities for China Lake to the Secretary of the Navy. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to report annually to the Secretary of the Interior, who shall then report to the appropriate congressional committees on the status of natural and cultural resources on such withdrawn lands. Makes the Secretary of the Navy responsible for the management of wild horses and burros on such lands. Terminates land withdrawals under this Act 15 years after this Act's enactment. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to publish a draft environmental impact statement on the continued or renewed withdrawal of lands under this Act. Requires such Secretary to hold a public hearing in California before the withdrawal's termination. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to maintain a decontamination program for such lands during their withdrawal. Requires the Secretary to report annually to the appropriate congressional committees on such decontamination efforts. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to notify the Secretary of the Interior, at least three years before the termination of the withdrawal, whether an extension is going to be requested and, if not, to what extent such lands are contaminated with hazardous materials. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to decontaminate relinquished lands, but if such decontamination is not practicable or economically feasible, authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to refuse to accept such lands. Requires the Secretary of the Navy to then: (1) warn the public of risks of entry; (2) conduct only decontamination activities on such lands after the expiration of the withdrawal; and (3) report to the Secretary of the Interior and the Congress on the status of such lands. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to publish the acceptance of withdrawn lands, indicating when such lands will be open and under what conditions. Exempts the United States from liability for injuries or damages resulting from nonmilitary activity on withdrawn lands. Authorizes an extension of the Navy's use of the El Centro Ranges in Imperial County, California, through 1989, subject to resource protection requirements. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to complete land exchanges between the Nature Conservancy and the Bureau of Land Management concerning the Coachella Valley Preserve. Continues the status of the U.S. Marine Corps Mountain Warfare Training Center in the Toiyabe National Forest, California, as both a training center and as part of such Forest, subject to resource protection requirements.</summary>
</bill>
