<bill session="100" type="h" number="1589" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Select Consolidations Act of 1986</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase Government economy and improve efficiency and to reduce the deficit by implementing certain recommendations of the President's Private Sector Survey on Cost Control relating to the consolidation of certain Department of Defense operations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="401203" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403476" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409219" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410010" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410641" joined="1987-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Military airlift"/>
    <term name="Military and naval supplies"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military transportation"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/1987--Introduced.
Defense Select Consolidations Act of 1986 - Title I: Consolidation and Administration of Depot Level Maintenance - Defines "depot level maintenance facility" as a Department of Defense (DOD) facility in which certain maintenance functions are performed and for which there is an extensive capital investment for the performance of such functions. Directs the Secretary of Defense, no later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to designate a single manager in DOD to be responsible for the administration of depot level maintenance facilities. Requires the manager, no later than two years after the enactment of this Act, to develop and implement a plan for the consolidation of: (1) depot level maintenance facilities; and (2) the performance of management functions related to such facilities. Requires such plans to be submitted to both the Secretary of Defense and the Inspector General of DOD. Requires the Inspector General to review such plan and make appropriate comments and recommendations to the Secretary. Directs the Secretary, no later than 90 days before the implementation of the plan commences, to submit the plan, together with the Inspector General's comments, to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees. Outlines the functions and control to be exercised by the manager. Directs the Secretaries of the military departments to consult with and make budget requests through the manager for the performance of depot level maintenance functions. Title II: Consolidation of Wholesale Depot Facilities - Defines "wholesale depot facility" as a DOD facility that receives, stores, and issues bulk quantities of materials to the ultimate user of the material. Directs the Secretary of Defense, no later than 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to designate a single manager in DOD to be responsible for the administration and operation of wholesale depot facilities. Requires the manager, no later than two years after the enactment of this Act, to develop and implement a plan for the consolidation of: (1) wholesale depot facilities; and (2) the performance of management functions related to such facilities. Requires such plan to be submitted to both the Secretary of Defense and the Inspector General of DOD. Requires the Inspector General to review such plan and make appropriate comments and recommendations to the Secretary. Directs the Secretary, no later than 90 days before the implementation of the plan commences, to submit the plan, together with the Inspector General's comments, to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees. Title III: Consolidation of Base Support Operations - Defines "base support operations" as various services provided in connection with military bases and installations. Directs the military departments to participate in the Defense Retail Interservice Support Program of the Department of Defense (the Program). Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) encourage consolidation of base support operations under the Program in all geographic areas in which there are two or more military installations located within 50 miles of each other; (2) utilize the Program to develop other specified consolidation of base support operations; and (3) submit to the Congress each year, at the same time the President's budget is submitted, the cost of base support operations performed under contract and a summary of planned actions to consolidate and reduce the cost of such operations. Title IV: Unification of Traffic Management - Directs the Secretary of Defense, no later than one year after the enactment of this Act, to establish a unified traffic management command to assume all traffic management functions assigned to the Military Traffic Command, the Military Sealift Command, and the Military Airlift Command. Requires the Secretary, within 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to develop and transmit to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees a plan to establish the unified traffic management command. Repeals a provision of the Department of Defense Authorization Act, 1983 which prohibits the consolidation of the military transportation commands.</summary>
</bill>
