<bill session="100" type="h" number="1623" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 17, United States Code, to implement the Berne Convention for the Protection of Literary and Artistic Works, as revised at Paris on July 24, 1971, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1987-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1987-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1988-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1987-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.4262 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2962"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4262"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright royalties"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1987--Introduced.
Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1987 - Amends the copyright law to implement the Berne Convention, the Convention for the Protection of Literary and Artistic Works, signed at Berne on September 9, 1886. Extends copyright protection to architectural works in conformance with such Convention. Extends comparable copyright protection to protectable works of nationals of Berne Union members. Establishes independent authorship rights (moral rights) in copyrighted works, entitling an author or successor in interest to claim authorship and object to distortions or mutilations of such work. Revises provisions concerning the licensing of coin-operated phonorecord players (jukeboxes). Permits copyright owners and operators of jukeboxes to directly negotiate the terms and royalty rates for performing copyrighted works if the Copyright Royalty Tribunal certifies that, over a one year period after this Act's enactment, such process has resulted in authorizing the use of a not substantially smaller quantity of work. Suspends the ratemaking activities of the Tribunal while such conditions are being met. Permits an author to waive or transfer moral rights. Limits the protection of architectural works to artistic character and design, not materials. Permits building owners to modify an architectural work to enhance utility without the copyright holder's or author's consent. Permits the use of a notice of copyright on publicly distributed copies of protected works, including phonorecords of sound recordings (current law requires such notice). States that such a notice is a bar to a defense of innocent infringement if the defendant had access to copies with such notice. Requires the continued use of a copyright notice identifying works of the U.S. Government. Eliminates notice provisions for contributions to collective works. Retains deposit requirements. Continues permissive registration. Entitles an author or author's successor to remedies such as injunctive relief, damages, profits, costs, or attorney's fees for violations of moral rights. Makes this Act effective the day after the Berne Convention enters into force with respect to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
