<bill session="100" type="h" number="1631" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aleutian and Pribilof Islands Restitution Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Aleutian and Pribilof Islands Restitution Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to accept the findings and implement the recommendations of the Commission on Wartime and Internment of Civilians with respect to the Aleut people.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1987-10-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on The Judiciary. Report No: 100-372.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 231.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaskan natives"/>
    <term name="Asian American ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Concentration camps"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government property"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/1987--Reported to House amended.
(Reported to House from the Committee on the Judiciary with amendment, H. Rept. 100-372) Aleutian and Pribilof Islands Restitution Act - Establishes within the Treasury the Aleutian and Pribilof Islands Restitution Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to appoint the Aleutian/Pribilof Island Association (or another person after consultation with leaders of affected Aleut villages and the Aleut Corporation) as the Administrator of the Fund. Directs the Secretary to make restitution for certain Aleut losses sustained in World War II. Requires the Secretary to: (1) establish a trust in the Fund; (2) designate trustees; and (3) deposit $5,000,000 in the trust. Allows the trustees to use the principal, interest, and other earnings of the trust for: (1) the benefit of the elderly, disabled, or seriously ill; (2) students in need of scholarship assistance; (3) the preservation of Aleut cultural heritage and historical records; (4) the improvement of community centers in affected Aleut villages; and (5) other purposes to improve Aleut life. Directs the Administrator to make an inventory and assessment of church property damaged or destroyed in Aleut villages during World War II. Directs the Secretary to provide compensation for such losses. Directs the Secretary to make payments of $12,000 from the Fund to eligible Aleuts. Provides that such payments shall not be considered income or resources for the purposes of Federal taxes or determining eligibility for Federal benefits or assistance. Directs the Secretary to provide compensation for the Aleuts' loss of lands on Attu Island. Sets forth procedures for determining the amount of such compensation. Allows the Secretary to convey the traditional Aleut village site on Attu Islands, Alaska, to the Aleut Corporation. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
