<bill session="100" type="h" number="1649" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Waste Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a requirement that no person may offer any high-level radioactive waste for transportation in interstate commerce unless licensed for such offering by the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404869"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1987--Introduced.
Nuclear Waste Transportation Act - Prohibits any person from offering high-level radioactive waste for transportation in interstate commerce unless a license to do so has been obtained from the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (the Commission). Prohibits any person from transporting such waste in interstate commerce unless: (1) an order designating the transportation route for such waste has been received from the Commission; and (2) such radioactive waste has been received from a person licensed by the Commission under this Act. Prescribes the guidelines under which the Commission is authorized to issue licenses to offer high-level radioactive wastes for transportation. Requires the Commission to: (1) provide written notification of such license applications to political subdivisions and Indian tribes through whose territories such waste may be transported; (2) solicit comments from the chief official of such affected areas with regard to the routing of such wastes; (3) issue an order to the transporter designating the transportation route for such waste after considering the information provided by the appropriate chief official; and (4) forward a copy of such order to such official. Requires a licensee under this Act to inform any chief official of the: (1) date of such radioactive waste transportation; and (2) emergency response procedures to be implemented in case of an accident. Requires such information to be furnished at least ten days prior to the transportation date. Authorizes the Commission to determine whether a license under this Act shall be effective for a single shipment or for a series of similar shipments from the same location. Prohibits any license from being effective for more than one year. Subjects violators of this Act to certain civil penalties under the Atomic Energy Act of 1954.</summary>
</bill>
