<bill session="100" type="h" number="1651" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intellectual Property Anti-Piracy and Market Access Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 17, United States Code, to improve international copyright protection, and to amend title 35, United States Code, to improve international patent and trademark protection.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-08-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1987--Introduced.
Intellectual Property Anti-Piracy and Market Access Act - Amends the copyright and patent laws to direct the U.S. Trade Representative to list all foreign countries and instrumentalities that deny adequate and effective protection of copyright, patent, and trademark rights to U.S. persons, specifying which countries are priority foreign countries based upon their practices and the potential market for U.S. products. Requires the President to negotiate with the priority foreign countries to establish adequate and effective protection for U.S. persons' rights. Directs the President to take action, such as terminating, withdrawing, or suspending any portion of a trade agreement or duty-free treatment, if unable to reach an agreement on such issues. Authorizes the President to defer such actions upon certifying to the Congress that negotiations are making substantial progress. Requires the President to consult with the Register of Copyrights, the Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks, and interested congressional Members and committees and to keep them informed of priorities, progress, and possible U.S. concessions.</summary>
</bill>
