<bill session="100" type="h" number="1661" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Export Trading Company Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend certain provisions of the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 relating to export trading companies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1987-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>See H.R.3.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA07" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Export trading companies"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1987--Introduced.
Export Trading Company Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Bank Holding Company Act of 1956 to set forth the following additional factors to be considered in determining whether a company is an "export trading company": (1) the operations of such company during the first two years shall not be taken into account in making such determination; (2) not less than four consecutive years of operations of such company (not including the first two years of operation) shall not be taken into account in such determination; and (3) fees derived from the facilitation, outside of the United States, of trade services shall be treated as revenue derived from exporting or facilitating exports to the extent the fees are remitted to the United States and the aggregate amount of such fees does not exceed one-half the amount of revenue derived from export operations or the facilitation of export services. Defines "facilitation of trade services." Prohibits the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System from disapproving a proposed investment solely on the basis of the proposed asset-to-equity ratio of the export trading company unless the proposed annual average ratio is greater than 15 to one. Prohibits the Board from establishing a maximum dollar limit on the value of goods which export trading companies may maintain in inventory. Authorizes the Board to establish a maximum dollar limit on the value of goods which an export trading company may maintain in inventory if the Board finds that such limitation is necessary to prevent risks that would affect the financial or managerial resources of an investor bank holding company.</summary>
</bill>
