<bill session="100" type="h" number="1679" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acid Deposition Control Act of 1985</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to control certain sources of sulfur dioxide to reduce acid deposition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402484"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid precipitation (Meteorology)"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Copper"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sulphur oxides"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
Acid Deposition Control Act of 1985 - Title I: Acid Deposition Control Program - Amends the Clean Air Act to establish an interstate transport and acid precursor reduction program. Designates an acid deposition impact region comprising a long-range transport corridor of 31 States east of the Mississippi and the District of Columbia. Sets forth sulfur dioxide emission reduction standards for such region of ten million tons below 1980 levels by the end of 1997. Requires such reduction to be accomplished in two phases, half the reductions to be made by the start of 1993. Directs the Acid Precipitation Task Force to conduct an accelerated research program during the first phase, examining the pattern of effects of atmospheric loading of pollutants such as sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides. Authorizes appropriations through FY 1991, the program itself to be completed by the start of 1991. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to evaluate the results by July 1, 1992. Authorizes the Administrator to change the second phase of the reduction program, based upon first-phase research, in any of the following areas: (1) excluding or including States; (2) restricting reallotment of reductions among States; (3) altering individual State or aggregate targets; and (4) requiring reduction of nitrogen oxide emissions. Requires alterations to be made through public rule-making and after notice to the Congress, demonstrating increased protection. Requires impact region States to reduce their sulfur dioxide emissions in two phases to achieve a rate of no more than 1.2 pounds of sulfur dioxide per million British thermal units (Btus). Grants credits for reductions achieved after 1980 and permits States to reallot reductions among themselves unless otherwise prohibited. Requires State Governors to submit to the Administrator for approval two-phase reduction plans and compliance schedules. Directs the Administrator to establish reduction standards for any major source in noncompliance with its own plan or in a State without an acceptable emissions reduction plan. Requires owners or operators of major sources of sulfur dioxide emissions to submit to the Administrator reduction plans for such emissions if their State does not have an approved plan. States that failure to do so constitutes an emissions violation. Sets forth alternative methods of maintaining emissions limitations in addition to enforceable continuous emission reduction measures if such measures are enforceable by entities and persons other than the State in which the emissions occur: (1) least emissions dispatch to meet electric generating demand at existing generating capacity; (2) retirement of major stationary sources at an earlier than provided for date; (3) investments in energy conservation where emission reductions can be identified with such investments; (4) trading of emission reduction requirements and actual reductions through emission reduction banks or brokerage institutions; (5) precombustion cleaning of fuels; and (6) fuel substitution. Directs the President and the Secretary of State to negotiate emissions reductions with the Governments of Canada and Mexico to protect U.S. air from pollution from foreign sources. Prohibits the importation of electricity from Canada until comparable progress is made on sulfur dioxide emission reductions. Requires the President and Secretary to seek the installation of air pollution control equipment on Mexican copper and other metal smelters. Directs the President to report periodically to the Congress on progress made. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress within four years on a study of long-range transport of pollutant problems in the remaining States. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress on the emission limitation and enforceable measures adopted by the States or major stationary sources and approved by the Administrator. Directs the Administrator to develop and report to the Congress within four years on an inventory of sources of oxides of nitrogen in the impact region, control methods, and recommendations for emissions standards. Requires all primary nonferrous smelters previously granted an order (exemption) from sulfur oxides emission limitations to be in compliance by January 2, 1988.</summary>
</bill>
