<bill session="100" type="h" number="1680" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Housing Energy Conservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to establish energy conservation standards for public housing projects and to carry out a program to demonstrate the effectiveness of energy conservation measures in public housing projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
Public Housing Energy Conservation Act - Directs the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development, within one year of enactment of this Act, to: (1) establish public housing energy conservation performance standards; and (2) revise public housing construction cost limits to reflect structural life-cycle costs and major heating and cooling systems. Requires public housing development and rehabilitation programs begun one year after enactment of this Act to incorporate such standards. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide financial assistance to the Chicago Housing Authority in the State of Illinois to implement public housing energy conservation measures; and (2) report annually to the Congress. Authorizes FY 1987 through 1991 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
