<bill session="100" type="h" number="1697" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to assist States in responding to the threat to human health posed by exposure to radon.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406994"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1987-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400300" joined="1987-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1987-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="411948" joined="1987-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radon"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to develop and implement activities to assist State radon programs such as: (1) establishing an information clearinghouse; (2) designing and implementing training seminars for government officials; (3) demonstrating radon mitigation methods; and (4) establishing a national data base on the location and amounts of radon. Authorizes the Administrator to provide a State with technical assistance in developing or implementing programs addressing radon, including: (1) surveys of radon location and occurrence; (2) public information programs; and (3) controlling radon in existing or new structures. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress annually on a plan to implement this assistance program. Authorizes the Administrator to make grants to States on an annual basis for radon assessment and mitigation, covering the same types of activities the Administrator may provide directly through technical assistance. Grants priority to State projects which involve serious radon contamination or potential for reduction, including the development of innovative techniques. Limits the Federal share of costs to 75 percent. Limits per State grants to 15 percent of the total funds available. Places other limitations on the uses of grant money. Directs the Administrator to study the extent of radon contamination in the Nation's school buildings, including a statistical survey of radon levels and a list of school districts where radon levels probably exceed target levels for remedial action. Authorizes the Administrator to provide technical assistance, information, and equipment to States for conducting radon tests. Authorizes the Administrator to undertake diagnostic and remedial effects at high radon level school buildings to develop the necessary technology. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress annually for two years on activities under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
