<bill session="100" type="h" number="1776" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Health Care Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide long-term care benefits under the medicare program and to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a deduction of premiums paid for long-term care policies and to permit pension plans to provide similar long-term care benefits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403203"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402833" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="403529" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405409" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400191" joined="1987-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1987-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Intermediate care facilities"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Long-Term Health Care Amendments of 1987 - Title I: Medicare Long-term Care Benefits - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to add a new part C entitled "Long-Term Care Benefit Program." (Redesignates the current part C as part D.) Provides coverage for the home health services and nursing care required by individuals who are eligible for part A (Hospital Insurance) benefits. Sets forth the formula for determining the long-term care deductible for a calendar year. Conditions payment of long-term care providers on: (1) such providers making written requests for payment within three years of furnishing service; and (2) a physician's certification that the beneficiary needs or needed nursing facility care or home health services, and that home health services are or were furnished while the individual is or was under a physician's care. Prohibits physician's who have a significant ownership interest in, or a significant financial or contractual relationship with, a home health agency from performing such a certification of the agency, unless it is a sole community home health agency. Pays providers the lesser of the reasonable cost or the customary charges for part C services. Prohibits part C payments: (1) to Federal providers; and (2) for services for which an individual is entitled to be paid under part A of the Medicare program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase hospital insurance tax rates and reduce old age, survivors and disability insurance tax rates for taxable years beginning with 1988. Includes nursing care furnished under the supervision of a registered or licensed professional nurse as well as care provided in a skilled nursing or intermediate care facility within the scope of nursing facility care. Requires the Board of Directors of the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund to provide for a separate accounting of the additional taxes deposited into such fund by reason of this Act and the disbursements from such fund for part C benefits. Makes Medicare the primary payor where part C benefits are also covered under employment-related group health plans. Title II: Incentives for Individuals to Purchase Long-Term Care Insurance - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individuals to deduct certain qualified long-term care insurance premiums they have paid on behalf of eligible beneficiaries. Defines a "qualified long-term care insurance policy" as a policy certified by the Secretary of Health and Human Services and providing coverage for diagnostic, preventive, therapeutic, rehabilitative, maintenance, or personal care services provided in a setting other than a hospital acute care unit. Title III: Incentives for Employers to Provide Group Long-Term Care - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide that a trust forming part of a pension plan shall not be treated as a nonqualified trust merely because such plan covers qualified long-term health care of employees or retired employees.</summary>
</bill>
