<bill session="100" type="h" number="1784" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Major Export Market Trade Equity Act of 1985</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend, under certain circumstances, nondiscriminatory treatment to the products of nonmarket economy countries that are currently ineligible for such treatment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Major Export Market Trade Equity Act of 1985 - Extends to an otherwise ineligible nonmarket economy country nondiscriminatory treatment (most-favored-nation treatment) during any market year after 1985 if the President determines that: (1) the country either has the potential to become a major export market for U.S. products which nondiscriminatory treatment will enhance, or is already such a market; (2) during the corresponding calendar year that country will not receive nondiscriminatory treatment for its products under any other U.S. law; and (3) during the preceding calendar year that country had a negative trade balance with the United States. Requires the President to determine those nonmarket economy countries eligible for such treatment before the start of each market year after 1985 and to publish a list of such countries in the Federal Register.</summary>
</bill>
