<bill session="100" type="h" number="1792" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to give the Board of Parole for the District of Columbia exclusive power and authority to make parole determinations concerning prisoners convicted of violating any law of the District of Columbia, or any law of the United States applicable exclusively to the District.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403695"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Empowers the Board of Parole for the District of Columbia with exclusive authority to release on parole, terminate the parole of, and to modify the terms and conditions of the parole of any prisoner convicted for violating a District of Columbia law or a Federal law applicable exclusively to the District. Requires that individuals convicted of violating both a law of the District of Columbia and a law of the United States shall be given separate and distinct sentences for such convictions. Provides that the United States Parole Commission shall retain parole authority over individuals who, prior to the date of enactment of this Act, received unified sentences for violations of both a law of the District of Columbia and a law of the United States. Requires, within one year after enactment of this Act, the Board of Parole for the District of Columbia to make parole eligibility determinations and set a date for full parole hearings for all individuals brought within the parole authority of such Board under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
