<bill session="100" type="h" number="179" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Education for Homeless Children Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the General Education Provisions Act to assure full and equal educational opportunities for homeless children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406740"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="402100" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404019" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1987-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1987-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406730" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1987-02-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="408313" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409344" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1987-01-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED01" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Education for Homeless Children Act of 1987 - Amends the General Education Provisions Act to condition receipt of assistance under any applicable program on State or local education agency compliance with the requirements of this Act. Requires each State education agency to adopt and implement a plan to ensure that each homeless child within the State is provided full and equal educational opportunities. Requires each local education agency to ensure that qualified personnel interview families and children in temporary housing within their district to determine the educational needs of homeless children. Prohibits any State or local residency requirement from barring any homeless child from attending school. Requires the local education agency where the child is living, subject to the best interest of the child, to: (1) continue the child's education in the district of origin for the remainder of the school year; or (2) enroll the child in the school district where the child is actually living. Makes such choice available regardless of whether the child is living with homeless parents or has been temporarily placed elsewhere by the parents. Requires that each homeless child be provided with adequate transportation to the school selected. Requires that the records of each homeless child be maintained so that they are immediately available when a child enters a new school district. Requires the local educational agency to ensure that each homeless child may participate in all educational programs and services.</summary>
</bill>
