<bill session="100" type="h" number="1795" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Partnership for Educational Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Federal, State, and local partnership for educational innovation in elementary and secondary education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400586"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1987-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-22">
      <text>See H.R.5.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED01" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Partnership for Educational Innovation Act - Chapter 1: Federal, State, and Local Partnership - Sets forth this Act's short title and table of contents. Chapter 2: Partnership for Educational Innovation - States that the purpose of this Act is to: (1) provide funding to enable State and local educational agencies to implement promising educational programs; (2) place responsibility for the administration of funds with State agencies; and (3) enhance the quality of teaching and learning. Part A: State and Local Programs - Subpart 1: Funding - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1993 to carry out the provisions of this Act. Sets forth the method for determining a State's allotment and the basis for the State's allocation to local educational agencies. Provides that not more than 20 percent of such allotment shall be used for statewide educational agencies. Subpart 2: State Programs - Sets forth the application requirements for any State which desires to receive allotments under this Act. Lists the activities for which such allotments may be used, including: (1) State administration of programs under this Act; (2) technical assistance and direct grants for local educational agencies and statewide activities; and (3) assistance to carry out "effective school programs." Subpart 3: Local Programs - Sets forth the application requirements for any local educational agency which desires to receive an allocation of funds under this Act. Grants the local educational agency complete discretion in determining how funds for local programs shall be divided among the authorized purposes of this subpart. Allows such funds to be used for: (1) programs and projects to meet the educational needs of at-risk and high cost children; (2) "effective schools programs and activities"; (3) innovative instructional programs and materials; (4) personnel enhancement; and (5) other special projects. Subpart 4: Effective Schools Programs - Defines "effective schools programs" as school-based programs that have the objective of: (1) promoting school-level planning, instructional improvement, and staff development; (2) increasing the academic achievements of children; and (3) achieving specified conditions in the school which stress the achievement of instructional goals and a safe and orderly school environment. Subpart 5: General Provisions - Sets forth provisions to ensure a maintenance of effort between State and Federal expenditures for educational programs, and for the participation of children enrolled in private schools. Sets forth reporting requirements for local educational agencies, State educational agencies, and the Secretary of Education. Grants the Secretary authority to issue regulations to ensure compliance with the requirements of this Act. Part B: National Programs and Activities - Authorizes the Secretary to carry out directly or through grants and contracts with State and local educational agencies specified educational projects and programs. Part C: General Provisions - Repeals Chapter 2 (Consolidation of Federal Programs for Elementary and Secondary Education) of the Education Consolidation and Improvement Act.</summary>
</bill>
