<bill session="100" type="h" number="1809" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Aid and Trade Missions Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish agricultural aid and trade missions to assist foreign countries to participate in United States agricultural aid and trade programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406191" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408575" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>See H.R.3.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04">
      <text>Favorable Executive Comment Received From State.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG04" subcommittee="Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American agricultural assistance"/>
    <term name="Commodity agreements"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Farm produce"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Agricultural Aid and Trade Missions Act - Title I: Agricultural Aid and Trade Missions - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of State, and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development to jointly establish agricultural aid and trade missions to eligible countries to encourage such countries to participate in U.S. agricultural aid and trade programs. Outlines administrative provisions concerning the composition and compensation of the U.S. representatives to such missions. Requires the establishment of seven missions within six months, and an additional eight missions within one year after enactment of this Act. Authorizes additional future missions. Requires members of such missions to: (1) meet with representatives of government agencies of the United States and the eligible country to plan the extent to which U.S. agricultural aid and trade programs could be used in a mutually beneficial manner; (2) provide technical expertise and information with respect to U.S. agricultural aid and trade programs and agricultural commodities and other assistance available to the eligible country; and (3) assist in obtaining firm commitments for proposals for food aid programs and agreements for commodity sales under agriculture export programs. Directs each mission, no later than 60 days after its completion, to report to the President, the Agriculture Committees of the Congress, the House Committee on Foreign Affairs, the Secretary of Agriculture, the Secretary of State, and the Administrator on its findings and recommendations in carrying out the purposes of this Act. Requires the Secretaries and the Administrator to jointly submit progress reports to the appropriate congressional committees during the two-year period beginning one year after enactment of this Act. Authorizes the use of the Commodity Credit Corporation to carry out the purposes of this Act. Title II: Expansion of Agricultural Exports and Markets - Subtitle A: Amendments to Title II of the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 - Amends the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 (ATDAA) to exempt nonemergency programs conducted by nonprofit voluntary agencies or cooperatives from any limitation on the generation and use of foreign currencies as a condition for obtaining assistance under ATDAA. Increases from five to ten percent of the aggregate value of the commodities distributed under nonemergency programs the amount that shall be used as foreign currency proceeds. Specifies uses of foreign currency proceeds from the sale or barter of commodities by such an agency or cooperative. Directs the President, no later than 45 days after submission, to take final action on a proposal submitted by a nonprofit voluntary agency or cooperative, with the concurrence of the field mission, for the delivery of commodities requested. Directs the President, no later than 30 days prior to the issuance of a final guideline issued to carry out title II of ATDAA, to provide notice of the proposed guideline to participating nonprofit agencies and cooperatives and to make such guideline available for review and comment. Subtitle B: Amendments to Section 416 of the Agricultural Act of 1949 - Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 (the Act, for purposes of this Subtitle) to specify wheat, rice, and feed grains acquired by the Commodity Credit Corporation through price support operations as eligible commodities for agricultural assistance programs under title II of ATDAA. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make available to nonprofit and voluntary agencies and cooperatives in a country commodities that are made available to such country as a country friendly to the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to approve multiyear agreements to make commodities available for distribution or sale by recipients under the Act. Outlines the authorized uses of foreign currencies generated from commodities distributed under the Act, and increases from five to ten percent of the aggregate value of commodities and products furnished for assistance programs the amount to be obtained from the sale of such commodities and products for foreign currency proceeds. Directs the Secretary, no later than 45 days after submission, to take final action on a proposal submitted by a nonprofit and voluntary agency or cooperative, with the concurrence of the field mission, for the delivery of commodities requested. Directs the Secretary, no later than 30 days prior to the issuance of a final guideline issued to carry out the Act, to provide notice of the proposed guideline to participating nonprofit agencies and cooperatives and to make such guideline available for review and comment. Increases the minimum quantities of eligible commodities that shall be made available by the Commodity Credit Corporation for distribution under the Act. Subtitle C: Foreign Agricultural Service - Specifies the authorized number of personnel for the Foreign Agricultural Service for FY 1987 through 1989 for the performance of the various agricultural export programs of the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with individuals abroad as determined necessary for the performance of export-market enhancement activities. Provides that any such individuals used shall be considered non-Federal employees. Subtitle D: Miscellaneous - Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to authorize multiyear agreements under the food for progress program. Directs the Secretary, no later than December 31, 1987, to report to the Agriculture Committees of the Congress and the House Committee on Foreign Affairs on the use of authority provided under the Food for Peace Act of 1966 to provide intermediate credit financing for the establishment of facilities in the importing countries which would: (1) improve the handling, processing, and distribution of imported agricultural commodities; (2) increase livestock production; and (3) increase markets for U.S. livestock and livestock products. Amends the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 to include the promotion of conservation and study of biological diversity among the self-help measures set forth under such Act.</summary>
</bill>
