<bill session="100" type="h" number="1847" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal Law and Procedure Minor Substantive and Technical Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make minor substantive and technical amendments to title 18, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400080"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Criminal Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.2182 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU07" subcommittee="Criminal Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2182"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gambling and Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grand jury"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Self-incrimination"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/1987--Introduced.
Criminal Law and Procedure Minor Substantive and Technical Amendments Act of 1987 - Makes technical and conforming amendments to the Federal criminal code. Provides increased criminal penalties where a bodily injury results during the commission of the crime of deprivation of rights under color of law. Grants the Associate Attorney General authority to: (1) approve certain civil rights prosecutions; (2) approve prosecutions for flight to avoid service of process; (3) summon special grand juries; (4) request a judicial grant of immunity; and (5) object to the disclosure of classified information under the Classified Information Procedures Act. Grants specially designated Assistant Attorneys General authority to approve certain civil rights prosecutions. Grants the Deputy Assistant Attorney General authority to request judicial grants of immunity. Permits the transmission of information on sports betting from a State where such betting is legal to a foreign country where such betting is legal. Permits prosecutions for certain obstruction of justice offenses to be brought in the district where the official proceeding was intended to be affected or in the district in which the conduct constituting the alleged offense occurred.</summary>
</bill>
