<bill session="100" type="h" number="1853" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Worker Readjustment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title III of the Job Training Partnership Act to improve the delivery of services under that title to rural areas, particularly to dislocated farmers and ranchers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404869"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="401628" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="402747" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404723" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="406799" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409651" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="410097" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="410641" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411585" joined="1987-03-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Employment Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED06" subcommittee="Employment Opportunities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural industries"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Census and Statistics"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Labor statistics"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/30/1987--Introduced.
Rural Worker Readjustment Act - Amends title III of the Job Training Partnership Act to allow the Secretary of Labor to use discretionary funds to provide assistance to individuals who are affected by economic downturns, such as those occurring in the agriculture industry. Allows the Governor of any State receiving allocations under such Act to reserve up to 30 percent for: (1) administration, technical assistance, and coordination; and (2) rapid response capabilities and for programs addressing statewide or regional displacement problems. Requires the remainder of funds to be distributed according to a formula established by the Governor, in consultation with the State advisory council. Subjects such formula to approval by the Secretary. Lists types of information which must be considered when establishing such a formula. Allows a farmer or rancher to be identified as an eligible dislocated worker if: (1) the operation of the farm or ranch will terminate because of one or more listed events (foreclosure, failure to return a profit during the preceding 12 months, bankruptcy proceedings, the inability to obtain necessary capital, the failure to make payments on loans secured by farm premises, or total debts exceeding 70 percent of total farm assets); or (2) the farmer or rancher is determined to leave farming or ranching because of excessive debts. Requires each State to ensure the establishment of a rapid response capability. Requires funds allotted by the Governor under such Act to be allotted among service providers to: (1) establish centers to provide for the comprehensive delivery of authorized services; and (2) insure the delivery such services to dislocated workers. Requires each service provider to submit a biennial plan to the Governor describing its programs, activities, and goals. Expands the authorized activities which may be provided under such Act to include: (1) basic education and occupational skills assessment; (2) literacy skills assessment; (3) basic, remedial and literacy education; and (4) the establishment and maintenance of rapid response capabilities. Allows a substate grantee to provide support services to participants if necessary to facilitate participation in an authorized program. Directs the Secretary to develop a means by which statistical data relating to rural unemployment can be collected and to publish a report based on such data.</summary>
</bill>
