<bill session="100" type="h" number="1871" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-04">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Developmental Disabilities Assistance Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Developmental Disabilities Assistance Extension Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Developmental Disabilities Assistance Extension Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act to extend the programs established in such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-01">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Energy and Commerce.  Report No: 100-265.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 167.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-08-04" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Laid on Table in House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>House Incorporated this Measure in S.1417 as an Amendment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1417"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed house, amended) Developmental Disabilities Assistance Extension Act of 1987 - Amends the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990 for: (1) State allotments for services to persons with developmental disabilities; (2) State allotments for a system to protect and advocate the rights of persons with developmental disabilities; (3) grants to university affiliated facilities for conducting studies regarding establishment of facilities, providing service-related training to parents, or conducting applied research on service delivery and professional training; and (4) grants for demonstration projects. Adds family support services to the definition of priority services. Revises the definition of supported employment of persons with developmental disabilities. Allows States, at their discretion, in their plan for the provision of services for persons with developmental disabilities, to provide for more than one priority service or for one or more of a list of optional services. Revises the requirements for membership in State Planning Councils to allow immediate relatives and guardians of previously institutionalized as well as of institutionalized persons with developmental disabilities to serve on the Councils. Amends the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act to create a new part relating to a developmental disabilities status report. Requires that, for each of the FY 1988 through 1990, the State plan for the provision of services for persons with developmental disabilities contain assurances that the State, by September 30, 1990, will submit a comprehensive description of: (1) its eligibility standards for the receipt of services by persons with developmental disabilities; (2) the services provided; (3) the extent to which the State is meeting the needs of such persons; (4) the extent to which the State is carrying out the purpose of this title; (5) the recommendations of the State for meeting the needs of all persons with developmental disabilities; and (6) the views of persons with developmental disabilities and the views of advocates for such persons. Requires the State plan to contain assurances that the State will conduct a study to obtain such views of persons with and advocates for persons with developmental disabilities. Requires the State plan to contain, for FY 1989 and 1990, a statement of progress toward completing such comprehensive description.</summary>
</bill>
