<bill session="100" type="h" number="1880" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Greater Opportunities Through Work Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to require States to establish and implement programs designed to afford greater opportunities for AFDC recipients to achieve self-sufficiency through employment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409443"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403203" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403769" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410097" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1987-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-29">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.1720.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Evaluation"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Unemployed"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Work incentive programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1987--Introduced.
Greater Opportunities Through Work Act of 1987 - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of the Social Security Act to require AFDC recipients to participate in employment-related activities. Lists AFDC recipients who are exempt from such participation, including: (1) dependent children under age 16; (2) persons who are ill, incapacitated, or age 60 or older; (3) persons needed at home due to the illness or incapacity of another member of the household; (4) women in their last trimester of pregnancy; (5) mothers with newborns; and (6) drug addicts and alcoholics who are undergoing treatment. Authorizes States to require applicants for AFDC benefits to participate in an employment search program. Directs States to assist AFDC recipients locate a position in one or more employment-related activities, including job search activities, work experience programs, vocational education, and the education necessary for one to earn a high school degree or its equivalent. Requires dependent children and relatives under age 19 with whom such children reside who have no high school degree or its equivalent to receive education as full-time students until such degree or its equivalent is obtained. Authorizes States to require or permit a relative with whom the dependent child resides and who is age 19 or older to participate in such educational activities. Provides that if those required to participate in such educational activities fail to participate they must be referred to another employment-related activity. Requires States to furnish, or reimburse an individual for expenses incurred in arranging, child care, transportation, and other supportive services necessary for the individual's participation in employment-related activities. Imposes sanctions on AFDC recipients who, without good cause: (1) fail to participate actively in employment-related activities to which they had been referred; (2) refuse a bona fide offer of employment in which they are able to engage; or (3) terminate or cut back on their existing employment. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate regulations specifying the conditions under which good cause will be found to exist as well as the periods for which sanctions will be applied. Reduces the Federal share of a States's AFDC expenses if such State fails to involve a specified percentage of nonexempt AFDC recipients in employment-related activities in each fiscal year. Repeals part C (Work Incentive Program) of title IV of the Act. Requires Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam to implement, to the maximum extent feasible, a coordinated program of activities designed to help AFDC recipients achieve self-sufficiency through employment. Authorizes appropriations, beginning in FY 1988, for payments to Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, and Guam for the implementation of such programs. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to research and evaluate the effectiveness of the programs established pursuant to this Act in reducing the welfare dependence of AFDC recipients. Authorizes appropriations from FY 1988 through 1991 for such research and evaluation. Requires the Secretary to issue outcome-based performance standards for State AFDC employment programs within six months of completing such research and evaluation.</summary>
</bill>
