<bill session="100" type="h" number="189" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Lottery Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of the Treasury to establish a national lottery and to provide that not less than 50 percent of the receipts from such lottery be used to reduce the Federal debt.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400544" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1987-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Gambling and Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Lotteries"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
National Lottery Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to establish and operate a national lottery in each State in which such operation is legal. Requires the deposit of 50 percent of lottery receipts into the general fund of the Treasury for the purpose of reducing the Federal debt. Establishes criminal penalties for unauthorized sale of lottery tickets, especially sale of such tickets to minors. Establishes the Lottery Fund for the deposit of receipts to provide prizes for winners, operational costs, and payments to States for their participation in conducting the lottery. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to report annually to the President pro tempore of the Senate and the Speaker of the House of Representatives on: (1) the operation of the lottery during the most recently concluded fiscal year; and (2) the proposed operation during each fiscal year in the five-year period beginning at the end of the most recently concluded fiscal year. Requires the Secretary to notify the Congress when monies in the lottery are inadequate to continue operation.</summary>
</bill>
