<bill session="100" type="h" number="1928" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Trade Competitiveness and Innovation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Small Business Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401446" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300017" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402833" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404401" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405209" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405887" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406994" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407306" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407400" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407519" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407558" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="408342" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400326" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409060" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409165" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409219" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409354" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400609" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409968" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410076" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="1987-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02">
      <text>House incorporated this measure into H.R. 3.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/1987--Introduced.
Small Business Trade Competitiveness and Innovation Act - Amends the Small Business Act to require the Office of International Trade (OIT) to work with relevant Federal agencies, Small Business Development Centers, local Small Business Administration (SBA) offices, small businesses, and State and local export promotion programs to: (1) develop a distribution network for trade promotion, finance, adjustment, and data collection programs through use of the SBA's regional and local offices and the Small Business Development Center (SBDC) network; and (2) market such programs and disseminate marketing information to small businesses. Requires the OIT to promote sales opportunities for small business goods and services abroad by: (1) developing a mechanism for identifying subsectors of the small business community with strong export potential, identifying areas of demand in foreign markets, prescreening foreign buyers for commercial and credit purposes, and disseminating information linking potential sellers and buyers; (2) assisting small businesses in the formation of export trading companies, export management companies, and research and development pools; (3) establishing a pilot program for the provision of translation services; and (4) working with the Department of Commerce to develop data collection systems for small businesses, improve the utility and accessibility of export promotion programs, increase the accessibility of the Export Trading Company facilitating service, and alleviate obstacles in the export licensing system for small high technology companies. Directs the OIT to: (1) work with the Export-Import Bank and small businesses to develop a program to identify, market, and increase the access of small businesses to export financing programs of the Bank and the SBA; (2) establish a Trade Assistance Division to assist small businesses in trade remedy proceedings; and (3) establish a committee to develop mechanisms for providing assistance to small businesses regarding export control policy and export licensing procedures. Directs the OIT to: (1) submit semiannual reports to the House and Senate Committees on Small Business on the implementation of such requirements; and (2) undertake and report to such Committees within six months on specified studies pertaining to small business exports. Authorizes the SBA to provide extensions and revolving lines of credit for export purposes and pre-export financing to small business concerns for periods not exceeding three years. Directs the SBA, when considering loan or guarantee applications, to give weight to export-related benefits. Authorizes additional grants to applicants already funded as SBDCs to be used solely to develop exports by small businesses or to assist in technology transfer. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the use of grant funds by SBDCs for management and technical assistance regarding export promotion and technology transfer. Directs SBDCs to work with the SBA's local offices, small businesses, and appropriate agencies to disseminate information on trade promotion, finance, adjustment, and data collection programs for small businesses. Includes among SBDC services: (1) developing new networks for technology transfer that encourage partnership between the small business and academic communities; (2) assisting small businesses in developing export markets, obtaining export financing, and implementing marketing and production strategies to better compete within the domestic market; (3) developing a program to serve as a distribution network and service delivery mechanism for Bank financing programs; (4) developing computer software for distribution to small firms aimed at enhancing their export capabilities; and (5) making translation services more readily available to small businesses doing business in foreign markets. Requires the Deputy Associate Administrator of the SBDC Program to implement mechanisms for the sharing of information between SBDCs or between SBDCs and program applicants. Directs SBDCs to work with the relevant State agency to develop a comprehensive plan for enhancing the export potential of small businesses in that State. Authorizes the SBA to guarantee industrial mortgage loans not exceeding $1,000,000 to assist small businesses in the production of goods and services involved in international trade where such loans are sold off into the secondary market. Specifies limitations on SBA participation in such loans on a deferred basis. Directs the SBA Administrator to report to the House and Senate Committees on Small Business on: (1) the viability of creating cooperative Federal-State guarantee programs, particularly for purposes of export financing, to encourage States to coinsure Federal loans; (2) amending the Small Business Innovation Research program to increase each agency's share of research and development expenditures and target products with export potential, make the program permanent with a congressional review every ten years, allocate an appropriate share of each agency's program fund for administrative purposes, determine annually each agency's compliance with laws concerning program funding, and create pooled solicitations of subjects submitted by small agencies expending $20,000,000 to $100,000,000 for extramural research and development; and (3) the effect of increased outsourcing on U.S. subcontractors, the impact of specific economic policies in facilitating outsourcing and other internationalized production arrangements, and recommendations for changes in Government policy to improve the competitive position of small U.S. subcontractors. Requires the SBA to conduct a National Conference on Small Business Exports during 1988. Directs the Conference to make recommendations regarding a subsequent International Summit on Small Business and Trade that would help develop a consensus regarding international and national institutional and policy changes necessary to build an international small business sector capable of long-term growth.</summary>
</bill>
