<bill session="100" type="h" number="193" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title I of the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to provide for more useful and effective disclosure by officials of the legislative branch, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Financial disclosure"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to revise financial reporting requirements for officials of the legislative branch. Requires the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct of the House of Representatives and the Select Committee on Ethics of the Senate to establish by March 31 of each odd-numbered year the minimum values of income, aggregate and individual gifts, and reimbursements subject to such reporting requirements based on current amounts that equal the values originally designated in 1978 dollars. Amends House and Senate rules to require the Clerk of the House of Representatives and the Secretary of the Senate, by April 15 of each year, to transmit to each individual subject to such financial reporting requirements a financial disclosure form, the text of such Act, a copy of applicable rules, and any other useful materials. Directs the congressional committees having legislative jurisdiction for the provisions of such Act, as soon as practicable in the 101st Congress, to conduct oversight hearings and report to their respective Houses on: (1) the amendments made by this Act; and (2) the categories of valuation specified for reporting financial information under such Act. Requires the committees to conduct similar reviews of such categories of valuation at least once every ten years thereafter.</summary>
</bill>
