<bill session="100" type="h" number="1946" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">District of Columbia Speedy Trial Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to assist in reducing crime and the danger of recidivism in the District of Columbia by requiring speedy trials in criminal cases in the District of Columbia courts, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404006"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Judiciary and Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSDT03" subcommittee="Judiciary and Education" name="House District of Columbia"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Speedy trial"/>
    <term name="Trials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/1987--Introduced.
District of Columbia Speedy Trial Act - Amends the District of Columbia Code to create a new chapter relating to speedy trials. Establishes time limits for: (1) setting or listing criminal cases for trial; (2) filing informations or indictments; (3) arraigning defendants; (4) refiling of complaints, informations, or indictments; and (5) subject to a specified extension, retrials. Makes transition rules regarding such time limits as they apply to the period between arrest and indictment. Excludes specified types of delays from the computation of such time limits. Specifies factors a judge must consider when determining whether to grant a continuance. States factors which may not serve as reasons for granting a continuance. Establishes rules regarding the: (1) calculation of time limits when a plea of guilty or nolo contendere is subsequently withdrawn; and (2) treatment of persons charged with an offense who are serving a term of imprisonment in any penal institution. Sets sanctions to be imposed for failure to meet such time limits (extended as provided by certain provisions of this Act), including dismissing the complaint, information, or indictment, with or without prejudice. Establishes rules regarding the effective dates of such time limits. Provides for interim time limits in certain circumstances and for a sanction for failure to timely commence trial in such circumstances. Requires the Superior Court to conduct a continuing study of the administration of criminal justice and to adopt, after consultation, a plan for the disposition of criminal cases in accordance with this Act. Authorizes the Court to modify such plan, after consultation, at any time. Requires the plan and any modifications to be forwarded to the Joint Committee on Judicial Administration and the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts. Requires the Court to adopt other plans regarding the disposition of cases during specified periods over four years. Makes the plan adopted under this Act and recommendations of the planning group public documents. Requires the plan to include: (1) specified information regarding the implementation of the time limits of this Act; (2) specified information and statistics concerning the administration of justice; (3) specification of needed rule changes, statutory amendments, and appropriations; and (4) recommendations for reporting forms, procedures, and time requirements. Requires the Superior Court, by specified deadlines, to submit periodic reports to the Congress and to the Council of the District of Columbia detailing the plan. Requires such reports to include recommendations for legislative changes and additional appropriations. Requires the Superior Court, within 60 days of the enactment of this Act, to convene a planning group to advise the Court regarding formulation of plans. Requires the Federal Judicial Center and the Administrative Office of the U.S. Courts to advise and assist the planning group and the Superior Court in regard to their duties under this Act. Sets forth regulations regarding collection and use of certain information required by this Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1978 to carry out the initial phases of planning and implementation of speedy trial plans under this Act. Prohibits expenditure of such funds except by two-thirds vote of the planning group. Authorizes the Chief Judge of the Superior Court, in certain circumstances, to order a suspension or extension of certain time limits imposed by this Act. Places restrictions on any such suspension or extension. Requires the Executive Officer of the District of Columbia courts, within ten days of such an order, to report the order to the Council of the District of Columbia, together with a written report with specified contents. Prohibits the Chief Judge from ordering an additional period of suspension without the consent of the Council, unless the Council fails to act within six months on the Chief Judge's request for such consent.</summary>
</bill>
