<bill session="100" type="h" number="1943" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIDS Public Information Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program of block grants to the States for the purpose of providing to the public information with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/6/1987--Introduced.
AIDS Public Information Act - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to make allotments to each State each fiscal year for providing to the public information relating to diagnosis, prevention, and control of acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Prohibits such allotments unless the State agrees to establish and carry out a program of tracing contacts of those exposed to AIDS. Provides a formula for determining the amount of such allotments. Requires the Secretary to allot, using a similar formula, any funds made available in appropriations Acts for allotments, if such allotments are not made because a State does not submit an application or because a State informs the Secretary it does not intend to expend its full allotment. Provides that any amounts paid to a State which remain unobligated at the end of the fiscal year shall remain available to the State for their original purpose. Requires each State to prepare and submit to the Secretary an annual report on the activities in regard to this Act. Requires a biennial financial and compliance audit, transmittal of such audit report to the State legislature and to the Secretary, and availability of such audit report for public inspection. Requires the U.S. Comptroller General to evaluate the expenditures by States under this Act. Requires the Secretary, in consultation with appropriate national organizations, to develop model criteria for the collection of data and information with respect to services provided under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to require repayment or withhold payment, if amounts received are not being expended in accordance with the purpose of this Act or with agreements required by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
