<bill session="100" type="h" number="1967" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Free Exchange of Ideas Judiciary Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938, as amended, to encourage the free flow of information, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1987-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Communists"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Right to travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1987--Introduced.
Free Exchange of Ideas Judiciary Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to replace the term "political propaganda" with the term "advocacy material." Deletes the requirement that an agent for a foreign principal must submit a signed statement in connection with certain mailings of advocacy material on behalf of such foreign principal. Deletes the requirement that an agent for a foreign principal must include the agent's address in such mailings. Deletes the requirement that agents of foreign principals must include in such mailings notice that their registration statements are available at the Department of Justice. Deletes the provision authorizing the Postmaster General to declare nonmailable certain material which is offered for transmittal in the United States to someone in another American republic if a representative of that republic has informed the Postmaster that such material is illegal in such republic and has requested that its transmittal be stopped. Amends the Subversive Activities Control Act of 1950 to repeal the provision denying passports to members of communist organizations.</summary>
</bill>
