<bill session="100" type="h" number="2006" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Health Care Benefits Administration Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the administration of veterans' health-care benefits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407838"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1987-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.2616.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2616"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="939"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="939"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Hawaii"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1987--Introduced.
Veterans' Health Care Benefits Administration Act of 1987 - Amends Federal veterans' benefits provisions to authorize the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to contract with non-Veterans Administration (VA) facilities for the provision of medical emergency care for veterans in authorized community nursing homes when VA facilities are not capable of providing such emergency service. Adds hospitalization for observation and examination to determine VA benefit eligibility to those services authorized to be contracted out. Allows the per diem cost of community nursing home care purchased by the VA in Alaska and Hawaii to equal 50 percent of VA-purchased hospital care in such States. Authorizes the Administrator to furnish hospital care and medical services to a veteran who is sojourning or residing abroad: (1) for a service-connected disability; or (2) when needed in a vocational rehabilitation program outside the United States. (Currently, such benefits are available only for veterans with service-connected disabilities who: (1) are citizens of the United States sojourning or residing abroad; or (2) are in the Republic of the Philippines.) Amends the Veterans' Health Care Amendments of 1979 to repeal a specified provision requiring annual reports from the Chief Medical Director of the VA to the Congress concerning the implementation of certain contracting-out provisions under such Act, and on the number of veterans provided contract treatment in each State.</summary>
</bill>
