<bill session="100" type="h" number="2010" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize modification of the structure of the Office of the Chief Medical Director, to clarify procedures for removal for cause of certain employees, to authorize the use of the Director Pay Grade within VA Central Office and for related purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407838"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1987-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Hospitals and Health Care.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSVR03" subcommittee="Hospitals and Health Care" name="House Veterans' Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1125"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1125"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospital personnel"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1987--Introduced.
Revises Federal law relating to the organization of the Office of the Chief Medical Director of the Department of Medicine and Surgery of the Veterans Administration (the Department) to provide that such Office shall consist of the following: (1) not to exceed two Associate Deputy Chief Medical Directors; (2) not to exceed seven Assistant Chief Medical Directors; (3) such Medical Directors as may be appointed by the Administrator of Veterans Affairs; (4) such directors of hospitals and other medical facilities as may be appointed by the Administrator; and (5) such other persons as may be appointed by the Chief Medical Director. Authorizes the Chief Medical Director to establish, modify, or abolish such positions and offices as are deemed necessary to carry out the needs of the Department. Outlines provisions concerning length of appointment to such offices and positions, and possible extensions or terminations of such appointment terms by the Administrator. Reduces the minimum and maximum annual salary rate for the position of Medical Director of the Department.</summary>
</bill>
