<bill session="100" type="h" number="201" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Infrastructure Improvement and Public Productivity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Federal program to assist State and local governments in addressing the urgent need to repair and rehabilitate aging public facilities and to encourage the establishment of capital improvement programs that include life-cycle management of capital improvements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400299"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Economic Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW06" subcommittee="Economic Development" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Capital investments"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Infrastructure Improvement and Public Productivity Act - Sets out State apportionments for amounts appropriated to carry out this Act. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to develop a representative tax system similar to a previously published tax system, to provide public notice of such system and opportunity to comment, and to submit a report on such system to the appropriate congressional committees as soon as practicable. States that such tax system shall take effect not sooner than 45 days after publication in final form in the Federal Register and concurrent transmittal to each House of the Congress. Sets aside one percent of amounts appropriated under this Act for research and development in the repair, maintenance, and future improvement of public facilities. Sets aside a percentage for Puerto Rico and the other U.S. territories. Directs the chief executive officer of each State and territory to set aside one percent of any amounts apportioned to such State or territory for capital budgeting and capital improvement programs. Directs such chief executive officer, after setting aside the proper amounts, to make the remainder available for grants for the construction, reconstruction, renovation, and repair of public facilities. States that a grant under this Act for a project for which no other Federal grant is made shall be for 50 percent of the cost of the project. Specifies limited conditions under which grants shall be made, including the requirement that the proposed project must expand the economic base, promote economic diversity, or enhance the economic development opportunities in the area. Directs the chief executive officer, in selecting projects for grants, to consider the ability of the proposed project to stimulate additional capital spending. Requires funds apportioned to a State to be allocated between rural and urban areas in an equitable manner in accordance with a specified formula. Directs the chief executive officer to conduct an audit of each project completed with a grant under this Act. Directs recipients of such grants to keep records to enable such officer to complete such audits, and to make such records available to the chief executive officer. Directs the Secretary to use the most recent available information before an apportionment is made to determine such apportionment. Directs the Secretary to determine population on the same basis that the Secretary determines resident population for general statistical purposes. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993.</summary>
</bill>
