<bill session="100" type="h" number="2038" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act to establish a grant program for foster care and adoption assistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401418"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404220" joined="1987-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1987-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1987--Introduced.
Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act to establish a program under which the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) will make grants to States for the provision of foster care and adoption assistance to children. Sets forth eligibility criteria to be met by States requesting grants, including the submission to the Secretary of a plan, which, among other required contents, must provide for: (1) merit-based personnel standards in operating the grant programs; (2) monitoring and periodic evaluation of the State's foster care and adoption assistance activities; (3) specific program goals and a description of how the State will proceed to achieve them; (4) the development of a case plan for each child and of a case review system; and (5) incentives for foster care facilities to work with adoption agencies in arranging for the permanent adoption of children who cannot be reunited with their parents. Directs the Secretary to discontinue or reduce payments to any State that fails to comply with grant requirements relating to its plan. Describes criteria to be met by both a case plan and a case review system implemented as components of the State plan. Requires the latter to assure that: (1) each child's case plan is designed to achieve placement in the most family-like setting available and in close proximity to the parents' home, consistent with the best interest and special needs of the child; (2) each child's status is reviewed at least once every six months; and (3) certain procedural safeguards will be applied, including a hearing, within a specified time following initial placement, to determine the child's future placement status. Directs the Secretary to conduct periodic evaluations of programs developed under this Act. Requires each grantee State to submit certain statistical reports with respect to children assisted under grant programs. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
