<bill session="100" type="h" number="2047" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Agency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Agency in order to provide for increased standards of safety with respect to radioactive emissions resulting from activities carried out at nuclear facilities of the Department of Energy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400109"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410765" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-04">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From DOD.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1987--Introduced.
Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Agency Act - Establishes in the executive branch the Defense Nuclear Facilities Safety Agency (the Agency), headed by an Administrator. Requires the Administrator to issue standards providing for the protection of the health and safety of the public from radioactive emissions resulting from activities carried out at nuclear facilities of the Department of Energy (DOE). Grants the Administrator necessary powers to issue such standards, including the authority to inspect current DOE nuclear facilities and to issue subpoenas commanding the testimony of witnesses and the production of evidence. Authorizes the appropriate district court to enforce such subpoena power. Authorizes the Administrator to suspend operations at any DOE nuclear facility if the health and safety of the public are not reasonably protected. Authorizes the Administrator to order construction of a new DOE nuclear facility suspended if such construction is not being carried out in accordance with applicable standards issued under this Act. Directs the Administrator to notify the Secretary of Energy of any suspensions of construction or operation of a DOE nuclear facility. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress after any such suspension is ordered, giving the reasons for such order. Directs the Administrator, not less than once every three months, to report to the Congress describing the extent to which DOE nuclear facilities are complying with applicable standards issued in accordance with this Act. Directs the Administrator, no later than January 31 of each year, to report to the Congress an estimate of the budget authority required by the Secretary of Energy to comply with applicable standards issued under this Act. Provides certain administrative authority to the Administrator. Provides for protection against conflicts of interest of any supervisory employee of the Agency. Authorizes the Administrator to delegate certain duties, and to procure experts and consultants in order to carry out the purposes of this Act. Authorizes the transfer of personnel to the Agency in order to carry out its functions. Authorizes the Administrator to issue regulations necessary to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
