<bill session="100" type="h" number="2068" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Bureau of Standards and Industrial Competitiveness Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Bureau of Standards and Industrial Competitiveness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407967" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409954" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1987-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Science, Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF06" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSSY03" subcommittee="Science, Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy"/>
    <term name="Industry"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1987--Introduced.
National Bureau of Standards and Industrial Competitiveness Act of 1987 - Renames the Bureau of Standards as the National Bureau of Standards and Industrial Competitiveness (the Bureau). Establishes an Industrial Competitiveness Division within the Bureau. Provides that the Division shall be headed (subject to specified requirements relating to an Industrial Competitiveness Board) by a Deputy Director for Industrial Competitiveness who shall be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Directs the President to afford the Industrial Competitiveness Board an opportunity to make recommendations with respect to such appointment. Sets forth the industrial competitiveness functions of the Bureau. Establishes an Industrial Competitiveness Board within the Bureau. Directs the Board to exercise general supervision and policy control of the Division. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to appoint as Board members three from the Federal Government and five from the private sector representing a cross-section of the industrial base, including large and small businesses. Authorizes the Board to establish special commissions. Directs the Secretary to formulate the programs and budgets of the Division in consultation with the Board. Requires the Deputy Director to submit an annual report to the Director of the Bureau, the Secretary, and the Congress, detailing activities of the Division. Establishes in the Treasury the Standards and Industrial Competitiveness Fund. Makes the Fund available to the Director, in accordance with appropriations Acts but without fiscal year limitation, for use as a revolving fund to carry out the industrial competitiveness functions of the Bureau. Outlines sources of deposits to the Fund. Authorizes appropriations to the Fund for the eight fiscal years beginning after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
