<bill session="100" type="h" number="2090" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-13">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Montana Natural Resources Protection and Utilization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Montana Natural Resources Protection and Utilization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Montana National Resources Protection and Utilization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain National Forest System lands in the State of Montana for release to the Forest Planning process, protection of recreation value, and inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411677"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forest, Family Farms, and Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-01">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-16">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-13">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-369 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-13">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-10-13" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-697.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>For Further Action See S.2751.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAG06" subcommittee="Forests, Family Farms, and Energy" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2751"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Montana"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Recreation and Recreational Facilities"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Montana Natural Resources Protection and Utilization Act of 1987 - Designates specified lands in the following national forests in Montana as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) Beaverhead National Forest; (2) Bitterroot National Forest; (3) Deerlodge National Forest; (4) Lolo National Forest; (5) Custer National Forest; (6) Helena National Forest; (7) Flathead National Forest; (8) Kootenai National Forest; (9) Lewis and Clark National Forest; and (10) Gallatin National Forest. Incorporates the Great Bear Wilderness Area and the Scapegoat Wilderness Area into the Bob Marshall Wilderness. Provides that the RARE II (second roadless area review and evaluation) final environmental statement (dated January 1979) with respect to national forest system lands in Montana shall not be subject to judicial review. Releases national forest system lands in Montana which were reviewed in the RARE II program from further review by the Department of Agriculture, pending the revision of initial national forest management plans. Releases lands in Montana reviewed in the RARE II programs and not designated as wilderness from management as wilderness areas. Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from conducting any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of national forest system lands in Montana without express congressional authorization. States that the provisions above shall also apply to national forest system lands in Montana which are less than 5,000 acres in size. Designates the following specified areas to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture as part of the National Forest System as specified: (1) the West Pioneers National Recreation Area in the Beaverhead National Forest; (2) the Mount Helena National Education and Recreation Area in the Helena National Forest; (3) the Ross Creek Cedars National Recreation Area in the Kootenai National Forest; (4) the Gibson Reservoir National Recreation Area in the Lewis and Clark National Forest; and (5) the Cottonwood Lake National Recreation Area in the Deerlodge National Forest. Requires that the Elkhorns National Recreation and Wildlife Area, Helena and Deerlodge National Forests, be managed to conserve recreation and wildlife values. Requires that the West Big Hole, Beaverhead National Forest, continue to be managed as a further planning area during the next five years as the Secretary of Agriculture completes and reports to the Congress on a special watershed study. Requires the completion of land consolidation studies for the Crazy Mountain Wilderness Study Area in the Gallatin and Lewis and Clark National Forests by specified dates. Designates as a component of the National Wildlife Preservation System the Gallatin Wilderness in the Gallatin National Forest. Designates the Hyalite National Education and Recreation Area in such forest and prohibits such lands from entry, appropriation, disposal, and timber harvesting. Permits the use within such area of motorized equipment and continued grazing. Directs the Forest Service to complete and report to the Congress on a study of consolidating certain lands in the Hyalite/Porcupine/Buffalo Horn Wilderness Study Area. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to exchange specified lands with the Burlington Northern Railroad Company. Expresses the sense of the Congress that this exchange should be completed within 90 days of enactment. Authorizes the Secretary to exchange mineral interests with the Burlington National Railroad Company, as specified. Directs the Secretary to study a potential horse trail in the Swan Range, Flathead National Forest. Redesignates the Rattlesnake National Recreation Area and Wilderness as the Rattlesnake National Education and Recreation Area and Wilderness. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
