<bill session="100" type="h" number="2126" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Regulatory Commission Inspector General and Investigations Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 to create an Office of Inspector General and an Office of Investigations in the Nuclear Regulatory Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401446" joined="1987-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408457" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4140.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4140"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1987--Introduced.
Nuclear Regulatory Commission Inspector General and Investigations Act of 1987 - Amends the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 to establish in the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (the Commission) the Office of Inspector General. Prescribes the oversight responsibilities of the Inspector General regarding Commission implementation of nuclear power safety regulations. Requires the Inspector General to appoint an Assistant Inspector General for Investigations and an Assistant Inspector General for Auditing with responsibility for supervising the performance of investigative and auditing activities. Requires the Inspector General to submit semiannual reports to the Commission (which in turn shall submit them to the Congress) summarizing the activities of the Office of Inspector General. Authorizes the Inspector General to investigate information received from Commission employees regarding violations, fraud, gross waste of funds, or a danger to the public safety. Prohibits any reprisal action taken against an employee for making a complaint or disclosing information to an Inspector General. Establishes in the Commission the Office of Investigations of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Prescribes the oversight responsibilities of the Director regarding the investigation of non-compliance with radiological health and safety laws on the part of Commission licensees, permittees, applicants, contractors, and vendors. Requires the Director to appoint a Deputy Director and an Assistant Director. Confers responsibility upon the Assistant Director for supervising investigations conducted by the Commission's regional offices. Requires the Director to submit semiannual reports to the Commission (which in turn shall submit them to the Congress) summarizing the activities of the Office of Investigations. Transfers the Commission's Office of Inspector and Auditor to the Office of Inspector General of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. States that no person may restrict the communication of any Commission employee with a member of Congress or the Inspector General regarding: (1) possible violations of law; or (2) mismanagement, gross waste of funds, abuse of authority, or danger to the public safety. Prohibits retaliatory personnel actions against Commission employees for making such a protected communication. Requires the Inspector General to: (1) investigate any allegations by a Commission employee regarding such violations or retaliatory actions; and (2) report investigation results to the Commission. Sets forth remedies for victims of retaliatory actions.</summary>
</bill>
