<bill session="100" type="h" number="2130" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Charitable Solicitation Disclosure Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 39, United States Code, to require the disclosure of certain information in connection with the solicitation of charitable contributions by mail, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Postal Personnel and Modernization.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB, US Postal Service.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO05" subcommittee="Postal Personnel and Modernization" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Direct mail advertising"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1987--Introduced.
Charitable Solicitation Disclosure Act of 1987 - Requires charitable organizations which solicit a contribution by mail to include the following information with such solicitation: (1) the legal name and principal business of the charitable organization; (2) whether the organization is exempt under the Internal Revenue Code of 1986; (3) the purpose of the solicitation and the intended use of the contribution, specifying whether the program or activities for which the contribution will be used are in existence or planned; and (4) the obligation of the organization to furnish a financial report upon the request of the person being solicited. Declares that solicitations made through the use of audio or visual communication and which do not exceed 60 seconds in duration are not subject to such requirement. Requires solicitations made in writing to: (1) be presented in readily understandable language; (2) be located in a conspicuous place; and (3) appear in conspicuous and legible type in contrast with other printed matter on the solicitation. Required solicitations made through audio communication to be clearly audible and in language readily understandable. Requires solicitations made through visual communication to: (1) appear in lettering of sufficient size to be easily read by the viewer; (2) be shown against a background which does not impair the legibility of the communication; and (3) remain in view for a period sufficient to enable the viewer to read the communication. Describes the information to be included in financial reports of organizations which solicit contributions by mail. Requires such organizations to furnish the Postal Service any information it may require to assure compliance with this Act. Describes the types of organizations to which this Act does not apply. Authorizes the Postal Service to issue certain cease and desist orders to organizations that solicit money for a charitable purpose without complying with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
