<bill session="100" type="h" number="2137" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Trade Policy of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA03" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1987--Introduced.
Declares it to be U.S. policy to: (1) reduce trade problems and current account deficits and to achieve an equilibrium in such accounts by 1992; and (2) maintain stable exchange rates in relation to the U.S. dollar through cooperation within the international financial community. Directs the President to enforce all appropriate procedures and treaties to achieve these objectives, including but not limited to: (1) implementing trade policy measures to expand markets for U.S. exports, discipline unfair trade policies of other nations, and require an equitable world trading system; (2) exerting greater efforts to coordinate economic and monetary policy with U.S. trading partners; and (3) recommending to the Congress appropriate changes in fiscal, regulatory, or general economic policy. Requires the Congress, in enacting future legislation, to give priority to the policy objectives of this Act and to presidential recommendations which further such objectives. Declares that the Congress seeks to hold the President and his designated representatives accountable to the people for the enforcement of a trade policy that would eradicate current abuses that undermine U.S. living standards, national security, and future prosperity. Calls on the President to make frequent reports to the Congress on specific steps that are being taken to reduce the trade deficit.</summary>
</bill>
