<bill session="100" type="h" number="2142" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-01">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-12-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Wilderness Designation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Nevada Wilderness Designation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Nevada Wilderness Designation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain lands in the State of Nevada as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401446"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forest, Family Farms, and Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-10">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-11-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-12-01">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-463 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-01">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-12-01" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-12-03">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29">
      <text>Incorporated in S.1508.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG06" subcommittee="Forests, Family Farms, and Energy" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="708"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2044"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1508"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/1/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Nevada Wilderness Designation Act of 1987 - Title I: Wilderness Designation - Designates the following lands in Nevada as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) the Alta Toquima Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (2) the Arc Dome Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (3) the Boundary Peak Wilderness in the Inyo National Forest; (4) the Currant Mountain Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (5) the East Humboldt Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (6) the Grant Range Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (7) the Jarbidge Wilderness Additions in the Humboldt National Forest; (8) the Mt. Charleston Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (9) the Mt. Moriah Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (10) the Quinn Canyon Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (11) the Ruby Mountains Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (12) the Santa Rosa Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (13) the Schell Peaks Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; and (14) the Table Mountain Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest. Provides that the RARE II (second roadless area review and evaluation) final environmental statement (dated January 1979) with respect to national forest system lands in Nevada shall not be subject to judicial review. Releases national forest system lands in Nevada which were reviewed in the RARE II program from further review by the Department of Agriculture, pending the revision of initial national forest management plans. Releases lands in Nevada reviewed in the RARE II program and not designated as wilderness from management as wilderness areas. Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from conducting any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of national forest system lands in Nevada without express congressional authorization. States that the provisions above shall also apply to national forest system roadless lands in Nevada which are less than 5,000 acres in size and other specified areas. Permits livestock grazing in such wilderness areas, subject to mandatory review by the Secretary of Agriculture. Designates the Mount Rose National Recreation Area in the Toiyabe National Forest to be administered by the Secretary of Agriculture as specified. Title II: Land Transfers - Transfers specified public lands to the Toiyabe or Inyo National Forests. Transfers specified national forest lands to the Bureau of Land Management. Requires wilderness study areas transferred to the national forest system to be managed as wilderness until the Secretary of Agriculture recommends wilderness designations to certain congressional committees and the President. States that other lands transferred to such system be deemed to have been adequately considered for wilderness for purposes of initial land management plan requirements. Sets forth other management provisions, including the administration of receipts and existing land use authorizations. Title III: General Provisions - Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
