<bill session="100" type="h" number="2186" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Veterans' Administration to provide for medical examinations and counseling for overseas volunteer support personnel who served in Vietnam during the Vietnam era, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="401986" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403904" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404752" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400243" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408621" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409353" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409500" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="411405" joined="1987-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2285"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Agent Orange"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health surveys"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Physical examinations"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Vietnam"/>
    <term name="Vietnamese Conflict"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to provide to certain persons who served during the Vietnam era as overseas volunteers a medical examination to determine if such individuals have any adverse health effects as a result of such service due to exposure to phenoxy herbicides or other herbicides. Provides that all individuals eligible for such medical examinations shall also be treated as veterans for purposes of eligibility for veterans' readjustment counseling. Terminates the eligibility for such medical examinations and counseling three years after the enactment of this Act. Requires the President to direct the Secretary of Defense, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to submit to the appropriate committees of the Congress a joint report on the question of U.S. Government responsibility for providing such volunteer personnel with health care and compensation for disabilities related to their service in Vietnam during the Vietnam era. Requires such report to be submitted to the Comptroller General for review and comments before submission to the Congress. Requires such report to be submitted within one year after the enactment of this Act. Directs the Administrator to determine whether women who served during the Vietnam era as overseas volunteer support personnel have experienced long-term adverse health effects (especially gender-specific adverse health effects) from either traumatic experiences during such service or from exposure to phenoxy herbicides or other chemicals during such service. Directs the Administrator, while making such determination, to consider the results of a similar study required under the Veterans' Health-Care Amendments of 1986, and to submit a report on the results of such study to the Congress not later than one year after the first report required under such Act is submitted.</summary>
</bill>
