<bill session="100" type="h" number="2187" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Radon Training, Testing, Reduction, and Quality Assurance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill relating to the testing for, and reduction of, radon in homes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409632"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radon"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1987--Introduced.
Radon Training, Testing, Reduction, and Quality Assurance Act of 1987 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to continue the voluntary Radon Measurement Proficiency and Quality Assurance program to inform the public of reliable firms or individuals that measure radon in homes. Requires the Administrator to continue to design and implement training seminars for government officials and private firms addressing radon monitoring, analysis, mitigation, health effects, and public information. Requires the Administrator to develop a voluntary radon reduction contractor quality assurance program to inform the public of reliable firms or individuals that can reduce radon levels in homes. Authorizes the Administrator to collect fees from private firms and individuals for information and services provided under this Act. Requires the deposit of such fees in the Radon Service Fee Account in the Treasury for use in activities under this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
