<bill session="100" type="h" number="2197" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Guaranteed Job Opportunity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to guarantee a work opportunity for all Americans, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Employment Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Federal Reserve, HHS, Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-23">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-24">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSED06" subcommittee="Employment Opportunities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment subsidies"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Nondiscrimination provisions"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1987--Introduced.
Guaranteed Job Opportunity Act - Establishes a grant program to assist local job projects for unemployed individuals. Requires any eligible area (a county or comparable unit of local government) which desires to receive funds under this Act to establish a District Executive Council (District Council). Sets forth the responsibilities of the District Councils, which include: (1) selecting projects to be assisted (pursuant to criteria prescribed by the Secretary of Labor); (2) preparing project plans; and (3) preparing annual reports on District Council activities. Directs the Secretary to make grants to the District Councils for the purpose of assisting local job projects which meet the requirements of this Act. Sets forth eligibility requirements for individuals participating in such job projects. Sets forth certain limitations with regard to: (1) the number of participants who reside in any household; and (2) individual and family income. Sets forth job project requirements and limitations. Requires each eligible job project participant to receive: (1) the applicable wage; (2) benefits comparable to those received by employees in similar occupations; and (3) other support services (which may include transportation, health care, special services and materials for the handicapped, and child care). Requires each District Council to establish job clubs to assist eligible participants in preparing resumes, developing interviewing techniques, and evaluating job search activities. Sets forth labor standards applicable to such job projects. Sets forth nondiscrimination provisions. States that no participant shall be employed in the construction, operation, or maintenance of any facility which is used, or is to be used, for sectarian instruction or religious worship. Requires the Secretary to provide any recipient who fails to comply with such provisions notice and an opportunity to comply before taking further action. Authorizes the Attorney General, under certain circumstances, to bring a civil action in district court for appropriate relief, including injunctive relief, in instances involving recipient violations of nondiscrimination provisions. Requires each District Council to maintain an evaluation file for each individual employed in a project assisted under this Act. Sets forth the manner in which funds appropriated for such projects shall be allotted and allocated. Grants the Secretary authority to: (1) prescribe rules and regulations necessary to carry out this Act; (2) accept, purchase, or lease property for use under this Act; and (3) waive certain requirements with respect to testing, education, and length of work week. Directs the Secretary to prepare and submit to the Congress an annual report on the administration of this Act. Grants the Comptroller General (and representatives of the General Accounting Office) access to the records of grant recipients. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1994.</summary>
</bill>
