<bill session="100" type="h" number="2231" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Allies Fair Share Defense Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prescribe an end strength level of United States forces assigned to permanent duty in NATO countries and Japan and to provide for the reduction of United States forces in these countries under certain circumstances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401947"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1988-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="402710" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1988-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Military Personnel and Compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from State.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-02">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-10">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From State.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel and Compensation" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asian and Pacific Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Collective security agreements"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Military policy"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1987--Introduced.
Allies Fair Share Defense Act of 1987 - Prohibits, after the end of FY 1988, the funding of U.S. armed forces assigned to permanent duty in member nations of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) or in Japan at levels in excess of a specified troop strength. Directs that for 1990, 1991, and 1992, such levels shall be reduced by a specified number each year. Waives such reduction in troop strength for NATO countries if either of the following occur: (1) each member nation of NATO has increased its defense spending by a specified amount; or (2) the Secretary of Defense certifies to the Congress in writing that the member nations of NATO other than the United States have accomplished certain objectives relating to the increase of defensive measures and the overall significant improvement of their conventional defense capability. Waives such reduction in troop strength for Japan if Japan has either: (1) increased its defense spending by a specified amount; or (2) increased its capability to defend its sea lanes to specified distances. Provides for smaller reductions of U.S. armed forces in NATO-member countries and Japan if at least one of the above-described objectives have been met, or if some, but not all, of the objectives have been met. Directs the Secretary of Defense, no later than March 1 of each of the calendar years 1988 through 1992, to report to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees on the status of the following matters as of January 1 of the year in which the report is submitted: (1) the supply of aerial and ground munitions of NATO-member nations; (2) the number of emergency operating facilities and semihardened aircraft shelters in such nations; and (3) other measures taken by such nations to improve their conventional defense capability. Outlines further information to be included in such reports concerning the attainment of objectives specified under this Act. States that this Act shall not apply if: (1) a declaration of war by the United States is in effect; (2) there is an armed attack on any NATO-member nation or Japan; or (3) the President declares a national state of emergency and immediately informs the Congress of such action and the reasons therefor.</summary>
</bill>
