<bill session="100" type="h" number="2245" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Self-Sufficiency Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish programs to provide comprehensive employment, training, educational, and other services for recipients of, and applicants for, aid to families with dependent children in order to promote economic self-sufficiency for such persons and their families, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400595"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401417" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.1720.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1987--Introduced.
Economic Self-Sufficiency Act of 1987 - Amends the Social Security Act to revise the scope of programs for individuals receiving aid to families with dependent children (AFDC) in order to enhance their long-term employability and self-sufficiency and to break the cycle of poverty and welfare dependency. Directs the Secretary of Labor (Secretary) to provide financial assistance for education, training, support services, and employment assistance programs in each State in the interest of enabling eligible participants to: (1) reduce their dependency on welfare; (2) obtain long-term employment and (3) increase family income through wages from such employment. Establishes an order of priorities for the allocation of assistance and services, with first priority accorded to AFDC recipients who are mothers under age 19. Sets forth general requirements with respect to the targeted assistance and services. Includes provisions to be applied when a program is implemented in the context of a community work experience program including limitations on participant eligibility and requirements related to support services and program accountability. Directs the Secretaries of Health and Human Services and of Labor to promulgate jointly regulations with respect to these expanded opportunities for family self-sufficiency. Requires a State triennially to develop and submit a State plan, covering a three-year period, in order to obtain an allocation for activities appropriate to this Act's purposes. Details the required procedures and contents applicable to such plans. Declares that a State plan shall be deemed approved unless the Secretary of Labor disapproves it in writing within 45 days of its submission. Prohibits final disapproval of a plan unless the relevant State agency has been afforded the opportunity for a hearing. Describes procedures for the organization of services under State plans, including provisions relating to: (1) the initial evaluation and subsequent counseling of eligible participants; (2) the development with the assistance of an appropriate State employee, of an employability plan based on the participant's long-term goals and specifying the services the participant chooses, the sources of such services, and the components of the plan for obtaining employment; and (3) assessment of the participant's progress under the plan. Requires that the comprehensive services to be recommended to participants as means of achieving objectives described in the employability plan include: (1) job search services, including career counseling, testing and assessment, and direct placement with employers; (2) education programs, including basic education, literacy training, and financial management classes; (3) training programs, including both institutional and on-the-job training, work experience, and programs to develop desirable work habits; and (4) necessary support services, such as transportation and child care assistance. Requires each appropriate State agency to keep certain records and to submit certain reports regarding program funding and performance. Directs the Secretary to conduct investigations, in each fiscal year, of the use of funds by various recipient States. Directs the Office of Technology Assessment to develop and prescribe outcome-oriented performance standards for the purpose of evaluating programs and determining allocation eligibility. Details the required underpinnings for such standards and fixes time limits for their establishment. Requires the Secretary to conduct, in accordance with a specified time schedule, evaluations of each State's progress in meeting its plan objectives. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to States not meeting the pertinent performance standards. Entitles a State to an incentive allotment to the extent it meets or exceeds performance standards. Applies sanctions in cases when the Secretary makes a determination that an individual has refused without good cause to participate in a program under this Act. Prohibits a final determination of such a refusal unless the individual has been offered an opportunity for a conciliatory resolution. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary as to their apportionment between incentive allocations and regular allotments to the States. Limits the Federal share of various components of a State's program expenditures. Makes technical amendments to the Job Training Partnership Act.</summary>
</bill>
