<bill session="100" type="h" number="2242" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to improve the awards program under which the Government recognizes superior accomplishments of Federal employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400590"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB, OPM.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO03" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Productivity in government"/>
    <term name="Suggestion systems"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1987--Introduced.
Requires each Federal agency to report annually to the Office of Personnel Management on how the agency is carrying out the incentive awards program for superior accomplishments. Requires such report to include: (1) the number of cash awards made and the amount of each award; (2) if no award was made, a statement of the reasons why no award was made, particularly any difficulty encountered in carrying out provisions of law governing the program; (3) a statement of measures taken or proposed to be taken in order to overcome any such difficulty; and (4) any other information which the Office may require. Directs the Office to report annually to the House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service, the Senate Committee on Governmental Affairs, and the head of each agency on: (1) the name of any agency which did not make any cash award during the period covered by the report or did not submit a report under this Act; (2) a description and evaluation of the manner in which each agency is carrying out the incentive awards program; and (3) recommendations for any legislation or administrative action which may be necessary to carry out such program more effectively.</summary>
</bill>
