<bill session="100" type="h" number="2268" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation Reform Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to ensure the future solvency of the pension benefit guaranty program for single-employer plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1988-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance rates"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Retirement"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="White collar crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/4/1987--Introduced.
Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation Reform Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) and the Internal Revenue Code to require an employer maintaining a single-employer defined benefit plan to provide to the Secretary of the Treasury, as a condition for the granting of a waiver of the minimum funding standards or an extension of an amortization period, evidence assuring the adequate future funding of such a plan. (No such requirement exists under current law, although the Secretary is authorized to request that security be provided.) Requires that such evidence be incorporated in the materials provided by the Secretary to the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) as part of their mandatory consultation process. Decreases from five to three the number of allowable waivers of the minimum funding standard for employee pension benefit plans. Amends ERISA to: (1) increase from $8.50 to $23.00 per plan participant the annual premium rate to be paid to the PBGC in the case of a single-employer plan; (2) institute a procedure for an annual determination to provide for possible reductions in such premium amount; (3) direct the PBGC to permit, to the maximum extent practicable, quarterly installment payments of annual premiums with respect to single-employer plans; (4) require the administrator of a single-employer plan to furnish quarterly reports to plan participants and beneficiaries on the plan's actuarial status; (5) authorize the PBGC to borrow from the general fund of the Treasury amounts to be transferred into the revolving fund for basic benefits under a single-employer plan when it determines that such action is necessary to ensure the solvency of the revolving fund; and (6) establish civil and criminal penalties for violations of fiduciary duties with respect to certain employee benefit plans.</summary>
</bill>
