<bill session="100" type="h" number="2276" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Diversification Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal assistance for economic development, economic stabilization, and job training in areas heavily dependent on defense contracts and bases or in areas that have been affected by the termination of major defense contracts or the closure of a defense base.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403529" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403695" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407351" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="408457" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410231" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Employment Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA05" subcommittee="Economic Stabilization" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED06" subcommittee="Employment Opportunities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Conversion of industries"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/1987--Introduced.
Economic Diversification Act - Title I: Defense Economic Diversification-Adjustment Council - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the Defense Economic Diversification-Adjustment Council (Council) in the interest of: (1) assisting affected persons in defense-dependent communities to make plans for nondefense economic alternatives to minimize dislocation in the event of a closure of a military installation or cancellation of a major defense contract; (2) providing incentives for business, industry, and the vocational education community to develop programs to retrain workers affected by such closures or terminations; and (3) notifying communities in advance of anticipated events that will require economic adjustments to nondefense alternatives. Directs the Council, among other things, to: (1) establish within the Executive Office of the President an Office of Economic Diversification-Adjustment to provide staff support for its work; (2) disseminate pertinent information to the appropriate Federal, State, and local authorities and to diversification-alternative use committees; (3) develop and coordinate data relating to defense economic diversification and adjustments; (4) serve as a resource for civilian job information for workers displaced from defense-related employment; (5) prepare and distribute a Diversification and Conversion Guidelines Handbook in accordance with prescribed content specifications outlined in this Act; and (6) make available for appropriate use information with respect to funds that could be used for diversification and conversion planning. Directs the Secretary of Defense to: (1) notify the Council one year in advance of any pending or proposed change in defense spending that would affect employment in the defense industry; and (2) furnish annually to the Council data with respect to future defense spending levels and contract progress. Title II: Community Economic Diversification - Adjustment Program - Directs the Council to establish a grant program to provide funds to be used for: (1) planning for economic diversification or conversion to avoid substantial dislocations; or (2) economic adjustment, in certain cases. Permits the awarding of grants to: (1) any community that is in the process of reducing a heavy dependency on defense-oriented activities or that is substantially affected by the reduction or elimination of Federal defense facilities or curtailment of defense contracts; (2) labor unions, business representatives, and private nonprofit economic development, job training, or education agencies located near or within such communities; and (3) the base management and civilian employees of a Federal military installation being closed or realigned. Directs the Council to establish grant eligibility criteria that will ensure assistance to the most vulnerable communities. Limits a community to a single grant for each major defense contract cancellation or military installation realignment. Instructs the Council to publish semiannually a listing of the currently eligible local government units. Permits any community not on such a listing to petition for inclusion. Requires every grantee to establish a diversification-alternative use committee to: (1) develop and review plans for the economic diversification of the defense-dependent area and for the alternative use of a major defense facility for other activity in the event of a Government decision affecting its continued role in defense; (2) review the industry-education partnership for training and retraining in defense-dependent areas and evaluate the particular manpower, environmental, and economic needs of the particular community; and (3) ensure that proper education and assistance are provided to employees displaced by defense-related facility closings. Sets forth criteria with respect to the contents of diversification and alternative use plans. Title III: Industry-Education Partnership - Amends the Carl D. Perkins Vocational Education Act to establish a program of grants to the States to carry out industry-education partnership vocational education programs designed to train and retrain workers in defense-related facilities or defense-dependent communities to allow them to find nondefense-related employment. Sets forth general guidelines for such grant program. Authorizes the use of grant funds for: (1) necessary administrative costs; (2) the training and retraining of instructional and guidance personnel; and (3) curriculum development and acquisition. Title IV: Miscellaneous - Authorizes FY 1988 through 1990 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
