<bill session="100" type="h" number="2282" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose to the Secretary of the military department concerned or the Secretary of Transportation the mailing addresses of certain members the Ready Reserve and to disclose to the Director of the Selective Service System the mailing addresses of persons required to register under the Military Selective Service Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407838"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Compulsory military service"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury, upon the request of the Secretary of the relevant military department (in some cases, the Secretary of Transportation) or of the Director of the Selective Service System, to disclose the mailing address of: (1) any member of the Ready Reserve who is required by law to notify the requesting Secretary of a change in address; or (2) any person who is required by law to register under the Military Selective Service Act and who has not done so. Restricts the use of the disclosed addresses to specified limited purposes.</summary>
</bill>
