<bill session="100" type="h" number="2315" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 to provide for the continuing evaluation and improvement of curricula in the fields of mathematics, science, and technology, and for the continuing evaluation of developments in educational applications of new technologies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404765"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Science, Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY03" subcommittee="Science, Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Curriculum evaluation"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Mathematics"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/1987--Introduced.
Amends the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 to direct the National Science Foundation to establish and maintain a program for the evaluation and development of curricula in mathematics, science, and technology for educational use at all levels. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires the Foundation to evaluate the status of developments in the area of educational applications of new technologies, supporting research, developing curricula, and encouraging private sector and university collaboration in teacher training. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
