<bill session="100" type="h" number="2326" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Footwear Trade Relief Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to remedy the injury to the United States shoe industry caused by increased imports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Clothing industry"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Shoe industry"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/1987--Introduced.
Domestic Footwear Trade Relief Act of 1987 - Limits the quantity of certain nonrubber footwear that may be imported into the United States in any calendar year after 1987 to no more than 75 percent of the expected apparent domestic consumption of such footwear for such calendar year. Requires the Secretary of Commerce, on the first day of the fourth quarter of 1987 and each calendar year thereafter, to determine on the basis of the best information available the expected apparent domestic consumption of such footwear for the next succeeding calendar year. Requires the Secretary to determine and publish in the Federal Register the allocation for the next succeeding calendar year of permissible nonrubber footwear imports. Provides for the revision and annual adjustment of the expected apparent domestic consumption and the volume of imports. Requires the President, not later than March 15, 1998, to submit to the Congress a report on the administration of this Act during the first decade that it is in effect.</summary>
</bill>
