<bill session="100" type="h" number="2329" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chitimacha Claims Settlement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the settlement of the land claims of the Chitimacha Tribe of Louisiana, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/7/1987--Introduced.
Chitimacha Claims Settlement Act - Deems any transfer of land or natural resources from, by, or on behalf of the Chitimacha Tribe of Louisiana before the date of enactment of this Act to have been made in accordance with the Constitution and laws of the United States. Distinguishes any title held by the Tribe before such a transfer and any claim of the Tribe to such land. Limits challenges to the constitutionality of this Act. Vests exclusive jurisdiction over actions concerning the constitutionality of this Act in the U.S. District Court for the Western District of Louisiana. Establishes the Chitimacha Claims Settlement Fund in the Treasury to be held in trust for the benefit of the Tribe. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to pay semiannually to the Tribe any income from the Fund. Requires the Secretary to spend up to a specified amount of the Fund's principal to acquire land selected by the Tribe which shall become part of the Chitimacha Reservation. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire options to purchase land for the Tribe. Authorizes appropriations to the Fund. Authorizes the Tribe to establish a tribal court system and a tribal police force. Gives the Tribe exclusive jurisdiction over Indian child custody proceedings. Prohibits Federal agencies from considering payments for the benefit of the Tribe under this Act in determining the eligibility of Louisiana or a political subdivision thereof under any Federal financial aid program. Excludes payments from Louisiana to the Tribe from consideration in determining the Tribe's eligibility under any Federal financial aid program, unless such program requires a showing of need. Prohibits the availability of money from the Chitimacha Claims Settlement Fund from being used as a basis to deny or reduce Federal financial assistance or benefits to the Tribe or members thereof.</summary>
</bill>
