<bill session="100" type="h" number="2357" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to replace the Travel and Tourism Advisory Board with a private, nonprofit corporation in order to better coordinate and implement national efforts to encourage foreigners to visit, and United States residents to travel throughout, the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400377"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401986" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300017" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407306" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1988-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/8/1987--Introduced.
Amends the International Travel Act of 1961 to replace the Travel and Tourism Advisory Board with the Tour USA Promotion Corporation. Establishes the Corporation as a private-nonprofit corporation. Specifies the various purposes of the Corporation, including: (1) optimizing the contribution of the tourism and recreation industries to the economic prosperity of the United States; (2) encouraging the free entry of individuals traveling to the United States; (3) eliminating unnecessary trade barriers to the U.S. tourism industry; (4) encouraging competition in the tourism industry; and (5) harmonizing all Federal activities in support of tourism and recreation with the needs of the general public and the States, territories, local governments, and the tourism and recreation industry. Requires the Corporation to carry out specified functions concerning tourism promotion including advising the Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Tourism Marketing in the development of a tourism marketing plan and implementing, and bearing the expenses of implementing, such plan. Sets forth administrative provisions concerning the operation of the Corporation. Authorizes appropriations. Makes the Corporation responsible for the advertising component of the tourism marketing plan to encourage travel to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
