<bill session="100" type="h" number="2369" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Energy Civilian Energy Programs Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations to the Department of Energy for civilian energy programs for fiscal year 1988.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406873"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407399" joined="1987-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Coal research"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fissionable materials"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Idaho"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear fusion"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Superconductivity"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1987--Introduced.
Department of Energy Civilian Energy Programs Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1988 - Title I: Authorization for Energy Research and Development Programs for Fiscal Year 1988 - Authorizes appropriations for the operating expenses of the following Department of Energy civilian research and development programs: (1) the fossil energy program; (2) clean coal technology; (3) energy conservation; (4) energy supply research and development; (5) general science and research; (6) nuclear fission energy; (7) magnetic fusion energy; and (8) inertial confinement fusion energy. Authorizes appropriations for capital equipment expenses not related to construction for the following Department of Energy civilian research and development programs: (1) the fossil energy program; (2) the energy conservation program; (3) the energy supply research and development programs associated with renewable energy, supporting research and technical analysis, environmental research and development, nuclear fission energy, and magnetic fusion; and (4) general science and research. Sets forth a specified amount which shall be allocated to the Department's multiprogram and single mission national laboratories to seek out potential users for promising inventions or copyrighted data developed at such laboratories. Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy for plant and capital equipment for specified prior year civilian research and development projects with respect to: (1) supporting research; (2) nuclear fission; (3) general science and research; and (4) environmental research. Authorizes appropriations for new construction projects. Requires specified reductions in authorizations for general science and research and for nuclear fission. Title II: Authorization for Other Activities for Fiscal Year 1987 - Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy for FY 1987 for operating expenses for: (1) fossil energy, Federal inspector for the Alaska gas pipeline; (2) the energy conservation program: (3) the energy supply research and development programs associated with renewable energy, nuclear energy, remedial actions, and low-level waste; (3) uranium supply and enrichment activities; (4) the Nuclear Waste Fund; (5) supporting services; (6) departmental administration; and (7) policy and management. Authorizes appropriations for capital equipment not related to construction for: (1) energy supply research and development, nuclear energy, and remedial action; (2) the Nuclear Waste Fund; (3) supporting services; and (4) departmental administration. Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy for a specified prior year civilian energy project at the Idaho National Engineering Laboratory, Idaho. Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Energy for new plant and capital equipment for specified uranium supply and enrichment projects and for specified supporting service projects. Title III: General Provisions - Prohibits the use of any appropriated funds for the superconducting super collider project. Sets forth limitations on the use of funds authorized under this Act, including that no appropriated amount may be used for any project deleted by the Congress. Directs the Secretary to treat as reimbursable contractor expenses all costs incurred by civilian energy research and development contractors who respond directly to congressional inquiries. Directs the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees regarding: (1) modification of the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 in order to achieve and operating repository by 1998; and (2) development of the atomic vapor laser isotope separation process for uranium enrichment under the administration's concept of privatization of the enrichment enterprise. Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations to issue class waivers for certain inventions or copyrighted material developed in the performance of a federally funded civilian research and development program.</summary>
</bill>
