<bill session="100" type="h" number="2374" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coast Guard Personnel Relocation Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide relocation assistance to certain Coast Guard employees.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT, Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Navigation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM01" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Navigation" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Relocation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1987--Introduced.
Coast Guard Personnel Relocation Assistance Act of 1987 - Amends the Demonstration Cities and Metropolitan Development Act of 1966 to authorize the Secretary of Defense to acquire, reimburse for certain losses on private sale, or foreclose certain residential property situated near a military installation which the Department of Defense or the Department of Transportation, with regard to the Coast Guard when not operating as a service of the Navy, has ordered closed or reduced in scope, under certain circumstances. Requires each contract awarded by the Coast Guard for construction or services to be performed in a State having an unemployment rate in excess of the national average unemployment rate to include a provision requiring the contractor to employ local residents to fulfill the work requirements of such contract.</summary>
</bill>
