<bill session="100" type="h" number="2430" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide an administrative procedure for certain noncontroversial suspensions of tariffs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404705"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400882" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402435" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411119" joined="1987-05-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from State, Treasury, Commerce, Labor, ITC, USTR.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1987--Introduced.
Authorizes a person who uses an article in the production of a product in the United States, or distributes an article which is used in the production of a product in the United States, to file with the International Trade Commission (ITC) a petition requesting the President to suspend duties imposed on such article. Authorizes a person who produces in the United States any article for which duties are suspended, any other article like, or directly competitive with, such article, or any article which is directly competitive with a product that is produced in the United States by means of a process which uses such article as a significant raw material or component, to file with the ITC a petition requesting the President to reinstate such duties. Requires such petitions to contain sufficient information to enable the ITC to determine whether an investigation into the suspension or reinstatement of duties is justified. Requires the ITC, within 15 days after a petition is filed with the ITC, to determine whether such information is sufficient to justify such an investigation. Requires the ITC, if there is an affirmative determination, to: (1) transmit a copy of the petition to the United States Trade Representative (USTR) and the Secretary of Commerce; (2) initiate an investigation of the suspension or reinstatement of duties regulated in the petition; and (3) publish in the Federal Register notice of the initiation of such investigation and the opportunity for public comment. Requires the ITC, upon the request of the President or the initiative of the ITC, to initiate an investigation of the suspension or reinstatement of duties. Requires the ITC to make specified determinations with respect to such investigation. Requires the ITC and the Secretary to make specified reports. Provides for the suspension or reinstatement of duties by the President. Limits the duration of a suspension of duties to no more than three years. Requires the USTR, whenever the President suspends duties on an article, to initiate negotiations with each foreign country that benefits from such suspension for the purpose of obtaining reciprocal trade concessions from such foreign countries for U.S. goods and services. Provides that no suspension of duty may be sought under this Act for any article that is the subject of a pending bill to temporarily suspend the duty on such article.</summary>
</bill>
