<bill session="100" type="h" number="2455" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Development Finance Corporation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for and promote the economic development of Indian tribes by furnishing the necessary capital, financial services, and technical assistance to Indian owned business enterprises and to stimulate the development of the private sector of Indian tribal economies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300017" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1987-05-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-24">
      <text>Field Hearings Held in Santa Fe, New Mexico.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-25">
      <text>Field Hearings Held in Denver, Colorado.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-04">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>For Further Action See S.721.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="721"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="721"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/1987--Introduced.
Indian Development Finance Corporation Act - Title I: Establishment of Corporation - Establishes the Indian Development Finance Corporation. Requires the Corporation to provide development capital and technical and managerial assistance for new and existing Indian businesses and to encourage Indian tribes and individuals to participate in the Corporation by owning its equity securities. Authorizes the Corporation to make loans to or purchase obligations of Indian businesses if they meet specified financial conditions. Directs the Corporation to provide the credit needed by Indian businesses at the lowest reasonable cost, taking into account the Corporation's cost of money, necessary reserve, and expenses. Authorizes the Corporation to guarantee all or any part of the principal and interest of any loan made to an Indian business by a State or federally chartered lending institution on terms permissible for Corporation loans. Authorizes the Corporation to purchase up to 25 percent of the ownership interest in an Indian business and to supervise or participate in the management of such business. Sets forth administrative provisions concerning the Corporation. Requires the Corporation's Board of Directors to submit annual reports to the Congress on its capital, operations, and financial condition. Title II: Capitalization - Authorizes the Corporation to issue stock. Requires at least 60 percent of the Corporation's outstanding stock to be owned by Indian tribes. Limits the ownership interest of any individual or single tribe to five percent of such outstanding stock. Sets forth provisions governing the sale of Corporation stock to Indian tribes and to the Government. Authorizes the Corporation to issue bonds and notes which shall be federally guaranteed until the later of: (1) 20 years; or (2) the date such securities may be readily sold on the open market at prevailing rates of interest and yield. Requires the Secretary to loan the Corporation a specified amount to provide initial operating funds. Requires the Corporation to invest loan proceeds in Government securities and use the interest thereon to provide financial services and pay operating expenses. Title III: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
