<bill session="100" type="h" number="2469" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Reorganization Act of 1985</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Social Security Administration as an independent agency, which shall be headed by a Social Security Board, and which shall be responsible for the administration of the old-age, survivors, and disability insurance program under title II of the Social Security Act and the supplemental security income program under title XVI of such Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407320"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1987--Introduced.
Social Security Reorganization Act of 1985 - Title I: Establishment of the Social Security Administration - Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act to establish as an independent executive agency a Social Security Administration, headed by a Social Security Board. Provides that it shall be the duty of the Administration to administer the programs established by titles II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) and XVI (Supplemental Security Income) of the Social Security Act. Establishes in the Administration a General Counsel and an Inspector General. Requires the Board to study and make recommendations as to the most effective methods of providing economic security through social insurance and as to legislation and matters of administrative policy. Establishes in the Administration: (1) a Commissioner of Social Security; (2) a Deputy Commissioner of Social Security; and (3) an Office of the Beneficiary Ombudsman, to be headed by a Beneficiary Ombudsman who shall represent the interests of beneficiaries under the Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance program and the Supplemental Security Income Program within the Administration. Requires the annual report of the Board to include a description of the activities of the Beneficiary Ombudsman. Requires the Board to make annual budgetary recommendations relating to the Administration. Requires that appropriations requests by the Administration for staffing and personnel be based upon a comprehensive workforce plan as established by the Board. Provides for the apportionment of administrative costs. Requires the annual report of the Board to include a section reflecting the use of budget authority provided to the Administration. Requires that authority for automated data processing procurement and facilities construction be provided in the form of contract authority covering the total cost of such acquisitions. Makes amounts needed for the liquidation of contract authority so provided available from the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund to the extent that such amounts are not needed to meet current obligations for benefit payments. Specifies the authorities which are to be delegated to the Board from the Administrator of the General Services Administration. Requires the Board to cause a seal of office to be made and judicial notice taken thereof. Provides for the transfer to the Administration of all functions carried out by the Secretary of Health and Human Services with respect to the programs and activities to be carried out by the Administration under this Act. Abolishes the position of Commissioner of Social Security in the Department of Health and Human Services. Title II: Miscellaneous and Conforming Amendments - Sets forth a contributor and beneficiary bill of rights under which: (1) all individuals are required to be treated fairly by the Board and the Secretary; (2) the Secretary and the Board are prohibited from discriminating on the basis of age, sex, race, creed, color, handicap, national origin, or economic condition; and (3) the Board and the Secretary should maintain prompt, professional, and effective service which is responsive to the community. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Board to report to Congress within 120 days after the beginning of each regular session on their administration under this Act. Requires the Secretary to study and make recommendations on the most effective methods of providing economic security and on the administrative policy for the programs which he or she administers. Title III: Effective Dates and Transitional Rules - Sets forth effective date and transitional rule provisions.</summary>
</bill>
