<bill session="100" type="h" number="246" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Competition Enhancement and Tax Relief Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to enhance competition by reinstating a 5 percent investment tax credit after 1987 for productive property, by eliminating estate and gift taxes on transfers of business interests to related persons, by eliminating tax on the proceeds from the sale of a small business if the proceeds are reinvested in another small business, by increasing from $10,000 to $25,000 the amount allowed for expensing depreciable business assets, by requiring nonprofit organizations to make available their tax returns to the public, by applying the Regulatory Flexibility Act to the Internal Revenue Service, and by providing for the regulation of employee leasing organizations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409654"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401029" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404170" joined="1987-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1987-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="408490" joined="1987-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1987-02-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Capital gains tax"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Family enterprises"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Internal revenue law"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Competition Enhancement and Tax Relief Act of 1987- Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a five percent investment tax credit after 1987 for tangible property which: (1) is used as a part of manufacturing, production, or extraction or of furnishing transportation, communications, electrical energy, gas water, or sewage disposal services; (2) constitutes a research facility used in connection with such activities; or (3) constitutes a facility used in connection with such activities for the bulk storage of fungible commodities. Exempts from estate taxes the transfer of an interest in a closely held business to a qualified heir of the decendent. Exempts from gift taxes the transfer of an interest in a closely held business to a member of the donor's family. Allows the nonrecognition of gain realized from the sale or exchange of the entire interest in an unincorporated trade or business to the extent such gain is used within a 24-month period to purchase property used in an unincorporated trade or business which is entirely owned by the taxpayer. Increases from $10,000 to $25,000 the annual limitation on the expensing of certain depreciable business assets. Requires the public availability of the annual returns of tax-exempt organizations. Denies special mailing privileges to organizations which are taxed on unrelated business income. Makes applicable to the Internal Revenue Service provisions of the Regulatory Flexibility Act relating to rule making. Provides that, for purposes of employee benefit plans, a leasing organization shall be deemed to be the sole employer of a leased employee if: (1) the organization retains the right to hire, transfer, pay, and direct the manner of the employee's performance of services; (2) the organization is responsible for paying its employees regardless of receiving fees from the recipient; (3) any employee benefits provided are comparable and nondiscriminatory among all employees; and (4) the organization bills the recipient on a total fee rather than a direct cost pass-through basis.</summary>
</bill>
