<bill session="100" type="h" number="2492" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Industrial Extension Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish within the National Bureau of Standards an Office of Extension Services to support, advise, and assist the various State Industrial Extension Services, and to provide for a 3-year pilot grant program to demonstrate methods by which the Federal Government can help States establish, improve, and expand such Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400035"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404019" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404733" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407051" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409325" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1987-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1319"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1319"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Industrial productivity"/>
    <term name="Industry"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1987--Introduced.
Federal Industrial Extension Act of 1987 - Establishes an Office of Extension Services within the National Bureau of Standards to inform State Industrial Extension Services of Federal research and development programs and to provide a contact point for such Services. Establishes a three-year Industrial Extension Service Grant Program in the Department of Commerce to demonstrate methods of Federal assistance to States for the development of State Industrial Extension Services designed to help businesses enhance competitiveness through the application of the latest science and technology. Limits participants to not more than 15 States, with preference given on the basis of need and regional distribution. Makes grants available for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires that funds be used to expand the number of businesses served or the quality of services provided. Requires that participating States provide at least 20 percent of the costs of such Program. Authorizes States to provide services directly or through other State agencies or through universities or nonprofit organizations. Permits the charging of fees. Requires States to report annually to the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress at the end of FY 1990 on the operation of the Program. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
