<bill session="100" type="h" number="2497" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sulfur and Nitrogen Emissions Tax Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose an excise tax on the emission from certain boilers of sulfur dioxide or nitrogen oxides and to create a trust fund for revenues from such tax.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403529" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1987-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1988-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control equipment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Pollution taxes"/>
    <term name="Sulphur oxides"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1987--Introduced.
Sulfur and Nitrogen Emissions Tax Act of 1987 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose an excise tax, at a rate based on the amount of pollutant emitted, on emissions of sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides from certain fossil fuel-burning boilers. Provides that such tax: (1) be phased in over a two-year period; and (2) be adjusted annually for inflation after 1990. Fixes the liability for the tax on the person owning or operating the taxable boiler. Exempts certain boilers from the tax. Sets forth the methodology for determining the amount of pollutants emitted, generally to be measured by a qualified continuous emissions monitoring device. Permits: (1) a quarterly credit against the emissions tax for costs of the taxpayer's qualified pollution equipment, based on ratable depreciation over ten years; and (2) an income tax deduction for emissions tax payments. Establishes in the Treasury the Sulfur and Nitrogen Emissions Trust Fund (SANE Trust Fund) to receive emissions excise tax revenue. Permits expenditures from this fund to: (1) assist taxpayers subject to the emissions tax in reducing their taxable emissions; and (2) pay administrative costs related to the emissions tax. Authorizes repayable advances to the SANE Fund. Sets limits and conditions to govern such borrowing.</summary>
</bill>
