<bill session="100" type="h" number="2516" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to control emissions of certain air pollutants from municipal waste incinerators.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="405687" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="407816" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409353" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1987-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate performance standards for emissions of specified air pollutants, including particulate matter, sulfur dioxide, and lead, from new or modified municipal waste combustion units. Requires such standards to reflect the greatest degree of emission limitation achieved in practice by similar units or contained in a State implementation plan. Makes specified technologies available, including spray dry scrubbers source separation, and wet flue gas denitrification. Requires initial standards to be promulgated within 12 months, in effect within 18 months, and reviewed every five years. Requires jurisdictions served by the municipal combustion unit to have an enforceable solid waste management plan before a State program may issue a permit for a new or modified unit. Requires such plan to reflect the operation of the new or modified unit. Sets a standard of emissions equivalent to that achieved by the five lowest emitting units should the Administrator fail to promulgate a standard for any of the specified pollutants. Directs the Administrator to promulgate regulations requiring existing units to meet the emissions standards promulgated under this Act according to a timetable which requires compliance at least within six years. Requires owners or operators of municipal waste combustion units to monitor emissions at the point such emissions move into the ambient air and at other points as necessary to protect human health and the environment. Sets monitoring standards, including continuous and periodic monitoring. Requires the Administrator to establish operating and maintenance requirements for all units. Directs the Administrator to establish a model State program for the training and certification of municipal waste incinerator personnel. Requires operating personnel to pass such training or be certified by an authorized State program. Requires unit permits to be terminated five years after their issuance unless the Administrator or an authorized State certifies such unit's compliance with emissions requirements. Permits States to submit for Administrator approval a State program of enforcement, treating the State as the enforcing entity under this Act. Authorizes the Administrator to withdraw such authority if the State is not adequately enforcing these requirements.</summary>
</bill>
