<bill session="100" type="h" number="2520" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Separation of Powers Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal certain provisions of law which violate the doctrine of separation of powers and to eliminate certain restrictions on the authority of the executive branch.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy Research and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA05" subcommittee="Economic Stabilization" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY06" subcommittee="Energy Research and Development" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans employed in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Civilian personnel positions"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Declaration of war"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Guided missiles"/>
    <term name="International control of nuclear power"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear exports"/>
    <term name="Nuclear nonproliferation"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sinai Peninsula"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1987--Introduced.
Separation of Powers Act of 1987 - Repeals the War Powers Resolution. Deletes the provision contained in the law providing for an early warning system in Sinai that permits the Congress to require the removal of U.S. civilian personnel assigned to Sinai if the Congress by concurrent resolution determines that the safety of such personnel is jeopardized or that continuation of their role is no longer necessary. Amends the International Emergency Economic Powers Act to repeal the authority of the Congress to terminate a declaration of a national emergency by concurrent resolution. Amends the Neutrality Act of 1939 to repeal the provision that authorizes the Congress by concurrent resolution to declare that a state of war exists between foreign states. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to delete certain provisions that give the Congress the authority to limit certain international aid programs, including nuclear transfers, by adopting a concurrent resolution. Deletes the provision prohibiting the use of foreign aid funds to train the police forces of foreign countries. Changes certain provisions relating to the Department of Defense that give the Congress the authority to limit actions of the Department of Defense by adopting a resolution or a concurrent resolution or by requiring the Department of Defense to notify the Congress before taking action (including provisions dealing with the ordering to duty of selected reserves, emergency construction projects, contributions for NATO infrastructure, Naval Petroleum Reserves, and a long-range proving ground for guided missiles). Amends certain Acts dealing with armed forces personnel and veterans' health care to limit the authority of the Congress to oversee programs contained in such Act. Amends the Federal Nonnuclear Energy Research and Development Act of 1974 to delete the provision authorizing the Congress to nullify a proposed rule or order by passage of a resolution. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 and the Nuclear Non-Proliferation Act of 1978 to delete certain provisions that give the Congress the authority to oversee actions, programs, or agreements under such Acts.</summary>
</bill>
