<bill session="100" type="h" number="2537" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Lease and Lease-Purchase Agreement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve disclosures to consumers of the terms of consumer leases and lease-purchase agreements, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401155"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1988-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403203" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1988-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-09-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405377" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1988-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1987-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1988-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408313" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408520" joined="1988-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1988-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411065" joined="1988-04-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Consumer Affairs and Coinage.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA02" subcommittee="Consumer Affairs and Coinage" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/1987--Introduced.
Consumer Lease and Lease-Purchase Agreement Act - Amends the Consumer Credit Protection Act to revise disclosure requirements, including advertisement disclosure requirements, for consumer leases and to establish separate disclosure requirements for lease-purchase agreements. Requires information disclosed pursuant to such requirements to be segregated from all other terms and information provided. Includes among revised disclosures for consumer leases: (1) the total lease cost; (2) the amount of any required security deposit; (3) statements explaining certain information about the consumer's liability based on the residual value of the property; and (4) a statement referring the consumer to the appropriate lease document for information concerning other possible costs. Requires the following information to be disclosed for lease-purchase agreements: (1) the number, individual amount, timing, and total amount of payments; (2) a statement that the consumer will not own the property until all payments are made; (3) a statement referring the consumer to the contract for an explanation of other possible costs; (4) a statement that the consumer is responsible for the fair market value of lost, stolen, damaged, or destroyed property; (5) a statement indicating whether the property is new or used; (6) a statement of the property's cash price; (7) the total of initial payments paid or required at or before consummation of the agreement or delivery of the property, whichever is later; (8) a clear summary of the terms of the consumer's option to purchase; (9) the identity of the party responsible for maintaining or servicing the property while it is being leased; (10) a brief description of insurance provided or paid for by the lessor; (11) a description of any security interest held or to be retained by the lessor; and (12) the date of the transaction and the identities of lessor and consumer. Requires each item of property displayed or offered by a lessor to have a tag or label disclosing specified information. Prohibits certain items from a lease-purchase agreement, including: (1) a confession of judgment; (2) a negotiable instrument; (3) a wage assignment; and (4) a waiver by the consumer of claims or defenses. Specifies provisions such an agreement must contain. Requires a lessor to provide the consumer a written receipt for each payment made by cash or money order. Requires that advertisements specify whether the advertised transaction is a lease or a lease-purchase agreement, except certain advertisements in the yellow pages of a telephone book. Provides that a renegotiation is a new lease or agreement requiring new disclosures. Requires no disclosures for a lease or agreement extension. Requires lessors to pay consumers' attorney fees only in unsuccessful suits to collect more than the prescribed maximum amount at the end of a lease. Prescribes civil and criminal penalties for violations and outlines defenses. Authorizes civil actions against lessor assignees only if a violation is apparent on the face of the disclosure statement.</summary>
</bill>
