<bill session="100" type="h" number="2530" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-29">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Mississippi National River and Recreation Area, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401526" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="410261" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="411405" joined="1987-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-02">
      <text>Field Hearings Held in St. Paul, Minnesota.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-319.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 196.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-09-29" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-02">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, OMB, Corps of Engineers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Interior Department. Unfavorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department, Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>For Further Action See S.2840.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2840"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Recreation and Recreational Facilities"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="River basin commissions"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Establishes the Mississippi National River and Recreation Area along the Mississippi River in the St. Paul-Minneapolis Metropolitan Area, Minnesota. Establishes the Mississippi River Coordinating Commission to assist Government authorities in developing and implementing a management plan for such lands and waters. Requires the Commission to submit a plan, within three years, to the Governor of Minnesota and the Secretary of the Interior for review and approval. Requires the Secretary to monitor such Area in the interim. Terminates the Commission after ten years. Authorizes the State, following the termination, to establish a State Commission to take over such Commission's functions. Transfers Federal property within the Area to the Secretary, except for Army Engineer facilities for navigation and other buildings or structures currently in use. Requires Federal entities to notify and receive the approval of the Secretary before engaging in any activities in or affecting such Area. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire land and interests in such Area, as specified. Requires the Secretary to review local plans and ordinances and their enforcement to assure conformance to the plan. Permits the Secretary to acquire lands without the owner's consent after appropriate notice and opportunity to cure a nonconforming plan or ordinance. Permits owners of acquired improved residential property to retain the right to residential use for 25 years or the owner's death. Sets forth other terms and conditions for such use. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants for land acquisition and to provide technical assistance for programs. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Tri-Rivers Management - Directs the Secretaries of the Army and the Interior to appoint representatives to a Tri-Rivers Management Board to coordinate development of the Mississippi, St.-Croix, and Minnesota Rivers within the St. Paul-Minneapolis Metropolitan Area, Minnesota. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
