<bill session="100" type="h" number="2575" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Part-Time and Temporary Workers Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide for more equitable treatment of part-time and temporary workers under pension plans and group health plans, and to ensure treatment as employees under such title of certain individuals whose services are leased or contracted for by employers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409650"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Part-time employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/1987--Introduced.
Part-Time and Temporary Workers Protection Act of 1987 - Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 (ERISA) to bring certain part-time employees within the participation, vesting, and accrual rules governing pension plans. Addresses any employee who, within a relevant 12-month period: (1) has customarily completed more than 500 but fewer than 1,000 hours of service; or (2) is employed in a type of position in which employment customarily consists of such a number of hours. Provides that completion of such hours of service will be treated as completion of 1,000 hours of service (thereby bringing the employee within the ERISA benefit framework). Permits a reduction in the employer-provided premium under a group health plan in the case of a part-time employee only when such employee: (1) has customarily completed fewer than 30 hours of service per week; or (2) is employed in a type of position in which employment customarily consists of such a number of hours. Limits such a premium reduction, when permissible, to not less than a ratable portion of the premium ordinarily provided in the case of an employee who completes 30 hours of service per week. Revises the ERISA definition of "employee" to include non-employees who, pursuant to a contract or agreement, provide employee-like services to an employer for at least one year at the rate of 500 or more hours per year.</summary>
</bill>
