<bill session="100" type="h" number="2572" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Youth Employment Opportunity Wage Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize an employer to pay a youth employment opportunity wage to a person under twenty years of age from May through September under the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 until September 30, 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407432"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300069" joined="1987-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor Standards.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED03" subcommittee="Labor Standards" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Summer employment"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/2/1987--Introduced.
Youth Employment Opportunity Wage Act of 1987 - Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to authorize employers to pay employees under 20 years of age, between May and September of each year, 75 percent of the minimum wage rate. Exempts such employees from special certificate requirements. Restricts such authorization to: (1) hours worked by eligible employees in compliance with applicable child labor laws; and (2) youth employed after May 1 of each year. Prohibits the removal of employees ineligible for the subminimum wage rate in order to replace them with employees who are eligible. Makes technical and conforming amendments to the Job Training Partnership Act. Terminates the minimum wage rate exception after September 30, 1989. Directs the Secretary of Labor to monitor the implementation of this Act and to report to the Congress concerning the employment effects of the wage authorized by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
