<bill session="100" type="h" number="2591" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Trucking Productivity Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend subtitle IV of title 49, United States Code, to increase productivity and competitiveness by reducing regulation of motor carriers of property, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407853"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407051" joined="1987-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Claims against common carriers"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Common carrier regulation"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Household moving"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor carrier rates"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Railroads and state"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Trade regulation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1987--Introduced.
Trucking Productivity Improvement Act of 1987 - Declares that the Interstate Commerce Commission (ICC) has no jurisdiction over motor carriers of property (except for transactions regarding mergers, consolidations, and acquisition of control). Retains ICC jurisdiction over motor carrier transportation of passengers. Repeals ICC responsibility for issuing certificates of registration for foreign motor carriers operating in the United States (effective six months after the date of enactment of this Act). Repeals provisions regarding: (1) the full applicable commercial rate to be paid for providing transportation services for the Federal Government; and (2) the disclosure of quoted or tendered rates by a carrier for transportation services for the Federal Government. Removes the proscription against the charging of predatory rates by any person providing household goods transportation services for the Federal Government. Authorizes the President to take action to respond to unfair practices against U.S. motor carriers of property by a contiguous foreign country. Authorizes the President to limit foreign-owned trucking operations in the United States if he determines it is in the national interest to do so. Repeals provisions regarding household goods carrier operations. Authorizes the ICC to approve agreements between motor common carriers of passengers with respect to the pooling or division of transportation services. Places under ICC jurisdiction the authorization of mergers, consolidations, and acquisitions of control between rail carriers and motor carriers of property. Prohibits any State regulation relating to interstate or intrastate operations of commercial motor vehicles engaged in interstate commerce. Removes the Federal standards of liability for motor carriers of property no longer under ICC jurisdiction (thus making such carriers subject to liability under State law). Repeals the dispute settlement program for household goods carriers. Transfers ICC jurisdiction over motor carriers of property to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC). Grants the FTC exclusive powers to enforce ICC regulations regarding household goods. Requires the FTC to review and revise such regulations to ensure that household goods shippers receive adequate protection in their dealings with carriers. Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to exempt motor carriers of property from ICC jurisdiction regarding unfair and illegal commercial trade practices and interlocking directorates. Prescribes guidelines for the service of notice and process on motor carriers of migrant workers. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to report to the Congress regarding the National Governors' Association Consensus Agenda on uniform State administrative requirements for interstate motor carriers. Declares that all exemptions or immunities from antitrust laws granted by the ICC with respect to motor carriers of property, with certain exceptions, are ineffective as of the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
