<bill session="100" type="h" number="2613" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and title I of the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 with regard to pension integration, participation, and vesting requirements, and to provide for studies relating to cost-of-living adjustments and pension portability.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406284"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Labor mobility"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/4/1987--Introduced.
Pension Reform Act of 1987 - Amends the Tax Reform Act of 1986 to extend to all accrued benefits existing in plan year 1989 and thereafter the amendments made with regard to the nondiscriminatory coordination of defined contribution plans with Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI). Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to repeal provisions that permit a certain disparity in simplified employee pension plan contributions with respect to nondiscriminatory coordination with OASDI. Provides for the repeal, effective for plan year 2000 and thereafter, of IRC rules with respect to: (1) the nondiscriminatory coordination of defined contribution plans with OASDI; and (2) pension integration exceptions. Amends the IRC to establish distinct minimum employee coverage requirements applicable in cases when an employer with respect to a plan is treated as operating a single line of business. Requires such a plan to benefit all the employer's employees. Limits the exception to minimum coverage requirements available to employers treated as operating separate lines of business for a year. Amends the IRC and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to eliminate the special vesting requirements governing multiemployer plans. Directs the Comptroller General of the United States, as soon as possible after this Act's enactment, to undertake thorough studies with respect to: (1) possible methods of requiring employee pension plans to provide cost of living and other adjustments to plan benefits; and (2) potential pension portability mechanisms, including ways to preserve and enhance the real value of deferred vested pension benefits. Lists specific items to be addressed in each study. Requires submission of the studies to specified congressional committees within two years of this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
