<bill session="100" type="h" number="2625" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that a certain amount of funds shall be available to the Secretary of Energy each fiscal year for cleanup of hazardous or radioactive waste from atomic energy defense activities and to require the Secretary of Energy to develop within one year a comprehensive plan for the cleanup of such waste.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407967"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402435" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404193" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410567" joined="1987-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Procurement and Military Nuclear Systems.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS07" subcommittee="Procurement and Military Nuclear Systems" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1987--Introduced.
Makes funds available to the Secretary of Energy, according to a specified formula, for the cleanup of hazardous or radioactive waste from atomic energy defense activities. Directs the Secretary of Defense to transfer to the Secretary of Energy the amount calculated according to such formula. Precludes the use of such funds for repository costs resulting from permanent disposal of high-level radioactive waste from atomic energy defense activities. Makes such funds available for FY 1988 through 1992. Requires the Secretary of Energy, in conjunction with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to: (1) develop a comprehensive plan, including a timetable and estimated costs, for the cleanup of hazardous or radioactive waste from atomic energy defense activities; and (2) submit such plan to specified congressional committees.</summary>
</bill>
