<bill session="100" type="h" number="2650" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hazardous Materials Transportation Safety Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to improve hazardous materials transportation safety and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402763"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1987-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle registration"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Railroad rolling stock"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1987--Introduced.
Hazardous Materials Transportation Safety Amendment of 1987 - Title I: General Provisions - Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989. Amends the Surface Transportation Act of 1982 to direct the Secretary of Transportation to make grants to States and political subdivisions for the designation of: (1) hazardous materials transportation routes; and (2) hazardous materials parking sites. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to require registered carriers of hazardous materials to maintain records of the routes followed in the transportation of certain hazardous materials and to prepare an annual registration statement. Prescribes registration fee guidelines. Amends the Internal Revenue Code (with respect to miscellaneous excise taxes) to finance the Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Response Trust Fund (established by this Act) by raising the excise tax on: (1) gasoline; (2) diesel and special motor fuels; (3) aviation fuels; and (4) fuels used in commercial transportation on inland waterways. Establishes the Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Response Trust Fund in the Treasury. Prescribes operations guidelines for such Fund. Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to direct the Secretary to make grants to the States to assist in the training and assistance equipment needs of emergency personnel responding to hazardous material transportation incidents. Prescribes grant administration and operation guidelines. Authorizes appropriations to fund such grants for FY 1988 through 1992 out of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Emergency Response Trust Fund. Outlines the emergency response information regulations to be promulgated by the Secretary within one year of the date of enactment of this Act. Sets forth minimum training certification requirements for personnel affecting hazardous material transportation safety. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress within 270 days after the date of enactment of this Act regarding specified aspects of hazardous materials transportation safety. Directs the Secretary to establish information dissemination procedures regarding enforcement actions pertaining to violations of the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act. Makes any person who commits a violation of this Act liable to the United States for a civil penalty (currently such violation must be knowingly committed). Establishes a minimum civil penalty of $500 for each such violation. Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations within 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act requiring the transportation of hazardous materials in intrastate commerce to be covered by the same Federal regulations that pertain to interstate transportation of such materials. Directs the Secretary (in cooperation with the Federal Emergency Management Agency and the Environmental Protection Agency) to provide technical and financial assistance regarding hazardous materials transportation safety to State, regional, or local government entities. Requires the Secretary to: (1) conduct a hazardous materials flow study and to report the results of such study to the Congress; and (2) conduct a risk analysis regarding the transportation of high level nuclear waste and spent nuclear fuel to geologic repository sites and monitored retrievable storage sites, and report the results to the Congress and the Secretary of Energy. Title II: Rail Transportation - Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations regarding emergency response procedures for rail carriers in accident or emergency situations involving the transportation and storage of hazardous materials. Prescribes the contents of such requirements. Prohibits railroad tank cars built before November 6, 1971, from being used in commercial hazardous materials transportation unless they meet all safety and design requirements imposed by the Secretary. Directs the Secretary to enter into a contract with the National Academy of Sciences for a study of railroad tank car design, and to report the results of such study to the Congress. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
