<bill session="100" type="h" number="2677" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-11-01">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-11-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Southern California Indian Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Southern California Indian Land Transfer Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish procedures for review of tribal constitutions and bylaws or amendments thereto pursuant to the Act of June 18, 1934 (48 Stat. 987).</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409165"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1987-06-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-10-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-453.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 283.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20">
      <text>Placed on Consent Calendar No: 15.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-07">
      <text>Called up by House by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-12-07" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-12-08">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-21">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-577.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1042">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1042.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-01">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-06" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-11-01" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-581" type="public" datetime="1988-11-01">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-581.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4834"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Asian American ethnic groups"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Constitutions"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian hunting and fishing rights"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Schools"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3355"/>
    <amendment number="s3356"/>
    <amendment number="s3357"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/1/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Title I: Indian Reorganization Act Amendments - Amends the Indian Reorganization Act to extend to any Indian tribe the right to adopt a constitution and bylaws which shall become effective when: (1) ratified by a majority of the adult members of the tribe; and (2) approved by the Secretary of the Interior. Establishes time periods following a tribal request within which the Secretary must hold elections on a proposed constitution or an amendment to a constitution. Requires the Secretary, during the period preceding an election, to provide requested technical assistance and to review the final draft of a proposed constitution or amendment to determine if any provision is contrary to applicable laws. Requires the Secretary to approve a constitution and bylaws or an amendment within a specified period after an election unless the constitution is contrary to applicable laws. Title II: Miscellaneous Amendments to Existing Laws - Amends the Old Age Assistance Claims Settlement Act to provide for a minimum ten dollar payment to heirs under the Act. Revises the land description for the reservation of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon. Makes effective upon enactment of this Act the judgement plan for funds awarded the Choctaw and Chickasaw Indians, under specified conditions. Makes provision for the transfer of income from the Chilocco Indian School property in Oklahoma. Amends an Indian employment preference provision relating to employees in the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Indian Health Service. Amends the Buy Indian Act as it relates to procurement of printing by the Bureau of Indian Affairs and the Indian Health Service. Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act to allow waste treatment aid to be provided to former Indian reservations in Oklahoma and to Alaska Native villages. Makes changes to the Indian Self-Determination and Education Assistance Amendments of 1988 as it relates to administrative appeals and other matters. Amends the Yakima Land Act to require the Secretary of the Interior to transfer certain lands acquired under the Act to trust status. Amends the Native Americans Programs Act of 1974 to provide that appropriations for the program must exceed 1987 funding levels before Pacific Islanders are eligible for funding. Amends the Agua Caliente Equalization Law regarding tax effects of payments made as compensation for the acquisition of the allottee's allotment for a public purpose. Directs the payment to the Tiospa Zina Tribal School at the Sisseton-Wahpeton Reservation, South Dakota, of amounts which should have been received previously as start-up costs. Allows claims for wildlife proceeds received between the date of withdrawal and the date of conveyance from harvests on certain conveyed Alaska Native lands. Title III: To Transfer Ownership of Certain Lands Held in Trust for the Blackfeet Tribe, and for Other Purposes - Provides compensation for and in settlement of all claims arising as a result of alleged errors in the Secretary of the Interior's approval of purported conveyances of land involved in the will of Garret White (aka Many Whitehorses), under certain conditions. Directs the Secretary to have an appraisal made of the land and provides that sums paid to the Blackfeet Tribe and Mary Lois Peterson Munoz may not exceed such appraisal, plus a maximum ten percent attorney's fee, notwithstanding any contract to the contrary. Title IV: Columbia River Treaty Fishing Access Sites - Provides for increased access to usual and accustomed fishing sites for Columbia River treaty fishing tribes (the Nez Perce Tribe, the Confederated Tribes of Umatilla Indian Reservation, the Confederated Tribes and Bands of the Yakima Indian Nation). Directs the Secretary of the Army to acquire additional lands adjacent to the Bonneville and take other actions in order to provide ancillary fishing facilities for the tribes. Authorizes appropriations. Grants the Secretary of the Interior the right of first refusal to accept any Federal agency lands made available adjacent to the Columbia River within the Bonneville, Dalles, and John Day Pools, under certain conditions. Title V: Southern California Indian Land Transfer - Southern California Indian Land Transfer Act - States that all U.S. right, title, and interest in certain California lands are held in trust for the benefit and use of specified bands and groups of Mission Indians. Declares such lands to be part of the reservations to which they are contiguous. Preserves existing rights and grants a right to purchase lands to holders of grazing permits. Provides for the proceeds from any land sales to be held in trust for the Indians. Transfers proceeds from rents and royalties to the Indians. Title VI: Potawatomi Judgment Funds - Provides for the use and distribution of funds awarded in the U.S. Claims Court to the Wisconsin Band of Potawatomi. Allocates funds between the Hannahville Indian Community and the Forest County Potawatomi. Title VII: Potawatomi Trust Lands - States that all U.S. right, title, and interest in certain Wisconsin lands are held in trust for the benefit and use of the Forest County Potawatomi Community of Wisconsin. Declares such lands as the reservation. States that all U.S. right, title, and interest in certain Michigan lands are held in trust for the benefit and use of the Hannahville Indian Community of Michigan. Declares such lands as the reservation.</summary>
</bill>
