<bill session="100" type="h" number="268" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to provide private remedies for injury caused by unfair foreign competition and violations of certain customs fraud provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411224"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-05">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>See H.R.3.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF06" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to prohibit a person from importing or selling within the United States any article manufactured in a foreign country if: (1) such article is imported or sold in the United States at a U.S. price which is less than the foreign market value or constructed value of such article; and (2) such importation or sale causes or threatens material injury to U.S. industry or labor or prevents the establishment of a U.S. industry. Allows a person to bring a civil action for injunctive relief or damages in the district court of the District of Columbia or the Court of International Trade against a manufacturer or exporter of such article or an importer of such article into the United States who is related to such manufacturer or exporter. Provides that the standard of proof in such cases is a preponderance of the evidence. Provides that a foreign manufacturer who sells products in the United States shall be deemed to have consented to the appointment of the district director of the U.S. Customs Service as his agent for service of process. Sets forth the statute of limitations for actions instituted under this Act. Sets forth provisions relating to discovery orders and confidential information. Allows the United States to intervene in actions brought under this Act as a matter of right. Subjects court orders to nullification by the President. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the provisions of this Act are consistent with the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade. Allows a person whose business, employment, or property has been damaged by violation of certain customs fraud provisions to bring a civil action for injunctive relief or damages in the district court of the District of Columbia or the Court of International Trade without respect to the amount in controversy. Subjects court orders to nullification by the President.</summary>
</bill>
