<bill session="100" type="h" number="2687" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make the antitrust laws applicable for a 2-year period to any professional baseball team that unfairly deprives its supporters of the opportunity to receive regular over-the-air television broadcasts of games in a season.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1987-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Baseball"/>
    <term name="Cable television"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Sports and Athletics"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting of sports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1987--Introduced.
Makes it unlawful for a major league professional baseball team to enter into or perform any contract that provides exclusive carriage for a one-year period of more than 50 percent of its televised games by any cable television system. Sets forth an exception to such prohibition if: (1) more than 75 percent of the residences in the home city of that team are located within an area served by a cable television system that carries more than 50 percent of the televised games of such team; or (2) such team has not had more than 65 percent of its televised games carried by an over-the-air broadcasting station during the preceding two-year period. Subjects a professional baseball team to the antitrust laws for a two-year period for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
