<bill session="100" type="h" number="2712" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-30">PASS_BACK:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for the Department of the Interior and related agencies for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411947"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-01">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held on the subject prior to measure being received from the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-06-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Rules Granted a Rule Waiving All Points of Order Against Consideration of the Bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Reported to House by House Committee on Appropriations.  Report No: 100-171.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 98.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-23">
      <text>Rule Passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Called up by House as Privileged Matter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Considered by House Unfinished Business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="218" datetime="1987-06-25" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 295 - 115 (Record Vote No: 218).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Interior Appropriations. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Byrd with amendments. With written report No. 100-165.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="322">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 322.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-30">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="288" datetime="1987-09-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 92-4. Record Vote No: 288.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-09-30">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Byrd; Johnston; Leahy; DeConcini; Burdick; Bumpers; Hollings; Reid; Stennis; McClure; Stevens; Garn; Cochran; Rudman; Weicker; Nickles; Hatfield.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>House Disagreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>House Agreed to Request for Conference and Speaker Appointed Conferees: Yates, Murtha, Dicks, Boland, AuCoin, Bevill, Whitten, Regula, McDade, Lowery (CA), Conte.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>For Further Action See H.J.Res. 395.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP06" subcommittee="Interior and Related Agencies" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP06" subcommittee="Interior and Related Agencies" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="hj" number="395"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automobile insurance"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Commission of Fine Arts"/>
    <term name="Continental shelf"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to the arts and humanities"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Gas in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Horses"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Jewish holocaust (1939-1945)"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Migratory bird conservation"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Mining leases"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Mountains"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nonviolence"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Range management"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Rhode Island"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="Sulphur"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="West Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zoos"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h272"/>
    <amendment number="h273"/>
    <amendment number="h274"/>
    <amendment number="h275"/>
    <amendment number="h276"/>
    <amendment number="h277"/>
    <amendment number="h278"/>
    <amendment number="h279"/>
    <amendment number="h280"/>
    <amendment number="h281"/>
    <amendment number="h282"/>
    <amendment number="s795"/>
    <amendment number="s796"/>
    <amendment number="s797"/>
    <amendment number="s798"/>
    <amendment number="s799"/>
    <amendment number="s800"/>
    <amendment number="s801"/>
    <amendment number="s802"/>
    <amendment number="s803"/>
    <amendment number="s805"/>
    <amendment number="s806"/>
    <amendment number="s807"/>
    <amendment number="s808"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/30/1987--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended, roll call #288 (91-5)) Title I: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for FY 1988 within the Department of the Interior for the Bureau of Land Management for management of lands and resources, construction and access, payments in lieu of taxes, land acquisition Oregon and California grant lands, range improvements, service charges, deposits and forfeitures, and miscellaneous trust funds. Requires the Bureau to report to the Appropriations Committees on the status of wild horse and burro populations. Sets forth uses and limitations of appropriations made to the Bureau of Land Management. Appropriates funds for: (1) the U.S. Fish and Wildlife Service for resource management, construction, anadromous fish, the Migratory Bird Conservation Account, land acquisition, and the National Wildlife Refuge Fund; and (2) the National Park Service for the operation of the National Park System (earmarking funds for the Martin Luther King, Jr. Center for the Study of Nonviolent Social Change), recreation and preservation programs, the Historic Preservation Fund, construction, land acquisition and State assistance, the John F. Kennedy Center for Performing Arts, and the Illinois and Michigan Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to charge entrance fees at all National Park System units, as specified. Restricts or earmarks the expenditure of funds at specified units of the System. Earmarks historic preservation funds for a Bicentennial Lighthouse Fund. Rescinds certain urban park funds. Requires an environmental impact statement before construction of a specified interchange on the George Washington Memorial Parkway, Virginia. Appropriates funds for: (1) the Geological Survey for surveys, investigations, and research, revising revenue sharing on Outer Continental Shelf lands; (2) the Minerals Management Service for leasing and royalty management; (3) the Bureau of Mines for the conduct of inquiries, technological investigations and research of mines and minerals; (4) the Office of Surface Mining Reclamation and Enforcement for regulation and technology, and the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund; (5) the Bureau of Indian Affairs for the operation of Indian programs, construction, road construction, miscellaneous payments, tribal trust funds, the revolving fund for loans, and the Indian Loan Guaranty and Insurance Fund, in authorizing the use of funds to pay off guaranteed loans in default; (6) the Office of Territorial and International Affairs for administration, for the Trust Territory of Pacific Islands, and for the Compact of Free Association; and (7) the Secretarial offices, including the Office of the Solicitor for salaries and expenses, the Office of Construction Management, and the Office of the Inspector General. Sets forth the uses and limitations on appropriations made available by this title. Makes such appropriations available for expenditure or transfer for the emergency reconstruction, replacement, or repair of aircraft, buildings, utilities, or other facilities or equipment damaged or destroyed by fire, flood, storm, or other unavoidable causes. Makes funds available for the suppression or emergency prevention of forest or range fires on or threatening lands under the Department of the Interior's jurisdiction, for emergency rehabilitation of burned-over lands, emergency actions related to earthquakes or volcanoes, and emergency reclamation projects. Makes appropriations available for the operation of warehouses, garages, shops, and similar facilities, wherever consolidation of activities will contribute to efficiency or economy. Makes appropriations available for the hire, maintenance, and operation of aircraft, hire of passenger motor vehicles, purchase of reprints, payment for telephone service in private residences in the field, and the payment of certain dues when authorized by the Secretary of the Interior. Makes appropriations available for uniforms or allowances. Limits the use of appropriations for services or rentals to contracts not exceeding 12 months. Prohibits the use of funds for the preparation for, or conduct of, pre-leasing and leasing activities of lands within a certain area of the Outer Continental Shelf off the coastline of Massachusetts. Makes available appropriations to provide insurance on official motor vehicles, aircraft, and boats operated by the Department of the Interior in Canada and Mexico. Prohibits the use of funds to detail any employee to an organization unless in accordance with Office of Personnel Management regulations. Authorizes the Secretary of the Navy to transfer to the Guam Power Authority certain electric power facilities. Title II: Related Agencies - Makes appropriations for FY 1988 for the Department of Agriculture for the Forest Service for forest research, State and private forestry, the National Forest System, construction, land acquisition, timber salvage sales, the Range Betterment Fund, acquisition of land for national forests, and miscellaneous trust funds. Rescinds certain funds for timber roads, purchaser election, and forest service. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to acquire specified lands in West Mt. Diablo Meridian Trinity County, California, in exchange for a reduction in a Farmers Home Administration loan. Modifies the boundary of the Cranberry Wilderness, West Virginia. Makes appropriations for the Department of Energy for Clean Coal Technology demonstrations, fossil energy research and development (including transfer of funds), naval petroleum and oil shale reserves, energy conservation, economic regulation, emergency preparedness, the Energy Information Administration, the SPR (Strategic Petroleum Reserve), and the SPR Account. Limits SPR acquisition to approximately 75,000 barrels per day through February 1, 1988, and increases such rate to 100,000 barrels per day thereafter. Makes appropriations to the Department of Health and Human Services for the Health Resources and Services Administration for Indian health services and facilities. Appropriates funds to: (1) the Department of Education for the Office of Elementary and Secondary Education for Indian education; (2) the Navajo and Hopi Relocation Commission for salaries and expenses; (3) the Smithsonian Institution for salaries and expenses; (4) construction and improvements at the National Zoological Park; (5) restoration and renovation of buildings owned or occupied by the Smithsonian Institution; (6) construction at the Fred L. Whipple Observatory and other facilities; (7) salaries and expenses of the National Gallery of Art (NGA); (8) salaries and expenses of the Woodrow Wilson International Center for Scholars; and (9) the Endowment Challenge Fund for such Center. Makes appropriations for the National Foundation on the Arts and the Humanities for: (1) expenses and matching grants for the National Endowment for the Arts and the National Endowment for the Humanities and for national capital arts and cultural affairs; (2) the Martha Graham Center of Contemporary Dance and a matching grant; (3) the Institute of Museum Services; (4) salaries and expenses for the Commission of Fine Arts, the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation, the National Capital Planning Commission, the Franklin Delano Roosevelt Memorial Commission, the Pennsylvania Avenue Development Corporation (as well as for public development activities and projects); and (5) the U.S. Holocaust Memorial Council. Title III: General Provisions - Limits procurement contracts for consulting services obtained through appropriations made by this Act to those contracts where expenditures are a matter of public record. Prohibits the use of appropriations by the Secretaries of Agriculture and of the Interior for the sale of unprocessed timber from Federal lands west of the 100th meridian which will be exported from the United States or which will be used as a substitute for timber from private lands which is exported by the purchaser. Prohibits the Secretaries of the Interior and Agriculture from using such funds for leasing of oil and natural gas by noncompetitive bidding on public lands within the Shawnee National Forest, Illinois. Prohibits the use of such funds for any activity that tends to promote public support for or opposition to legislative proposals on which congressional action is incomplete. Declares that no part of any appropriation contained in this Act shall remain available for obligation beyond the current fiscal year unless expressly so provided herein. Provides that none of the funds appropriated to any department or agency shall be obligated or expended to provide a personal cook, chauffeur, or other personal servants to any officer or employee of such department or agency unless otherwise provided. Provides that none of the funds appropriated in this Act shall be obligated for any aspect of the processing or issuance of permits or leases pertaining to exploration for or development of coal, oil, gas, oil shale, phosphate, potassium, sulphur, gilsonite, geothermal resources on Federal lands within any component of the National Wilderness Preservation System or within any Forest Service RARE II areas recommended for wilderness designation or allocated to further planning, with certain exceptions. Prohibits the use of funds in this Act to evaluate, consider, process, or award oil, gas, or geothermal leases on Federal lands in the Mount Baker-Snoqualmie National Forest, State of Washington. Prohibits assessments from being levied against any program, budget activity, or project funded by this Act without approval by the Committees on Appropriations. Provides that employment funded by this Act shall not be subject to any personnel ceiling or other personnel restriction for permanent or other than permanent employment except as provided by law. Authorizes the Secretaries of the Interior, Agriculture, and Energy, and the Smithsonian Institution to enter into contracts with State and local governments for procurement of services in the presuppression, detection, and suppression of fires. Prohibits the use of funds for deer hunting in the Loxahatchee National Wildlife Refuge. Prohibits the use of funds to implement the proposed jurisdictional interchange program until the enactment of legislation. Requires the Forest Service and the Bureau of Land Management to complete their respective Forest Land and Resource Management Plans as quickly as possible. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate Rhode Island as a contract health service delivery area of the Indian Health Service for specified purposes. Delays the effective date for a specified rule relating to eligibility for the health care services of the Indian Health Service. Prohibits the Secretary of Agriculture from transferring specified lands in the Black Hills National Forest, South Dakota.</summary>
</bill>
