<bill session="100" type="h" number="2720" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the investment of the United States in the Panama Canal by certain amounts in the Panama Canal Commission Fund, and to use that amount of tolls and other receipts that covers interest on that increased investment for a Scholarship for Democracy Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404068"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1987-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from State, Treasury, Panama Canal Comm.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM05" subcommittee="Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Foreign students"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Panama Canal Act of 1979 to increase the investment of the United States by the amount of tolls and other receipts that covers interest on the investment of the United States and that was deposited in the Panama Canal Commission Fund before December 23, 1985. Establishes the "Scholarship for Democracy Program." Authorizes the Panama Canal Commission to provide scholarships under such program for undergraduate study at U.S. institutions of higher education by nationals of the Republic of Panama who have completed their secondary education. Sets forth guidelines for the administration of such program. Establishes a Scholarship Appointment Board. Specifies the membership of such Board. Authorizes the Board to choose the recipients of such scholarships. Requires that the part of tolls and other receipts of the Panama Canal Commission that covers interest on the increase in the investment of the United States in the Panama Canal provided for in this Act shall be deposited in a separate account in the Treasury. Makes available the amounts in such separate account for use by the scholarship program established by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
