<bill session="100" type="h" number="2773" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIDS Medical Records Confidentiality and Nondiscrimination Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require confidentiality for medical records maintained with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome on the same basis as is required by law for medical records maintained with respect to alcoholism and alcohol abuse and drug abuse and dependence and to require nondiscrimination in the admission to hospitals of persons with human immunodeficiency virus infection.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404019" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404220" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="406765" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1987-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1987-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-07-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1987-07-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospital patients"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1987--Introduced.
AIDS Medical Records Confidentiality and Nondiscrimination Act - Requires that records maintained in connection with acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS) be subject to the same provisions of the Public Health Service Act regarding confidentiality as are records relating to alcoholism and alcohol abuse. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to issue regulations enforcing a policy prohibiting discrimination regarding admission and treatment of persons with human immunodeficiency virus infection in hospitals and outpatient facilities which receive any support from any program administered by the Secretary. Authorizes the Secretary, on violation by any hospital or outpatient facility and with due process, to suspend or revoke all or part of any support received by the hospital. Authorizes the Secretary to consult with officials administering other Federal programs from which the hospital or outpatient facility receives support, regarding the suspension or revocation of such Federal support.</summary>
</bill>
