<bill session="100" type="h" number="2780" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Energy Policy and Conservation Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406740"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409793" joined="1987-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to direct the Secretary of Energy to implement during FY 1988 a program for filling the Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR) at a minimum average rate of 100,000 barrels per day until the quantity of crude oil in storage is at least 750,000,000 barrels. Mandates that the Secretary require each importer to provide for storage in the Reserve an amount of petroleum product equal to a percentage which, if applied uniformly to all importers, produces the fill rate for the requisite amount of barrels. Requires the Secretary to assess and collect charges (beginning in FY 1988) from each person who has petroleum product stored in the Reserve according to the program established by this Act. Sets forth guidelines for the assessment of such charges. Earmarks such charges for the construction, maintenance, and administration of the SPR storage facilities. Increases from 75,000 to 100,000 barrels per day the average daily rate of crude oil in storage in the Naval Petroleum Reserve per fiscal year. Terminates the authorities regarding the Petroleum Reserve on September 30, 1995.</summary>
</bill>
