<bill session="100" type="h" number="2790" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-14">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-12-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Buildings Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Public Buildings Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Public Buildings Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of management of public buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405687"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401837" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407816" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1987-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-25">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Government Activities and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Grounds.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-12-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-12-11">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.  Report No: 100-474 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-14">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="479" datetime="1987-12-14" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 271 - 86 (Record Vote No: 479).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO03" subcommittee="Government Activities and Transportation" name="House Government Operations"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW04" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Grounds" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1222"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2778"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/14/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended, roll call #479 (271-86)) Public Buildings Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Public buildings Act of 1959 to require congressional approval for any alteration or acquisition which exceeds the estimated maximum cost of $1,500,000 (currently, $500,000). Requires congressional approval for any alteration to leased space which exceeds such amount. Requires the Administrator of General Services, prior to leasing certain space, to certify in writing to specified congressional committees that the leasing of such space is necessary to meet requirements which cannot be met in public buildings. Describes such space as any space to accommodate: (1) major computer operations; (2) secure or sensitive activities related to national defense or security (except where inappropriate); (3) offices which would require major alterations in the structure or mechanical system of the building to be leased; or (4) a permanent courtroom, judicial chamber, or administrative office for any U.S. court. Provides that funds made available to the Administrator for the payment of rents shall also be available for the purpose of leasing space in buildings erected by the lessor on land owned by the United States. Authorizes the Administrator to adjust amounts for any alteration or acquisition annually to reflect a percentage increase or decrease in construction costs during the preceding calendar year, as determined by the composite index of construction costs of the Department of Commerce. Requires that any adjustment be reported to specified congressional committees. Authorizes the Administrator to issue debt instruments for purchase by the Secretary of the Treasury, to the extent authorized in annual appropriations Acts, in amounts necessary to finance the acquisition or construction of any public building (with prospectus approval as required). Provides for terms, conditions, and interest rates to be determined by the Secretary. Authorizes the Administrator to relinquish to a State, commonwealth, territory, or U.S. possession all or part of the jurisdiction of the United States over land or interests under the control of the Administrator in such State, commonwealth, territory, or possession. Prohibits the Administrator from making any agreement or undertaking any commitment which will result in the construction of any building for lease to, and for predominant use by, the United States until the Administrator has by regulation established detailed specification requirements for such building. Requires the Administrator to procure the construction of any such building only by soliciting competitive bids. Directs the Administrator to inspect such building during construction to ensure compliance with specifications. Requires the contract for construction of such building to contain provisions permitting a reduction of rent during any period when such building is not in compliance with specifications. Requires that buildings constructed or altered by a Federal agency comply with nationally recognized model building codes and with local zoning laws and other local requirements. Provides for State and local government consultation, review, and inspection. Requires the Administrator or appropriate agency to give due consideration to State and local government recommendations. Declares that no action may be brought against the United States for failure to meet requirements with respect to nationally recognized codes and recommendations. Provides that such requirements apply to projects for which funds are appropriated after FY 1989. Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to increase from three years to five years the period for which the Administrator may enter into contracts for the inspection, maintenance, and repair of fixed equipment and building services. Repeals the provision of Federal law which limits the maximum rental rate on leased buildings. Revises current provisions relating to the protection of Federal property by special policemen under the jurisdiction of the Administrator to state that the Administrator may provide such protection on property owned or occupied by the United States and under the charge and control of the Administrator.</summary>
</bill>
