<bill session="100" type="h" number="2795" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SSI Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVI of the Social Security Act to increase the effectiveness and improve the administration of the SSI program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400256"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404213" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>See H.R.3545.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1987--Introduced.
SSI Amendments of 1987 - Title I: Personal Needs Allowance Changes - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to increase SSI benefits payable to residents of medical facilities. Provides for cost-of-living adjustments of such benefits. Requires States making supplementary payments to residents of medical facilities who receiving SSI benefits to increase and then maintain them at the increased level. Continues the provision of full SSI benefits to individuals whose institutionalization is likely not to exceed three months during a continuous period of institutionalization and who need to continue to maintain and provide for the expenses of the home or living arrangement to which he or she may return after institutionalization. Title II: Changes in SSI Income and Resources and Income Eligibility Requirements - Excludes real property which, for specified reasons, cannot be sold from SSI resource eligibility determinations. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Resources, where necessary to avoid undue hardship, to suspend the penalties applied when individuals become SSI eligible by disposing of their resources at less than market value. Applies such penalties only where resources were disposed of within the past 24 months at more than $3,000 below their market value. Eliminates the SSI benefits reduction imposed on persons living in another's household and receiving support and maintenance in kind if such person pays a reasonable portion of the household expenses. Excludes from SSI income eligibility determinations: (1) retroactive old age, survivors and disability insurance (title II of the Act) benefits which are attributable to benefit underpayments for prior months; and (2) payments under part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Act. Excludes from SSI resource eligibility determinations: (1) interest and appreciation on amounts set aside to meet burial and related expenses; and (2) amounts received under the Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance (OASDI) program or the SSI program for the underpayment of benefits within the preceding 12 months. (Currently, the latter exclusion applies to reimbursement for underpayments within the preceding six months.) Reduces, from six months to one month, the period during which the income and resources of separated couples must be treated as jointly available for SSI eligibility purposes. Waives the one-month separation requirement where an individual applying for benefits has been the victim of domestic violence or other emergency circumstances exist. Amends the Employment Opportunities for Disabled Americans Act to authorize States to treat a husband and wife living in the same medical facility, whether or not they share a room, as though they were an SSI-eligible individual and his or her eligible spouse rather than two eligible individuals. Title III: Deemed SSI Status for Certain Individuals - Amends the SSI program to treat individuals who are ineligible for SSI benefits by reason of their receipt of widow's or widower's insurance benefits under the OASDI program as SSI recipients for purposes of title XIX (Medicaid) of the Act. Amends the Employment Opportunities for Disabled Americans Act to make a provision of such Act, treating individuals who are ineligible for SSI benefits by reason of their entitlement to, or an increase of, child's insurance benefits under the OASDI program as continuing to receive SSI benefits for Medicaid-eligibility purposes, applicable to individuals who become ineligible for SSI benefits after 1980. Extends, until July 1, 1987, the deadline for disabled widows or widowers who became ineligible for SSI benefits by reason of the increase in OASDI benefits caused by the Social Security Amendments of 1983 to apply for Medicaid coverage. Title IV: Provisions Related to Emergency Assistance - Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 to permanently disregard in-kind assistance provided by nonprofit organizations to SSI or AFDC recipients in determining the need or eligibility of such recipients. Amends the SSI program to authorize the Secretary to make an emergency cash advance to presumptively eligible individuals who are initially applying for SSI benefits up to the amount which would be payable for the first month to an eligible individual with no other income. Extends Federal reimbursement of State interim SSI assistance to cover such assistance provided for the period during which: (1) an individual's benefits were erroneously terminated or suspended; or, (2) an issued benefit check was lost or stolen before being negotiated and was not promptly replaced. Prohibits individuals who are in a public emergency shelter for the homeless for more than 12 consecutive months from being eligible for SSI payments. (Currently, SSI eligibility terminates when an individual has been in such shelter for more than three months in a 12-month period.) Title V: Provisions Related to the Blind - Entitles individuals who are applying for or receiving SSI benefits on the basis of blindness to elect to receive either supplementary notice by telephone or initial notice by certified mail of any determination made or other action taken with respect to such individual's SSI rights. Directs the Secretary to study the desirability and feasibility for extending such notification rights to other individuals who may lack the ability to read. Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Makes this Act's amendments effective on October 1, 1987, unless otherwise specified.</summary>
</bill>
