<bill session="100" type="h" number="2805" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Allied Commission on Out-of-Area Issues Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of a commission on out-of-area issues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402159" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403446" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403769" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404705" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404765" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405377" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405646" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407215" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1987-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA02" subcommittee="International Operations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA03" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asian and Pacific Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alliances"/>
    <term name="Collective security"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International organization"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/1987--Introduced.
Allied Commission on Out-of-Area Issues Act - Sets forth the purpose of this Act as providing a framework for the establishment of a commission on out-of-area issues (Commission) and encouraging the President to seek the establishment of such a Commission. States that such a Commission would include participants from among the group of militarily allied Western nations and would be regarded by the United States as a principal institution for consideration of allied perspective and policy options with respect to out-of-area issues. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Commission should: (1) promote a better understanding of how Western nations might respond to out-of-area events and issues without formally engaging NATO and other security alliances; (2) specifically define potential out-of-area contingencies which might threaten the West; (3) better relate, for planning purposes, the out-of-area security concerns of Japan and America's other Asian allies with those of NATO; (4) explore the possibility of better coordinating the foreign and military aid programs of the Western allies as a means of promoting growth and stability in less developed countries; and (5) promote better coordination among Commission participants in the other multinational organizations to which they belong. Authorizes the President to invite the member states of NATO and Japan to participate with the United States in a commission on out-of-area issues and to also invite member states of the Security Treaty between Australia, New Zealand, and the United States (ANZUS), the Southeast Asia Treaty Organization (SEATO) and other appropriate countries to participate in the Commission. Expresses the sense of the Congress that such a Commission should: (1) be established within an already existing, nonsecurity-oriented, multinational framework; (2) be composed of nationally appointed delegates of demonstrated ability appointed by national executive branches of government; (3) convene at least twice yearly for the purpose of assessing works in progress and establishing future agendas; and (4) compile and dissemination task force reports, findings, and policy memoranda as well as an annual report. Requires the President to submit a report to the Congress on progress toward implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
