<bill session="100" type="h" number="2839" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-11-23">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-11-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to correct historical and geographical oversights in the establishment and development of the Utah component of the Confederated Tribes of the Goshute Reservation, to unify the land base of the Goshute Reservation, to simplify the boundaries of the Goshute Reservation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-10-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-10-27">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-402.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-27">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 260.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-27">
      <text>Placed on Consent Calendar No: 14.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-16">
      <text>Called up by House on Call of Consent Calendar.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-16">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Senate Committee on Indian Affairs discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported in lieu of S. 1687 with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. With written report No. 100-549.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="996">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 996.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-21" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-11-14">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-11-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-11-23" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-708" type="public" datetime="1988-11-23">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-708.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1687"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1687"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3765"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/21/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Declares specified Indian lands in Utah to be held in trust by the United States for the use and benefit of the Confederated Tribes of the Goshute Reservation. Provides the effective date for determining water rights, and priorities related to such rights, in such lands. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to deprive a person of any valid existing right or interest in such lands which such person may hold upon enactment of this Act. Transfers all valid Federal rights-of-way, leases, permits, the right to receive compensation for the use of such lands, and other land use rights or authorizations, except mining claims, to the Tribe and the Secretary of the Interior as trustee. Requires the Secretary, not later than two years after enactment of this Act, to determine the validity of all mining claims that exist on such lands upon enactment of this Act. Declares that all right, title, and interest of the United States in certain additional lands are to be held in trust by the United States for the use and benefit of the Tribe and are to be a part of the Reservation. Prohibits such lands from being developed for commercial purposes as long as they are held in trust by the United States. Requires the Secretary to publish a legal description of such lands in the Federal Register. Requires that a map depicting the lands added to the Reservation by this Act be on file in the Bureau of Indian Affairs' Land Title Record Office having jurisdiction over such lands. Requires the approval of the Secretary before any transfer of certain Federal lands adjacent to the Reservation. Extinguishes the right of the United States to construct ditches and canals on specified Indian lands. Subjects Indian lands added to the Reservation under this Act to Federal laws to the same extent as those laws apply to the Reservation on the date of enactment of this Act. Subjects the conveyance of interests by the United States in specified lands to the payment by the Tribe of fair market value as determined by the Secretary. Declares specified Indian lands in Utah to be held in trust for the benefit of the Ute Mountain Ute Indian Tribe and to be part of the Ute Indian Reservation.</summary>
</bill>
