<bill session="100" type="h" number="2851" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Onshore Oil and Gas Leasing Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Onshore Oil and Gas Leasing Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920 to reform the onshore oil and gas leasing program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Mining and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-378 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary Sequentially, for a Period Ending not Later than Nov 6, 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Criminal Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture Sequentially, for a Period Ending not Later than Nov 20, 87.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-06">
      <text>House Committee on The Judiciary Granted an Extension for Further Consideration Ending not Later Than November 20, 1987.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forest, Family Farms, and Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20">
      <text>House Committee on The Judiciary Discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20">
      <text>House Committee on Agriculture Discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 285.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-01">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3545.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII02" subcommittee="Mining and Natural Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU07" subcommittee="Criminal Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSAG06" subcommittee="Forests, Family Farms, and Energy" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/15/1987--Reported to House amended, Part I.
(Reported to House from the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs, amended, H. Rept. 100-378 (Part I)) Federal Onshore Oil and Gas Leasing Reform Act of 1987 - Amends the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920 regarding competitive leasing of oil and gas for onshore Federal lands to increase from 640 acres to 2,560 acres the units of land open to competitive leasing. Restricts the maximum units in Alaska to 5,760 acres. Provides for lease sales to be: (1) conducted by oral bidding (but with sealed bids permitted); and (2) held at least quarterly in each State (or more frequently at the Secretary of the Interior's discretion). Conditions such lease sales upon the payment of specified royalties. Sets forth a $75 bidding fee. Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to accept the highest bid from a responsible bidder. Authorizes the Secretary not to issue a lease if, in his discretion, he determines that the highest bid would not represent a reasonable return to the public. Makes lands available for leasing without competitive bidding for a maximum one-year period if no bids have been received. Increases the annual lease rental from 50 cents to $2 per acre for the first five years, and for a minimum of $3.00 per acre per year for each year thereafter. Increases the minimum royalty upon discovery of oil or gas in paying quantities from $1 per acre to $3.00 per acre. Requires the Secretary to make maps and narrative descriptions available to the public at least: (1) 60 days before offering lands for lease; and (2) 30 days before substantially modifying lease terms. Directs the Secretary to provide periodic notice to State and local governments and to the public regarding pending applications for drilling permits. Prescribes guidelines under which the Secretary (or the Secretary of Agriculture for national public domain forest lands) must regulate surface-disturbing activities conducted upon lease lands. Authorizes the Secretary to disapprove specified lease assignments at his discretion. Amends lease cancellation conditions to provide that leases will not be cancelled due to the lessee's non-compliance with lease terms if: (1) the leasehold contains a well capable of oil or gas production in paying quantities; or (2) the lease is committed to an approved cooperative, unit plan, or communitization agreement which contains a well capable of unitized substances production in paying quantities. Permits the issuance of oil or gas leases on public lands (or public domain national forest lands) only if such leasing has been evaluated and approved in a land use plan meeting certain statutory requirements. Prescribes guidelines for such land use plans. Prohibits the issuance of oil or gas leases upon certain lands allocated or designated as wilderness areas. Sets forth guidelines for the promulgation of regulations regarding lease sales. Imposes civil and criminal penalties upon persons who willfully and knowingly misrepresent the value of lands and leases under this Act. Grants to the States concurrent civil and criminal jurisdiction for violations of this Act. States that Federal law regarding competitive leasing of oil and gas for onshore Federal lands may be cited as the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920.</summary>
</bill>
