<bill session="100" type="h" number="2865" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pension Plan Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide that the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation may require security as a condition of certain pension plan funding waivers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403641"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-01">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Pension trust guaranty insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/1987--Introduced.
Pension Plan Protection Act of 1987 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code and the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to authorize the Pension Benefit Guaranty Corporation (PBGC) to require security as a condition of certain pension plan funding waivers and extensions. Provides that such security may be required of single-employer defined benefit plans where: (1) accumulated funding deficiencies exceed $1,000,000; and (2) the fair market value of the assets of the plan does not exceed 70 percent of an amount equal to the present value of benefits under the plan which would be treated as accrued were the plan terminated on the determination date. Provides that, if any benefit under the plan is payable under an irrevocable commitment from an insurer, the fair market value of such commitment and the present value of the benefits payable under such commitment shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the asset/benefit ratio. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to provide the PBGC with information to carry out such security requirements. Decreases the amount of accumulated funding deficiencies exempt from waiver limitations. Authorizes the PBGC to require security for a pension plan where the fair market value of the assets of a single-employer defined benefit plan does not exceed 70 percent of the present value of accrued benefits under the plan. Provides that, if any benefit under the plan is payable under an irrevocable commitment from an insurer, the fair market value of such commitment and the present value of the benefits payable under such commitment shall not be taken into account for purposes of determining the asset/benefit ratio. Provides for imposition of a lien where there is a failure to provide the requested security.</summary>
</bill>
