<bill session="100" type="h" number="29" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home Mortgage Disclosure Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to permanently authorize the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410231"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Home Mortgage Disclosure Act Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act of 1975 to include as a "depository institution" subject to certain disclosure requirements for federally-insured mortgage loans, any mortgage banking subsidiary of a bank holding company or savings and loan holding company or any savings and loan service corporation that originates or purchases mortgage loans. Requires depository institutions, generally, to list, by State, each mortgage loan originated or purchased and secured by property located outside metropolitan statistical areas. Requires the disclosure statements for a calendar year to be made available to the public at central depositories of data by the following June 1. Repeals the expiration date for such Act. Directs the Federal Financial Institutions Examination Council to study and report to the Congress on the costs to depository institutions of disclosure reports required under such Act, the estimated usage of the data provided, obstacles to usage, and recommendations for action by the Federal financial institutions' regulatory agencies to increase public awareness about the availability of such data.</summary>
</bill>
