<bill session="100" type="h" number="2921" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration and Nationality Efficiency Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to improve the administration of the immigration and nationality laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bus drivers"/>
    <term name="Census and Statistics"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor bus lines"/>
    <term name="Naturalization"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Performing arts"/>
    <term name="Population statistics"/>
    <term name="Professions"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Statistical services"/>
    <term name="Temporary employment"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Widowers"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/1987--Introduced.
Immigration and Nationality Efficiency Amendments of 1987 - Title I: Entry and Adjustment of Status - Part A: Entry and Adjustment of Status of Immigrants - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to exclude returning permanent resident aliens from the definition of "entry" for purposes of this Act. Provides for the admission of a limited number of specified employees of multinational corporations and their families as special immigrants. Requires members of professions to have appropriate college degrees or significant work experience for purposes of such Act. Allows surviving spouses of citizens to petition for entry under immediate relative status. Reduces the Amerasian sponsorship requirement from five years to two years. Allows private agency sponsorship for adult Amerasians. Repeals the employment offer requirement for preference entry purposes for specified aliens with extraordinary ability in the arts. Extends reentry permit length from not more than two years to five years. Part B: Entry and Adjustment of Status of Nonimmigrants - Provides for the temporary admission into the United States of operators of (passenger) motor common carriers. Broadens the classification of nonimmigrant treaty trader and investor to include supervisory services or transfer of technology. Permits admission as nonimmigrants of non-treaty traders or investors who invest substantial amounts of money and employ at least five U.S. workers from countries providing similar reciprocal immigration rights to U.S. nationals. Requires the Attorney General and the Secretary of State to monitor such admissions and report to the Congress within two years. Separates "H" status nonimmigrants into professionals or executives and aliens of distinguished merit and ability. Requires alien trainees to participate in formal training programs. Part C: Refugee-Related Provisions - Provides for permanent resident status to be granted to refugees immediately upon entry. Title II: Exclusion and Deportation - Authorizes the waiver of literacy requirements (for purposes of exclusion) for sole surviving siblings 55 years of age or older. Provides for the deportation of an alien who enters the United States under a work-related preference visa and does not engage in such employment or occupation within 12 months of entry. Replaces the existing individual suspension of deportation reporting requirement with an annual reporting requirement regarding numbers and nationality of suspended deportations. Title III: Enforcement - Provides for the temporary release on parole of an alien involved in exclusion or deportation proceedings. Prohibits such release under specified circumstances. Increases specified Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS) fines. Authorizes the INS to receive 50 percent of such amounts. Title IV: Citizenship and Naturalization - Permits a child born outside the United States to derive citizenship automatically upon naturalization of the parent if the child resides permanently in the United States and is less than 18 years old at the time such naturalization occurs. Permits nonprofit organizations approved by the Attorney General to receive naturalization material. Directs the Commissioner of the INS to provide for, and make available to the Congress and to the public, statistical information useful in evaluating the social, economic, environmental, and demographic effects of this Act's provisions.</summary>
</bill>
