<bill session="100" type="h" number="2931" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Olmsted Public Parks Landscapes Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to identify, commemorate, and preserve the legacy of historic publicly owned parks of Frederick Law Olmsted, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407162" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-14">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.17.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="17"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1670"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1670"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Landscape architecture"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1987--Introduced.
Olmsted Public Parks Landscapes Act of 1987 - Requires the Secretary to encourage maximum public participation in carrying out the purposes of this Act. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Director of the National Park Service, to prepare a State-by State inventory of Olmsted public parks. Requires that such parks be evaluated for inclusion on the National Register of Historic Places. Requires periodic updating of the inventory. Requires appropriate access to such inventory at the Library of Congress, the Frederick Law Olmsted National Historic Site in Brookline, Massachusetts, the National Park Service regional headquarters, and appropriate State offices. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to: (1) promulgate general standards for preservation of Olmsted public parks in Federal control; (2) provide technical assistance to Federal agencies, State and local governments, private organizations, and other interested individuals on the identification, commemoration, and preservation of Olmsted public parks; (3) catalog and evaluate Olmsted documents; and (4) encourage a program for the use of the Frederick Law Olmsted National Historic Site in Massachusetts as a center for research. Requires the Secretary to provide for the coordination of applications for grants for the preservation of Olmsted public parks. Requires the Secretary to conduct appropriate activities during the period 1987 to 1995 to commemorate the Olmsted achievements and influence on American life. Establishes the Technical Committee on Olmsted public parks to assist the Secretary on matters that relate to Olmsted heritage landscapes. Terminates such Committee after December 31, 1997.</summary>
</bill>
