<bill session="100" type="h" number="2957" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-03">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for improvements in the National Cemetery System administered under title 38, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400211"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400906" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403576" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405114" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="405313" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405985" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406682" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407432" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407673" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407838" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="408520" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409219" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409442" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410245" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400389" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="411929" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.  Report No: 100-246.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 152.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="295" datetime="1987-08-03" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 393 - 0 (Record Vote No: 295).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29">
      <text>Certain Provisions Included in H.R.2616.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2616"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="American Battle Monuments Commission"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Amends Federal provisions relating to cemeteries and memorials to remove the per-State limitation on the receipt of grant funds used for the establishment, expansion, and improvement of veterans' cemeteries. Authorizes the Administrator of Veterans Affairs (the Administrator) to make contributions to local authorities for the construction of traffic controls, road improvements, or other devices on land adjacent to a national cemetery if the Administrator determines that such a contribution is necessary for safe ingress and egress to or from such cemetery. Authorizes the Administrator to provide an approved grave liner for the interment of remains in cemeteries within the National Cemetery System and in Arlington National Cemetery, Arlington, Virginia. Authorizes the Administrator to provide for flat grave markers in the following instances: (1) in the case of gravesites of cremated remains that are interred in the ground; (2) in the case of graves on land transferred to the Department of Memorial Affairs from the Department of Medicine and Surgery of the Veterans Administration for the expansion of a cemetery at the Clement A. Zablocki Veterans' Administration Medical Center in Milwaukee, Wisconsin; and (3) at the national cemetery at Indiantown Gap, Pennsylvania. Establishes in the Treasury an account to be known as the Foreign Currency Fluctuations, American Battle Monuments Commission, Account (the Account). States that funds from the Account shall be used by the American Battle Monuments Commission (the Commission) to eliminate losses due to fluctuations in currency exchange rates of foreign countries which occur after a budget request for the Commission is submitted to the Congress. Requires any limits applicable to appropriations available to the Commission to be adjusted to account for any such foreign currency fluctuations. Authorizes funds originally transferred from the Account to be transferred back to the Account if foreign currency fluctuations necessitate such action. Requires unobligated balances of funds appropriated to the Commission for a fiscal year to be transferred into the Account within a specified time and to be merged with and available for the same period and purposes as the Account. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to report to the Congress annually on funds made available under this provision. Authorizes appropriations to the Account.</summary>
</bill>
