<bill session="100" type="h" number="2967" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Waste Policy Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Nuclear Waste Policy Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Nuclear Waste Technical Review Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Nuclear Waste Policy Review Commission, an Office of the Nuclear Waste Negotiator, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300049" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="405687" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-15">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-08">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-10-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-11-05">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-425 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3545.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2888"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/1987--Reported to House amended, Part I.
(Reported to House from the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs with amendment, H. Rept. 100-425 (Part I)) Nuclear Waste Policy Amendments Act of 1987 - Title I: The Nuclear Waste Policy Review Commission - Establishes in the legislative branch the Nuclear Waste Policy Review Commission to advise the Congress regarding the safe disposition of radioactive waste after a review and evaluation of the current status of radioactive waste disposal. Requires the Commission to report its findings and recommendations to the Congress within 12 months after enactment of this Act. Terminates the Commission within 60 days after submission of its report. Authorizes appropriations. Prohibits the Secretary of Energy from expending any funds to conduct specified activities regarding a nuclear waste site until six months after submission of such report. Annuls and revokes the Draft Area Recommendation Report issued by the Secretary on January 16, 1986. Prohibits the Secretary from giving preferences to sites identified in such report. Directs the Secretary to consult with and provide impact mitigation assistance to: (1) States; (2) governmental units; (3) Indian tribes; and (4) special purpose taxing districts. Directs the Secretary to provide grants equal to taxes to special purpose taxing districts (in addition to impact mitigation assistance). Authorizes the Secretary to study the feasibility of siting a monitored retrievable storage facility in any State upon its request. Title II: The Office of the Nuclear Waste Negotiator - Establishes within the Executive Office of the President the Office of the Nuclear Waste Negotiator, headed by the Nuclear Waste Negotiator who shall be appointed by, and hold office at the pleasure of, the President (with the advice and consent of the Senate). Requires the Negotiator to: (1) find a State or Indian tribe willing to host a repository (or monitored retrievable storage site (MRS)); and (2) submit to the Congress any proposed agreement regarding such repository host. Directs the Secretary, upon the Negotiator's request, to prepare an environmental assessment of any site that is under negotiation. Prescribes guidelines for environmental assessments and site characterization. Authorizes grants to assess the feasibility of siting an MRS within the affected locality. Declares that the issuance of a repository construction authorization shall be considered a major Federal action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 (thus requiring the Secretary of Energy to prepare a final environmental impact statement). Sets forth alternative termination dates for the Office. Authorizes appropriations. Title III: Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board - Nuclear Waste Technical Review Act of 1987 - Establishes the Nuclear Waste Technical Review Board as an independent entity within the executive branch to evaluate the Secretary's activities, including site characterization and the packaging and transportation of radioactive waste. Outlines the Board's membership, terms of office, and administrative parameters. Requires the Board to report its findings and recommendations biannually to the Congress and the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates such Board within one year after the date on which the Secretary begins repository disposal of high-level radioactive waste or spent nuclear fuel.</summary>
</bill>
