<bill session="100" type="h" number="2971" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-20">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-08-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniform Cotton Classing Fees Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Uniform Cotton Classing Fees Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Uniform Cotton Classing Fees Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Uniform Cotton Classing Fees Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide continuing authority to the Secretary of Agriculture for recovering costs associated with cotton classing services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405747"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Cotton, Rice, and Sugar.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-27">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Agriculture. Report No: 100-242.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-27">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 150.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-27">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-07-27" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="268">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 268.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1987-08-05" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1987-08-05">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1987-08-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1987-08-20" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-108" type="public" datetime="1987-08-20">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-108.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAG02" subcommittee="Cotton, Rice, and Sugar" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing regulation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Grading (Agricultural products)"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Uniform Cotton Classing Fees Act of 1987 - Amends the Cotton Statistics and Estimates Act to extend the Secretary of Agriculture's authority to provide cotton classification services and to collect fees for such services through FY 1992. Provides that the uniform cotton per bale classification for a crop year shall be the previous year's fee, exclusive of prior adjustments, and as may be adjusted for the percentage change in the Implicit Price Deflator for Gross National Product as indexed during the most recent 12-month period. Provides that the uniform per bale classification fee for a crop year may be increased, or decreased, by up to one percent for every 100,000 bales produced below, or above, 12,500,000 bales. Stipulates that such adjustments shall not exceed 15 percent unless fees and other income sources will not provide an ending operating reserve of at least ten percent of estimated operating expenses. Authorizes the Secretary to add a special surcharge or up to five cents a bale if the projected fiscal year ending reserve is less than 25 percent of estimated operating expenses. Prohibits the Secretary from establishing a uniform per bale classification fee if (when combined with other revenues and adjusted for expenses) doing so will result in a projected operating reserve of more than 25 percent. States that the Secretary should continue to recognize that central billing can reduce administrative costs. Directs the Secretary to announce: (1) the uniform classification fee and any crop surcharge by June 1 of the year that such fee applies; and (2) the FY 1987 fee as soon as practicable after enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary to: (1) conduct a study (and perform testing as necessary) of the differences between processing efficiency and product quality for Light Spotted and White grade cottons; (2) conduct a survey and research to determine why an increasing proportion of the cotton crop is being classified as Light Spotted; and (3) submit an initial report to the appropriate congressional committees by October 1, 1988, and a final report as soon as practicable.</summary>
</bill>
