<bill session="100" type="h" number="3019" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Literacy Corps Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide financial assistance for the establishment and operation of literacy corps programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404170"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401446" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404213" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405687" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407471" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409344" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1987-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-10-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="410623" joined="1988-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410926" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1987-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Community and college"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/1987--Introduced.
Literacy Corps Assistance Act of 1987 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to institutions of higher education for up to two years to carry out literacy corps programs. Authorizes use of funds under this Act for: (1) grants to institutions of higher education for institutional participation costs and student coordinator stipends in the Literacy Corps Program; and (2) technical assistance, information collection and dissemination, and evaluation. Limits to $50,000 the amount of a grant to an institution of higher education. Limits to $25,000 the amount of such grant which may be expended in the first year. Sets forth grant application requirements. Requires the institution to have one or more courses of instruction for academic credit which are designed to combine the training of undergraduates in various academic departments with experience as tutors. Requires such individuals, as a condition of receiving credit in such course, to perform at least six hours of voluntary, uncompensated service each week of the academic term as a tutor in a public community agency's educational or literacy program. Requires that such tutoring service be under the supervision of qualified personnel. Requires the institution to demonstrate that it has participated in community service activities, including the use of a portion of its work study program allotment for community service learning, or the conduct of a cooperative education program. Allows a waiver of such institutional community service requirement if the institution has conducted another significant program involving community outreach and service, or its prior failure will not impede its ability to engage in necessary outreach efforts, and it will use a portion of any work-study program allotment it receives for community service learning programs. Authorizes the Secretary, directly or by other arrangement, to: (1) provide technical assistance to grant recipients; (2) collect and disseminate information on programs under this Act; and (3) evaluate and report on such programs. Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act for FY 1988 and thereafter, but limits such authorization to two fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
