<bill session="100" type="h" number="3077" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Regional Monitored Retrievable Storage Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to suspend certain activities of the Secretary of Energy under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982, to authorize construction of regional monitored retrievable storage facilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407967"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy Research and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>See H.R.3545.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY06" subcommittee="Energy Research and Development" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive waste disposal in the ground"/>
    <term name="Radioactive waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1987--Introduced.
Regional Monitored Retrievable Storage Act - Prohibits the expenditure of funds for any site-specific activity under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 until an Act reauthorizing the resumption of such activity is enacted after the date of enactment of this Act (thus indefinitely suspending such activity). Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to authorize the Secretary of Energy to construct at least four monitored retrievable storage facilities meeting prescribed design prerequisites. Directs the Secretary to: (1) establish site selection criteria for such facilities within 180 days after the enactment of this Act, and to submit them to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and to the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (the Commission); and (2) select one monitored retrievable storage facility site in each of four specified regions. Directs the Commission to issue licensing regulations for such facilities. Prohibits repository construction in any State in which a facility is already located. Requires the Secretary to: (1) provide financial assistance to States and Indian tribes regarding the construction and operation of such facilities; and (2) make annual impact aid payment to local government units. Directs the Secretary of Energy to accelerate a demonstration program for subseabed disposal of high-level radioactive waste, and to establish a university-based consortium (including private research firms) to investigate the feasibility for such disposal. Authorizes appropriations for alternative disposal systems. Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to prescribe guidelines under which the States (or their political subdivisions) may regulate hazardous waste materials transportation.</summary>
</bill>
