<bill session="100" type="h" number="3070" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-13">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">PCB Regulatory Improvements Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">PCB Regulatory Improvements Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act to require persons handling polychlorinated biphenyls to comply with the manifest and financial responsibility requirements of the Solid Waste Disposal Act and to require persons carrying out certain intermediate activities with respect to polychlorinated biphenyls to obtain approval from the Environmental Protection Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410589"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1988-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="401923" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1987-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407351" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408575" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1987-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409966" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1987-11-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411488" joined="1987-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-13">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Energy and Commerce.  Report No: 100-692.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-13">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 414.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-13">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-06-13" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/13/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) PCB Regulatory Improvements Act of 1988 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to require all handlers of polychlorinated biphenyl (PCB) waste to notify the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) of their handling activity. Directs the EPA to provide handlers with an indentification number within 30 days of receiving such notification. Requires all handlers of PCB waste to comply with the requirements of an EPA manifest system or, if such system is not established within 120 days of this Act's enactment, with the system set forth in the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Requires that a manifest be initiated when PCB waste leaves its generation site and is not owned or controlled by its generator, or leaves a storage site owned by such generator. Directs PCB waste transporters to comply with EPA PCB waste transportation requirements or, if such requirements are not promulgated within 90 days of this Act's enactment, with the requirements for the transportation of hazardous waste set forth under the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Makes such requirements applicable when PCB waste leaves its generation site and is not owned or controlled by its generator, or leaves a storage site owned by such generator. Requires PCB storage facilities to obtain EPA approval for their storage activity within 270 days of this Act's enactment. Identifies minimum criteria by which the EPA is to make the approval determination. Makes the storage approval requirement inapplicable to: (1) generators who store their own PCBs; (2) storers of PCBs generated by a corporate parent, subsidiary, or sister subsidiary of the same parent; (3) storage incidental to disposal which has been approved by the EPA. Requires PCB storage and disposal facilities to comply with EPA financial responsibility, contingency plan, facility closure, and post-closure care requirements or, if such requirements are not promulgated within 180 days of this Act's enactment, with such requirements for hazardous wastes contained in the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Directs the EPA to review and, if necessary, modify all PCB storage and disposal approvals within at least five years of their issuance or reissuance. Requires that approvals issued after this Act's enactment be for a fixed term. Authorizes the EPA to revoke an approval for a person's noncompliance with Toxic Substances Control Act requirements. Requires the EPA to: (1) thoroughly inspect all PCB storage and disposal facilities at least once every two years; and (2) publish by June 30 of each year a notice of any enforcement actions for violations of PCB requirements concluded during the previous year.</summary>
</bill>
