<bill session="100" type="h" number="3095" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Financial Security Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 and the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to authorize controls on the export of capital from the United States, to control exports supporting terrorism, to prohibit ownership of United States banks by controlled countries, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="401628" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="402928" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405448" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300062" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409237" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409423" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="410529" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411247" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1987-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA07" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA03" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Bank mergers"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Emigration"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jews"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1987--Introduced.
International Financial Security Act of 1987 - Amends the Export Administration Act to state congressional findings that loans and other transfers of capital to the Soviet Union and its allies increase the ability of those countries to obtain sensitive goods and technology and to more easily divert funds to purposes inimical to U.S. interests. Declares that it is U.S. policy to use export controls to: (1) restrict the export of capital, the extension of credit, or the transfer of financial resources to destinations or persons abroad in order to promote the national security, including antiterrorism, the foreign policy interests of the United States, the advancement of emigration of Soviet Jews and other ethnic minorities, and human rights policies of the Soviet Union and other East Bloc countries; and (2) restrict the export of goods and technology where such export will likely support terrorism against U.S. citizens or benefit terrorists or countries supporting international terrorism. Authorizes the President to restrict the export or transfer of goods and technology if such export will likely support terrorism against U.S. citizens or benefit terrorists or countries supporting international terrorism. Provides for negotiations with other countries to obtain their cooperation with such export controls on capital, goods, and technology. Requires export license applications for the export of capital to be submitted to the Secretary of the Treasury, who shall make all determinations with respect to such application. Requires the annual report on the administration of the Export Administration Act of 1979 to include a report on actions taken to carry out export controls on capital. Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to require that any notice of a change in control of an insured bank include the nationality of the person or persons making the acquisition. Sets forth criminal penalties for violation of any change in control requirement. Requires Federal banking agencies to disapprove any proposed acquisition which would result in the ownership or control of an insured bank by a country subject to national security export controls or a national agency, or instrumentality of any such country. Requires federally-insured banks to include in reports of condition and reports to shareholders, and make available to the public, information concerning the number and amount of each untied loan made to any controlled country. Requires designated financial institutions to report annually to the appropriate Federal regulatory agency, and make available to the public, information on the number and amount of investments in any East Bloc obligation.</summary>
</bill>
