<bill session="100" type="h" number="3091" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Taxpayer Protection Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 to regulate and limit collection procedures of the Internal Revenue Service in order to provide protection of taxpayer civil rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.4333.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Churches"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Estate tax"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Gift tax"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Internal revenue law"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Religion and Clergy"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax auditing"/>
    <term name="Tax courts"/>
    <term name="Tax liens"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1987--Introduced.
Taxpayer Protection Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to subject the Internal Revenue Service (IRS), in the collection of taxes, to provisions of the Fair Debt Collection Practices Act regarding communication and harassment in connection with debt collection. Prohibits the publication of any tax deficiency which has not been adjudged to be payable by a competent court. Permits individual taxpayers to bring a civil action in a U.S. district court for damages resulting from collection practices prohibited by this Act. Requires a Federal court order before property of a taxpayer may be levied upon for the collection of tax. Specifies that a showing of fraud or malfeasance or a misrepresentation, for purposes of modifying or reconsidering a closing agreement between an individual taxpayer and the Secretary of the Treasury, shall be taken into account only if such a showing or misrepresentation is determined by a competent court. Prohibits the Secretary from consenting to extend for more than one year the period for assessment of the income tax liability of any individual taxpayer. Requires the Secretary to prepare, for distribution to taxpayers, brief but comprehensive statements which set forth in nontechnical terms: (1) the rights and obligations of taxpayers during an audit; (2) the procedures which the IRS may use in enforcing revenue laws; and (3) the procedures by which a taxpayer may appeal adverse decisions, prosecute refund claims, and file taxpayer complaints. Requires a copy of such statement to accompany any tax forms sent to taxpayers. Prescribes criminal penalties for: (1) any investigation by employees of the United States in connection with Federal tax laws which inquires into the beliefs, associations, or activities of any individual or organization; or (2) the maintenance of any records containing information derived from such an investigation. Creates a civil cause of action for any taxpayer aggrieved by a prohibited investigation or by the deprivation of any civil rights. Permits the award of a judgment of costs, including reasonable attorney's fees, to a prevailing taxpayer in proceedings before the Tax Court. Makes binding on the Secretary: (1) a tax return prepared for the taxpayer by an IRS officer or employee acting in official capacity to provide such assistance; and (2) written information or advice given to the taxpayer by such an officer or employee acting in official capacity. Places the burden of proof upon the IRS in administrative and judicial proceedings involving the IRS and a taxpayer. Directs that the property of taxpayers, for purposes of the estate and gift tax, be valued at historical cost (original cost to the taxpayer or the basis of the property if it was not purchased). Prohibits the use in IRS personnel evaluations of amounts collected pursuant to audits or investigations. Precludes the Secretary from exercising any enforcement authority over churches or certain other organizations. Prohibits the audit of any group of taxpayers unless the Secretary has first met certain notice requirements or permitted members of the group to file an amended return. Sets forth conditions which must be met by the IRS before any action is taken to interfere with the property rights of a taxpayer. Requires the IRS, before securing the records of or personal data concerning any taxpayer, to: (1) notify the taxpayer in writing of the demand, the material sought, and the need for the material; (2) have commenced an action in a competent court against the taxpayer; and (3) have justified its need before the court consistent with the discovery rules of the Federal Rules of Civil Procedure. States that the IRS shall have no authority, in enforcing the tax obligations of any person, which conflicts with rights and privileges granted under the Constitution.</summary>
</bill>
