<bill session="100" type="h" number="3123" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Protections and Safety Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Department of Energy Nuclear Safety Board Oversight Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Mixed Hazardous Waste Amendment Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Radiation Study Advisory Board Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create an independent oversight board to ensure the safety of United States Government nuclear facilities, to apply the provisions of OSHA to certain Department of Energy nuclear facilities, to clarify the jurisdiction and powers of Government agencies dealing with nuclear wastes, to ensure independent research on the effects of radiation on human beings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403726"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and Safety.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED05" subcommittee="Health and Safety" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1987--Introduced.
Nuclear Protections and Safety Act of 1987 - Title I: Independent Nuclear Safety Board Oversight Over Department of Energy Facilities - Department of Energy Nuclear Safety Board Oversight Act of 1987 - Amends the Energy Reorganization Act of 1974 to establish a Department of Energy Nuclear Safety Board to: (1) annually evaluate health and safety standards and Department of Energy Orders at each Department of Energy nuclear facility; (2) recommend necessary changes; (3) investigate events at such facilities which might adversely affect the public health or safety; (4) recommend specific measures to the Secretary of Energy (the Secretary) to minimize the likelihood of such events; and (5) issue periodic reports for congressional and governmental agencies regarding health and safety issues at Department of Energy nuclear facilities. Requires the Secretary to implement the Board recommendations, with provision for exemptions. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1993. Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards to provide assistance as requested by the independent Nuclear Safety Board. Authorizes the Committee to expand its membership in order to provide such assistance. Directs the Secretary to reimburse the Committee for the costs incurred in providing such assistance. Authorizes the Director of the Naval Propulsion Program to assist and advise the Board from time to time. Directs the Board to request the National Academy of Sciences or some other independent group of experts to assist it in conducting its first annual review through evaluating and interpreting the differences between Nuclear Regulatory Commission regulations and the Department of Energy orders governing nuclear facilities, including safety implications. Title II: Application of OSHA and NIOSH to DOE Nuclear Facilities - Applies the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (OSHA), with specified exceptions, to: (1) a production or utilization facility under the control or jurisdiction of the Secretary; (2) a facility subject to the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 under the control or jurisdiction of the Secretary; and (3) a waste storage facility under the control or jurisdiction of the Secretary. Requires the Secretary of Labor to promulgate regulations to govern application of OSHA to such facilities. Specifies the content of such regulations. Requires the National Institute for Occupational Safety and Health (and its Director) to perform its statutory functions at such facilities. Directs the Secretary and each contractor operating such facility to cooperate with either the Secretary of Labor or the Secretary of Health and Human Services in the conduct of facility inspections or investigations (including granting access and providing information). Title III: Mixed Hazardous Waste - Mixed Hazardous Waste Amendment Act of 1987 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to redefine the term "solid waste" to exclude: (1) source, special nuclear, or byproduct materials (as defined in the Atomic Energy Act of 1954) unless such materials are a part of any mixture or combination, if the other constituent part of such mixture or combination is a solid waste; or (2) wastes at the time they are emplaced at a nuclear waste repository. Title IV: Radiation Study Advisory Board Act of 1987 - Radiation Study Advisory Board Act of 1987 - Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish the Radiation Research Review Board to advise and assist the Secretary of Energy in conducting epidemiological studies of radiation effects. Requires the Secretary of Energy to provide the Board with all requests for proposals concerning epidemiological studies of radiation health effects if such studies call for an expenditure (or authorization) of funds greater than $100,000. Requires the Board to review such proposals and make written recommendations if it believes such proposals should be modified or not funded. Requires the Secretary of Energy to: (1) implement Board recommendations prior to the authorization or expenditure of funds; or (2) inform the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Congress of his intention not to implement such recommendations. Requires the Board to review epidemiological studies annually and to advise the Secretary of Energy as to the scope and direction of future studies. Directs the Secretary of Energy to: (1) insure that all such studies shall be subject to peer review; and (2) promulgate guidelines regarding data dissemination of such studies to researchers who are not associated with the Department of Energy. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide the Board with necessary funds, facilities, and staff.</summary>
</bill>
