<bill session="100" type="h" number="3128" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hospital Indigent Care Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to impose an excise tax on an employer's cost of providing medical benefits to his employees and to amend the Social Security Act to provide support for hospitals in meeting indigent care costs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Self-employed"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1987--Introduced.
Hospital Indigent Care Assistance Act of 1987 - Title I: Amendments of Internal Revenue Code of 1986 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose on employers an excise tax equal to one percent of the amounts paid by an employer to provide employee medical benefits. Subjects self-employed individuals to a corresponding tax based on the amount allowed as a tax deduction for health insurance costs. Establishes in the Treasury the Hospital Indigent Care Assistance Trust Fund (Fund) to receive amounts generated by such excise tax. Makes Fund moneys available solely for Medicare program expenditures. Title II: Assistance to Hospitals Providing Indigent Care - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to make payments from the Fund to eligible applicant hospitals to cover a specified percentage of their uncompensated care costs, determined in accordance with this Act. Sets forth eligibility criteria, including a requirement that the Medicare allowable costs of providing patient care services exceed the hospital's patient revenues for the pertinent cost reporting period. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide for a study of the extent of uncompensated health care provided by various health care providers; and (2) report the results to the Congress by July 1, 1990.</summary>
</bill>
