<bill session="100" type="h" number="3127" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Steel Import Stabilization Extension Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide authority for the negotiation of bilateral arrangements regarding imported steel products in order to implement effectively the national policy for the United States steel industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409654"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401417" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406995" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407215" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="409251" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411948" joined="1987-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Customs unions"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1987--Introduced.
Steel Import Stabilization Extension Act of 1987 - Amends the Steel Import Stabilization Act to define "voluntary restraint agreement (VRA) country" to mean a foreign country or customs union that is a party to a bilateral arrangement with the United States concerning steel imports. Defines "non-VRA country" to mean a foreign country or customs union that is not a party to such an arrangement with the United States and whose exports of steel products to the United States: (1) have been increasing since 1984; or (2) are subsidized or dumped, or both. Requires the U.S. Trade Representative to decide which foreign countries and customs unions are "non-VRA countries." Directs the President to negotiate with VRA countries to extend, through September 30, 1992, existing bilateral steel arrangements with such countries in order to implement the national policy for the U.S. steel industry. Directs the President to negotiate and enter into similar arrangements with non-VRA countries. Sets forth time requirements with respect to negotiations with non-VRA countries. Authorizes the President, if such VRA countries and non-VRA countries refuse to negotiate in good faith, to impose, through September 30, 1992, such quantitative restrictions as may be necessary to ensure that annual imports of steel products from such countries do not exceed levels set forth in any applicable bilateral arrangement or levels consistent with U.S. national policy. Requires the President to report annually to the House Committee on Ways and Means and the Senate Committee on Finance on implementation of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
