<bill session="100" type="h" number="3140" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Defense to establish standards, based on recommendations of an advisory committee established by the Secretary, for inventory accounting systems used by Department of Defense contractors, and to require defense contractors to certify compliance with such standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403178"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403190" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405855" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400590" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406682" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407196" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408180" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409060" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409325" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1987-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Readiness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-10-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAS03" subcommittee="Readiness" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Inventories"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Defense, within 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to establish standards for inventory accounting systems used by contractors of the Department of Defense (DOD), giving due considerations to the advisory committee established under this Act. Directs the Secretary, within 30 days after the enactment of this Act, to establish an advisory committee to make recommendations on the standards required to be established by the Secretary earlier under this Act. Requires the advisory committee to develop recommendations on minimum standards for the acceptability of inventory accounting systems, addressing specified inventory and accounting questions. Directs the Secretary, within 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to submit to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees a report describing the recommendations of the advisory committee and the actions taken by the Secretary on the recommendations. Directs the Secretary to require defense contractors to certify, within 180 days after the establishment of the above-described standards, that their inventory accounting systems are in compliance with applicable laws and regulations, with the standard adopted under this Act, and with the contractor's disclosed accounting practices.</summary>
</bill>
