<bill session="100" type="h" number="3154" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program of Federal grants to assist local educational agencies to establish and provide for a school year of not less than 240 days and to establish Federal grants to recognize achievement in education by local educational agencies.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406765"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405747" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED01" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Academic performance"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Education to establish a program of grants to assist local educational agencies (LEAs) to establish and provide for a school year of not less than 240 days. Directs the Secretary, in considering LEA applications, to ensure an equitable distribution of such assistance among LEAs in urban, rural, and suburban areas. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to establish a program of grants to LEAs whose students perform above the national average on national educational competency and achievement examinations. Directs the Secretary, in considering LEA applications, to ensure an equitable distribution of such assistance among LEAs in urban, rural, and suburban areas. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
