<bill session="100" type="h" number="3172" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Relying on Ethanol for America Program Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the increased use of motor fuel blended with ethanol in order to enhance the energy security of the United States and to expand markets for agricultural commodities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400236" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300083" joined="1987-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forest, Family Farms, and Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-04">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-21">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Treasury.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG06" subcommittee="Forests, Family Farms, and Energy" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural research"/>
    <term name="Agricultural surpluses"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air quality"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alcohol tax"/>
    <term name="Alternative and renewable resources"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Fuel research"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/1987--Introduced.
Relying on Ethanol for America Program Act - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an Ethanol Development Fund to guarantee loans made to finance eligible ethanol-related projects. Declares that such Fund shall be administered by the Assistant Secretary of Agriculture for Science and Education (the Assistant Secretary). Requires the Commodity Credit Corporation to make specified amounts available to such Fund in each of the next five fiscal years to enable it to finance ethanol development projects. Sets forth the eligible activities and participants with respect to ethanol development projects, including such participants' allocated share of projects loan guarantees. Requires the Assistant Secretary to issue regulations requiring the private fuel industry to gather ethanol research and production data into a usable form for commercial ventures. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to consider projects funded by States under this Act as contributing toward clean air standards. Requires the Assistant Secretary to report annually to specified congressional committees regarding the financial and development status of the Development Fund program. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to select research and development projects eligible to receive Federal research funds for the production of marketable crops that may be specifically used in the production of ethanol or food for export. Prescribes guidelines for such projects. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend from 1993 to 2000 the excise tax rate reductions applicable to ethanol.</summary>
</bill>
