<bill session="100" type="h" number="318" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-08-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the restoration of Federal recognition to the Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and the Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402750"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1987-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-01">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-36.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-01">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-01">
      <text>Placed on Consent Calendar No: 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Called up by House on Call of Consent Calendar.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Passed Over by House Without Prejudice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-21">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-04-21" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-06-26">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 100-90.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-06-26" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="211">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 211.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-23">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1987-07-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-07-24">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1987-08-07">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1987-08-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-89" type="public" datetime="1987-08-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-89.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Gambling"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/23/1987--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Ysleta del Sur Pueblo and Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas Restoration Act - Title I: Ysleta del Sur Pueblo Restoration - Redesignates the Tiwa Indians of Ysleta, Texas, as the Ysleta del Sur Pueblo. Restores the Federal trust relationship with the tribe and associated rights and benefits. Provides that nothing in this Act shall affect the power of the State of Texas to enact special legislation to benefit the tribe. Authorizes Texas to perform services that benefit the tribe. Recognizes the authority of the Tribal Council. Declares the tribe's reservation to be a Federal Indian reservation. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to accept and hold in trust tribal lands conveyed by the tribe and Texas. Grants Texas civil and criminal jurisdiction within such reservation. Allows the tribe to acquire, lease, or sell additional land within El Paso and Hudspeth Counties and permits the Secretary, upon the tribe's request, to accept and hold title to such lands in trust for the tribe. Repeals the Tiwa Indians Act. Prohibits gambling, lottery, or bingo, as defined by Texas' laws, on the tribe's reservation and on tribal lands. Subjects any violation of this prohibition to the same civil and criminal penalties provided by the laws of Texas except such provision shall not be construed as a grant of civil or criminal jurisdiction to Texas. Provides that the Federal courts will have exclusive jurisdiction over violations of the Federal ban on gaming and that Texas may seek injunctive relief in the Federal courts to enforce such ban. Specifies the membership of the tribe and provides for removal of individuals from the tribal roll. Title II: Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas - States that the Alabama and Coushatta Indian Tribes of Texas shall be considered as one tribal unit for purposes of Federal law. Restores the Federal trust relationship with the tribe and associated rights and benefits. Authorizes Texas to perform services that benefit the tribe. Provides that nothing in this Act shall affect the power of the State of Texas to enact special legislation to benefit the tribe. Retains the existing tribal constitution and bylaws. Requires the Secretary, upon the request of the Tribal Council, to hold an election for the members of the tribe for the purpose of adopting a new constitution and bylaws. Recognizes the authority of the Tribal Council. Sets forth provisions similar to title I regarding civil and criminal jurisdiction, the tribal reservation, and gaming laws for the tribe.</summary>
</bill>
