<bill session="100" type="h" number="3194" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to grant Federal recognition to the Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians as a distinct Indian tribe, to clarify the status of members of the band, to provide trust lands to the band, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408957" joined="1987-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409651" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410926" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411119" joined="1987-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act - Extends Federal recognition to the Lake Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians (Band). Provides that all Federal laws applicable to Indians will also apply to the Band, unless they are inconsistent with this Act. Makes the Band and its members eligible for all Federal benefits furnished to federally-recognized Indian tribes. Makes the Indian Reorganization Act applicable to the Band. Requires the Band, within six months of the enactment of this Act, to submit to the Secretary of the Interior its membership roll listing all eligible individuals. Sets forth membership requirements. Requires the Secretary, after completing the roll, to immediately publish notice in the Federal Register. Directs the Band to ensure that the roll is maintained and is current. Requires the Secretary to transfer the land which is held in trust by the United States for the Keweenaw Bay Indian Community to the United States to be held in trust for the Band.</summary>
</bill>
