<bill session="100" type="h" number="3217" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Superconductivity, Competitiveness and National Security Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a national Federal program effort in close collaboration with the private sector to develop as rapidly as possible the applications of superconductivity to enhance the Nation's economic competitiveness and strategic well-being, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407399"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406790" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407967" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1987-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Research and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Science, Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy Research and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Aviation and Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-07">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From DOD.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS01" subcommittee="Research and Development" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSSY03" subcommittee="Science, Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY06" subcommittee="Energy Research and Development" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSSY07" subcommittee="Transportation, Aviation and Materials" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International cooperation in science"/>
    <term name="Military research"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Superconductivity"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
National Superconductivity, Competitiveness and National Security Act of 1987 - Directs the President, working through the National Critical Materials Council (NCMC), to establish a five-year National Federal Program on Superconductivity Research and Development (the Superconductivity Program). Directs the NCMC to draw upon the recommendations and advice of the National Commission on Superconductivity and collaborate with the Office of Science and Technology Policy and the Office of Management and Budget in developing the Superconductivity Program. Sets forth the content and scope of such Program. Requires the Superconductivity Program plan to be presented to specified congressional committees within six months after the enactment of this Act. Directs the Chairman of NCMC to appoint, within 60 days after enactment of this Act, a National Advisory Commission on Superconductivity (Advisory Commission) to review all major policy issues regarding U.S. applications of recent research advances in superconductors. Provides for coordination and staff support by NCMC. Requires the Advisory Commission to report, within six months after enactment of this Act, to the NCMC Chairman with recommendations regarding methods of enhancing the research, development, and implementation of improved superconductor technologies in all major applications. Sets forth required contents of such report. Terminates the Advisory Commission 60 days after submission of its report. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish, within 60 days after enactment of this Act, an Office of Superconductivity to coordinate and direct all activities of the Department of Energy in implementing the Superconductivity Program under the Department's responsibility. Provides that the Director of the Office shall be designated by and report directly to the Secretary. Makes the Director responsible for establishing, coordinating, and directing superconductivity research and development activities in the Department and directing and coordinating the Consortia for Enabling Superconductivity Technologies. Directs the Secretary of Energy, operating primarily through the Department's National Federal Research Laboratories (NFRLs), to establish within six months one or more Consortia for Enabling Superconductivity Technologies (Consortia). Requires that each Consortium be led by an appropriate NFRL designated by the Secretary. Requires the designated lead laboratory to have appropriate university and industrial connections and have demonstrable expertise in specified research. Requires each Consortium to consist, in addition to the designated lead laboratory, of appropriate industry, university, and/or other research institutions, including other NFRLs. Provides that each Consortium shall be considered a joint research and development venture. Requires the participant to share the costs of conducting such research and development. Authorizes temporary exchanges of personnel between Consortia members.. Allows up to 25 percent of funds under this Act for each Consortium to be used to conduct superconductivity research and development under the discretion of the Director of the designated lead laboratory. Requires the Department of Energy's superconductivity research and development activities to focus on fundamental research, materials processing, and applications of new superconducting materials. Directs the Secretary of Energy to create a program of Industrial Fellowship to support the education and training of graduate engineers and scientists in the area of superconductivity and related academic fields. Provides that recipients shall be selected from qualified applicants seeking degrees from member institutions of the Consortia. Directs the Department of Energy, working primarily through the NCMC, to coordinate its programs with those of the Department of Commerce, the Department of Defense, the National Science Foundation, and other appropriate departments and agencies. Requires the Secretary of Defense to establish, within 60 days after the enactment of this Act, an Office of Superconductivity to coordinate and direct all Department of Defense research activities in implementing the Superconductivity Program under the Department's responsibility. Makes the Director of such Office responsible for establishing, coordinating, and directing superconductivity research and development on activities of the Department. Requires such activities to focus on fundamental research, materials processing, and applications of new superconducting materials. Requires the Department, working primarily through the NCMC, to coordinate its programs with those of the Department of Commerce, the Department of Energy, the National Science Foundation, and other appropriate departments and agencies. Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation (NSF) to establish within 60 days an Office of Superconductivity to coordinate and direct all NSF activities in implementing the Superconductivity Program under NSF responsibility. Makes the Administrator of such Office responsible for establishing NSF superconductivity research and development programs and for directing and coordinating the National Superconductivity Research Centers. Requires the NSF Director to establish a program of National Superconductivity Research Centers. Requires that an appropriate number of universities be selected as sites for such Centers based largely on their scientific and technical qualifications. Requires the Centers to focus efforts in the development and support, in an interdisciplinary manner, of manufacturing science and processing as it applies to superconducting materials. Declares that the Centers' programs shall supplement the other NSF activities in the conduct of superconductivity research and development programs. Requires the NSF to continue to operate primarily through individual and block-fund grants with the university community and to be responsible for maintaining an appropriate balance of such grants for support of basic and fundamental research on superconducting materials. Directs the NSF, working primarily through the NCMC, to coordinate its programs with those of the Departments of Energy and Commerce, and other appropriate departments and agencies, taking appropriate steps to ensure the existence of a comprehensive program of fundamental superconductivity research. Requires the NSF Director to establish a program of graduate fellowships to support the education and training of advanced degreed research engineers and scientists in the areas of superconductivity, manufacturing science and processing, and related academic fields. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish, within 60 days after the enactment of this Act, an Office of Superconductivity to coordinate and direct all activities of the Department of Commerce in implementing the Department's responsibility under the Superconductivity Program. Makes the Administrator of such Office responsible for establishing (with the Director of the National Bureau of Standards), coordinating, and directing superconductivity research and development activities in the Department. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to ensure the accelerated transfer of superconductivity technology resulting from research and development provided for in this Act and for the application of such technology by the U.S. private and public sectors. Directs the National Bureau of Standards, in coordination with the Department of Energy, the NSF, and other appropriate departments and agencies, to establish and conduct a program of fundamental research and materials standards to accelerate the use and application of the new superconducting materials. Directs the Department of Commerce, working primarily through the NCMC, to coordinate its programs with those of the Department of Energy, the NSF, and other appropriate departments and agencies. Directs the President to establish a program of international cooperation in the conduct of basic research on superconducting materials, including the exchange of basic information and data and the development of international standards for the use and application of superconducting materials. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993 to carry out specified provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
