<bill session="100" type="h" number="3267" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Defense Acquisition Corps Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to establish a Defense Acquisition Corps for purposes of improving the efficiency of the defense acquisition process, and to require the Secretary of Defense to establish by regulation a Defense Acquisition University.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405409"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/15/1987--Introduced.
Defense Acquisition Corps Act of 1987 - Establishes in the Department of Defense (DOD) a Defense Acquisition Corps (DAC) consisting of acquisition-related positions in the Office of the Secretary of Defense, the military departments, and certain defense agencies. Requires the Secretary to make appointments to the DAC from the best-qualified civilian applicants and military personnel. Directs the Secretary to establish by regulations a personnel system for civilian personnel within the DAC. Outlines information to be included in such regulations. Allows the Secretary to exempt civilian personnel of the DAC from any otherwise applicable competitive service requirements. Directs the Secretary to establish by regulation a merit pay system for such members of the DAC as the Secretary deems appropriate. Provides for the assignment of members of the DAC. Requires the Secretary, not later than one year after the enactment of this Act, to: (1) establish the DAC; (2) review existing acquisition-related positions in the military departments to determine which positions should be included in the DAC; and (3) make appointments to such positions. Directs the Secretary to establish by regulation a Defense Acquisition University that includes existing acquisition-related defense schools.</summary>
</bill>
