<bill session="100" type="h" number="3285" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Energy Reorganization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to reorganize the functions of the Nuclear Regulatory Commission by abolishing the Commission and in its place establishing the Nuclear Energy Regulatory Agency, an inspector general thereof, and a Nuclear Safety Board in order to promote safer and more effective and efficient nuclear regulation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1987--Introduced.
Nuclear Energy Reorganization Act of 1987 - Title I: Nuclear Energy Regulatory Agency - Establishes as an independent regulatory agency the Nuclear Energy Regulatory Agency which shall succeed the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Sets forth the Agency's officers and administration, including an Administrator to be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate. Abolishes the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Title II: Office of Inspector General - Establishes in the Nuclear Energy Regulatory Agency (NERA) an Office of Inspector General, headed by an Inspector General who shall report to the NERA Administrator only. Precludes the Administrator from preventing the Inspector General from implementing any audit or investigation. Cites circumstances under which the President may remove the Inspector General. Outlines the Inspector General's oversight responsibilities, including fraud and abuse within NERA programs and operations. Requires the Inspector General to submit semiannual summaries of Office activities to the NERA Administrator and the Nuclear Safety Board (established by this Act). Requires the Administrator to forward such reports to specified congressional committees (and to make them public upon request). Authorizes the Inspector General to receive and investigate information received from any NERA employee regarding: (1) violations of law; (2) mismanagement; (3) gross waste; or (4) safety hazards. Prohibits reprisals in the form of adverse actions against employees who provide such information. Transfers to the Office of the Inspector General from the Nuclear Regulatory Commission the Office of Inspector and Auditor, and other Commission offices within the Administrator's discretion (with the exception of program operating responsibilities). Title III: Nuclear Safety Board - Establishes the Nuclear Safety Board as an independent Federal agency to assess and report upon: (1) the safety status of nuclear facilities and activities; (2) Federal nuclear safety regulations; and (3) nuclear facility events which could have potential adverse public health or safety effects. Provides for public access to Board information, with specified exceptions. States that whenever the Board submits a nuclear safety recommendation to the Administrator or the Secretary of Energy, such official shall submit a written response within 90 days of receipt. Sets forth civil penalties for violations of Board-established reporting requirements relating to: (1) operation or construction of licensed nuclear facilities; or (2) the processing (including transportation and storage) of licensed nuclear materials. Provides for judicial review of Board orders. Requires the board to submit annual reports to the President and the Congress regarding its activities and recommendations. Transfers to the Board such offices within the Nuclear Regulatory Commission as are determined by the Administrator to further the purposes of this Act, including the Office for Analysis and Evaluation of Operational Data, and the functions of the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards. Excludes program operating responsibilities from such transferred functions. Abolishes the Advisory Committee on Reactor Safeguards. Title IV: Conforming Amendments and Effective Date - Sets forth conforming amendments and the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
