<bill session="100" type="h" number="3331" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Indian Art and Culture Institute Transition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide certain interim measures relating to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Art Development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409205"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1708"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1708"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaskan natives"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts"/>
    <term name="Colleges"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Handicraft"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/1987--Introduced.
Indian Art and Culture Institute Transition Act - Amends the Higher Education Amendments of 1986 to require the Secretary of the Interior to provide technical and support assistance to the Institute of American Indian and Alaska Native Culture and Arts Development (Institute) until October 1, 1989 (currently October 1, 1988), unless the Institute's Board of Trustees provides otherwise. Requires that the transfers of functions of the Institute of American Indian Arts to the Institute be completed by June 1, 1988. Continues the Secretary's control of the Institute until the earlier of: (1) June 1, 1988; or (2) a date agreed to by the Board and the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to enter into a contract with the University of New Mexico which shall: (1) include all administrative systems which are customary for a national art institute; (2) require the University to provide technical assistance to the Institute and establish an advisory council that makes recommendations on the operation of the contract; (3) allow the University to fulfill its obligations through subcontracts; (4) provide for the expiration of the contract within six months, but allow an extension; and (5) provide for any materials the University furnishes to become the Institute's property. Requires the advisory council to consist of: (1) a delegate of the executive director of the National Congress of American Indians; (2) a delegate of the president of the American Indian Higher Education Consortium; and (3) at least five individuals knowledgeable about Indian arts and culture, a majority of whom shall be Indians.</summary>
</bill>
