<bill session="100" type="h" number="3340" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Shortage Relief Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish programs with respect to providing for an increase in the number of professional nurses.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400987" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402435" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1988-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404170" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1988-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1988-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1988-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1988-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1987-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="406729" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407069" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407351" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407399" joined="1988-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1987-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1988-05-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400524" joined="1987-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409052" joined="1988-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1987-10-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409423" joined="1987-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1988-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="409500" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1988-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410231" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410623" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410765" joined="1987-11-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-02-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1987-10-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Home nursing"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Rural manpower policy"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1987--Introduced.
Nursing Shortage Relief Act of 1987 - Amends title VIII (Nurse Training) of the Public Health Service Act to add a new part on initiatives to reduce nursing shortages. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to establish a special advisory committee to develop a comprehensive plan regarding long-term solutions to problems in recruiting and retaining nurses. Requires nurses to be included on the committee. Directs the Secretary to determine whether a nonprofit private entity with a record in supporting innovative health initiatives has completed or is completing a project to demonstrate and evaluate innovative hospital nursing practice models. Requires models to include initiatives to: (1) restructure the role of the hospital nurse, through changes in the composition of hospital staff and through innovative approaches for interaction between hospital administration and nursing personnel; (2) test innovative wage structures for nurses; and (3) evaluate the effectiveness of providing benefits such as pensions, sabbaticals, and payment of educational expenses for nurses. Directs the Secretary, if the Secretary so determines, to make a grant to the nonprofit private entity for dissemination of information describing the results of such project. Directs the Secretary, if no such project has been or is being completed, to make grants for carrying out such projects and disseminating the results. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Secretary to make grants to or enter into contracts with public and nonprofit private entities accredited for the training of nurses for projects to: (1) demonstrate and evaluate innovative nursing practice models regarding long-term health care services in the home or in long-term care facilities; and (2) develop collaborative clinical practice setting alternatives for nursing students. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Secretary to make grants to and enter into contracts with public and nonprofit private entities to develop, establish, and operate at least one and not more than five regional model professional nurse recruitment centers to recruit individuals to enter into programs to train nurses. Directs the Secretary, in making grants, to ensure inclusion of not less than one center in a rural area. Sets forth requirements for centers. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Secretary to make grants to develop and establish local educational outreach and nurse recruitment programs. Directs the Secretary, in making grants, to give priority to applicants carrying out associated degree programs in nursing education that train not more than 20 nursing students per year and have arrangements with baccalaureate degree nursing programs. Requires grant funds to be used for identifying a local area's long-term nursing needs, designing local recruitment programs, and providing for the modification and expansion of existing nursing programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
