<bill session="100" type="h" number="3341" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fisheries Research Funding Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen fisheries research through the imposition of fees on the harvesting and processing of fish within the exclusive economic zone and through the licensing of recreational fishing within such zone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409534" joined="1987-11-19" withdrawn="1988-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sports and Athletics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1987--Introduced.
Fisheries Research Funding Act of 1987 - Prohibits harvesting or processing of fish in the exclusive economic zone (EEZ) unless the fisheries research fee imposed by provisions of this Act has been paid. Imposes the fee on the owner or operator of any harvesting or processing vessel. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to deposit all fees collected in the Fisheries Research Fund. Prohibits anyone who has reached the age of 16 from engaging in recreational fishing within the EEZ unless the individual has in his or her possession a recreational fishing license issued to that individual. Directs the Secretary to issue licenses for recreational fishing during each fiscal year, collect a fee for each license, and deposit all fees collected into the Fisheries Research Fund. Establishes in the Treasury the Fisheries Research Fund. Directs the Secretary, to the extent provided for in advance in appropriation Acts, to distribute the aggregate amount of money in the Fund, for the carrying out of fisheries research, in specified percentages, to the regional fishery management councils established under the Magnuson Act, the Pacific Marine Fisheries Commission, the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission, the Gulf States Marine Fisheries Commission, and the National Marine Fisheries Service, prorating the amounts received by the fishery management councils on the basis of the amount of the fisheries research fees collected from vessels engaged in the respective regions under the jurisdiction of the councils. Provides penalties for violations, including civil fines and suspension of harvesting or processing privileges. Authorizes the Secretary to collect necessary data to carry out this Act and to enter into contracts or agreements with other agencies, States, or entities to collect data. Provides for confidentiality of the data. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
