<bill session="100" type="h" number="3359" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Opportunities for Employment Preparation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide, through greater targeting, coordination, and structuring of services, assistance to strengthen severely economically disadvantaged individuals and families by providing greater opportunities for employment preparation which can assist in promoting family economic stability.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404019" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407399" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Employment Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED06" subcommittee="Employment Opportunities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1987--Introduced.
Opportunities for Employment Preparation Act of 1987 - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act (the Act) to establish a program of targeted assistance for severely economically disadvantaged individuals. Defines "severely economically disadvantaged" as individuals who have received benefits under Aid to Families with Dependent Children (AFDC) provisions of the Social Security Act for two years or more, who have been unemployed or without steady employment for two years or more, and who are not eligible under title III (Employment and Training Assistance for Dislocated Workers) of the Act. Requires the job training program in each service delivery area to establish a feeder system using community-based organizations to conduct outreach and provide preemployment services to severely economically disadvantaged individuals. Requires such outreach and feeder system to include: (1) skills assessment; (2) registration with the Bureau of Employment Security; (3) preemployment training, including an eight-week internship; (4) employment training, including vocational, adult, and community college and other postsecondary programs; and (5) on-the-job and other employment preparation activities available under the Act. Requires preemployment services to include: (1) educational preparation and basic skills development to increase literacy and computational skills; (2) programs to strengthen attitude and motivation for work; (3) guidance and counseling to assist with occupational choice and selection of employment preparation programs; (4) counseling, referral and follow-up for those experiencing personal or family problems; and (5) parenting and home and family living skills, including nutrition and health education, targeted to teenage parents. Requires supportive services, including child care and transportation assistance, to be given to program participants. Provides that program participants will not lose any other Federal benefits because of program participation. Requires State plans to include descriptions of coordination of other programs with such targeted assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
