<bill session="100" type="h" number="3351" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Aid Impact Assessment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require periodic assessments of the impact and effectiveness of United States economic assistance to foreign countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400192"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400906" joined="1987-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400023" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1987-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="401628" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300029" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403184" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1988-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406799" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407457" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410574" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1987-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1987-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1987--Introduced.
Foreign Aid Impact Assessment Act - Requires the President to submit to the Congress, by December 31, 1988, and December 31 of each third year thereafter, a report analyzing the impact and effectiveness of U.S. economic assistance provided during the preceding three fiscal years. Directs that such report include for each recipient country: (1) an analysis of the impact of such assistance on the country's economic development, including a description of the specific objectives sought and the extent to which they were not achieved and why; (2) a description of the amount and nature of the assistance provided by other donors during that period; (3) a discussion of the commitment of the host government to addressing the country's needs in each development sector; (4) a description of the trends in each sector; (5) statistical and other information necessary to the evaluation; and (6) a comparison of the analysis provided in the report with relevant analyses by international or nongovernmental organizations or donor countries. Requires that each report: (1) be submitted to the Congress as a separate document; and (2) identify those countries in which economic assistance has been most and least successful, explain why the assistance was not more successful, and specify what the United States has done as a result.</summary>
</bill>
