<bill session="100" type="h" number="3394" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the City of Los Angeles, California, to make improvements to the Hyperion Wastewater Treatment Plant in accordance with a construction schedule.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406765"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from EPA, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1987--Introduced.
Requires the city of Los Angeles, California, to make improvements to the Hyperion Wastewater Treatment Plant in accordance with the Hyperion Full Secondary Project Schedule. Provides for reducing the number of permits the city may issue for the use of sewage treatment facilities if the city has not completed the Plant by June 30, 1989. Establishes enforcement procedures for the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency and authorizes citizen suits for violations of this Act. Provides for the Administrator to adopt an amended accelerated schedule to implement such Act when practicable. Requires the city to report quarterly to the Administrator on progress in making improvements to the Plant. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress on whether requirements under this Act are being fulfilled.</summary>
</bill>
