<bill session="100" type="h" number="3401" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Domestic Industry Safeguard Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to impose certain restrictions on the conduct of hostile takeovers by foreign-based persons, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404869"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign corporations"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Investors"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Tender offers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1987--Introduced.
Domestic Industry Safeguard Act - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to establish additional reporting requirements for foreign investors. Requires such investors to file statements: (1) specifying whether they intend to sell or close any facility, or terminate or alter any operation, during the two-year period following completion of the acquisition; (2) estimating the number of jobs that are likely to be lost during that two-year period; (3) specifying their aggregate amount of liabilities and equity (before and after such acquisition); and (4) describing the manner in which such assets will be treated and used. Subjects any person who makes false or misleading statements to civil liability. Prohibits such foreign investors from selling, leasing, or disposing of (with certain exceptions) any assets of an issuer during the two years following acquisition. Sets forth additional restrictions with respect to tender offers for securities made or consummated by or for a foreign investor. Directs the Securities and Exchange Commission to conduct a study to: (1) determine the amount of foreign investment in the United States; (2) gather information on corporate takeovers of U.S. companies by foreign investors; and (3) analyze the need for additional Federal regulations to protect local jobs and regional economies from adverse consequences of such foreign investment and takeovers. Directs the Commission to submit the results of such study to the Congress. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct a study of the loss of revenues occurring as a result of the deductibility of debt services expenses incurred by a foreign acquirer in the course of conducting a hostile takeover of a U.S. company. Directs the Secretary to submit the results of such study to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
