<bill session="100" type="h" number="3419" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIDS Prevention Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish certain grant programs with respect to the prevention and control of acquired immune deficiency syndrome and related conditions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406255"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401628" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402675" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403184" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="405448" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400617" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407162" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410574" joined="1987-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1987--Introduced.
AIDS Prevention Act of 1987 - Title I: Education with Respect to Prevention and Control of Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to State and local educational agencies, institutions of higher education, and other public and nonprofit private entities for demonstration projects for the development and implementation of programs for educating students in secondary schools and institutions of higher education with respect to the prevention of exposure to, and the transmission of, the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Authorizes the use of grant funds for the development and dissemination of educational materials, the training of teachers and counselors, the instruction of students, outreach activities, technical assistance, and activities with respect to the evaluation of such programs. Prohibits making grants unless the applicant agrees that: (1) the educational materials will provide scientific information regarding the etiologic agent, discourage high risk behaviors, promote sexual abstinence before marriage and fidelity within marriage, and be appropriate for the age of the students for whom the program is developed; and (2) the applicant will provide notice to the community involved that the program is to be developed and will solicit and consider comments from interested persons. Directs the Secretary of Education, in making the grants, to give preference to geographic areas where there is a particular risk regarding AIDS. Prohibits making the grants unless the applicant submits a description of the intended uses of the grant and agrees to expend the grant so as to supplement and not to supplant State, local, and other non-Federal funds. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Title II: Testing for Infection with Etiologic Agent for Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary), in each fiscal year, to make an allotment for each State. Prohibits making payments of the allotments unless the State agrees to use the payments to carry out a program of: (1) mandatory, routine, and voluntary testing, under confidential conditions, for the etiologic agent; and (2) confidential contact tracing and confidential counseling regarding infection with the etiologic agent. Prohibits making payments to a State unless the State provides, directly or through donations from public or private entities, in cash or in kind, non-Federal contributions as matching funds for 25 percent of the testing program costs in FY 1988, 50 percent in FY 1989, and 75 percent in FY 1990. Prohibits making payments unless the State agrees to provide mandatory or routine testing of any individual who: (1) is to donate blood, semen, or an organ; (2) receives health care relating to substance abuse or to a sexually transmitted disease; (3) is imprisoned in any State penal or correctional institution; (4) is between 15 and 50 years of age and is admitted to a hospital for health care; (5) receives health care or counseling from a family-planning clinic; or (6) applies for a marriage license. Authorizes States to expend payments for voluntary testing. Allows the use of either procedures requiring or procedures not requiring the identity of the individual to be provided to the testing entity. Prohibits making payments to a State unless the State agrees, in carrying out the mandatory or routine testing, to require that the name and address of any individual infected with the etiologic agent be reported to the State public health officer and to require that the officer carry out a program of contact tracing. Prohibits making payments to a State unless the State agrees, in carrying out mandatory, routine, or voluntary testing, that the State will require that individuals undergoing the testing receive appropriate counseling on the medical importance of of measures for the prevention of exposure to, and the transmission of, the etiologic agent. Prohibits making payments to a State unless the State agrees to require confidentiality in testing, contact tracing, and counseling, disclosing information only in specified circumstances and providing penalties for violation of confidentiality. Prohibits making payments to a State unless the State agrees to use 90 percent of the payments for mandatory or routine testing, reporting and contact tracing, and counseling as provided in this title. Directs the Secretary to establish criteria relating to the administration, analysis, and quality control of the tests, and the technical qualifications of individuals who administer and analyze the tests and of individuals who provide the counseling. Prohibits making payments to a State unless the State agrees to carry out the program of testing, tracing, and counseling in accordance with the criteria. Prohibits making payments unless the applicant submits a description of the intended uses of the payment, including coordination with similar programs and activities of public and private entities. Prohibits making payments unless the State agrees to prepare and submit to the Secretary an annual report and to make the report available for public inspection. Directs the Comptroller General, from time to time, to evaluate State expenditures. Provides for determination of the amount of allotments, including consideration of: (1) the extent to which a State is at risk with respect to infections with the etiologic agent; and (2) the actual costs incurred by the State in carrying out the testing, tracing, and counseling. Authorizes the Secretary to require a State to repay amounts not expended in accordance with the agreements required by provisions of this title and, if such repayment is not made, to offset such amounts against any payment due to be paid. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to the State, or any public or nonprofit private entity designated by the State, directly or through contract or grants, without charge to the State. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress on the activities of States under provisions of this title. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Title III: Research with Respect to Cost-Effective Methods of Payment of Treatment Cost for Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for research into the development of cost-effective methods of providing assistance to individuals in paying the medical cost of treatment for AIDS. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
