<bill session="100" type="h" number="3413" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of General Services to convey certain property to the Museum of the American Indian.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411426"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403476" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404139" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404765" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="405646" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400188" joined="1987-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1987-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406746" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407141" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407196" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407457" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407471" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408244" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300087" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410455" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1987-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Government Activities and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-28">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-09">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from GSA, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Grounds.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO03" subcommittee="Government Activities and Transportation" name="House Government Operations"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW04" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Grounds" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of General Services to convey to the Museum of the American Indian the Old United States Custom House in New York, New York. Subjects the conveyance to the following conditions: (1) the property shall be used by the Museum solely as a museum to preserve the customs and history of North, South, and Central American Indians; (2) the Museum shall maintain the historic architectural character of the property; (3) the Museum shall give the Advisory Council on Historic Preservation a reasonable opportunity to comment on proposed renovations or alterations; and (4) the Museum shall obtain the approval of the Administrator before commencing any renovation or alteration. Provides that all right, title, and interest in the property shall revert to the United States if: (1) the Museum at 3753 Broadway in New York City does not operate as a branch of the Museum to be established at the property; (2) the Museum does not continuously use such property solely as a North, South, and Central American Indian museum and maintain its historic architectural character; (3) the Museum does not maintain such property in a manner that ensures that adequate services are provided to the U.S. courts on the fifth and sixth floors; or (4) the Museum interferes with the occupancy of such property by the courts. Prohibits the Museum from using such property as security for any obligation. Reserves to the United States: (1) air and development rights associated with such property; and (2) the right to occupy the fifth and sixth floors of the property for use by U.S. courts until the Administrator provides suitable permanent accommodations for such courts at the Foley Square Courthouse Annex. Requires the Museum to submit a plan detailing any proposed renovation or alteration of the property to the Administrator, who shall approve such action unless it would not preserve the property's historic architectural character.</summary>
</bill>
