<bill session="100" type="h" number="3418" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish certain grant programs, requirements, and prohibitions for the purpose of protecting emergency response employees from infectious diseases, including acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403726"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400898" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400987" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401446" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401986" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402159" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402600" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403529" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404019" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404170" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404213" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405409" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405448" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1987-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406148" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="408520" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400318" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409052" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409966" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410567" joined="1987-10-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1987-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1987-11-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1987-12-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="1987-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Curricula"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in public facilities"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control, to develop a curriculum for educating emergency response employees (EREs) with respect to the prevention of exposure to infectious diseases during the process of responding to emergencies. Directs the Secretary to establish a task force to assist in developing the curriculum, appointing to the task force representatives of the Centers for Disease Control, State governments, and EREs. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to make grants to States to assist in purchasing educational materials and protective equipment recommended in the curriculum, with at least 75 percent of the grant spent for educational materials. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to make grants to States to assist in conducting demonstration projects for programs of screening EREs for infectious diseases and immunizing them against vaccine-preventable infectious diseases. Prohibits the grants unless the applicant agrees that screenings and immunizations will be conducted only with the consent of the emergency response employee (ERE) involved. Exempts, from the screening and immunization provisions, infection with the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome (etiologic agent). Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to make grants to States to assist in the initial implementation of programs of testing notified EREs for infection with the etiologic agent. Prohibits grants unless the applicant agrees that the testing will be conducted only with the consent of the ERE. Requires the amount of the grant to be determined on the basis of the population of the geographic area relative to the U.S. population. Prohibits grants unless the applicant agrees to provide counseling before and, for both those testing negative and those testing positive, after testing. States that such agreements do not prohibit providing the counseling services to an ERE who will not undergo testing. Authorizes appropriations. Requires a medical facility to notify the employer of EREs if the facility determines that a victim the EREs transported to the facility has an infectious disease. Requires a medical facility, upon request of an employer of EREs, to notify the employer if the facility makes a determination that a victim transported by EREs has an infectious disease. Makes notification requirements apply to both the facility receiving the victim and, if the victim dies, to the facility ascertaining the cause of death. Requires such disclosure on request by any ERE employer. Sets forth notification procedures. Directs the public health officer of each State to designate one official of each employer of EREs to make requests and receive notifications. Prohibits other individuals from receiving notifications. Provides for notification of EREs and for requests from an ERE to an employer that the employer request notification from the medical facility. Prohibits: (1) persons providing testing or counseling services from disclosing the identity of any notified ERE; and (2) persons receiving a disclosure of protected information from disclosing the information. Provides for exceptions to the prohibitions. Prohibits a person from discriminating against an otherwise qualified notified ERE in employment, housing, public accommodations, governmental services, or the provision of benefits under any program receiving Federal financial assistance, solely because the ERE is, or is regarded as being, infected with the etiologic agent. Prohibits a person who obtains, as a result of notification provisions of this Act, information relating to the identity of a victim of an emergency who is infected with the etiologic agent, from disclosing such information. Provides, for violations of certain provisions of this Act, for civil monetary penalties, injunctive relief, civil causes of action, and criminal penalties.</summary>
</bill>
