<bill session="100" type="h" number="3438" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Private Long-term Care Insurance Promotion Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide that long-term health care insurance contracts shall be treated for purposes of determining the income taxation of insurance companies in the same manner as noncancellable accident or health insurance contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300100"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403529" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406284" joined="1987-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1987--Introduced.
Private Long-Term Care Insurance Promotion Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require that, for the purpose of determining the income tax liability of insurance companies, guaranteed renewable insurance contracts providing for qualified long-term health care be treated in the same way as noncancellable accident or health insurance contracts. Applies this requirement to contracts covering diagnostic, preventive, therapeutic, rehabilitative, and personal care services that are: (1) required by a chronically ill or disabled individual; and (2) provided by a qualified licensed provider (other than a family member) in a nursing facility, including hospitals and nursing homes, or in a home (if home care is a substitute for care in a nursing facility).</summary>
</bill>
