<bill session="100" type="h" number="3441" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 with respect to the taxation of life insurance contracts and annuity contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404705" joined="1987-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Life insurance"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax shelters"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code with respect to income tax treatment of life insurance contracts and annuity contracts. Provides that loans under certain life insurance contracts (including single premium life insurance contracts), amounts pledged or assigned under such contracts, and the transfers of such contracts made without adequate consideration shall be included in gross taxable income to the extent allocable to income on the contract (thus conforming the tax treatment of loans under life insurance contracts to the law currently applied to annuity contracts). Applies these loan and transfer rules to corporations as well as to individuals and amends the corresponding law currently applied to annuity contracts to include corporations. Reverses the ordering rules for distributions under life insurance and endowment contracts so that distributions would be treated first as income and then as basis. Imposes a ten percent penalty tax on the amount of any taxable distribution or loan under a life insurance contract. Exempts from this penalty any distribution: (1) made on or after the date on which the taxpayer attains age 59 1/2; (2) attributable to the taxpayer's becoming disabled; (3) that is part of an annuity-like plan under which periodic payments are made over the taxpayer's life; or (4) allocable to investment in the contract on or before October 7, 1987.</summary>
</bill>
