<bill session="100" type="h" number="3451" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Access Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to require certain procedures to be followed by fiscal intermediaries in denying certain claims for home health services, to provide for notification of beneficiary rights with respect to home health services, post-hospital extended care services, and extended care services furnished under such title, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408621"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402833" joined="1987-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1987-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1762"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1762"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1987--Introduced.
Medicare Access Protection Act of 1987 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require that agreements with fiscal intermediaries mandate that: (1) notice be made and a reconsideration procedure be made available to the provider and the individual with respect to whom a claim for home health services is made in the event of denial of the claim on the ground that the service is not medically necessary; and (2) the intermediary consult, at least biannually, with service providers, beneficiaries, and the Health Care Financing Administration with respect to problems with any of the activities of the intermediary. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to develop and distribute to each provider a standard form concerning rights of coverage and appeal and practical steps required for initiating appeals. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the standard document is made available to any individual covered: (1) at the time the individual begins to receive home health, post-hospital extended care, or extended care services; and (2) whenever a fiscal intermediary makes an appealable determination regarding such services.</summary>
</bill>
