<bill session="100" type="h" number="3481" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Development Reorganization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that the Department of Agriculture shall be known as the Department of Agriculture and Rural Development, to transfer the administration of certain conservation programs from the Farmers Home Administration to the Soil Conservation Service, to establish the Rural Development Administration within the Department of Agriculture and Rural Development, to transfer the administration of certain rural housing programs from the Farmers Home Administration to the Rural Development Administration, to provide that the Farmers Home Administration shall be known as the Farm Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401417" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403904" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400146" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405209" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="405313" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="409353" joined="1988-06-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400377" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410765" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1988-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-13">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Conservation Credit and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG01" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, and Rural Development" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG04" subcommittee="Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="National growth policy"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Water use"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1987--Introduced.
Rural Development Reorganization Act of 1987 - Title I: Reorganization Within Department of Agriculture - Amends Federal law to rename the Department of Agriculture the Department of Agriculture and Rural Development. Retitles the Secretary of Agriculture the Secretary of Agriculture and Rural Development. Establishes the Rural Development Administration within such Department. Renames the Farmers Home Administration the Farm Administration. Makes conforming administrative changes. Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to permit the Secretary to provide employment-related technical assistance in economically distressed rural areas. Directs the Secretary to carry out the provisions of the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act, except for specified loan provisions, through the Rural Development Administration. States that titles V and VI of the Rural Development Act of 1972 shall be carried out through the Rural Development Administration. Amends the Agriculture and Food Act of 1981 to expand the number of designated assistance areas from 225 to 450. Transfers certain conservation loan programs from the Farmers Home Administration to the Soil Conservation Service. Makes conforming amendments to specified agricultural and rural affairs Acts. Title II: Administration of Federal Rural Housing and Community Development Programs - Transfers to the Rural Development Administration current Farmers Home Administration (FmHA) loan programs for: (1) business and industry; (2) community facilities; (3) water and waste disposal (including grant authority); and (4) rural development and planning, excluding farm production. Transfers to the new Farm Administration current FmHA single-family housing loan programs. Makes conforming amendments to the Housing Act of 1949. Provides for farm ownership assistance to be carried out through such Administration. Makes conforming amendments to the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act and the Federal Financing Bank Act of 1973. Title III: Administrative Provisions - Sets forth administrative provisions.</summary>
</bill>
