<bill session="100" type="h" number="3542" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill amending title 49, United States Code, to improve procedures for rail line abandonments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400281"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Railroad abandonments"/>
    <term name="Railroad facilities"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/1987--Introduced.
Amends Federal filing and applications procedures regarding rail line abandonments to require a rail carrier to mail a copy of the abandonment or discontinuance notice to appropriate local government officials. Extends from 45 days to 60 days the time in which the Interstate Commerce Commission must determine whether an investigation is needed to determine what disposition to make of a rail line abandonment or discontinuance application if the Commission has received a protest regarding such application. Requires the Commission to hold hearings in communities affected by a proposed railroad line abandonment if requested to do so by community protestants. Requires a rail carrier to apply for Commission approval of any action which would encumber the right-of-way of an abandoned or discontinued rail line so as to impede its future use as a rail line. Sets forth the notice and hearing procedures prior to such Commission approval. Revises railroad line abandonment procedures to provide that a rail carrier must wait one year before resubmitting a previously denied abandonment application, unless a substantial change in circumstances can be shown. Precludes the Commission from exempting a proposed rail line abandonment or encumbrance from the requirements of this Act. Declares the effective date of this Act is June 1, 1987.</summary>
</bill>
