<bill session="100" type="h" number="3584" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Driftnet Impact Monitoring, Assessment, and Control Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve efforts to monitor, assess, and reduce the adverse impacts of driftnets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410496"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403266" joined="1987-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404220" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1987-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406148" joined="1987-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1987-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="407967" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409344" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1987-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, Interior, State, Marine Mammal Comm, DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-18">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.3674.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3674"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental monitoring"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fish kills"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/29/1987--Introduced.
Driftnet Impact Monitoring, Assessment, and Control Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary of Commerce (Secretary) and the Secretary of the Interior, to initiate negotiations with each foreign government that conducts, or authorizes its nationals to conduct, driftnet fishing concerning marine resources of the United States, in certain waters of the North Pacific Ocean, for the purpose of entering into agreements regarding cooperative monitoring and assessment of the numbers of marine resources of the United States killed and retrieved, discarded, or lost by the foreign government's driftnet fishing vessels. Authorizes the Secretary to deny any permit, for fishing or for receiving at sea or transporting U.S. harvested fish, to any vessel of any foreign government that fails to enter into such an agreement. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress regarding the results of the negotiations. Directs the Secretary to provide to the Congress a report identifying the nature, extent, and effects of driftnet fishing on U.S. marine resources. Directs the Secretary to request relevant information from foreign governments and to include such information in the report, along with an evaluation of the adequacy and reliability of such information. Directs the Secretary of State, in consultation with the Secretary and the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating, to initiate negotiations with foreign governments that conduct driftnet fishing in certain North Pacific Ocean waters for the purpose of entering into agreements for the enforcement of laws regarding the foreign government's driftnet fishing vessels. Directs the Secretary of State to certify to the President any foreign government's failure to enter into an enforcement agreement. Deems such certification to be a certification for the purposes of the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 relating to restrictions on the importation of fishery or wildlife products from countries which violate international fishery or endangered or threatened species programs. Directs the Secretary to evaluate the feasibility of and develop recommendations for: (1) the establishment of a driftnet marking, registry, and identification system; and (2) the use of alternative materials in driftnets to increase the rate of decomposition of driftnets discharged or lost at sea. Requires a report to the Congress on such recommendations. Declares that this Act does not expand or diminish the sovereign rights of the United States as stated in a specified presidential proclamation. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
