<bill session="100" type="h" number="3602" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology to Educate Children With Handicaps Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide financial assistance under the Education of the Handicapped Act to assist severely handicapped infants, children, and youth to improve their educational opportunities through the use of assistive device resource centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400306"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="402710" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404213" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300058" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408632" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="411488" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1988-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1586"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1586"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education of handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/1987--Introduced.
Technology to Educate Children With Handicaps Act - Amends the Education of the Handicapped Act to add provisions for assistive device resource centers. Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to pay the Federal share of the cost of establishing assistive device resource centers. Directs the Secretary to make State allotments based on the number of handicapped children. Sets forth a minimum State allotment. Requires that each center serve severely handicapped: (1) infants and toddlers; (2) children and youth; and (3) individuals who have attained 21 years of age if the State plan prescribes a targeted population of such individuals. Requires each center to: (1) train and assist specialists in local educational agencies and nonprofit community organizations to evaluate a handicapped student's potential to benefit from assistive devices; (2) instruct teachers, therapists, paraprofessionals, parents, and handicapped students in the appropriate use of assistive devices; (3) provide follow-up services and collect data to determine the effectiveness of the services provided; (4) develop a statewide service delivery system for severely handicapped children; (5) be able to assist in the development of assistive devices to meet the needs of handicapped individuals; (6) disseminate information to local educational agencies and nonprofit community organizations; and (7) provide in-service training to specialists, teachers, parents, and others on the benefits of assistive devices to promote improved educational performance and increased interaction between handicapped and nonhandicapped individuals. Requires each State to assure priority of services for handicapped children from birth through age 21. States that nothing in this Act precludes the provision of center services to handicapped individuals who are no longer eligible for services under the Education of the Handicapped Act. Requires each center to establish an Advisory Committee. Prohibits Federal funds from being used for the operations of such Committee. Sets forth required contents of State allotment applications. Allows any public agency or private nonprofit organization or institution to apply to a State for a grant to establish a center. Makes the Federal share of the cost 70 percent in FY 1988, 65 percent in FY 1989, and 60 percent in FY 1990. Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
