<bill session="100" type="h" number="3618" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shareholders Rights Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to repeal the Williams Act amendments to the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403545"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tender offers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/9/1987--Introduced.
Shareholders Rights Act of 1987 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to repeal provisions concerning: (1) required reports by persons acquiring more than five percent of an issuer's securities; (2) the prohibition against purchases of securities in violation of regulations concerning fraudulent or manipulative practices; (3) required reports by institutional investment managers; and (4) required statements of equity security ownership by an owner of more than five percent of an issuer's securities. Repeals provisions concerning: (1) tender offers by an owner of more than five percent of a class of securities of an issuer; (2) the prohibition against false statements of material fact or omissions of act with respect to a tender offer; and (3) the prohibition against the election or designation of a majority of directors of an issuer by the owner of more than five percent of a class of securities at other than a meeting of security holders. Specifies that the repeal of such provisions shall not relieve any person from liability for failure to comply with such provisions at any time prior to the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
