<bill session="100" type="h" number="3647" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Awareness and Prevention Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for minority populations outreach, education, counseling, prevention, and research activities relating to acquired immunodeficiency syndrome, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403695"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1988-07-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority health care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1987--Introduced.
Minority Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Awareness and Prevention Act of 1987 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to create a new title on prevention and public awareness of acquired immunodeficiency syndrome (AIDS) among minority populations. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, acting through the Director of the Office of Minority Health, to make grants to community-based organizations for projects for the development and implementation of activities among minority populations regarding information on and prevention of AIDS. Requires grant applicants to: (1) establish a community resource panel to assist in the development and implementation of the project; and (2) report to the community served for each year that the recipient receives a grant. Requires the Office of Minority Health to make grants to national minority organizations with local chapters or affiliates to provide coordination, technical assistance, and promotion. Specifies minimum and maximum limits for the grants. Authorizes appropriations for the grants to community-based organizations and for grants to national minority organizations for FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Secretary, for each fiscal year, to prepare and transmit to the Congress a written strategy for education, counseling, prevention, training, treatment, research, and service delivery activities relating to AIDS that are specifically directed toward Blacks, Hispanics, and other minority populations. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Minority Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome Advisory Committee to monitor and advise the Secretary with respect to efforts by Federal agencies to combat the AIDS epidemic in minority communities. Directs the Secretary to establish a minority AIDS clearinghouse to provide, primarily to minority communities and individuals, access to information relating to specified aspects of AIDS. Amends title XVII (Health Information and Health Promotion) of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish, in the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health, an Office of Minority Health. Sets forth the duties of the new office regarding AIDS and other minority health matters. Requires the Secretary to appoint a Director for the new office who is a member of the Public Health Service corps. Authorizes appropriations for title XVII for FY 1988 through 1990. Revises provisions relating to the research, community, and information programs the Secretary is authorized to conduct and support to insert references to minorities and minority communities and to make other changes. Directs the Secretary to submit to the President for transmission to the Congress an annual report on the status of minority health care efforts.</summary>
</bill>
