<bill session="100" type="h" number="3667" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Infant Health Demonstration Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable the Secretary of Health and Human Services to fund a program to demonstrate innovative methods to address the problem of high infant mortality among the Medicaid-eligible population, and other high-risk groups, through case-managed, comprehensive services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400571"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1987-12-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Abortion, Birth Control, and Family Planning"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/1987--Introduced.
Infant Health Demonstration Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants under provisions of the Social Security Act to selected States administering programs under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Act for demonstrations of programs addressing high infant mortality, low birth weight, and other unsatisfactory pregnancy outcomes among Medicaid-eligible women through referral for or provision of case-managed, comprehensive services to such women and their infants through the first year of life. Requires a final evaluation report and an independent evaluation. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992. Repeals a provision of title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act which requires the Secretary to make payments to States in connection with the offering, arranging, and furnishing of family planning services and supplies.</summary>
</bill>
