<bill session="100" type="h" number="3672" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tenant Credit Reporting Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Credit Reporting Act to establish certain requirements and restrictions respecting the retention and furnishing of information by consumer reporting agencies on individuals renting residential property.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300087"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Consumer Affairs and Coinage.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA02" subcommittee="Consumer Affairs and Coinage" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Consumer credit"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Landlord and tenant"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/1987--Introduced.
Tenant Credit Reporting Act - Amends the Fair Credit Reporting Act to include within the definition of "consumer report" any information received from a consumer reporting agency for the purpose of establishing a consumer's eligibility for rental of any property as a principal place of residence. Permits the use of information obtained from a consumer reporting agency in connection with the rental of any property by the consumer as a principal place of residence. Sets forth information which may not be included in any such consumer report, including the consumer's involvement with tenants organizations, any safety or sanitation complaints, any rent abatements, or unadjudicated landlord complaints. Requires a consumer reporting agency that records and retains any information regarding an adverse rental action to make a clear and accurate disclosure to the consumer involved. Sets forth information which a consumer reporting agency must disclose to a consumer when the agency furnishes a report to a person in connection with the consumer's rental of any property as a principal place of residence. Requires the user of a consumer report that results in an adverse rental action to inform the consumer of the name and address of the consumer reporting agency making the report.</summary>
</bill>
