<bill session="100" type="h" number="3679" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-08">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the Federal relationship to the Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians as a distinct Indian tribe, to clarify the status of members of the band, to transfer title to trust lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400110" joined="1988-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1988-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408957" joined="1988-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409651" joined="1988-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1988-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-08">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-584.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Placed on Consent Calendar No: 17.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 350.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-02">
      <text>Called up by House on Call of Consent Calendar.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-05-02" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="653">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 653.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1735 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-07-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 1735 with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-08-25">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-08-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-09-08" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-420" type="public" datetime="1988-09-08">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-420.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1735"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended, in lieu of S. 1735) Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians Act - Reaffirms the Federal recognition of, and trust relationship with, the Lac Vieux Desert Band of Lake Superior Chippewa Indians. Provides that all Federal laws applicable to Indians shall apply to the Band unless they are inconsistent with this Act. Recognizes the Band as an independent tribal entity. Makes the Band and its members eligible for all special programs and services provided by the United States to Indians. Requires the Band to submit to the Secretary of the Interior for approval its membership roll which shall include only eligible individuals who are not members of any other federally recognized Indian tribe. States eligibility requirements. Provides that: (1) within one year following the enactment of this Act, the Band's governing body shall propose a governing document and the Secretary shall conduct an election as to the adoption of the proposed document; (2) until the Band adopts and the Secretary approves a governing document, the Band's interim governing document shall be the Lac Vieux Desert Constitution, approved June 18, 1986; and (3) until the Band elects a new governing body under the new governing document, the Band's governing body shall consist of its current Band officers or any new officers selected under the election procedures of the interim governing document. Authorizes the Keweenaw Bay Indian Community to convey to the United States in trust for the Band all lands located in Gogebic County, Michigan, which on the date of the enactment of this Act are held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the Community. Provides that, upon acceptance of the deed to such lands by the Secretary, such lands shall constitute the reservation of the Band. Allows the Secretary to place other land into trust for the benefit of the Band. Provides that all such lands located in Gogebic County shall become part of the reservation. Provides that for purposes of the per capita distribution of funds appropriated and apportioned to the Community in satisfaction of certain judgments awarded the Lake Superior Chippewas and Mississippi Chippewas the Secretary shall accept the tribe's certification of enrolled membership. Provides that individuals who are or become members of the Band and who are eligible for per capita shares out of funds apportioned to the Keweenaw Bay Indian or Sokaogan Chippewa Community shall continue to be eligible for such per capita payments notwithstanding their relinquishment of their enrollment in either community pursuant to this Act. Directs the Secretary to call an election within 90 days of receipt of a resolution of the Keweenaw Bay Tribal Council requesting an election for the purpose of amending provisions of the constitution of the Keweenaw Bay Indian Community. Makes any spending authority provided under this Act effective for any fiscal year only to such extent or in such amounts as are provided in advance in appropriation Acts.</summary>
</bill>
