<bill session="100" type="h" number="3683" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Individual Appropriations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that each title of any bill or joint resolution making continuing appropriations that is reported by a committee of conference and is agreed to by both Houses of the Congress in the same form during a 2-year period shall be presented as a separate joint resolution to the President.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402435"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1835"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="1835"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional conference committees"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/2/1987--Introduced.
Individual Appropriations Act - Requires the committee of conference to report a separate conference report for each title of a bill or joint resolution making continuing appropriations for a period of 30 days or more, together with any amendments in disagreement for each title. Requires each title to be assigned a bill number and considered separately. Makes it out of order in the House of Representatives and the Senate: (1) to consider such bill or joint resolution unless each title corresponds to a regular appropriation bill; and (2) for any general provisions of such bill or joint resolution to not be contained in the appropriate title. Excludes any bill or joint resolution making supplemental appropriations from provisions of this Act. Makes such Act applicable to FY 1988, 1989, and 1990.</summary>
</bill>
