<bill session="100" type="h" number="3695" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIDS Reporting and Spousal Notification Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require each State to establish certain reporting requirements with respect to individuals infected with the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome and to establish certain requirements with respect to the notification of spouses of such individuals.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406463"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1988-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/1987--Introduced.
AIDS Reporting and Spousal Notification Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to reduce payments to a State unde title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act unless the State by law establishes and enforces requirements regarding: (1) reporting to State public health authorities by physicians and medical technicians of the name and address of individuals infected with the etiologic agent for acquired immune deficiency syndrome, including asymptomatic individuals; and (2) notification of the person who is, at the time of reporting, the spouse of such infected individual. Provides a formula for determining the amount of the reduction.</summary>
</bill>
