<bill session="100" type="h" number="3707" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reconstruction Finance Corporation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Reconstruction Finance Corporation to make loans and loan guarantees to individuals or concerns engaged in industry, agriculture, and commerce, who would otherwise be unable to obtain needed financing or refinancing essential for continued operation thereby preventing unemployment and resulting disruption of the economy, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA05" subcommittee="Economic Stabilization" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Federally-assisted loans"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/3/1987--Introduced.
Reconstruction Finance Corporation Act of 1987 - Establishes the Reconstruction Finance Corporation. Authorizes the appropriation of $5,000,000,000 as the capital stock of such Corporation. Authorizes the Corporation, in order to aid in financing agriculture, commerce, and industry, to make loans to businesses for: (1) plant construction, conversion, or expansion or acquisitions; (2) working capital; or (3) the payment of current debts or obligations. Prohibits a loan to any business unless it is otherwise unable to obtain one on reasonable terms. Allows a term for such a loan of up to ten years, extendable to 12 years. States that each loan shall bear interest at a rate equal to the current average yield on all outstanding obligations of the United States as of the last day of the month immediately preceding the month in which the loan is made. Prohibits the payment of fees or commissions by any applicant for a loan or loan guarantee under this Act. Requires priority in awarding financial assistance to manufacturers or processors of goods or services in short supply. Authorizes the Corporation to guarantee the payment of a loan made by a non-Federal lender under certain circumstances. Limits loan guarantees to a period not exceeding ten years. Limits the aggregate principal amounts of guaranteed loans outstanding at any time. Permits the Corporation to subscribe for common or preferred stock in specified businesses or to purchase their capital notes or debentures and to sell such stock or notes in the open market. Authorizes the Corporation to have outstanding obligations in an aggregate amount not exceeding three times its subscribed capital. Exempts all obligations issued by the Corporation from all taxation (except surtaxes, estate, inheritance, and gift taxes). Exempts the Corporation from all taxation except real property taxation. Requires quarterly reports to the Congress on the Corporation's operations and annual audits of the Corporation's accounts. Establishes criminal sanctions for false statements or fraudulent acts in connection with transactions with the Corporation. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
