<bill session="100" type="h" number="3717" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bus Safety Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain actions by the Secretary of Transportation to improve bus safety.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405687"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1987-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="1987-12-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Bus drivers"/>
    <term name="Common carrier regulation"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor bus lines"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/1987--Introduced.
Bus Safety Act of 1987 - Requires the Secretary of Transportation to take the following actions regarding bus safety: (1) issue a final rule extending full coverage of the Federal motor carrier safety regulations to all motor carriers of passengers operating in interstate commerce; (2) develop and implement an education and enforcement program to inform all private motor carriers of passengers that compliance with the Federal motor carrier safety regulations is mandatory when operating in interstate commerce; (3) submit periodic reports to the Congress regarding the regulations and the status of the education and enforcement program; (4) amend specified regulations in the Code of Federal Regulations to include motor vehicles and drivers operating wholly within a municipality or its commercial zone; (5) promulgate regulations requiring all motor carriers of passengers to carry on all vehicles operating in interstate commerce written evidence of compliance with minimum insurance requirements; (6) require motor carriers of passengers operating in interstate commerce without certification by the Interstate Commerce Commission to display prominently within such vehicle an identification number issued by the Department of Transportation; (7) establish Federal standards for periodic inspection of commercial motor vehicles; (8) prohibit any State from requiring an additional periodic inspection of a commercial motor vehicle that has been the subject of a current inspection that meets the Federal standards; (9) remove from the definition of "on-duty time," for purposes of hours of service computation, time spent by a driver resting inside the motor vehicle; (10) establish an Office of Bus Safety in the Federal Highway Administration for the enforcement of Federal safety regulations affecting passenger carrying motor vehicles; (11) report to the Congress regarding the status of such Office and of the rulemaking proceedings required by this Act; and (12) report to the Congress explaining in detail every rule required by this Act that has not been adopted.</summary>
</bill>
