<bill session="100" type="h" number="3728" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Blood Donor Locator Service Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act and the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for a Blood Donor Locator Service to assist in prompt notification of blood donors who are found to have or have had the virus for acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405939"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.4333.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Blood donors"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/1987--Introduced.
Blood Donor Locator Service Act of 1987 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors, and Disability Insurance) (OASDI) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish and conduct a Blood Donor Locator Service, under the direction of the Commissioner of Social Security, to be used to obtain and transmit to any authorized person the most recent mailing address of any blood donor who, as indicated by the donated blood or by the history of the subsequent use of the blood, has the virus for acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS), in order to inform the donor of the possible need for medical care and treatment. Sets forth recordkeeping requirements applicable to authorized persons receiving address information, including measures regarding the security and confidentiality of the information. Amends provisions of the Internal Revenue Code relating to disclosure of taxpayer identity information to direct the Secretary of the Treasury to disclose the mailing address of taxpayers to the Blood Donor Locator Service. Sets forth provisions relating to safeguards applicable to the disclosed information.</summary>
</bill>
