<bill session="100" type="h" number="3725" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend for one year the provision of title II of the Social Security Act which allows continued payment of disability insurance benefits during appeal, and to make permanent the provisions of titles IV and XVI of such Act which permit or require the disregarding of in-kind assistance to AFDC and SSI recipients.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404097"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407676" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1987-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>See H.R.3545.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3545"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative remedies"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/1987--Introduced.
Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to extend for one year the operation of provisions continuing disability insurance benefit payments during administrative appeal of terminations of such benefits. (Currently, such payments are not to be made for months succeeding May 1988.) Amends the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 to permanently disregard in-kind assistance provided by nonprofit organizations to recipients of benefits under title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) or part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Social Security Act in determining the need or eligibility of such recipients for program benefits.</summary>
</bill>
