<bill session="100" type="h" number="3769" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Planning Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the program of assistance for family planning services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404213" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1988-04-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407069" joined="1987-12-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409534" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410407" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300100" joined="1988-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion, Birth Control, and Family Planning"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Statistics"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/15/1987--Introduced.
Family Planning Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends title X (Population Research and Voluntary Family Planning Programs) of the Public Health Service Act to remove provisions authorizing the Secretary of Health and Human Services to reduce the amount of a grant for family planning projects by the value of supplies or equipment furnished by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations for grants and contracts for such projects for FY 1989 through 1991. Repeals provisions authorizing the Secretary to make formula grants to State health authorities to assist in planning, establishing, maintaining, coordinating, and evaluating family planning services. Amends provisions relating to training grants and contracts to authorize the grants and contracts to provide technical assistance and clinical training for obstetric-gynecologic nurse practitioners and training for educators, counselors, and other personnel to carry out family planning service programs described in provisions relating to projects for family planning services and to informational and educational materials. (Current law provides for the grants and contracts to be used to provide the training for personnel to carry out family planning service programs described in provisions relating to projects for family planning services and to formula grants to States for family planning services.) Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct and to make grants for research into the development of new or improved contraceptive devices, drugs, and techniques and their evaluation. Authorizes appropriations. Amends provisions authorizing the Secretary to conduct and make grants for research to add authorization for contraceptive evaluation and for research to improve the clinical management and direct delivery of family planning services. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and enter into contracts to assist in making available information and education to enable persons to make responsible choices concerning human sexuality, pregnancy, and parenthood. (Current law provides for grants and contracts for family planning and population growth information, including educational materials.) Requires the information and education to be made available to all persons desiring it, with special emphasis on adolescents and parents. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary to annually collect data regarding family planning services and regarding unintended pregnancies. Authorizes the Secretary to use grants or contracts for the data collection. Requires the data to be made public. Requires a plan regarding family planning mandated by current law to be based on the data.</summary>
</bill>
