<bill session="100" type="h" number="3808" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">1987 Amendments to the Merchant Marine Act, 1936</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Merchant Marine Act, 1936.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400844" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403266" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406746" joined="1987-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Merchant Marine.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSMM06" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Cargo preference"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant marine"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Subsidies"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/18/1987--Introduced.
1987 Amendments to the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 - Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 to add liner vessels in international trade to the categories of vessels eligible for operating-differential subsidies (ODS), with limits on the routes of operation for the first three years after enactment of this Act. Makes provisions requiring a subsidy determination by the Secretary of Transportation of necessity in order to meet foreign-flag competition apply to bulk vessels. (Current provisions apply to vessels without regard to whether they are bulk vessels.) Deems liner vessels meeting certain requirements to have been built in the United States for the purposes, subject to exception, of ODS, and for the purposes of certain cargo preference provisions. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) the content of applications for written permission to pay subsidies in connection with vessels engaging in coastwise or intercoastal trade; (2) the factors to be considered by the Secretary in a hearing on written permission; (3) the terms and conditions to be included in the permission; and (4) deadlines for a decision on applications for permission. Grants automatic approval to tug and barge services in operation as of enactment of this Act in specified geographic areas.</summary>
</bill>
