<bill session="100" type="h" number="3825" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">AIDS Research Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act with respect to research programs relating to acquired immune deficiency syndrome.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400987" joined="1988-02-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-02-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.4850 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4850"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Blood banks"/>
    <term name="Centers for Disease Control and Prevention (CDC)"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disease control"/>
    <term name="Drug safety and regulation"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Food and Drug Administration (FDA)"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Vaccines"/>
    <term name="Vital statistics"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/20/1987--Introduced.
AIDS Research Act of 1987 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to create a new title on research with respect to acquired immune deficiency syndrome (AIDS). Requires the Directors of the Centers for Disease Control (CDC), the National Cancer Institute (NCI), and the National Institute of Allergy and Infectious Disease (NIAID) and the Commissioner of Food and Drugs (Commissioner) to each: (1) prepare and submit directly to the President each fiscal year a budget estimate for research with respect to AIDS; and (2) receive from the President and Director of the Office of Management and Budget (OMB) all funds appropriated to the official involved by the Congress for such research. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to develop and implement a plan to expedite the award of grants, contracts, and cooperative agreements for research projects relating to AIDS. Requires the Director of the Office of Personnel Management or the Administrator of General Services, as applicable, to respond to priority requests by such Directors or the Commissioner within 14 days. Deems a request not disapproved to be approved. Prohibits the Director of the OMB from taking any action to prevent such Directors or the Commissioner from making a priority request under provisions of this Act. Authorizes additional personnel for the CDC, the National Institutes of Health (NIH), the Food and Drug Administration, the Health Resources and Services Administration, and the Office of the Assistant Secretary for Health. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the NIAID, to establish the AIDS Clinical Research Review Committee to: (1) advise the Director on research; (2) review research, issue reports, conduct studies, and convene meetings regarding clinical treatment; and (3) establish a telephone hotline to provide information to health professionals. Directs the Secretary, through the Directors of the NCI and the NIAID, to establish in each Institute a clinical evaluation unit. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the NIAID, to establish a program for the evaluation of drugs which are not approved by the Commissioner for AIDS treatment and which are being used by individuals infected with the etiologic agent for AIDS. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and enter into contracts and cooperative agreements for the purpose of conducting the drug evaluations. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the NIH, to make grants to and enter into contracts with international organizations concerned with public health: (1) for international research on vaccines and treatment; and (2) to support programs in education, information, and risk reduction, projects for training individuals in skills and technical expertise, and epidemiological research. Authorizes the provision of technical assistance for foreign governments. Requires support provided by the Secretary to be in furtherance of the World Health Organization's Special Programme on Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires the Secretary to obligate not less than 50 percent of amounts appropriated for support through the World Health Organization and the Pan American Health Organization. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the NIAID, to make grants for centers for basic and clinical research into, and training in, advanced diagnostic, prevention, and treatment methods for AIDS. Prohibits grants from being used to provide training for which National Research Service Awards may be provided. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the NIAID, to provide for the establishment of a virus and serum bank in which all human immunodeficiency virus serotypes and serum are available to qualified investigators and organizations. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, acting through the National Library of Medicine, to establish the International Acquired Immune Deficiency Syndrome Research Data Bank to collect and disseminate information to the public, general practitioners, and investigators. Directs the Secretary to establish a schedule of charges for foreign users of the data bank. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the CDC, to develop an epidemiological data base and provide for long-term studies. Authorizes grants for long-term research into treatments for AIDS developed from knowledge of the genetic nature of the etiologic agent for AIDS. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the CDC, to establish fellowship and training programs to develop epidemiology, counseling, laboratory analysis, and other skills relating to AIDS. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Secretary to make grants for training health care personnel with regard to AIDS. Requires non-Federal matching funds in cash or in kind. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Defines "acquired immune deficiency syndrome," for the purposes of the new title added by this Act, to include any condition arising from infection with the etiologic agent for such syndrome. Amends title IV (National Research Institutes) of the Public Health Service Act to require the Director of the NIAID to develop and expand clinical trials of treatments and therapies for infection with the etiologic agent for AIDS. Authorizes the Director to: (1) establish or support efforts using specialized biological materials; (2) support research and training outside the United States; (3) support training with respect to conducting research; (4) encourage and coordinate research by industrial concerns; (5) acquire and maintain real and personal property; (6) make grants for the construction or renovation of facilities; (7) acquire buildings in or around the District of Columbia; and (8) enter into contracts and cooperative agreements as necessary to expedite and coordinate research. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of the CDC, to conduct a study of AIDS mortality rates among various groups, among geographic areas, and among individuals with varying financial resources for the payment of health care services. Directs the Secretary, through the Director of NIAID, to conduct a study of the consensus among health care professionals on clinical treatment for preventing the development of symptoms arising from infection with the etiologic agent for AIDS. Directs the Secretary to request the National Academy of Sciences and other similar institutions to report regarding the establishment of consortia for research and development.</summary>
</bill>
