<bill session="100" type="h" number="3841" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-01-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-01-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-01-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New School Child Care Demonstration Projects Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for demonstration projects for the improvement of child care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400216"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1988-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409651" joined="1988-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-01-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED01" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED07" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Public schools"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/25/1988--Introduced.
New School Child Care Demonstration Projects Act of 1987 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services (the Secretary) to make grants to States to pay the Federal share of the cost of childcare demonstration projects conducted in existing public elementary and secondary school buildings. Reserves specified portions of funds for evaluation and for special demonstration projects. Allots the remainder of funds to States on the basis of population of children under 16 years old. Provides for allotment adjustments and reallotments. Directs the Secretary to provide, through grants and contracts, for continuing evaluation of State and Federal demonstration projects under this Act. Directs the Secretary to publish summaries and results of evaluative research. Directs the Secretary to submit to the appropriate congressional committees copies of all such research studies and evaluation summaries. Sets forth application requirements for demonstration grants and rules for membership of advisory committees to monitor and evaluate such projects. Requires that specified reserved funds be used for grants to public and nonprofit private entities for special demonstration projects to be awarded at the discretion of the Secretary. Sets forth problem areas for the focus of such grants. Sets the Federal share of the demonstration grants to States at 90 percent of the cost of project activities. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990 to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
