<bill session="100" type="h" number="386" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Pay Management Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the testing of alternative systems of compensation for Federal employees; to modify the pay comparability system for Federal employees; to modify the manner in which the authority to increase minimum rates of pay for certain Federal employees may be exercised; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408313"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402159" joined="1987-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403266" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1987-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1987-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404634" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="405687" joined="1987-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1987-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1987-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408520" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409353" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1987-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB, OPM, GAO, DOD, DOE.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO02" subcommittee="Compensation and Employee Benefits" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining in government"/>
    <term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
    <term name="Evaluation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Wage surveys"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Federal Pay Management Act of 1987 - Title I: Alternative Compensation Programs - Establishes a Federal Compensation Board to design and implement Federal employee compensation programs utilizing the alternative systems set forth in this Act and to carry out oversight functions with respect to such programs. Describes the types of alternative systems as follows: (1) a system under which annual pay adjustments are made so that total pay and benefits are comparable to those of private enterprise for the same level of work; (2) a system under which annual pay adjustments are made so that rates of basic pay are consistent with those for the same level of work in private enterprise within the same geographic region; (3) a system under which conditions of employment shall be subject to collective bargaining; (4) a system which identifies separate career categories, adjusts pay based on specified factors, provides pay differentials, and authorizes special awards and performance recognition; and (5) any combination of the aforementioned. Establishes a Commission on Federal Pay Management to evaluate each alternative system as implemented, and to make similar evaluations with respect to the current system. Requires a report to the President and the Congress at the end of the five-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act. Terminates the Commission after submission of the report. Title II: Amendments Relating to Pay Comparability System - Specifies the methodology to be used in connection with Federal pay adjustments. Revises the method for making such pay adjustments. Provides that mandatory wage and price controls are a basis for submission of an alternative plan to a Federal pay adjustment. Requires the enactment of a joint resolution of approval before any such plan becomes effective. Title III: Authority for Agencies to Establish Higher Minimum Rates of Basic Pay - Grants to agency heads the authority to establish higher minimum rates of basic pay for certain occupations with recruitment problems. (Currently such authority is granted to the President.) Requires agency heads to notify the Office of Personnel Management before exercising such authority. Provides that any decision of the Office that such action is unwarranted shall be accompanied by a statement of the reasons for such decision. Authorizes the agency head to appeal to the President.</summary>
</bill>
