<bill session="100" type="h" number="3899" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Prevention, Identification, and Treatment of Elder Abuse Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide financial assistance for programs for the prevention, identification, and treatment of elder abuse, neglect, and exploitation, to establish a National Center on Elder Abuse, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408313"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-03">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against the elderly"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Elder abuse"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1988--Introduced.
Prevention, Identification, and Treatment of Elder Abuse Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish an office known as the National Center on Elder Abuse to: (1) compile an annual summary of recently conducted research on elder abuse; (2) develop and maintain an information clearinghouse on all programs for the prevention and treatment of such abuse; (3) compile training materials for personnel engaged in elder abuse prevention; (4) provide technical assistance for the planning and implementation of programs relating to the problems of elder abuse; and (5) investigate the causes and national incidence of elder abuse. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to or enter into contracts with public agencies or nonprofit organizations for demonstration projects designed to prevent and treat elder abuse. Sets forth the terms and conditions for such grants. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to or enter into contracts with public agencies or nonprofit organizations for demonstration projects designed to prevent and treat elder abuse. Sets forth the terms and conditions for such grants. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to States for the development and implementation of elder abuse prevention and treatment programs. Requires such States to have in effect a State elder abuse law with mandatory reporting provisions. Sets forth other requirements for eligibility. Prohibits the use of assistance for construction of facilities. Directs the Secretary to establish criteria to achieve equitable distribution of assistance among the States. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
