<bill session="100" type="h" number="3912" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hostilities Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to help ensure that the collective judgment of both the Congress and the President are exercised concerning the involvement of United States Armed Forces in hostilities, and to repeal the War Powers resolution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400617"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative procedure"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1988--Introduced.
Hostilities Act of 1987 - Requires the President to consult and confer with the Congress whenever U.S. armed forces are introduced: (1) into hostilities or situations where imminent involvement in hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances; (2) into the territory, airspace, or waters of a foreign nation while equipped for combat; or (3) in numbers which substantially enlarge U.S. armed forces equipped for combat already located in a foreign nation. Requires that such consultation take place before the President decides to introduce U.S. armed forces in such situations, except in exceptional and compelling circumstances, where such consultation must take place within 48 hours after such a decision is made. Specifies the Members of Congress to be involved in such a consultation. Requires the President, in the absence of a declaration of war, to submit a written report to the Congress within 48 hours after U.S. armed forces are introduced into or involved in situations requiring a consultation with the Congress. Requires the report to include the justification and authority for the use of U.S. armed forces and the estimated scope and duration of hostilities. Requires the President to periodically (but in no event less often than once every three months) report to the Congress so long as U.S. armed forces continue to be engaged in hostilities or situations. Sets forth expedited congressional procedures for the consideration of legislation imposing, revising, or repealing limitations on the use of U.S. armed forces. Sets forth congressional procedures for the addition of limitation measures with respect to Department of Defense appropriations. Sets forth special procedures for the reconvening of Congress after an adjournment sine die or for more than three days in order to consider: (1) legislation imposing limitations on the use of U.S. armed forces; or (2) a presidential report concerning the introduction of U.S. armed forces. Repeals the War Powers Resolution and provisions of the Department of State Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1984 and 1985 relating to expedited congressional procedures for certain joint resolutions and bills concerning U.S. armed forces in hostilities.</summary>
</bill>
