<bill session="100" type="h" number="3971" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-29">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Child Abduction Remedies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">International Child Abduction Remedies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">International Child Abduction Remedies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">International Child Abduction Remedies Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">International Child Abduction Remedies Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish procedures to implement the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400231"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1988-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-03-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on The Judiciary. Report No: 100-525.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 321.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-03-28" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="1988-03-29" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="605">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 605.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-04-12" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-04-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-04-25" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-04-25">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-04-29" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-300" type="public" datetime="1988-04-29">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-300.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2673"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Parental kidnapping"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1932"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/12/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) International Child Abduction Remedies Act - Grants State courts and U.S. district courts concurrent original jurisdiction with regard to actions arising under the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction. Retains Federal court jurisdiction in cases arising under the Convention where such jurisdiction would otherwise exist under Federal law (Federal question, diversity of citizenship, etc.). Sets forth requirements with regard to notice and burden of proof for such actions. Allows any court exercising jurisdiction over a petition filed pursuant to the Convention or this Act to take provisional measures under Federal or State law to protect the well-being of the child or prevent the child's removal or concealment. Prohibits any court from ordering the provisional removal of a child from the person having physical control unless the applicable requirements of State law are satisfied. States that any application submitted to the U.S. Central Authority or petition seeking judicial remedies in accordance with the terms of the Convention shall be admissible in court without regard to the need for authentication. Directs the President to designate a Federal agency to serve as the Central Authority for the United States for the purposes of: (1) issuing regulations to implement the Convention and this Act; (2) obtaining information from the Parent Locator Service; and (3) collecting, maintaining, and disseminating information for purposes relating to the Convention and this Act. Places certain limitations on the dissemination of Government information to the Central Authority. Directs the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Attorney General to designate Federal employees and private citizens to serve as an interagency coordinating group to monitor the operation of the Convention and provide advice on its implementation. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into an agreement with the Central Authority which would make the services of the Parent Locator Service available to the Central Authority. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the purposes of the Convention and this Act.</summary>
</bill>
