<bill session="100" type="h" number="3991" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">ATV User Safety and Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to declare 3-wheel all terrain vehicles to be banned hazardous products under the Consumer Product Safety Act, to direct the Consumer Product Safety Commission to promulgate consumer product safety rules for all terrain vehicles, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="401155" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="1988-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="406730" joined="1988-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="406746" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409237" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300156" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1988-06-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>See H.R.3343.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSIF06" subcommittee="Commerce, Consumer Protection, and Competitiveness" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3343"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Recreation and Recreational Facilities"/>
    <term name="Recreational vehicles"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/24/1988--Introduced.
ATV User Safety and Equity Act - Provides that three-wheeled all-terrain vehicles (ATVs) shall be considered to be banned hazardous products under the Consumer Product Safety Act. Permits the sale of three-wheeled ATVs by other than manufacturers, distributors, or dealers. Requires the manufacturers of three-wheeled ATVs to provide refunds to persons who purchased such vehicles before the effective date of this Act (in accordance with regulations promulgated by the Consumer Product Safety Commission). States that the failure of a manufacturer to comply with the refund requirements of this Act shall be considered a violation of the Consumer Product Safety Act. Directs the Commission to promulgate a consumer product safety rule which will require: (1) manufacturers to offer free training in the operation of ATVs to all purchasers; (2) manufacturers to offer helmets and other protective equipment with the sale of ATVs; (3) manufacturers to provide notice (warning labels and other appropriate means) of the risk of injury or death presented by ATVs; (4) manufacturers and distributors to establish programs to ensure compliance by dealers with the safety requirements of the rule; and (5) retail dealers to provide purchasers with safety information respecting the operation of such vehicles. Directs the Commission to promulgate a consumer product safety rule to improve the safety of ATVs by prescribing: (1) appropriate performance standards for ATVs; and (2) design characteristics. Sets forth a consumer product safety rule to be placed into effect in the event that the Commission does not promulgate a final rule within the prescribed time period.</summary>
</bill>
