<bill session="100" type="h" number="4058" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Export-Import Bank Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to require appropriations for the amount of any loan subsidy provided by the Export-Import Bank of the United States and to authorize appropriations for such purposes for fiscal years beginning after September 30, 1989.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401155" joined="1988-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Subcommittee on International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy Prior to Introduction (Fed 25, 88).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Export finance"/>
    <term name="Export subsidies"/>
    <term name="Export-Import Bank of the United States"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1988--Introduced.
Export-Import Bank Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to prohibit the aggregate amount of loan subsidies provided by the Export-Import Bank (Bank) from exceeding the amount of funds appropriated for such subsidies for any fiscal year after FY 1989. Requires the Bank to include in its annual budget proposal and appropriation request: (1) the amount requested to be provided in an appropriations Act for such fiscal year for spending or credit authority provided under such Act; and (2) an estimate of the total amount of the subsidies involved. Requires the Bank to use Office of Management and Budget guidelines in estimating subsidy amounts. Defines "subsidy" as the difference between the cost to the borrower of a loan made, insured, or provided an interest subsidy by the Bank and the cost the borrower would have incurred in obtaining the financing from private sources without Bank action. Authorizes appropriations for such subsidies. Specifies that any amount appropriated for subsidies shall: (1) become available to the Bank as loans, loan obligations, and commitments are made by the Bank; and (2) be permanent additions to the capital and reserves of the Bank.</summary>
</bill>
