<bill session="100" type="h" number="405" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Older Persons Comprehensive Counseling Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act and the Public Health Service Act to provide expanded counseling assistance for the elderly, sick, and disabled.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409353"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED07" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Retirement"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Older Persons Comprehensive Counseling Assistance Act of 1987 - Title I: General Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1982 through 1986 for specified programs under this Act. Directs the United States Commissioner on Aging, through the National Information Resource Clearinghouse for the Aging, to collect, analyze, and disseminate information related to counseling services for older persons. Title II: Counseling Assistance Programs - Requires each State desiring a grant under this Act to submit a comprehensive State plan for providing counseling assistance to the elderly. Requires such plan to conform to specified criteria. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to States having approved plans based on statewide needs and priorities. Permits the use of grants to fund counseling assistance outreach programs, preretirement counseling programs, career counseling assistance programs, referral services, community activities, and counseling for families of sick and disabled senior citizens. Sets forth requirements for State programs and for State training and retraining programs for counseling personnel. Directs the Commissioner on Aging to contract with postsecondary educational institutions and area agencies on aging for the purpose of providing needed training and retraining of counseling personnel. Directs the Commissioner on Aging to carry out a demonstration and evaluation program for specified purposes, including: (1) identification of existing effective practices in counseling older persons; (2) identification of areas where further development is needed; and (3) development of model training programs for professional counselors.</summary>
</bill>
