<bill session="100" type="h" number="4054" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-26">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Government Printing Office Inspector General Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house" partial="1">Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Government Printing Office Inspector General Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Inspector General Act of 1978 to establish offices of inspector general in certain departments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401837"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405646" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1988-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-17">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-17">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Government Operations.  Report No: 100-771.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 468.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-07-26" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Laid on Table in House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>House Incorporated this Measure in S.908 as an Amendment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" name="House Government Operations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="908"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Oaths"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Printing"/>
    <term name="Railroad Retirement Board"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Title I: Inspector General Act Amendments - Inspector General Act Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to establish an Office of Inspector General in the Departments of Justice and of the Treasury and in the Federal Emergency Management Agency. Conforms the Offices of Inspector General in the Departments of Energy and Health and Human Services and in the Railroad Retirement Board to the Inspector General Act of 1978. Transfers to the new Offices of Inspector General the functions of specified existing audit and investigation units. Requires that there be established in each designated Federal entity an Office of Inspector General. Requires the Inspector General to be appointed by, report to, and be under the general supervision of, the head of each Federal entity governed by this Act. Requires the head of any Federal entity who removes an Inspector General from office to communicate the reasons for such removal to the Congress. Requires each Federal entity which is not a designated Federal entity to prepare and transmit to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and to the Congress a report which: (1) states whether there has been established in such entity an internal audit office that meets requirements under this Act; (2) lists actions taken to ensure that the entity's audits meet standards issued by the Comptroller General; and (3) summarizes matters relating to the personnel, programs, and operations of the entity referred to prosecutive authorities. Requires the Chief Postal Inspector of the United States Postal Service to: (1) hold the position of Inspector General of the United States Postal Service; (2) be under the general supervision of the Postmaster General; and (3) be appointed by the Governors of the United States Postal Service. Directs the Governors to promptly notify the Congress of the reasons for removal or transfer of the Chief Postal Inspector. Requires the following additional information to be included in the semiannual report of an Inspector General: (1) a listing of each audit report issued during the reporting period, including ineligible costs and unsupported costs; (2) a summary of each particularly significant report; (3) statistical tables showing the total number of audit reports and, where applicable, ineligible costs, unsupported costs, and amounts subject to management decision; (4) a summary of each particularly significant audit report issued before the commencement of the reporting period for which a management decision was not made within six months after the issuance of such report, an explanation of the reason a decision was not made, and a statement as to current status of each such report; (5) a description of, and explanation of the reasons for, any significant revised management decision; (6) information concerning any significant management decision with which the Inspector General is in disagreement; and (7) separate sections of information with respect to each audit and investigative office outside the Office of Inspector General. Sets forth information to be included in reports by the head of an establishment on final action taken on reports by Inspectors General. Authorizes audit unit directors or Inspectors General to administer to or take from any person an oath, affirmation, or affidavit when necessary. Requires that an audit entity of the Federal Government perform any reviews of Offices of Inspector General to determine whether internal controls are in place and whether audit standards, policies, and procedures are being followed. Provides that when the Coast Guard operates as a service of a department or agency other than the Department of Defense, a member of the Coast Guard shall be deemed to be an employee of such department or agency. Requires a report to the Director of the Office of Management and Budget and to the Congress by the head of each designated Federal entity on that entity's progress in establishing an Office of Inspector General. Requires the President to include in the budget a separate appropriation account for appropriations for each Office of Inspector General headed by a presidentially appointed Inspector General. Title II: Government Printing Office Inspector General - Government Printing Office Inspector General Act of 1988 - Establishes an Office of Inspector General in the Government Printing Office to: (1) conduct and supervise audits and investigations relating to the Government Printing Office; (2) provide leadership and coordination and recommend policies to promote economy, efficiency, and effectiveness; and (3) provide a means of keeping the Public Printer and the Congress fully and currently informed about problems and deficiencies. Provides for the appointment of the Inspector General by the Public Printer and sets forth the duties and responsibilities of such office.</summary>
</bill>
