<bill session="100" type="h" number="4069" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1988 and 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405687"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400844" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="1988-03-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-02">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Hazardous Materials Transportation Act to direct the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations for the safe transportation of hazardous materials in domestic and foreign commerce (including route designations). Cites the area in which Federal regulations preempt State hazardous materials transportation requirements. Authorizes the Secretary to promulgate regulations for dispute resolution among the States regarding hazardous materials highway route designations. Permits States to petition for judicial review of the dispute resolution decision. Grants the Secretary discretion to either adopt or reject hazardous materials transportation standards adopted by international bodies according to the Secretary's perception of the public interest. Requires motor carriers of specified hazardous materials (including radioactive materials) to possess a valid safety permit issued by the Secretary authorizing the carrier to engage in such transportation. Cites circumstances under which such permits may be suspended or revoked. Amends the definition of radioactive materials to state that it does not include any material determined by the Secretary to be of such low radioactivity that it does not pose a significant hazard when transported. Revises the scope of civil penalties to impose liability for any infraction of regulations (currently such liability only attaches to violations knowingly committed). Prescribes guidelines under which the preemption of State laws conflicting with this Act shall be determined. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1989.</summary>
</bill>
