<bill session="100" type="h" number="4121" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Energy Nuclear Facilities Safety Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an independent safety board to oversee Department of Energy nuclear facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409793"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-03-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408313" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1988-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-09">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Procurement and Military Nuclear Systems.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS07" subcommittee="Procurement and Military Nuclear Systems" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/9/1988--Introduced.
Department of Energy Nuclear Facilities Safety Act of 1988 - Establishes the Federal Facilities Nuclear Safety Board (the Board) as an independent body in the executive branch. Empowers the Board to: (1) review and evaluate health and safety standards at each Department of Energy (Department) nuclear facility; (2) investigate events or practices at each facility which may adversely affect public safety; (3) review a facility's design and construction as it pertains to public health and safety; and (4) recommend to the Secretary of Energy (the Secretary) the health and safety measures needed to ensure adequate protection of the public. Grants the Board access to Department nuclear facility design and operational data. Authorizes the Board to: (1) establish reporting requirements which shall be binding upon the Secretary; and (2) enter into agreements with the National Research Council of the National Academy of Sciences (and non-Federal experts) to evaluate differences between Nuclear Regulatory Commission regulations and Department orders governing nuclear facilities. Requires the Secretary to cooperate fully with the Board and provide it ready access to facilities, personnel, and information requested by the Board to implement its mandate. Sets forth guidelines under which the Board's recommendations and the Secretary's decision to accept or reject them shall be publicized in the Federal Register and reported in writing to the Congress. Requires the Secretary to prepare plans to implement recommendations. Sets forth a review procedure for Board recommendations regarding a severe or imminent threat to public health and safety. Requires implementation of any such recommendations which the Secretary accepts. Requires the Board and the Secretary to report annually to the Congress regarding their respective activities. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993.</summary>
</bill>
