<bill session="100" type="h" number="4134" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Standardization and Safety Reform Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to encourage the development and use of preapproved standardized designs; to promote safer and more effective nuclear regulation, siting, and licensing; to abolish the Nuclear Regulatory Commission and establish the Nuclear Safety Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407899"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1988-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1988-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400018" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402159" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400500" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="403184" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="403190" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405747" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406255" joined="1988-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406746" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406873" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407558" joined="1988-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408190" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1988-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1988-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410010" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1988-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-10">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant sites"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/1988--Introduced.
Nuclear Standardization and Safety Reform Act of 1988 - Title I: Establishment of Agency - Establishes the Nuclear Safety Agency as an independent regulatory agency to succeed the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Sets forth the Agency's officers and administration (including a Director and Deputy Director to be appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate). Abolishes the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Transfers Commission functions, assets, and staff to the Nuclear Safety Agency. Sets forth transition procedures. Title II: Standardization and Licensing - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to direct the Agency to establish procedures for the preapproval of a limited number of standardized facility designs for production or utilization facilities for a ten-year period. Authorizes the Agency to consider design approval requests for any major subsystem that represents discrete elements of a production or utilization facility. Requires the Agency to specify by regulation the criteria and requirements for any subsystem approval. States that a design approval shall be considered to be a license. Sets forth guidelines for the issuance of a design approval, including ten-year renewal terms. Authorizes the Director to issue a site approval permit for a ten-year period even if an application for a construction permit or operating license has not been filed. Outlines the site approval procedure and the procedures for facility construction permits and operating licenses. Title III: Conforming Amendments - Sets forth conforming amendments. Title IV: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
