<bill session="100" type="h" number="4143" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a reservation for the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400987"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-631.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 375.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Placed on Consent Calendar No: 19.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-20">
      <text>Called up by House on Call of Consent Calendar.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-06-20" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-29">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Inouye without amendment. With written report No. 100-479.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="898">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 898.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-08-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-08-25">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-08-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-09-09" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-425" type="public" datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-425.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3060"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3061"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2276"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2276"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Railroad land grants"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Railroads and state"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/20/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Provides that specified lands shall be held in trust for the Confederated Tribes of the Grand Ronde Community of Oregon and shall constitute their reservation. Describes such lands. Provides that the establishment of the Grand Ronde reservation shall not grant or restore any hunting, fishing, or trapping rights beyond those designated in a specified court decree. Directs the State of Oregon to exercise criminal and civil jurisdiction over the reservation. Provides that specified Indian lands in Oregon will be treated as revested Oregon and California railroad grant lands. Requires that all moneys received from those lands be deposited in the Treasury in the Oregon and California land-grant fund, except for receipts from timber removed from such lands before enactment of this Act. Declares that the memorandum of agreement between the Confederated Tribes and the Department of the Interior, relating to the disposition of timber resources on the reservation and the use of funds for economic development, shall apply over a 20-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act. Incorporates such agreement into this Act. Directs the Confederated Tribes to maintain a separate account dedicated to economic development and to deposit into such account 30 percent of the income from tribal timber resources received into the Tribes' Federal trust funds account.</summary>
</bill>
