<bill session="100" type="h" number="4157" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration for research and development, space flight, control and data communications, construction of facilities, and research and program management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409353"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Space Science and Applications.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Aviation and Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY02" subcommittee="Space Science and Applications" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY07" subcommittee="Transportation, Aviation and Materials" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Astronautics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cost accounting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Space"/>
    <term name="Space policy"/>
    <term name="Space programs"/>
    <term name="Space sciences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/15/1988--Introduced.
National Aeronautics and Space Administration Authorization Act, 1989 - Authorizes FY 1989 appropriations to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) for specified activities relating to: (1) research and development; (2) space flight, control, and data communications; (3) construction of facilities; and (4) research and program management, including scientific consultations. Permits appropriations for the first two categories to be used for certain items of a capital nature (other than land acquisition) required for the performance of research and development contracts, and for grants to nonprofit educational and research organizations to augment their research facilities. Prohibits the use of these funds for the construction of any major facility whose estimated cost exceeds $500,000, unless the Administrator of NASA notifies specified congressional leadership and committees. Permits upward variances of funds for facilities construction under circumstances outlined in this Act. Authorizes certain fund transfers and makes available specified funds for the construction and modification of laboratories and other installations. Requires the Administrator to notify specified congressional leadership and committees of the nature, cost, and need for such construction before expending the funds in question. Prohibits, until 30 days following congressional receipt of the Administrator's full explanation, the use of funds appropriated pursuant to this Act for any program that: (1) has been eliminated by the Congress; (2) is in excess of the amount actually authorized for the particular program (except for construction of facilities); or (3) has not been presented to either of the relevant congressional committees. Authorizes the Administrator, for a two-year period, to hire up to 15 individuals. Waives Federal retirement limitations or reduction requirements if retired civil servants are hired. Amends the National Aeronautics and Space Act of 1958 to permit the Administrator to prohibit the public disclosure of certain technical data requiring an export license. Declares it to be the sense of the Congress that it is in the national interest to consider geographical distribution, in allotting Federal research funds and that NASA should explore ways to do so.</summary>
</bill>
