<bill session="100" type="h" number="4165" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Assimilative Crimes Act Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, with respect to penalties, for driving under the influence of drugs and alcohol in the special maritime and territorial jurisdiction of the United States, and with respect to implied consent for certain test to determine the drug and alcohol content of blood.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300033"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Criminal Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU07" subcommittee="Criminal Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Marine crimes"/>
    <term name="Maritime law"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1988--Introduced.
Assimilative Crimes Act Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Federal criminal code to provide that the criminal penalty for operating a motor vehicle under the influence of a drug or alcohol in a special maritime or territorial jurisdiction of the United States shall be the punishment provided under the law of that State, territory, possession, or district. States that whoever operates a motor vehicle in such a jurisdiction consents to certain tests if arrested for driving under the influence of a drug or alcohol. States that such tests shall be administered upon the request of a police officer having reasonable grounds to believe that the person arrested was driving under the influence of drugs or alcohol. States that any person refusing to sumit to such tests, after having been advised of the consequences of such a refusal, shall be denied the privilege of operating a motor vehicle for one year.</summary>
</bill>
