<bill session="100" type="h" number="4169" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Electric Power Bankruptcy Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 11 of the United States Code to provide for participation by affected States and consumers of electric power in cases involving debtors who are engaged primarily in the business of selling electric power.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409443" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1988-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy courts"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/16/1988--Introduced.
Electric Power Bankruptcy Amendments of 1988 - Amends Federal bankruptcy provisions to require that, in a reorganization case involving a debtor who is engaged primarily in the business of selling electric power, the trustee shall assume any executory contract for the sale or purchase of electric power from a nonnuclear source. Provides, in such a case, for the appointment by the court (as soon as practicable after the order for relief) of a committee of ten petitioners who regularly purchase electric power from the debtor (five residential and five nonresidential users) to act as a creditors' committee. Allows a representative of the legislative body of a State in which the electric power is consumed by persons who regularly purchase electric power from the debtor to raise an appeal and be heard on any issue in the case. Limits the powers of the court to supersede, modify, or interfere with the operation of nonbankruptcy law applicable to the sale or purchase of electric power from a nonnuclear source by such a debtor.</summary>
</bill>
