<bill session="100" type="h" number="4217" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to construct, operate, test, and maintain the Lake Meredith Salinity control Project, New Mexico and Texas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401628"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400079" joined="1988-03-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII05" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Saline water conversion"/>
    <term name="Saline waters"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water quality"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/22/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to construct, operate, test, and maintain the Lake Meredith Salinity Control Project, New Mexico and Texas, to improve the quality of water to the Canadian River downstream of Ute Reservoir, New Mexico, and entering Lake Meredith, Texas. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a contract with the Canadian River Municipal Water Authority of Texas (Authority) for the design and construction management of project facilities by the Bureau of Reclamation and for the payment of construction costs by the Authority. Makes it the responsibility of the Authority to operate and maintain the facilities upon completion of construction and testing. Requires the Authority to advance all costs of construction of project facilities as the non-Federal contribution. Declares the Federal share to be all project costs for verification, design preparation, and construction management. Provides for transferring control of the project works to the Authority or to a bona fide entity agreeable to New Mexico and Texas upon completion of construction and testing, or upon termination of activities at the request of the Authority. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
