<bill session="100" type="h" number="4238" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">State Justice Institute Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the purposes of carrying out the activities of the State Justice Institute for fiscal years 1989, 1990, and 1991, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401417" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403446" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403888" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405114" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410076" joined="1988-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1988--Introduced.
State Justice Institute Authorization Act - Amends the State Justice Institute Act of 1984 to authorize appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 to carry out the activities of the State Justice Institute. States that officers and employees of the Institute shall be considered Federal employees for the purpose of certifying vouchers for the disbursement of funds by the Secretary of the Treasury. Allows Institute funds to be used to conduct research on alternative means for using judicial personnel in court decisionmaking activities. Provides that such funds may no longer be used to assist State and local courts in meeting requirements of Federal law applicable to recipients of Federal funds. States that grant recipients who file a timely application for refunding shall no longer receive automatic interim funding. Establishes certain restrictions on the disclosure of information by officers and employees of the Institute, and by recipients of Institute assistance.</summary>
</bill>
