<bill session="100" type="h" number="4262" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-31">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 17, United States Code, to implement the Berne Convention for the Protection of Literary and Artistic Works, as revised at Paris on July 24, 1971, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400076" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409650" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409968" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1988-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>For Previous Action See H.R.1623.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-28">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-06">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on The Judiciary. Report No: 100-609.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-06">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 360.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="116" datetime="1988-05-10" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 420 - 0 (Record Vote No: 116).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="672">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 672.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 1301 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-05" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-12" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-31" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-568" type="public" datetime="1988-10-31">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-568.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1623"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1301"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Architecture"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Copyright royalties"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="Phonorecords"/>
    <term name="Sound recording and reproducing"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended (Inserted Text of S. 1301 as passed Senate)) Berne Convention Implementation Act of 1988 - Amends the copyright law to implement the Berne Convention, the Convention for the Protection of Literary and Artistic Works, signed at Berne on September 9, 1886. Extends copyright protection to architectural works in conformance with such Convention. Extends comparable copyright protection to protectable works of nationals of Berne Union members. Revises provisions concerning the licensing of coin-operated phonorecord players (jukeboxes). Permits copyright owners and operators of jukeboxes to directly negotiate the terms and royalty rates for performing copyrighted works if the Copyright Royalty Tribunal certifies that, over a one year period after this Act's enactment, such process has resulted in authorizing the use of a not substantially smaller quantity of work. Suspends the ratemaking activities of the Tribunal while such conditions are being met. Provides that the scope of Federal preemption remains unaffected by U.S. adherence to the Berne Convention. Makes discretionary instead of mandatory the use of a notice of copyright on publicly distributed copies of protected works, including phonorecords of sound recordings (thus bringing U.S. law into conformance with the Berne Convention). States that such a notice is a bar to a defense of innocent infringement if the defendant had access to copies with such notice. Declares that the copyright notice requirements do not apply to publications incorporating U.S. Government works unless the notice of copyright on such works identifies those sections which are not U.S. Government works. Removes the copyright notice requirements with respect to all publicly distributed copies of works. Makes registration a prerequisite to a copyright infringement action except for actions regarding Berne Convention works whose country of origin is not the United States (thus exempting only non-domestic Berne Convention members from the formality of registration as a prerequisite to initiating a lawsuit for copyright infringement). Increases statutory damages. Authorizes the Tribunal to set jukebox interim rates, as specified. States that works in the public domain remain unprotected. Makes this Act effective the same day the Berne Convention enters into force with respect to the United States.</summary>
</bill>
