<bill session="100" type="h" number="4272" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-26">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enlarge the San Francisco Bay National Wildlife Refuge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403776"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401612" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406463" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-03-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1988-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.  Report No: 100-971.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 582.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-09-26" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>House Incorporated this Measure in H.R.5117 as an Amendment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5117"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2710"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2710"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Coast (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Estuaries"/>
    <term name="Estuarine area conservation"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Interstate commissions"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="North Carolina"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Seashores"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="Submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Virginia"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wetlands"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wildlife management"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Amends Federal law establishing the San Francisco Bay National Wildlife Refuge to adjust the boundaries of such refuge to include specified additional lands, marshes, tidal flats, salt ponds, submerged lands, and open waters in the San Francisco Bay area which the Secretary of the Interior determines are: (1) valuable fish and wildlife habitat; or (2) necessary to buffer the human impact on fish and wildlife within the refuge. Expands the total area of such refuge to include such additions. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of the Interior to acquire such additional areas. Amends the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation Establishment Act to authorize the Secretary to continue to provide facilities and necessary support services to the National Fish and Wildlife Foundation after March 26, 1989, on a space available, reimbursable cost basis. Amends the National Wildlife Refuge System Administration Act of 1966 to increase penalties for violations of such Act. Imposes specified fines and/or one year imprisonment for such violations. Authorizes appropriations for the Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation Act for FY 1989 through 1991. Makes such Act effective until the end of FY 1991. Extends the funding of striped bass studies under the Anadromous Fish Conservation Act through FY 1991. Authorizes the Atlantic States Marine Fisheries Commission to make specified determinations at any other time it deems necessary (in addition to its required annual determinations in December of each fiscal year). Requires the Director of the United States Fish and Wildlife Service, in consultation with the Assistant Administrator of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for Fisheries, to: (1) undertake a study of the striped bass fishery resources and habitats of the Albemarle Sound-Roanoke River basin area; (2) develop short-term and long-term recommendations for Federal and State government agencies for restoring and conserving such resources and habitats; and (3) submit such study results and recommendations to the Congress and the States of North Carolina and Virginia, within 36 months after enactment of this Act. Provides for study contents, participation by specified State and Federal agencies, and consultation with various entities. Authorizes appropriations for such study. Directs the Secretary of Commerce, upon request by the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Council, and when a State regulatory scheme or a Federal moratorium on Atlantic striped bass fishing within the coastal waters of such State is in effect, to promulgate regulations governing Atlantic striped bass fishing in any portion of the Exclusive Economic Zone adjacent to that State. Requires Federal regulations to be consistent with specified provisions of the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act and appropriate to: (1) ensure the effectiveness of such State regulation or Federal moratorium; and (2) achieve conservation and management goals for the Atlantic striped bass resource.</summary>
</bill>
