<bill session="100" type="h" number="4271" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Amended Military Construction Authorization Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain construction at military installations for fiscal year 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403364"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407196" joined="1988-03-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29">
      <text>For Further Action See H.R.4264.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4264"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Collective security agreements"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military construction operations"/>
    <term name="Military housing"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="National Guard"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Urban planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/1988--Introduced.
Amended Military Construction Authorization Act, 1989 - Title I: Army - Authorizes the Secretary of the Army to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire military family housing units, to carry out architectural and engineering services and construction design activities, and to improve existing military family housing units (waiving maximum amounts per unit in some locations) in specified amounts at specified installations. Authorizes appropriations to the Army for fiscal years beginning after FY 1988 for military construction projects, unspecified minor construction projects, architectural and engineering services and construction designs, and military family housing functions. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Extends the authorization for certain FY 1985, 1986, and 1987 military construction projects. Title II: Navy - Authorizes the Secretary of the Navy to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire military family housing units, carry out architectural and engineering services and construction design activities, and improve existing military family housing units (waiving maximum amounts per unit in some locations) in specified amounts at specified installations. Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years beginning after FY 1988 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Department of the Navy. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Title III: Air Force - Authorizes the Secretary of the Air Force to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire military family housing units, carry out architectural and engineering services and construction design activities and improve existing military family housing units (waiving maximum amounts per unit in some locations) in specified amounts at specified installations. Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years beginning after FY 1988 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions of the Department of the Air Force. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Extends the authorization for certain prior-year military construction projects. Title IV: Defense Agencies - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to acquire real property and carry out military construction projects in specified amounts at specified installations and locations. Authorizes the Secretary to construct or acquire three family housing units at classified locations for a specified amount and to improve existing military family housing units in a specified amount. Authorizes the Secretary to contribute funds to the Government of the Netherlands for the U.S. share of the cost of a certain international education project in Brunssum, Netherlands. Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act, 1987 to authorize the Secretary to carry out military construction projects not otherwise authorized by law for conforming storage facilities. Authorizes appropriations to the Department of Defense (DOD) for fiscal years beginning after FY 1988 for military construction, land acquisition, and military family housing functions. Limits the total cost of construction projects authorized by this title. Title V: North Atlantic Treaty Organization Infrastructure - Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to make contributions for the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) Infrastructure Program, and authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for fiscal years after FY 1988 for such contributions. Title VI: Guard and Reserve Forces Facilities - Authorizes appropriations for fiscal years after FY 1988 for acquisition, architectural and engineering services, and construction of facilities for the Guard and Reserve forces in specified amounts. Title VII: Expiration of Authorizations; Effective Dates - Terminates all authorizations contained in titles I through V of this Act on October 1, 1990, or the date of enactment of the Military Construction Authorization Act for fiscal year 1991, whichever is later, with specified exceptions. Title VIII: General Provisions - Increases from 20 to 32 years the permissible length of long-term facilities contracts authorized to be entered into by the Secretary of the military department concerned. (Such contracts provide for the provision of ancillary services on or near a military installation.) Amends the Military Construction Authorization Act, 1984 to allow military rental housing program agreements to include provisions which allow for free utilities, trash collection, and entomological services to be provided for occupants of rental housing on Government land to the same extent that these services are provided to occupants of Government-owned housing. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to make grants or provide other appropriate community planning assistance required by a publicly-announced planned major reduction in DOD spending affecting the community, or by the encroachment of surrounding civilian community on an installation, if the Secretary determines that such assistance is necessary. Requires a planned reduction to involve the loss of at least 1,000 or more full-time DOD and contractor employee positions in a community during a five-year peroid in order to qualify for such assistance. Authorizes the Secretary to provide community planning assistance in specified amounts for communities located near newly-established Light Infantry Division Posts and Navy Strategic Dispersal Program homeports. Terminates such authority on September 30, 1991.</summary>
</bill>
