<bill session="100" type="h" number="4318" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:09-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">General Accounting Office Personnel Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">General Accounting Office Personnel Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">General Accounting Office Personnel Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">General Accounting Office Personnel Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the administration of the personnel systems of the General Accounting Office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409650"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-07">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB, GAO, OPM.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-21">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.  Report No: 100-599 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-09">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-05-09" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Glenn without amendment. With written report No. 100-463.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-08" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="879">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 879.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-08-11" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-08-25">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-08-30">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-09-09" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-426" type="public" datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-426.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" name="House Government Operations"/>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPO03" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Blue collar workers"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/9/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) General Accounting Office Personnel Amendments Act of 1988 - Title I: Personnel Appeals Board - Amends Federal law to repeal the requirement that an individual have three years full-time or part-time experience in adjudicating or arbitrating personnel matters before appointment to the General Accounting Office Personnel Appeals Board. Requires the Comptroller General to consider candidates who are recommended for appointment to such Board by organizations composed primarily of individuals experienced in adjudicating or arbitrating personnel matters. (Currently, the Comptroller General must appoint a candidate recommended by such organizations.) Changes the term of office of Board members from three years to five years. Increases the rate of pay of the General Counsel of the Board. Removes the entitlement to travel expenses and per diem allowances of non-Government Board members. Allows judicial review of final Board decisions by the United States Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit. (Currently, such final decisions may be reviewed by the United States Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia Circuit or by the court of appeals of the United States for the circuit in which the petitioner resides.) Allows the payment of attorney fees if an officer, employee, or applicant for employment is the prevailing party in a proceeding where the decision is based on a finding of discrimination prohibited under the Civil Rights Act of 1964. Title II: Retirement and Annuities - Provides that a Comptroller General or Deputy Comptroller General may retire after becoming 70 years of age and completing ten years of service as Comptroller General or Deputy Comptroller General (as the case may be). (Current provisions require the Comptroller General or Deputy Comptroller General to retire on becoming 70 years of age.) Revises provisions regarding survivor annuities for service as a Comptroller General. Includes as a dependent child one who is between the age of 18 and 22 years and is pursuing a full-time course of study at a recognized educational institution. Decreases from two years to one year the length of time a surviving spouse must have been married to a Comptroller General to be eligible for an annuity. Includes as a limitation that such surviving spouse must not have remarried before age 55. Requires a reduction in the annuity of a Comptroller General if the Comptroller General elects to provide survivor benefits. Reduces the interest payable on amounts required to be deposited in the Treasury. Provides for the payment of a survivor annuity if a Comptroller General dies in office and has at least 18 months (currently, five years) of civilian service and had made deductions or deposits for the last 18 months (currently, five years) of civilian service. Revises the method of computing survivor annuities. Provides for making cost of living adjustments in the annuity of a Comptroller General in the same manner as those made for other civil service retirees. Title III: Miscellaneous Provisions - Includes the General Accounting Office under the statute governing the pay of prevailing rate Federal employees. Increases the number of positions in the General Accounting Office that may be at rates not more than the GS-18 basic pay rate of the General Schedule.</summary>
</bill>
