<bill session="100" type="h" number="4343" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arctic National Wildlife Refuge Energy Plan Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the preparation of an energy plan regarding the oil and gas reserves within the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406974"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401585" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-08">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, DOE, EPA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII05" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1988--Introduced.
Arctic National Wildlife Refuge Energy Plan Act - Requires the Secretary of the Interior to report to the Congress within three years (but not earlier than two years) an energy plan which: (1) includes a national energy policy objectives statement; (2) focuses upon petroleum demand over an estimated period of potential production from the Arctic Coastal Plain; and (3) describes a resource portfolio to meet such demand. Outlines the contents of such report. Requires the Secretary to evaluate potential alternatives to meet petroleum demand scenarios on a consistent basis. Requires the Secretary to prepare a study of present and future oil and gas development in the Alaskan Arctic regions, (excluding the Arctic National Wildlife Refuge). Outlines the study contents. Requires that the energy plan and study be accompanied by a certain report incorporating a legislative action recommendation concerning the future management of specified lands under the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act of 1980 (Coastal Plain lands). Prohibits oil or gas exploration or production within the Coastal Plain, including land exchanges or leasing activities leading to production or exploration, until authorized by an Act of Congress.</summary>
</bill>
