<bill session="100" type="h" number="4359" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Military Child Abuse Prevention Plan Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a comprehensive analysis of Department of Defense capabilities to detect, prevent, and treat abuse and neglect of children on military installations and to provide for recommendations for the improvement of such capabilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403696" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409325" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1988-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-18">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Military Personnel and Compensation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS02" subcommittee="Military Personnel and Compensation" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/1988--Introduced.
Military Child Abuse Prevention Plan Act of 1988 - Establishes a task force to analyze the quality and sufficiency of, and develop recommendations concerning, Department of Defense (DOD) personnel and agencies responsible for monitoring the welfare of children at military installations. Authorizes funds previously appropriated to DOD to be used for the task force in FY 1988 and authorizes appropriations for FY 1989. Directs the task force to develop recommendations to improve the capability of DOD to prevent, detect, and respond to child abuse and neglect of children of members of the armed forces or civilian DOD employees for whom child care services are provided on military installations, based on an analysis of the quality and sufficiency of DOD personnel and agencies at selected installations. Requires the task force to make additional recommendations concerning whether there should be: (1) better standardized policies and procedures applicable throughout DOD with respect to child abuse and neglect; (2) child abuse and neglect oversight committees on military installations; (3) minimum standards for education, training, and experience for military personnel responsible for the prevention, detection, and treatment of child abuse; (4) improved liaison with other Federal and community agencies; and (5) improved monitoring and evaluation throughout DOD. Directs that the analysis of the quality and sufficiency of DOD personnel and agencies be made at representative military installations, including installations at specified locations. Specifies information to be collected for such analysis, including: (1) a description of DOD military and civilian personnel who direct, coordinate, or oversee child welfare policy at the installation or who might be called upon to respond to allegations of child abuse, and their training; (2) an evaluation of the ability of such personnel to effectively detect and prevent, and respond to allegations of, abuse or neglect; (3) an evaluation of any relationship, agreement, or cooperation between such personnel and State or local officials responsible for investigation, prosecution, and follow-up with respect to reports of abuse or neglect; and (4) an evaluation of the quality of family counseling and support services available for abused or neglected children and their families. Directs that such analysis be carried out principally through interviews at each installation surveyed and that specified persons be interviewed. Requires the task force to report its recommendations to the Secretary of Defense, who shall report on implementation of such recommendations to the Congress. Terminates the task force 90 days after submission of its report.</summary>
</bill>
