<bill session="100" type="h" number="4354" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-18">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain National Forest System lands in the State of Oklahoma for inclusion in the National Wilderness Preservation System, create the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400540"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forest, Family Farms, and Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-24">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-792 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-03">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-03">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Agriculture. Report No: 100-792 (Part II).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 511.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-08-08" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 2571 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-09-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 2571 with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Considered by House Unfinished Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-18" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-499" type="public" datetime="1988-10-18">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-499.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAG06" subcommittee="Forests, Family Farms, and Energy" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2571"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Botanical gardens"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fishing"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Hunting"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="National recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Recreation and Recreational Facilities"/>
    <term name="Recreation areas"/>
    <term name="Trapping"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended, in lieu of S. 2571) Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area Act - Designates specified lands in the Ouachita National Forest, Oklahoma, as the Black Fork Mountain Wilderness and the Upper Kiamichi River Wilderness, and as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System. Declares that the RARE II (second roadless area review and evaluation) final environmental statement (dated January 1979) with respect to national forest system lands in Oklahoma shall not be subject to judicial review. Releases national forest system lands in Oklahoma which were reviewed in the RARE II program from further review by the Department of Agriculture. Releases lands in Oklahoma reviewed in the RARE II program and not designated as wilderness from management as wilderness areas. Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from conducting any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of national forest system lands in Oklahoma without express congressional authorization. Establishes the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation Area in the Ouachita National Forest. Sets forth provisions with respect to the management of such Area. Designates specified lands in the Ouachita National Forest as the Robert S. Kerr Memorial Arboretum, Nature Center and Botanical Area and as the Beech Creek Botanical Area. Designates certain lands in the Ouachita National Forest as the Indian Nations National Scenic and Wildlife Area and the Beech Creek National Scenic Area. Sets forth provisions with respect to the management of such areas. Provides that such designated wilderness, national recreation area, national scenic and wildlife area, national scenic area, and botanical areas shall be collectively known as the Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to submit to the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs and the Committee on Agriculture, and the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and the Committee on Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry a report on the timber management program on such lands in the Ouachita National Forest. Provides that such report shall also include a statement regarding the economic impact of such forest on the timber, tourism, and recreation industries. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory committee to provide information and recommendations with respect to such lands. Sets forth provisions concerning the Ouachita National Forest with respect to: (1) timber management; (2) management planning; (3) tourism and recreation; (4) fire, insects, and disease; (5) grazing rights; (6) fishing and wildlife; (7) permits for use of Winding Stair Mountain National Recreation and Wilderness Area facilities; and (8) land acquisition by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
