<bill session="100" type="h" number="4357" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Municipal Solid Waste Incinerator Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend subtitle D of the Solid Waste Disposal Act to regulate municipal solid waste incinerators and municipal solid waste incinerator ash.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406994"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400055" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402159" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402926" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410147" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411585" joined="1988-04-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Incineration"/>
    <term name="Landfills"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/11/1988--Introduced.
Municipal Solid Waste Incinerator Act of 1988 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to publish guidelines, within 18 months of this Act's enactment, identifying materials which should be removed from solid waste before its incineration in a municipal solid waste incinerator. Directs the Administrator to promulgate regulations, within two years of this Act's enactment, applicable to the operation and management of municipal solid waste incinerators, and to the disposal, or recycling and reuse of municipal solid waste incinerator ash. Requires that landfills into which such ashes are disposed provide for groundwater monitoring and: (1) place such ashes in a monofill having a leachate collection system and a single liner designed and operated to prevent the migration of any constituent into such liner; or (2) have two or more liners and a leachate collection system above and between such liners. Authorizes the regulations to waive such ash disposal requirements on the basis of site specific factors or in the case of existing facilities which have been demonstrated to provide human and environmental protection equivalent to that provided by such single or double liner landfills. Directs the Administrator to prescribe criteria and testing procedures for identifying the hazardous properties of municipal incinerator ash so that ash which does not exhibit such properties may be placed in sanitary landfills meeting current criteria. Requires that ash which is hazardous to human health or the environment be treated prior to recycling or reuse. Requires States to adopt and implement a permit program, within 18 months after the Administrator issues incinerator and ash management regulations, to ensure that municipal solid waste incinerators and persons who deal with such ash comply with the Administrator's regulations and this Act's requirements. Sets forth transitional provisions.</summary>
</bill>
