<bill session="100" type="h" number="4358" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Employees Liability Reform and Tort Compensation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, to provide for an exclusive remedy against the United States for suits based upon certain negligent or wrongful acts or omissions of United States employees committed within the scope of their employment, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408490" joined="1988-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1988-04-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-17">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.4612 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4612"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Constitutional law"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/1988--Introduced.
Federal Employees Liability Reform and Tort Compensation Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal Tort Claims Act to include the judicial and legislative branches of Government within the definition of the term "Federal agency." States that, for actions brought under such Act, the United States shall be entitled to all defenses otherwise available to an employee of the United States, including presidential, judicial, prosecutorial, and legislative immunity. Makes such Act the exclusive remedy for actions brought against the United States for injury or loss of property, personal injury, or death resulting from the negligent or wrongful act or omission of Government employee acting within the scope of their office or employment. States that this restriction shall not apply to cognizable actions against Government employees for money damages for a violation of the Constitution. Provides that, upon certification by the Attorney General that the employee was acting within the scope of the employee's office or employment at the time of the incident out of which the claim arose, any action commenced upon such claim in a U.S. district court shall be deemed an action against the United States under the provisions of such Act, and the United States shall be substituted as the party defendant. States that such certification shall conclusively establish scope of office or employment for the purpose of removing such an action to a U.S. district court.</summary>
</bill>
