<bill session="100" type="h" number="4388" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States-Mexico Joint Development Bank Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a United States-Mexico Joint Development Bank.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404634"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Development Institutions and Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA06" subcommittee="International Development Institutions and Finance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/1988--Introduced.
United States-Mexico Joint Development Bank Act - Authorizes the President to enter into an agreement with Mexico to establish a United States-Mexico Joint Development Bank (the Bank) to make economic development loans in Mexico and in the border region of the United States. Sets forth information that shall be included in the agreement, including the requirements that: (1) assistance provided by the Bank shall be directed at improving employment opportunities and enhancing the economic development of the geographic and economic sectors of Mexico which are the major sources of undocumented Mexican nationals who enter the United States; and (2) the United States and Mexico contribute equally to the Bank. Directs the President to appoint the U.S. Directors of the Bank. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury, upon the United States entering into an agreement with Mexico to establish the Bank, to subscribe to the capital stock of the Bank. Authorizes appropriations to pay for such subscription. Requires reports with respect to the operation of the Bank to be included in the first report of the National Advisory Council on International Monetary and Financial Problems transmitted after the United States accepts participation in the Bank. Prohibits any person or agency, on behalf of the United States, unless authorized by the Congress, from: (1) agreeing to an increase in the U.S. subscription to the Bank; (2) agreeing to an agreement which increases U.S. obligations or which would change the Bank's purpose or functions; or (3) providing financing to the Bank.</summary>
</bill>
