<bill session="100" type="h" number="4393" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Judicial Discipline and Impeachment Reform Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Commission on Judicial Impeachment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend provisions of title 28, United States Code, relating to judicial discipline, and to establish a commission to study the constitutional issues involved in the impeachment of an article III judge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400537" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1988-04-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Impeachments"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial tenure"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/14/1988--Introduced.
Judicial Discipline and Impeachment Reform Act of 1988 - Title I: Judicial Discipline - Amends the Federal judicial code to modify the procedures for disciplining Federal judges. Allows the Judicial Conference to transmit to the House of Representatives a determination that consideration of impeachment may be warranted where a judge or magistrate has been convicted of a felony and opportunity for appeal has been exhausted. Permits the reimbursement of attorneys' fees and expenses where a complaint against a Federal judge or magistrate has been dismissed. Title II: National Commission on Judicial Impeachment - National Commission on Judicial Impeachment Act - Establishes the National Commission on Judicial Impeachment to: (1) investigate and study the problems and issues involved in the appointment and tenure (including discipline and removal) of article III judges; (2) evaluate the advisability of proposing alternatives to current arrangements with respect to such problems and issues; and (3) prepare and submit to the Congress, the Chief Justice, and the President a report detailing the findings and conclusions of the Commission. Terminates the Commission 30 days after the submission of such report. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
