<bill session="100" type="h" number="4414" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Trauma Care and Emergency Services Quality Assurance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to assure appropriate provision and coordination of emergency medical services under Statewide trauma and emergency medical services plans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1988-05-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1988-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/19/1988--Introduced.
Medicare Trauma Care and Emergency Services Quality Assurance Act of 1988 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require each State to develop a statewide trauma and emergency medical services plan which: (1) provides for the designation of hospitals as level I, level II, or level III trauma centers; (2) establishes standards for the prehospital care and emergency transport of trauma patients; and (3) sets forth guidelines for the transfer of patients to trauma centers. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to States for the development and implementation of such plans. Covers 40 percent of State expenditures on such plans, but limits State allotments to five cents multiplied by the number of State residents. Requires the Secretary to conduct a study and report to the Congress by March 1, 1990, on the adequacy of Medicare payments for trauma discharges.</summary>
</bill>
