<bill session="100" type="h" number="4427" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-22">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Exclusion and Deportation Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Immigration Exclusion and Deportation Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act with respect to the grounds for exclusion and deportation of aliens.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400543" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403581" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1988-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406191" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406765" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407306" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409446" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400354" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1988-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411025" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1988-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-20">
      <text>For Previous Action See H.R.1119.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-12">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on The Judiciary. Report No: 100-882.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-12">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 521.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1119"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/12/1988--Reported to House amended.
(Reported to House from the Committee on the Judiciary with amendment, H. Rept. 100-882) Immigration Exclusion and Deportation Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to make only the following classes of aliens ineligible to receive visas for admission into the United States: (1) any alien with a communicable disease of public health significance; (2) any alien with a record of recent physical or mental disorder that poses a threat to property or safety; (3) any alien with a drug addiction; (4) any alien convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude, with specified exceptions; (5) any alien convicted of specified drug violations or involved in drug trafficking; (6) any alien who has engaged in prostitution, or procurement of prostitutes, within ten years of the date of application for U.S. entry; (7) any alien likely to be a security risk; (8) any alien who has engaged in terrorist activity or likely to engage in such activity (including, for purposes of such Act, an officer, representative, or spokesman of the Palestine Liberation Organization); (9) any alien whose entry would endanger the lives or property of U.S. citizens living abroad; (10) any alien whose entry would convey the impression of U.S. support for a government or group that the United States does not recognize or support, or whose entry would have a serious negative effect on U.S. diplomatic relations; (11) any alien who participated in Nazi persecutions; (12) any alien who is a trade union officer, official or employee of an organization which is an instrument of a totalitarian government, with exceptions for members of independent associations; (13) any alien who is likely to become a public charge, with admission on bond at the discretion of the Attorney General; (14) any alien seeking to enter the United States for the purpose of performing skilled or unskilled labor, with specified exceptions (teaching, postgraduate research, and science or arts), or in situations of insufficient U.S. workers; (15) any alien who is a graduate of a medical school not accredited by a body approved for such purpose by the Secretary of Education, with certain exceptions; (16) any excluded or deported alien who seeks readmission within one year of the event, unless such readmission is consented to by the Attorney General; (17) any alien seeking to enter the United States by fraud or the willful misrepresentation of a material fact; (18) any stowaway alien; (19) any alien who aids any other alien in illegal entry; (20) any immigrant not in possession of a valid immigrant visa and passport at the time of admission; (21) any nonimmigrant without a valid passport authorizing the alien to return to the country from which he or she came or without a valid nonimmigrant visa or border crossing card, (provides for a Guam visa waiver for up to 15-day pleasure or business entries); and (22) any alien ineligible for U.S. citizenship, including a person who left or remained outside the United States to avoid U.S. military service in time of war or national emergency. Repeals the ideological grounds for exclusion. Directs the Attorney General and the Secretary of State to jointly develop guidelines for the review of exclusion lists and other mechanisms used to screen alien visa applicants. Requires the Attorney General and the Secretary to report jointly to the appropriate committees regarding the development of such guidelines (within one year) and the results of the review of such alien lists (within two years). Makes deportable by the Attorney General only those aliens within one of the following classes: (1) any alien who at the time of entry was within one or more of the classes of aliens excludable by then existing law; (2) any alien entering the United States without inspection or at a time and place other than as designated by the Attorney General; (3) any alien admitted as a nonimmigrant who has failed to maintain such status; (4) any alien admitted as a temporary agricultural worker (H-2A visa) whose status has been terminated (with family hardship exceptions); (5) any alien who within five years of entry knowingly and for gain has aided another alien to illegally enter the United States; (6) any alien admitted as an additional special agricultural worker who fails to show the necessary number of seasonal work days; (7) any alien who gained U.S. entry through marriage fraud; (8) any alien convicted of a crime involving moral turpitude committed within five years from the date of entry and who is either sentenced or confined for a term of one year or longer; (9) any alien who at any time after entry is convicted of two or more crimes involving moral turpitude; (10) any alien who at any time after entry is convicted of a violation of certain drug laws; (11) any alien who is a drug abuser or addict; (12) any alien who at any time after entry is convicted under weapons-possession laws; (13) any alien who at any time is convicted on any of various specified loyalty laws (e.g. sabotage, treason and sedition, selective service, etc.); (14) any alien who fails to comply with alien registration laws or foreign agent registration laws; (15) any alien convicted of fraud or misuse of visas or other entry documents; (16) any alien engaging in activity which endangers the public safety or national security, including terrorist activity; (17) any alien who within five years after entry has become a public economic burden; (18) any alien who has engaged in terrorist activity; (19) any alien who participated in Nazi persecutions; (20) any alien whose presence could endanger the lives or property of U.S. citizens living abroad; or (21) any alien whose presence could convey the impression of U.S. support for a government or group that the United States does not recognize or support, or whose presence could have a serious negative effect on U.S. diplomatic relations.</summary>
</bill>
