<bill session="100" type="h" number="4449" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-08">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize expenditures for fiscal year 1989 for the Panama Canal Commission to operate and maintain the Panama Canal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1988-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD, State, Treasury, Panama Canal Comm.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-26">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From Panama Canal Comm.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From State.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-08">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Reported to House by House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.  Report No: 100-831.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 503.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSMM05" subcommittee="Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="Panama"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/1988--Introduced.
Panama Canal Commission Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989 - Authorizes expenditures for FY 1989 for the Panama Canal Commission (Commission) to operate and maintain the Panama Canal. Limits the amount of funds which may be used for official reception and representation expenses. Prohibits the use of funds to implement an increase in the rates of tolls for use of the Panama Canal during FY 1989. Authorizes the use of funds for the purchase of passenger motor vehicles for the use of Commission personnel without regard to certain price limitations. Specifies a maximum amount of funds which may be used for capital outlays. Requires the Commission to provide written advance notice to the Congress regarding: (1) any proposed change in rates of tolls for use of the Panama Canal that may be necessary after the end of FY 1989; (2) any payment estimated to be due Panama under provisions of the Panama Canal Treaty of 1977; and (3) the initiation of any capital acquisition or construction project exceeding a certain amount, which is not specified in the budget estimates submitted to the Congress for the fiscal year in which the project will occur. Authorizes the use of funds for pay increases for Commission employees which are not in excess of statutory increases granted for the same period in corresponding rates of compensation of other U.S. Government employees in comparable positions.</summary>
</bill>
