<bill session="100" type="h" number="4469" updated="2016-06-29T08:43:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Hoopa-Yurok Settlement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to partition certain reservation lands between the Hoopa Valley Tribe and Yurok Indians, to clarify the use of tribal timber proceeds and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401612"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402710" joined="1988-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1988-04-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.  Report No: 100-938.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-31">
      <text>For Further Action See S.2723.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5340"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Right-of-way"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal sites"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1988--Reported to House amended.
(Reported to House from the Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs with amendment, H. Rept. 100-938) Hoopa-Yurok Settlement Act - Provides for the partition of the joint Hoopa Valley and Yurok Reservation. Requires the Hoopa Valley Tribe to waive all claims against the United States before the partition shall become effective. Establishes the Hoopa Valley Reservation and the Yurok Reservation. Requires the unallotted trust lands and assets of each tribe to be held in trust by the United States for the benefit of the respective tribes. Places all national forest lands within the Yurok Reservation in trust for the use and benefit of the Yurok Tribe, subject to valid existing rights and subject to the adoption of a resolution of the Interim Council of the Yurok Tribe. Sets the boundary between the Hoopa Valley and Yurok Reservations. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to manage the unallotted trust land and assets of the Yurok Reservation until the tribe has organized. Requires, thereafter, that such land and assets be administered as tribal trust land and governed by the tribe. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire lands or interests in lands, including rights-of-way for access to trust lands in the Reservation. Establishes the Hoopa-Yurok Settlement Fund for distributions pursuant to this Act. Divides fund assets between the tribes based on settlement roll calculations. Authorizes appropriations to the Fund. Prescribes preparation and eligibility criteria for the Hoopa-Yurok settlement roll. Allows an election among the following settlement options: (1) Hoopa tribal membership option (based on the criteria of the court decision in the Short case); (2) Yurok tribal membership option; and (3) lump sum payment option. Extinguishes interest in tribal property of persons receiving payments. Provides for division of the remaining settlement funds. Ratifies the existing documents of the Hoopa Valley Tribe and confirms its status. Provides for recognition and organization of the Yurok Tribe. Establishes an Interim Council of the Yurok Tribe preceding election and installation of the tribal governing body. Allows the land assignment on the Hoopa Valley Reservation made to the Smokers family to continue to relatives of one-fourth or more Indian blood. Provides for a merger of the Rancherias with the Yurok Tribe if certain conditions are met. Adds representatives of the Yurok Tribe and the Karuk Tribe to the Klamath River Basin Fisheries Task Force. Specifies the term of office. Provides that the proceeds of the sale of timber from Indian trust lands, after deduction for administrative expenses, shall be used: (1) as determined by the governing bodies of the tribes concerned and approved by the Secretary; or (2) in the absence of such a governing body, as determined by the Secretary for the tribe concerned. Sets limitations on actions challenging the joint reservation partition under this Act. Requires the Secretary to submit to the Congress a report describing any claims decisions.</summary>
</bill>
