<bill session="100" type="h" number="4507" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to remove certain limitations on charitable contributions of certain items.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400365"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2160"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2160"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Art objects"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Charitable contributions"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Literature"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Poetry"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Valuation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide that the amount of a qualified artistic charitable contribution for income tax deduction purposes shall be the fair market value of the property contributed (determined at the time of the contribution). Defines "qualified artistic charitable contribution" as the contribution of any literary, music, artistic, or scholarly composition, letter or memorandum, or similar property, but only if: (1) such property was created by the personal efforts of the taxpayer making the contribution no less than one year prior to the contribution; (2) there is included with the tax return a written appraisal of the fair market value of the property; and (3) the use of such property by the donee is related to the purpose or function constituting the basis for the donee's tax exemption. Limits the amount of qualified artistic charitable contributions available to a taxpayer in any taxable year to the taxpayer's artistic adjusted gross income, as defined in this Act. Prohibits public officials from taking a deduction for the donation of their papers if the papers were generated as their work product while employed as officers or employees of the United States or of any State.</summary>
</bill>
