<bill session="100" type="h" number="4508" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Weapons Production Health and Safety Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Radiation Research Reorganization Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for independent health and safety regulation of Department of Energy nuclear facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409954"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-02">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-02">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-06">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOE.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Procurement and Military Nuclear Systems.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS07" subcommittee="Procurement and Military Nuclear Systems" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear facilities"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/2/1988--Introduced.
Nuclear Weapons Production Health and Safety Act of 1988 - Title I: Nuclear Weapons Production Health and Safety Board - Establishes as an independent agency in the executive branch the Nuclear Weapons Production Health and Safety Board (the Board) whose function is to establish environmental protection and public and occupational health and safety standards for Department of Energy nuclear facilities. Empowers the Board to investigate: (1) any event at a Department of Energy nuclear facility posing a threat to the environment or to the public health and safety; and (2) nuclear materials transportation to and from such facilities which may pose threats. Directs the Board periodically to review the design and operation of such nuclear facilities to determine ways to enhance environmental and public protection. Requires the Board to report to the Congress and the Secretary of Energy (the Secretary) after each review and investigation with recommendations for improved safety measures. Requires the Board to maintain an onsite investigatory and review staff at each facility. Authorizes the Board to issue subpoenas and administrative orders compelling compliance with its standards and with Federal and State standards. Requires the Board to submit a written notice to the Secretary to abate any facility activity which presents imminent and substantial danger to the environment and public health. Outlines the Board's enforcement parameters. Sets forth civil penalties for non-compliance with the Board's administrative orders. Requires the Board to establish procedures for petitions by citizens for Board action with respect to matters within its purview. Authorizes the Board to enter into agreements with the States providing for discontinuance of the Board's regulatory authority during the period in which the State assumes such authority. Requires the Board to: (1) periodically review such agreements to ensure compliance with this Act; and (2) make grants to an agreement State to cover the costs of program implementation. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993. Terminates the Board and the requirements of this title six years after the date of enactment of this Act. Requires the Board to report to the Congress five years after the date of enactment of this Act regarding the efficacy of its oversight and regulatory activities. Title II: Licenses for Department of Energy Nuclear Facilities - Prohibits any Department of Energy facility from commencing operations as of the date of enactment of this Act unless it has received a Nuclear Regulatory Commission license issued pursuant to environmental and public health safety standards compatible with this Act. Title III: EPA Authority - Amends the Clean Water Act to include within the definition of "pollutant" any byproduct, source, and special nuclear material. Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to exclude source, special nuclear, or byproduct materials from the definition of "solid waste" unless such materials are a part of any mixture or combination comprising a solid waste. Title IV: Radiation Research Reorganization Act of 1988 - Radiation Research Reorganization Act of 1988 - Transfers to the Secretary of Health and Human Services the authority of the Secretary of Energy to conduct epidemiological studies of the effects of radiation. Mandates that such authority be exercised through the Director of the Centers for Disease Control with respect to health effects of radiation in places of employment. Establishes an advisory panel to be appointed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services to advise such Secretary in implementing the epidemiological studies.</summary>
</bill>
