<bill session="100" type="h" number="4512" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act to provide for more effective enforcement of restrictions on foreign fishing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1988-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from State, Commerce, Treasury, DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From State.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Equipment and supplies"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act to mandate that certain permits for fishing by foreign vessels require that, while the vessel is in an area of the exclusive economic zone in which the vessel is not authorized to fish, all fishing gear on board is placed where it is not readily available for fishing. Sets forth civil penalties for violation. Establishes within the Treasury the Fishery Enforcement Fund, to be available to the Coast Guard, subject to appropriations, for enforcement of this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to deposit into the Fund all amounts received as a result of enforcement of this Act, including civil penalties and fines and proceeds of property forfeited. Directs the Secretary of State to enter into negotiations with each GIFA (governing international fishery agreement) nation to amend the GIFA with regard to: (1) specified Federal regulations relating to activities reports which foreign fishing vessels are required to file; and (2) the requirements imposed by this Act. Provides for increased fishing fees for a GIFA nation which has not agreed to amend its GIFA by a specified deadline. Declares that a certification by the Secretary of State that a GIFA nation has not agreed to amend its GIFA is deemed to be certification of that country for purposes of provisions of the Fishermen's Protective Act of 1967 relating to restrictions on importation of fishery or wildlife products.</summary>
</bill>
