<bill session="100" type="h" number="4520" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Shellfish Indicator Research Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program of financial assistance for research relating to pathogenic indicators of contamination of shellfish growing areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405258" joined="1988-05-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406863" joined="1988-05-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-16">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, Interior, National Science Foundation, HHS, EPA, NIH.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From National Science Foundation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Disease control"/>
    <term name="Diseases"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental health"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Epidemiology"/>
    <term name="Estuarine fisheries"/>
    <term name="Evaluation"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to fisheries"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sanitary engineering"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Shellfish fisheries"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/3/1988--Introduced.
Shellfish Indicator Research Act - Directs the Chief Scientist of the National Oceanographic and Atmospheric Administration to establish a shellfish indicator research program, including: (1) an environmental assessment of U.S. commercial shellfish growing areas, including the relationships between sewage contamination and human enteric pathogens; (2) an evaluation of such relationships to potential risks to public health; (3) a comparison of current microbiological and new technological methods; (4) design of epidemiological methodology regarding actual risks to human health; and (5) recommendations for improving the capabilities of Federal and State sanitation regulatory agencies to effectively manage and regulate shellfish resources. Requires the program to evaluate representative estuaries and make recommendations pertaining to shellfish management for specified shellfish growing regions. Directs the Chief Scientist to make grants to carry out the program according to a specified timetable. Sets forth the factors the Chief Scientist must consider in deciding whether to award assistance. Directs the Chief Scientist to consult with the Environmental Protection Agency, the Department of the Interior, the National Science Foundation, the National Institutes of Health, the Food and Drug Administration, and appropriate State agencies and industry representatives with respect to the identification of research objectives and in preparing reports to the Congress required by this Act. Directs the Chief Scientist to undertake a biennial review of the program. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1992.</summary>
</bill>
