<bill session="100" type="h" number="4563" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INTERPOL Authorities Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide authorization of appropriations to the Department of Justice for U.S. National Central Bureau (USNCB) of Interpol for hosting periodically the General Assembly of INTERPOL and to allow the Attorney General to solicit, receive and make gifts and bequests for official Interpol activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409344"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/1988--Introduced.
INTERPOL Authorities Act of 1988 - Authorizes the Attorney General to: (1) make payments from Department of Justice appropriations for the periodic hosting of the annual meeting of the General Assembly of INTERPOL and for the periodic sponsorship of INTERPOL meetings; (2) make gifts to individuals and organizations in connection with official INTERPOL activities (with specified conditions and limitations); and (3) solicit and accept gifts for the benefit and support of the United States National Central Bureau of INTERPOL. Directs the Attorney General to: (1) promulgate rules for soliciting, accepting, and giving gifts pursuant to this Act; and (2) submit annual reports to the Congress regarding all gifts accepted or given pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
