<bill session="100" type="h" number="4568" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Law Enforcement National Labor-Management Relations Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to guarantee the right of law enforcement officers to organize and bargain collectively.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402626"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409325" joined="1988-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor-Management Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED02" subcommittee="Labor-Management Relations" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO03" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government employee unions"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Labor union membership"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Municipal ordinances"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Unfair labor practices"/>
    <term name="Union security"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1988--Introduced.
Law Enforcement National Labor-Management Relations Act - Declares it to be the policy of the United States to recognize the rights of law enforcement officers employed by States, local governments, and territories and possessions of the United States to organize and bargain collectively. Establishes procedures for settlement of disputes between such employees and their employers. Sets forth the rights of such officers as employees, and the rights of their employee organizations. Obliges each such employee to pay a representation fee to the exclusive representative if it has been recognized for the employees in an appropriate collective bargaining unit. Sets forth procedures for such recognition and exclusive representation. Sets forth an impasse procedure. Provides for appointment of an arbitration panel. Sets forth provisions for: (1) hearing before arbitration panels; (2) records, transcripts, and decisions; (3) awards and enforcement; and (4) arbitration costs. Sets forth unfair labor practices which are unlawful for an employer or an employee organization or exclusive representative to commit. Sets forth the nature of the duty to bargain. Empowers the Commission to prevent any person from engaging in any unfair labor practice enumerated under this Act. Sets forth complaint procedures. Sets forth a no strike provision. Prohibits any law enforcement officer or exclusive representative from engaging in a strike or inducing, encouraging, or condoning any strike, work stoppage, slowdown, or withholding of services by law enforcement officers. Sets forth this Act's relation to other laws. Makes this Act, with a specified exception, the exclusive method for regulating the relationship between employers and their law enforcement officer employees in regard to all matters covered by the Act, preempting any provision of any Federal, State, or local law which is inconsistent with it. Allows any State, city, or territory or possession of the U.S. which establishes a system substantially equivalent to the one established by this Act to apply to the Secretary of Labor for an exemption from it. Provides for judicial review of the Secretary's determinations of such exemptions. Provides that, except as otherwise expressly provided in this Act, nothing in it shall be construed to annul, modify, or preclude the renewal or continuation of any lawful agreement entered into before enactment of this Act between an employer and an employee organization covering the terms and conditions of employment and related matters of mutual concern.</summary>
</bill>
