<bill session="100" type="h" number="4567" updated="2014-12-10T13:14:39-05:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making appropriations for energy and water development for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401417"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-22">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-14">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Hearings.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>First Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>Final Day of Subcommittee Mark-up.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Reported to House by House Committee on Appropriations.  Report No: 100-618.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 367.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Rules Granted a Rule Waiving All Points of Order Against Specified Provisions of the Bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H.Res.447 Reported to House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-17">
      <text>Rule Passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="133" datetime="1988-05-17" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 384 - 20 (Record Vote No: 133).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-07">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Water Development. Approved for full committee consideration with amendments favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-09">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with amendments. With written report No. 100-381.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="726">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 726.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Motion to proceed to consideration of measure agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 96-2. Record Vote No: 179.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by motion.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair sustained by Yea-Nay Vote. 68-29. Record Vote No: 180.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Considered by Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="181" datetime="1988-06-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 92-5. Record Vote No: 181.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Senate insists on its amendments, asks for a conference, appoints conferees Johnston; Stennis; Byrd; Hollings; Burdick; Sasser; DeConcini; Hatfield; McClure; Garn; Cochran; Domenici; Specter.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>House Disagreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>House Agreed to Request for Conference and Speaker Appointed Conferees: Bevill, Boggs, Chappell, Fazio, Watkins, Thomas (GA), Whitten, Myers (IN), Smith (NE), Pursell, Conte.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22">
      <text>Conference Report 100-724 Filed in House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>House Agreed to Conference Report by Yea-Nay Vote: 384 - 17 (Record Vote No: 217).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>House Receded and Concurred in Senate Amendments 003, 013, 014, 025, 030, 032.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>House Receded and Concurred With an Amendment in Senate Amendments 010, 012, 024, 029, 034, 036, 044.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate. By Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="By Voice Vote" type="pingpong" datetime="1988-07-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendment to Senate amendments Nos. 10, 12, 24, 29, 34, 36, and 44. By Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="226" datetime="1988-07-07" where="s" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 91-3. Record Vote No: 226.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-07-19" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-371" type="public" datetime="1988-07-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-371.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSAP10" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" name="House Appropriations"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSAP10" subcommittee="Energy and Water Development" name="Senate Appropriations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="100" type="hr" number="447"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Delaware River Basin Commission"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of the Army"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Electric power transmission"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Energy supplies"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest fires"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Hydroelectric power"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Nuclear Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="River basin commissions"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Susquehanna River Basin Commission"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Uranium enrichment"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h686"/>
    <amendment number="h687"/>
    <amendment number="h688"/>
    <amendment number="h689"/>
    <amendment number="s2353"/>
    <amendment number="s2354"/>
    <amendment number="s2355"/>
    <amendment number="s2356"/>
    <amendment number="s2357"/>
    <amendment number="s2358"/>
    <amendment number="s2359"/>
    <amendment number="s2360"/>
    <amendment number="s2361"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/30/1988--House receded and concurred with amendment.
(House receded and concurred in certain Senate amendments with an amendment) Energy and Water Development Appropriations Act, 1989 - Title I: Department of Defense - Civil - Makes appropriations for FY 1989 for authorized civil functions of the Department of the Army relating to rivers and harbors, flood control, and beach erosion (including projects which involve State and local governmental participation). Authorizes appropriations for national emergency preparedness programs. Title II: Department of the Interior - Makes appropriations for FY 1989 to the Department of the Interior Bureau of Reclamation for: (1) engineering and economic investigations of Federal reclamation and water conservation projects; (2) construction and rehabilitation projects; (3) soil and moisture conservation projects; (4) operation and maintenance of reclamation projects; (5) loans to irrigation districts for construction of distribution systems on authorized Federal reclamation projects; (6) general administrative expenses in certain Bureau of Reclamation offices; (7) the "Emergency Fund" as authorized by an Act of June 26, 1948; (8) acquisition of computer capacity for the Administrative Systems Modernization project; (9) replacement passenger motor vehicles; and (10) recovery of archaeological and paleontological remains in specified areas. Makes appropriations available to the Department of the Interior for: (1) damaged facilities or equipment belonging to the Department of the Interior; (2) emergency prevention of forest or range fires; and (3) general administrative expenses. Cites conditions for expenditure of funds for administrative expenses for the Central Utah Project. Title III: Department of Energy - Makes appropriations to the Department of Energy for FY 1988 for: (1) specified energy supply, research, and development activities; (2) uranium supply and enrichment activities; (3) general science and research activities; (4) nuclear waste disposal (including funds for the State of Nevada to conduct its oversight responsibilities under the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982); (5) atomic energy defense activities; (6) departmental administrative expenses; (7) water and electrical power projects of the Alaska Power Administration; (8) official reception and representation costs of the Bonneville Power Administration (authorizes such Administration, without fiscal year limitation, to incur obligations for authorized purposes in excess of its borrowing authority and cash in the Bonneville Power Administration Fund); (9) operational and maintenance expenses related to electric power transmission for the Southeastern Power Administration and the Southwestern Power Administration; (10) operational and maintenance expenses of the Western Area Power Administration; (11) salaries and expenses of the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission; (12) geothermal energy research and development; and (13) Department of Energy general passenger vehicles and security guard expenses. Directs the Department of Energy, during FY 1989, to give priority when approving plans submitted by States whose unemployment exceeds ten percent to those plans which are consistent with the Agreement approved July 7, 1986, in Re: Department of Energy Stripper Well Exemption Litigation M.D.L. 378 (thus ensuring that restitution for petroleum pricing violations will be distributed by such States for low-income weatherization and energy assistance and conservation programs pursuant to statutory mandate and court orders). Deems approved any such plan submitted in FY 1989 if the Department fails to act on it within 45 calendar days after submission and if the Governor (or designated State official) certifies in writing that the use of funds in such plans is consistent with the applicable terms of such Agreement. Declares that it is the intent of Congress that the purpose of this provision is to help such States gain prompt approval of such plans for the purposes proposed by them so long as the plans are consistent with the terms and conditions of the agreement. Title IV: Independent Agencies - Makes appropriations for: (1) programs authorized by the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965; (2) salaries and expenses of the Delaware River Basin Commission; (3) expenses of the Interstate Commission on the Potomac River Basin; (4) Nuclear Regulatory Commission expenses; (5) expenses of the Susquehanna River Basin Commission; and (6) expenses of the Tennessee Valley Authority. Title V: General Provisions - Sets forth guidelines for the expenditure of appropriations under this Act. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act to compensate parties intervening in regulatory or adjudicatory proceedings funded in this Act. Prohibits appropriations for the Power Marketing Administration or the Tennessee Valley Authority (including the expenditure of funds from the Bonneville Power Administration Fund and the Tennessee Valley Authority Fund) from being used for procuring extra high voltage (EHV) power equipment unless such agencies award contracts for equipment manufactured in the United States when they determine that there are one or more manufacturers of domestic end products offering a product that meets the technical requirements at a price not exceeding 130 percent of the bid or offering price of the most competitive foreign bidder. Declares that for purposes of the Buy American Act, any temporary structure to be constructed by the Army Corps of Civil Engineers shall be treated in the same manner as a permanent dam constructed by the Secretary of the Army. Provides that sums for FY 1989 pay raises for programs funded by this Act shall be absorbed within levels appropriated in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
