<bill session="100" type="h" number="4565" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Santa Rita Public Lands Exchange Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the transfer of certain lands in the State of Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411025"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-16">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-17">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>See S.2840.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2840"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/1988--Introduced.
Santa Rita Public Lands Exchange Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior, acting through the Bureau of Land Management, to transfer to, or exchange with, the State of Arizona all of the lands in the Santa Rita Experiment Station lying outside of the National Park System. Requires the Secretary to use such lands to: (1) satisfy the remaining Federal debt to Arizona for relinquishments of land for the Central Arizona Project; and (2) acquire Catalina State Park and other specified lands in accordance with the Federal Land Policy and Management Act of 1976. Provides that those lands in the Catalina State Park and Madera-Elephant Head Trail area that are acquired in accordance with this Act shall be included in the National Forest System, and that such Park shall be managed cooperatively by Arizona and Federal authorities. Provides that all lands acquired by the Government under this Act shall be exempt from any further planning requirements of the 1976 National Forest Management Act until the 1986 Coronado Forest Plan is revised, at which time future management direction shall be determined as part of planning for the entire National Forest. Revokes executive and public land orders which withdrew the Santa Rita Experimental Range for a Forest and Range Experiment Station. Withdraws from entry under the public land laws certain lands lying within the Coronado National Forest for use as a Forest and Range Experiment Station administrative headquarters site. Revokes a certain public land order which withdrew lands for forest administrative sites. Places specified Federal lands into the National Wildlife Refuge System as part of the Cabeza Prieta National Wildlife Refuge. Revokes certain orders which withdrew lands from the Colorado River Storage Project, for the Havasu National Wildlife Refuge, for the Imperial National Wildlife Refuge, and in aid of the Salt River Project. Adjusts a boundary of the Coronado National Forest. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
