<bill session="100" type="h" number="4570" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill concerning human rights violations in Tibet by the People's Republic of China.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409400"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="406765" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400239" joined="1988-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407351" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1988-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Development Institutions and Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA06" subcommittee="International Development Institutions and Finance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA02" subcommittee="International Operations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asian and Pacific Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest clearcutting"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tibet"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1988--Introduced.
Directs the President to encourage the United Nations Commission on Human Rights to send a special representative to Tibet to investigate the human rights situation. Requires the Congress to hold hearings on human rights violations indicated by such representative's findings. Requires the President: (1) to monitor continuously the human rights policies and practices in Tibet of the Government of China; and (2) within 60 days after enactment of this Act and one year thereafter, to submit a report to the Congress addressing the human rights situation in Tibet. Requires certain sanctions against China unless the President makes and publishes a determination that China: (1) has improved its treatment of human rights in Tibet; and (2) is allowing congressional delegations, human rights organizations, and the foreign press unrestricted access to Tibet to investigate the human rights situation. Specifies such sanctions as: (1) the suspension of the preferential treatment for Chinese products under the Generalized System of Preferences regardless of whether China obtains entry to the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade; (2) U.S. disapproval of multilateral financial assistance to China; and (3) the suspension of nondiscriminatory treatment (most favored nation status) for Chinese products. Specifies procedures for the Congress to disapprove of any presidential determination related to Chinese human rights practices in Tibet. Requires the Voice of America to broadcast to Tibet in the Tibetan language. Earmarks a specified amount of funds appropriated to the Agency for International Development for development assistance for FY 1988 and 1989 to be made available to the Tibetan community in exile for the purpose of preserving Tibetan culture. Earmarks a specified amount of funds appropriated to the Department of State for migration and refugee assistance for FY 1988 and 1989 to be made available exclusively for the assistance of displaced Tibetans. Directs the Secretary of State to request the United Nations Environment Programme to carry out an environmental assessment of deforestation and destruction of wildlife habitat in Tibet. Directs the President to establish the Tibet Commission for the purpose of ascertaining information about the environmental and natural resource conditions in Tibet. Requires the Commission to report its findings to the Congress within one year after enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
