<bill session="100" type="h" number="4580" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to exempt freelance authors, photographers, and artists from the capitalization rules added by the Tax Reform Act of 1986, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.4333.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4333"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Art"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Music"/>
    <term name="Photographers"/>
    <term name="Poetry"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide that the income tax rules requiring cost capitalization shall not apply in connection with the qualified artistic work expenses of freelance writers, artists, and photographers. Excludes from qualified expenses those related to printing, photographic plates, motion picture films, video tapes, and similar items. Applies the same exemption with respect to qualified indirect costs of film producers, not including any direct costs of a motion picture film or video tape. Permits these same categories of individuals to use income averaging if their gross income is at least 50 percent attributable to their production of creative property. Disallows this benefit to nonresident aliens and to individuals who receive more than half of their support from others.</summary>
</bill>
