<bill session="100" type="h" number="4593" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage the coverage of individuals by private long-term health care insurance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300049"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="401874" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400085" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1988-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to require that, for the purpose of determining the income tax liability of life insurance companies, qualified long-term care insurance be treated as accident or health insurance. Applies this provision to policies covering at least 12 consecutive months of necessary diagnostic, preventive, therapeutic, rehabilitative, or personal care services that are provided in a setting other than an acute care unit of a hospital. Describes the tax reserve method to be used to compute reserves in connection with qualified long-term health care insurance contracts. Treats qualified long-term care insurance as accident or health insurance and its benefits as benefits for personal injuries or sickness for purposes of determining appropriate tax exclusions for employer contributions or employee benefits. Allows an income tax deduction of long-term health care expenditures. States that benefits provided under certain employer-funded long-term health care insurance shall not be treated as deferred compensation plans for purposes of the tax deduction available for employer contributions to benefit plans.</summary>
</bill>
