<bill session="100" type="h" number="4648" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Education Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program to assist students in financial need to enter careers in nursing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300001" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="401585" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403709" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400155" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404856" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400600" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="409344" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410231" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1988-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1988--Introduced.
Nursing Education Partnership Act - Amends title VIII (Nurse Education) of the Public Health Service Act to create a new subpart on nursing scholarships. Defines "eligible individual" in terms of academic performance and enrollment. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants and loans to eligible individuals for certain associate degree or bachelor degree nursing education programs. Prohibits individuals from receiving any other form of Federal student financial assistance under any Federal law while receiving assistance under this subpart. Provides for application and repayment. Directs the Secretary to allocate funds available for grants and loans under the title among institutions in order to provide funds for applications meeting the requirements of this Act. Requires the awards to be: (1) equal to the cost of attendance for those applicants demonstrating the greatest financial need, determined on the basis of expected family contributions; and (2) made in the order of that need. Requires the award to be composed of 25 percent grant and 75 percent loan. Sets forth criteria a higher education institution must meet in order to participate in this program, including establishing and operating a program which lets high school counselors, teachers, and students learn about nursing career opportunities and which targets low income students. Allows entities desiring to employ students who have obtained degrees with assistance under this part to enter into a sponsorship agreement with the Secretary, including: (1) an agreement that the health care provider will repay two-thirds of the loan; and (2) assurances that the provider has established a program to recruit junior or senior high school students to enter nursing careers. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 and each of the succeeding fiscal years.</summary>
</bill>
