<bill session="100" type="h" number="4656" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kenai Native Equity Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for settlement of the land rights of the Kenai Natives Association, Inc., under section 14(h)(3) of the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act, by providing for and authorizing grants and exchanges of lands and interests between such corporation and the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaskan natives"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Cemeteries and funerals"/>
    <term name="Easements"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1988--Introduced.
Kenai Native Equity Act - Provides for the exchange of lands in Alaska between the Kenai Natives Association, Inc., and the United States in settlement of the land rights of the corporation under the Alaska Native Claims Settlement Act. Grants the corporation certain mineral rights on lands conveyed to the corporation. Includes the lands conveyed to the United States by the corporation in the Kenai National Wildlife Refuge. Removes lands conveyed to the corporation from such refuge. Designates the old Kenai native village site and cemetery as a national historical site. Grants the natives of Kenai, their families, and descendants a perpetual right and easement of access to visit such site.</summary>
</bill>
