<bill session="100" type="h" number="4686" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-11-03">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 relating to aviation research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406790"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1988-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407399" joined="1988-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Aviation and Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-08">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.  Report No: 100-894.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-08">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 531.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-09-20" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="989">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 989.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S. 2746 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate in lieu of S. 2746 with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-27">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-27">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-11-03" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-591" type="public" datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-591.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSSY07" subcommittee="Transportation, Aviation and Materials" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2746"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Automation"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Aviation medicine"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Technology and social problems"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended, in lieu of S. 2745) Aviation Safety Research Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to initiate aviation maintenance and safety research on: (1) fire and smoke resistance technologies; (2) specified aspects of aircraft maintenance and structural technologies; (3) the relationship between human factors and aviation accidents; and (4) air traffic control (including dynamic simulation models). Requires the Administrator to submit a national aviation research plan to the Congress. Cites plan contents. Requires the Administrator to report annually to certain congressional committees concerning the previous year's research accomplishments. Establishes within the FAA the Civil Aeromedical Institute to: (1) conduct specified aspects of civil aeromedical research; (2) advise on human factor aspects of proposed air safety rules, aviation personnel training programs, and joint aviation projects; and (3) provide medical consultation services regarding medical certification of airmen. Establishes a research advisory committee within the FAA to advise the Administrator regarding the aviation research program. Amends the Airport and Airway Improvement Act of 1982 to authorize appropriations for FY 1989 through 1990 for aviation projects. Directs the Administrator to research the effects of automation on the performance of the next generation of air traffic controllers and the air traffic control system, and to report to the Congress regarding such research. Authorizes the Administrator to enter into an agreement with the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration (NASA) regarding the use of NASA facilities to study the human factor aspects of a highly automated environment upon air traffic controllers. Prescribes the contents of such research. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Administrator to: (1) issue an advance notice of proposed rulemaking to determine the feasibility of installing (in all air carrier aircraft) rupture resistant crashworthy fuselage fuel tanks and fuel lines which disconnect and seal in the event of an accident; and (2) undertake research to develop technologies to prevent rapid fuel dispersal and combustibility after an air crash.</summary>
</bill>
