<bill session="100" type="h" number="4693" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Air Traffic Control Service Improvement Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a federally chartered corporation for the operation of the air traffic control system, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400018"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/1988--Introduced.
Air Traffic Control Service Improvement Act of 1988 - Title I: Air Traffic Control Corporation - Establishes the Airways Corporation as a nonprofit corporation to operate the U.S. air traffic control system. Declares that such Corporation is not a Federal agency or establishment. Directs the President to appoint five incorporators to serve as the initial board of directors. Authorizes the Corporation to issue capital stock. Authorizes the Corporation to own and operate an air traffic control system. Outlines the Corporation's powers, including the establishment of nondiscriminatory fees for the provision of air traffic control services. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to issue regulations for the review and appeal of such fees. Directs the Corporation to notify the Secretary of State whenever it enters into negotiations with a foreign entity with respect to air traffic control matters. Confers jurisdiction upon the Federal district courts for violations of this Act. Requires the Corporation to submit annually a detailed operations report to the President and to the Congress. Directs the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to submit annual evaluations to the Congress regarding the Corporation's operations and capital structure. Title II: Miscellaneous - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to transfer to the Corporation all Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) facilities and equipment which are part of the air traffic control system. Requires the Corporation to pay a certain amount into the Treasury General Fund and to relinquish all rights to amounts in the Airport and Airway Trust Fund. Authorizes an airport to charge air carriers and air transportation passengers user fees after the transfer of FAA facilities to the Corporation. Prohibits the denial of access to a public-use airport if the aircraft operator is in compliance with all aviation safety laws and offers to pay all fees. Declares the Corporation immune from all tort liability which is not based on fault.</summary>
</bill>
