<bill session="100" type="h" number="4705" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to modify the boundary of the Uinta National Forest, Utah, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1988-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/1988--Introduced.
Modifies the exterior boundary of the Uinta National Forest, Utah. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to settle the specific rights, interests, and privileges of the Strawberry Water User's Association in Strawberry Project lands within the extended boundary of such Forest, pursuant to the Strawberry Valley Agreement dated February 2, 1988. Provides for transitional funding under the Memorandum of Understanding between the Bureau of Reclamation and the U.S. Forest Service dated February 2, 1982, until this Act takes effect. Requires the Congress to provide funding to the Forest Service for rehabilitation of the Strawberry Project lands. Makes the planning and execution of the rehabilitation plan the responsibility of the Forest Service. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to exchange or sell specified National Forest System lands in order to acquire administrative sites and offices together with improvements at certain Utah locations. Directs that a special account be set up for moneys collected from such sale and authorizes expenditure of such moneys. Requires that any lands exchanged be of equal value (or, if unequal, that they be equalized by the payment of money to the grantor or the Secretary as long as the payment does not exceed 25 percent of the total value of the land transferred out of Federal ownership). Directs the Secretary to make every reasonable effort to keep any such payment to the minimum amount necessary to equalize the values involved.</summary>
</bill>
