<bill session="100" type="h" number="4701" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to prohibit certain practices involving commercial uses of automatic telephone dialing systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Unfair or deceptive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Communications Act of 1934 with respect to automatic telephone dialing systems (telephone terminal equipment with the capacity to store or produce numbers, dial them, and deliver a prerecorded message without manual assistance). Makes it unlawful for any person in interstate or foreign communications to: (1) use such a system to call anyone on record with a common carrier as objecting to the receipt of such message; or (2) use any automatic telephone dialing system not in compliance with prescribed technical standards that, among other things, provide for release of the receiving party's line within five seconds after that party hangs up. Directs common carriers to maintain a list of persons who notify them of their objection to receiving messages from automatic dialing systems.</summary>
</bill>
