<bill session="100" type="h" number="4738" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Cultural Survival Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect and promote cultural survival throughout the world.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400536"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="401585" joined="1988-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400538" joined="1988-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1988-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1988-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1988-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409400" joined="1988-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-09-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Tribes and tribal system"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1988--Introduced.
International Cultural Survival Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of State and the Administrator of the Agency for International Development (AID) to ensure that: (1) U.S. foreign policy and foreign assistance promote the rights of indigenous and tribal people throughout the world; and (2) U.S. foreign assistance is not provided for any project or program detrimental to indigenous or tribal peoples' rights or livelihood. Requires the Administrator, in consultation with the Secretary, to prepare and submit to the Congress a baseline report on indigenous and tribal peoples in developing countries, including a discussion of the effects of U.S. bilateral and multilateral assistance. Requires the Administrator to consult with U.S.-based nongovernmental organizations (NGOs) with experience in monitoring and reporting on indigenous and tribal peoples, and with other interested persons, throughout the preparation of such report. Requires AID (in consultation with the Department of State) to use such organizations to monitor and analyze the situtation of indigenous and tribal peoples in developing countries on a regular basis. Requires the Administrator to prepare and submit to the Congress annual reports concerning the monitoring of indigenous and tribal peoples and updating of the required baseline report. Requires that a description of proposed activities to address the problems facing indigenous and tribal peoples be included in such report.</summary>
</bill>
