<bill session="100" type="h" number="4740" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Smoking Cost Recovery and Education Tax Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to increase the excise tax on cigarettes by 25 cents per pack and to provide that a portion of the revenues from such increase be used for programs to discourage cigarette smoking particularly by youth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400882"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1988-06-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-03">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Smoking and youth"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
    <term name="Tobacco tax"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1988--Introduced.
Smoking Cost Recovery and Education Tax Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to increase the excise tax on cigarettes from: (1) $8 to $20.50 per thousand for small cigarettes; and (2) $16.80 to $43.05 per thousand for large cigarettes. Establishes in the Treasury the Smoking Cost Recovery and Education Trust Fund, to be available to finance educational programs (including paid advertising) concerning the hazards of cigarette smoking, with emphasis on discouraging smoking by youth. Appropriates to the Fund ten percent of the tobacco tax revenue generated by this Act's rate increase. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to conduct an ongoing study and to report biennially to specified congressional committees on: (1) the effects of smoking on health care costs; and (2) the incidence of cigarette smoking by youth, including the relationship between cigarette tax rates and youth smoking.</summary>
</bill>
