<bill session="100" type="h" number="4752" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Education and Incentives Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the programs of nurse education established in title VIII of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-06-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="401923" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1988-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409237" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410589" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="410641" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400397" joined="1988-06-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1988--Introduced.
Nursing Education and Incentives Act of 1988 - Title I: Special Projects - Amends title VIII (Nurse Education) of the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 for special project grants and contracts under specified provisions, setting forth certain priorities. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 for not less than eight innovative demonstration projects each fiscal year to upgrade nursing skills, with projects distributed geographically proportionate to the need. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to and enter into contracts with schools of nursing for projects relating to geriatrics. Requires peer review of applications. Prohibits approval or disapproval of an application unless the Secretary has received peer review recommendations and has consulted with the National Advisory Council on Nurse Training. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. Title II: Assistance to Nursing Students - Directs the Secretary to make grants to schools of nursing for traineeships for students in the final academic year of nursing master's degree programs, giving priority to programs involving nurse practitioners, clinical specialists, nurse midwives, and specialties requiring advanced education. Authorizes appropriations for these and other nursing traineeships for FY 1989 through 1991. Includes, as qualifying for loan repayment under specified provisions, nursing service in an Indian Health Service health center, a Native Hawaiian health center, certain hospitals, a migrant health center, a community health center, a nursing facility, or other health facilities as the Secretary determines. Authorizes appropriations for loan repayments for FY 1989 through 1991. Title III: General Provisions of Title VIII - Amends title VIII (Nurse Education) of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary to provide for evaluations of projects carried out under title VIII and for the dissemination of information developed as a result of the projects. Sets forth reporting requirements. Title IV: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
