<bill session="100" type="h" number="4759" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of the Calumet National Historical Park in the State of Michigan and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403266"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402325" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404220" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405377" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405409" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1988-06-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408957" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409651" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410926" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="411119" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-07-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/8/1988--Introduced.
Title I: Establishment of Park and Preservation District - Establishes the Calumet National Historical Park, including the Quincy Mining National Historic Landmark, Michigan, and the Calumet and Hecla Mining National Historic Landmark, Michigan, as a unit of the National Park System. Establishes the Calumet Historic Preservation District in the village of Calumet, Michigan. Provides for the cooperation of Federal agencies whose activities affect the park or preservation district. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Role of the Secretary - Requires the Secretary of the Interior, not later than three years after funds are made available to carry out this Act, to establish and submit to the Congress a management plan for the park. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire historic properties within the park. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with any owner of property with national historic or cultural significance within the park or preservation district to provide for interpretive exhibits or programs. Sets forth provisions relating to general administrative functions of the Secretary. Title III: Role of the Commission - Establishes the Calumet Historic Preservation Commission within the Department of the Interior to administer the preservation district and provide certain services within the park. Requires the Commission, within 18 months after it conducts its first meeting, to submit to the Secretary a park preservation plan which meets specified requirements. Prohibits the Secretary from making funds available to the Commission until such plan has been approved and submitted to the Congress. Sets forth the powers of the Commission.</summary>
</bill>
