<bill session="100" type="h" number="4786" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Insular Areas Drug Abuse Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the U.S. Insular Areas Drug Abuse Act of 1986, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403314"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401526" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1988-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Insular and International Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>See H.R.5210.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII07" subcommittee="Insular and International Affairs" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice personnel"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Micronesia"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Palau Islands"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1988--Introduced.
Insular Areas Drug Abuse Amendments of 1988 - Amends the United States Insular Areas Drug Abuse Act of 1986 to add the Secretary of Education as a principal in administering such Act's enforcement and administration provisions. Applies such Act to substance abuse generally rather than limiting it solely to drug abuse. Replaces current authorizations with an authorization for FY 1989 and subsequent fiscal years for grants to the Governments of American Samoa, Guam, the Northern Mariana Islands, Puerto Rico (amounts to remain available until expended), and Palau, to be spent in accordance with an approved plan. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to provide the Government of American Samoa with a vessel for narcotics enforcement and other law enforcement activities. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes appropriations for a grant to the Government of Guam to be spent for drug abuse law enforcement equipment in accordance with an approved plan. Directs the Administrator of the Drug Enforcement Administration to station not fewer than four agents: (1) to an office in Guam who shall be assigned to the Micronesian region; and (2) in the Virgin Islands who shall be assigned to the eastern Caribbean region. Authorizes FY 1990 and subsequent fiscal year appropriations, to remain available until expended, to the Government of the Virgin Islands to be spent in accordance with an approved plan. Requires the Attorney General and the Secretaries of Health and Human Services and of Education to provide appropriate law enforcement training, technical assistance, and equipment upon the request of the government of any insular area covered under such Act. Directs the Attorney General to assign at least two assistant U.S. attorneys to serve in the office of the U.S. Attorney for the Virgin Islands to assist in the prosecution of narcotics law violations. Authorizes appropriations, effective FY 1989, for a grant to the Virgin Islands Government to be used for a substance abuse facility in accordance with an approved plan. Brings Palau within the jurisdiction of such Act. Authorizes the major Federal law enforcement entities, including the Drug Enforcement Administration and the Customs Service, upon the request of the Palau Government, to cooperate with Palau's law enforcement agencies in investigating U.S. criminal law violations there. Sets October 1 as the transmission date for the President's annual reports to specified congressional committees on the illegal transit of controlled substances from insular areas into the United States and from other nations into the insular areas. Suspends the expenditure of funds for both the Office of Territorial and International Affairs of the Department of the Interior and the Office of Freely Associated State Affairs for the relevant fiscal year if the reports are not timely.</summary>
</bill>
