<bill session="100" type="h" number="4788" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Competitiveness Policy Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to declare a national competitiveness policy, to establish the Council on Competitiveness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400104"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400567" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401203" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401628" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300014" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="403184" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300033" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403769" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400176" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="405448" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406995" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407215" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400307" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="409165" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409654" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410010" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400504" joined="1988-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="410574" joined="1988-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA05" subcommittee="Economic Stabilization" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Regulatory impact statements"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1988--Introduced.
National Competitiveness Policy Act of 1988 - Title I: National Competitiveness Policy - Subtitle A: Declaration of Policy - Sets forth the Congress' findings, purposes, and declaration of national competitiveness policy. Subtitle B: Responsibilities Under the Policy - Requires House of Representatives and Senate reports accompanying bills or joint resolutions to contain a statement prepared by the Director of the Congressional Budget Office detailing: (1) the favorable and adverse effects on the competitiveness of U.S. industries that will result if such legislation is enacted; and (2) any other adverse effects on such industries, other than on U.S. competitiveness, that will result if such legislation is enacted, including the displacement of U.S. workers. Declares that it shall not be in order in the House or the Senate to consider a bill or joint resolution if the accompanying report does not contain such statement. Sets forth provisions relating to executive agency responsibilities with respect to the competitiveness of U.S. industries. Requires such agencies to review their rules and policies for compliance with the requirements of this title. Provides that any specific responsibility of Federal agencies under this Act shall not affect their statutory obligations to comply with U.S. trade agreements. Requires the President to transmit annually to the Congress a National Competitiveness Report summarizing the competitiveness of U.S. industries. Subtitle C: The Council on Competitiveness - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the Council on Competitiveness. Requires the Council to: (1) assist the President in the preparation of the National Competitiveness Report; and (2) gather, study, and review information regarding the competitiveness of U.S. industries. Title II: Limitation on Regulatory Costs - Provides that it shall not be in order in the House or the Senate to consider any bill or joint resolution (including any amendment) authorizing an executive agency to issue rules if: (1) the enactment of such measure imposes on U.S. industries requirements that adversely affect their production of goods and services of a type imported into or exported from the United States; and (2) substantially equivalent requirements do not adversely affect the production of such goods or services by industries located in major trading partners, and major trade competitors, of the United States. Specifies exceptions to this point of order. Deems certain laws enacted after the enactment of this Act to contain an authorization limiting to $5,000,000 annually the total costs that may be imposed on industries located in the United States by all the rules issued under the authority of such laws. Provides for adjustment of such cost limiting authorizations. Prohibits an executive agency from issuing a rule under such an authorization unless: (1) it submits to the Council on Competitiveness a final estimate of the costs that would be imposed annually on U.S. industries as a result of the rule, if issued; and (2) the Council notifies the executive agency that it accepts or rejects the final estimate; or (3) the period for review of such estimate by the Council expires. Requires the Council, within the 60-day period beginning on the date a final estimate is submitted to it, to notify the executive agency submitting such estimate of its decision to accept or reject such estimate. Requires an executive agency, whenever it issues, and publishes in the Federal Register, a rule with respect to authorizations limiting regulatory costs, to include in such publication: (1) its final regulatory cost estimates, if accepted by the Council; or (2) the calculation of regulatory cost estimates prepared by the Council, if it rejects such estimate. Prohibits an executive agency from issuing a final rule if such rule substantially deviates from the agency's proposed rule. Prohibits a court from having jurisdiction to review: (1) a final regulatory cost estimate accepted by the Council; or (2) a calculation of such estimate of regulatory costs prepared by the Council when it rejects the estimate. Prohibits an executive agency from issuing rules that violate authorizations limiting regulatory costs. Provides for the periodic review of regulatory cost estimates and any calculation of rejected cost estimates, or new calculation of cost estimations proved inaccurate. Requires the Council, with respect to each authorization that limits regulatory costs or is deemed to limit such costs, to: (1) calculate each day the total costs imposed on U.S. industries by each rule issued by an executive agency; and (2) maintain, and revise each day, a tabulation of such total costs for a one-year period. Sets forth the method for calculating such costs.</summary>
</bill>
