<bill session="100" type="h" number="4809" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Thrift Institution Prudent Investment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Federal Home Loan Bank board to prescribe regulations to limit the direct investment authority of thrift institutions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA07" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Savings banks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/1988--Introduced.
Thrift Institution Prudent Investment Act of 1988 - Requires the Federal Home Loan Bank Board (FHLBB) to prescribe regulations to limit the extent to which any insured thrift institution may make direct investments. Specifies that under such regulations the aggregate amount of direct investments of any insured thrift institution may not exceed the aggregate amount of direct investments which an insured bank may make under regulations prescribed by the appropriate Federal banking agencies. Exempts from such regulations certain State thrift institutions. Sets forth transitional rules. Prohibits an insured thrift institution which has a capital-to-assets ratio of five percent or less from making any loans or investments other than home loans secured by real property and certain other specified loans and investments. Reduces from $100,000 to $20,000 the Federal deposit insurance coverage for an insured thrift institution which has a capital-to-assets ratio of ten percent or less.</summary>
</bill>
