<bill session="100" type="h" number="4804" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles I, II, IV, and V of the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977, and to add a new title X, to encourage the remining and reclamation of abandoned mined lands by active mining operations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402657"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407400" joined="1988-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Mine wastes"/>
    <term name="Reclamation of land"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Strip mining"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Surface Mining Control and Reclamation Act of 1977 to encourage surface coal mining operations to maximize reclamation of abandoned mine lands concurrently with coal production. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to promote the reclamation of abandoned mined lands by active surface coal mining operators. Authorizes the use of moneys in the Abandoned Mine Reclamation Fund for specified reclamation measures. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) waive or reduce the mining reclamation fee; (2) enter into agreements for land stabilization and conservation measures; (3) develop a reclamation bond guarantee program to compensate operators with reclamation bond credits for reclamation costs; (4) establish a planning process to designate abandoned mine land recovery zones suitable for reclamation by surface coal mining activities; (5) make funds available upon official request to States or Indian tribes for geologic and hydrologic data collection to assist applicants for surface coal mining permits; and (6) use previously allocated funds for the establishment and administration of reclamation bond pool programs and to grant Reclamation Bond Guarantees under such programs to surface coal mine operators in return for reclamation work. Directs the Secretary to promulgate regulations for coal mine waste removal and reclamation. Mandates that, in order to enhance use of coal waste materials as an alternative energy fuel, certain alternative energy fuel regulations apply to coal as the primary energy source to the same extent that such regulations apply to geothermal and small power production facilities and qualifying small power production facilities.</summary>
</bill>
