<bill session="100" type="h" number="4806" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Atmospheric Nuclear Testing Compensation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill establishing a system of compensation for individuals harmed by nuclear testing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400552"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408190" joined="1988-06-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Mine safety"/>
    <term name="Miners"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Uranium"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/1988--Introduced.
Atmospheric Nuclear Testing Compensation Act - Establishes the Commission on Compensation for Atmospheric Nuclear Testing which shall determine whether or not to compensate an individual who alleges that exposure to ionizing radiation: (1) from open-air atomic bomb tests conducted at the Nevada test site from January 1, 1951, to July 31, 1962, caused cancer in the individual or killed or harmed the individual's livestock; or (2) while working in a uranium mine in Colorado, New Mexico, Arizona, or Utah from 1947 through 1961 caused cancer in the miner. Directs the Commission to certify to the Secretary of the Treasury that actual damages be paid to claimants: (1) whose livestock were injured or died; or (2) for whom there is a sizable possibility that they developed cancer due to such exposure. Requires that funds allotted for a fiscal year which are not used to provide such compensation or cover Commission administrative expenses be used to: (1) provide medical screening to residents of areas that received the greatest amount of fallout from the Nevada tests; (2) improve accessibility to health care for such residents; and (3) endow existing programs which provide such services. Establishes the Atmospheric Nuclear Testing Compensation Trust Fund from which amount shall be allocated by the Secretary of the Treasury to the Commission for each fiscal year over the 15-fiscal year life of such Trust Fund. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress by March 1 of each such year on the operation and status of such Trust Fund. Sets a limit on allotments for Commission administrative expenses. Sets forth rules for assessing claims. Authorizes the Commission to establish a maximum amount of damages which may be paid to any claimant. Permits the proration of damages where the probability of radiogenic causation is less than 50 percent. Bars an individual who files a petition for compensation under this Act from seeking damages in a civil action for the same incident on which such petition was based. Subjects Commission members and employees to fines and/or imprisonment for using information supplied pursuant to this Act for purposes other than those for which it was supplied, or for giving other access to such information, except in authorized reports. Limits attorneys' fees for representing claimants under this Act. Prohibits a damage award made pursuant to this Act from being offset against insurance claims. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Commission on October 1 of the year occurring 15 years after this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
