<bill session="100" type="h" number="4822" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Free America Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a customs fee for provision of customs services in connection with processing passengers on international flights; to provide for the establishment of a Western Hemisphere Drug Strike Force and a North Atlantic Treaty Organization Drug Strike Force; and to require States, as a condition of receiving certain funds for criminal justice, to include in probation sentences imposed on certain individuals convicted of drug offenses a requirement that such individuals perform community service.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401986"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403769" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406995" joined="1988-07-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU06" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Community-based corrections"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Military assistance"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Probation"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1988--Introduced.
Drug Free America Act of 1988 - Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to collect a customs fee from each passenger aboard a flight which begins outside the United States and terminates within the United States. Exempts passengers on flights conducted by the Department of Defense from such fee. Authorizes the Secretary to use such fees to pay the costs incurred by the U.S. Customs Service in conducting drug interdiction activities associated with processing such passengers. Requires the President to develop plans for multinational drug strike forces in which Western Hemisphere countries and North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO) countries, respectively, would participate to combat illicit narcotics production and trafficking through military actions and coordination of intelligence activities. Urges the President to negotiate with Western Hemisphere and NATO countries to implement such plans. Directs the President to report to the Congress on such plans and negotiations. Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to require States, as a condition of receiving discretionary and drug law enforcement funding, to certify that they require individuals who are convicted and placed on probation for first offenses similar to those established in the Controlled Substances Act to be sentenced to perform community service. Provides that such eligibility requirement will not apply to any State that cannot make such certification until the conclusion of the first regular legislative session of such State.</summary>
</bill>
