<bill session="100" type="h" number="4827" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Refugee Resettlement Extension Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to extend for 4 years the authorization of appropriations for refugee assistance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407306"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.5037 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5037"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Laos"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1988--Introduced.
Refugee Resettlement Extension Act of 1988 - Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to extend the authorization of appropriations for refugee assistance through FY 1992. Authorizes FY 1989 through 1992 appropriations for alternative refugee projects. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to implement alternative projects for Hmong and Lowland Lao refugees who have been in the United States for at least 24 months. Requires any State or private nonprofit voluntary agency that submits a proposal to administer an alternative project to coordinate its efforts with other refugee assistance programs. Requires the President to file the annual fiscal year refugee admissions and resettlement report with the appropriate congressional committees by June 1. Provides for congressional initiation of related consultations. Includes specified funding and budget provisions within the context of such consultations. Amends the Migration and Refugee Assistance Act of 1962 to permit the use of the United States Emergency Refugee and Migration Assistance Fund for refugee resettlement in the United States. Amends the Refugee Act of 1980 to direct the United States Coordinator for Refugee Affairs to establish a refugee resettlement advisory committee within 90 days of enactment of this Act. Directs the Coordinator to report annually to the appropriate congressional committees regarding efforts to coordinate Federal, State, local, and private refugee resettlement activities. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to repeal the provision for FY 1986 and 1987 initial refugee resettlement audits. Requires a voluntary agency receiving Federal funds for initial refugee resettlement to submit annual audits to the Secretary of State. Requires certain subrecipients to submit audits to their administering Federal agency. Transfers responsibility for initial placement policy from the Director of the Office of Refugee Resettlement to the administering Federal agency.</summary>
</bill>
