<bill session="100" type="h" number="4828" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to extend penalties for the operation of a vehicle while under the influence of alcohol or drugs in the transaction of the business of a common carrier to those who participate in the operation of such a vehicle, to extend such penalties to the operation of a locomotive, to increase such penalties if such operation results in serious bodily injury or death, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407669"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Crime.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU06" subcommittee="Crime" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Alcohol"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/15/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to revise provisions prescribing penalties for the operation of a common carrier while under the influence of alcohol or drugs. Imposes existing penalties on anyone who operates, directs, or participates in the operation of a railroad car, locomotive, bus, water craft, or aircraft while under the influence of alcohol or drugs in the transaction of the business of a common carrier. Establishes increased penalties to be imposed whenever such operation, direction, or participation results in death or serious bodily injury.</summary>
</bill>
