<bill session="100" type="h" number="483" updated="2016-06-29T08:42:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Support Payment Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Federal right of every unemancipated child to be supported by such child's parent or parents and therefore, to confer upon certain local courts of the District of Columbia and every State and territory of the United States jurisdiction to enforce such right regardless of such child's residence.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405939"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1987--Introduced.
Federal Support Payment Act - Amends the judicial code to provide for the enforcement of State court-ordered child support payments in sister States. Authorizes State-ordered child support payments to be registered under specified conditions in any State court for enforcement purposes. Establishes guidelines for enforcement and contempt proceedings in such State courts. Confers original jurisdiction upon State courts over civil actions brought by citizens of sister States to order citizens of the forum State to make child support payments, subject to specified conditions.</summary>
</bill>
