<bill session="100" type="h" number="4844" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-06">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Aviation Administration Drug Enforcement Assistance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Federal Aviation Administration Drug Enforcement Assistance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Alcohol and Drug Traffic Safety Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house" partial="1">Federal Aviation Administration Drug Enforcement Assistance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Federal Aviation Administration to provide assistance to law enforcement agencies in their efforts with respect to drug trafficking interdiction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400844"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400015" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401612" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402657" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404401" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400240" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407432" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407816" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="408244" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="408632" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409353" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409442" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400369" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409954" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410261" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410529" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410531" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411065" joined="1988-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Hearings Held by the Committee on Public Works and Transportation Prior to Introduction and Referral (June 8, 88).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-07">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.  Report No: 100-891.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-07">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 528.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Considered by House Unfinished Business.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="437" datetime="1988-10-06" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 413 - 1 (Record Vote No: 437).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1136">
      <text>Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1136.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-18">
      <text>See H.R.5210.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft pilots"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Avionics"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Drunk driving"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended, roll call #437 (413-1)) Subtitle A: Federal Aviation Administration Drug Enforcement Assistance - Federal Aviation Administration Drug Enforcement Assistance Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to direct the Federal Aviation Administrator to modify systems relating to aircraft registration, airman's certification, and fuel system alterations in order to make such systems more responsive to the needs of drug law enforcement authorities. Cites the areas to be modified. Requires the Administrator to issue final regulations implementing such modifications within ten months after the date of enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Administrator to establish and collect user fees to cover the costs associated with such systems' modification. Prescribes user fee guidelines. Requires the Administrator to report annually to the Congress for a five-year period regarding the progress being made under this Act. Establishes civil and criminal penalties for violations under this Act. Cites conditions under which an aircraft used in connection with violations under this Act may be seized by or forfeited to drug law enforcement authorities. Requires the Administrator to report annually to the Congress for a three-year period on progress being made regarding: (1) informational assistance to drug law enforcement authorities; (2) registration and certification suspensions; and (3) the training of Federal Aviation Administration personnel with respect to controlled substances traffic. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress on the funding resources needed on an annual basis to implement this Act during a five-year period. Requires that budget requests transmitted by the Administrator to the President or the Secretary of Transportation relating to implementation of this Act be concurrently submitted to certain congressional committees and officials. Requires the Office of Personnel Management to report to the Congress within 120 days after enactment of this Act regarding the results of its review of a certain position classification scheme. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to report to the Congress the results of a feasibility study relating to the cost/benefit ratio (with respect to drug interdiction) of requiring aircraft entering the continental United States to: (1) have an operating transponder installed; and (2) have a flight plan filed with the Federal Aviation Administration before such entry. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to report to the Congress the results of a feasibility study pertaining to: (1) the interception of aircraft deviating from established flight corridors across the borders of the continental United States; and (2) the impact of the establishment of such corridors on safe and efficient aircraft movement and upon drug interdiction. Modifies the guidelines for revoked airmen's certificates to prohibit certification to any person whose certificate has been revoked (current law limits such proscription to five years). Permits the Administrator to issue such a certificate to a person whose certificate has been revoked if to do so will facilitate law enforcement efforts. Authorizes waiver of statutory revocation requirements upon the request of Federal or State law enforcement officials if the Administrator determines that such waiver will facilitate law enforcement efforts. Declares that this Act applies only to aircraft which are not used to provide specified air transportation. Subtitle B: Drug Recognition Expert Regional Training Program - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a regional program for training law enforcement officers to recognize and identify motor vehicle operators under the influence of drugs and alcohol. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY 1989 through 1993. Subtitle C: Alcohol and Drug Traffic Safety - Alcohol and Drug Traffic Safety Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary to make basic and supplemental grants to States which adopt and implement drunk driving enforcement programs. Sets forth guidelines for such grants and authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. Directs the Secretary to publish final regulations for program implementation in the Federal Register and to transmit them to the Congress. Directs the Secretary to transmit to the Congress within one year after enactment of this Act the results of a study by the National Academy of Sciences regarding which blood alcohol concentration levels impair the efficiency of motor vehicle operators. Requires such study to establish standards for determining impairment by a controlled substance or any other drug. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989.</summary>
</bill>
