<bill session="100" type="h" number="4872" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish education and prevention programs relating to the illicit use of drugs by youth.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-23">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Education and Labor.  Report No: 100-779.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 472.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Administration of juvenile justice"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism counseling"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Community and school"/>
    <term name="Community facilities"/>
    <term name="Community organization"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Educational innovations"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Gangs"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Narcotics and crime"/>
    <term name="Nutrition policy"/>
    <term name="Physical education and training"/>
    <term name="Police services for juveniles"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of criminals"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation of juvenile delinquents"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Sports and Athletics"/>
    <term name="Sports and recreation"/>
    <term name="Sports and state"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
    <term name="Summer employment"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in recreation"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in social service"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1988--Reported to House amended.
(Reported to House from the Committee on Education and Labor with amendment, H. Rept. 100-779) Title I: Drug Education and Prevention Relating to Youth Gangs - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (HHS) to make grants and contracts for projects and activities for drug education and prevention relating to youth gangs. Includes among such projects: (1) prevention and reduction of youth drug abuse and participation in gang-committed, drug-related crimes; and (2) support of local law enforcement outreach activities. Sets forth grant and contract application requirements for public and nonprofit private agencies, organizations (including community-based organizations with demonstrated experience in this field), institutions, and individuals. Sets forth application approval priorities. Directs the Secretary of HHS to coordinate the program under this title with the programs and activities of the Attorney General and with those under the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. Title II: Innovative Alcohol Abuse Education Programs - Amends part F (Secretary's Fund for Innovation in Education) of title IV (Special Programs) of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for innovative alcohol abuse education programs. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to develop materials for such programs, especially ones that focus on the effect of the disease of alcoholism on the families of alcoholics, particularly the children. Requires that programs for which such materials are developed be designed to benefit young children, particularly those in grades five through eight. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to training programs for educators that are designed to: (1) increase awareness of children's problems that may be caused by an alcoholic parent; (2) enhance educators' ability to identify children at risk for alcohol abuse; (3) inform educators concerning referral of children of alcoholics for appropriate professional treatment; and (4) train educators to inform the public about the special problems of children who have an alcoholic parent. Title III: Drug Abuse Education and Prevention Programs for Incarcerated Individuals - Amends the Adult Education Act to allow certain funds set aside by a State to be used for the cost of drug abuse education and prevention programs and referral to drug abuse treatment programs for criminal offenders in corrections institutions. Title IV: National Youth Sports Program - Authorizes the Secretary of HHS to make grants to carry out a national youth sports program. Makes eligible for such grants organizations whose members are institutions of higher education with access to high-quality educational and sports facilities. Requires such a program to provide disadvantaged youth: (1) medical and nutrition services; (2) exposure to college and university campuses; (3) sports instruction and competition in settings that provide high quality facilities and supervision; and (4) related educational and counseling services (including instruction on drug and alcohol abuse prevention, educational and career opportunities, health and nutrition, study practices, and job responsibilities). Sets forth grant application requirements. Requires that at least 90 percent of youth participants be from families with incomes below the poverty line. Requires matching contributions from the eligible entities. Sets forth required activities under such program. Requires, in the application selection process, that special emphasis be placed on drug abuse education and prevention activities. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. (Provides that program grants will be used to carry out activities for a one-year period, concentrating such activities in June, July, and August.) Title V: Programs Relating to Juvenile Delinquency and to Runaway and Homeless Youth - Subtitle A: Program to Enhance Juvenile Delinquency Prevention - Part 1: Projects and Activities of State and Local Governments - Directs the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention (the Administrator) to make grants to States to plan, establish, operate, coordinate, and evaluate projects, directly or through grants and contracts with public and private agencies, to: (1) develop more effective education, prevention, treatment, and rehabilitation services related to the illicit use of drugs by juveniles; (2) refer juveniles and their families to these and other appropriate services; and (3) coordinate such referral and services. Allots such funds to States on the basis of population of individuals less than 18 years old. Sets forth a minimum allotment for States and allotments for specified U.S. territories and possessions. Sets forth requirements for applications for allotments. Requires States to give priority to specified types of projects. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991, but only if the aggregate amount appropriated to carry out title II of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 for the fiscal year in question is not less than such amount for the preceding fiscal year. Part 2: Other Projects and Activities - Directs the Administrator to make grants to and contracts with, on a competitive basis, public and private nonprofit agencies, organizations, institutions, and individuals for: (1) juvenile delinquency prevention or reduction through drug abuse education, prevention, and treatment; (2) research on illicit use of drugs by juveniles, effects on juveniles of illicit use of drugs by family members, and innovative and effective prevention and treatment of such use; (3) community outreach and counseling projects (involving juveniles providing services to juveniles) to reduce and prevent the illicit use of drugs; and (4) training and technical assistance for innovative and effective drug abuse education, prevention, and treatment provided to persons and organizations involved in juvenile delinquency prevention and treatment. Limits any such grant or contract to not more than three years' duration. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991, but only if the aggregate amount appropriated to carry out title II of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Act of 1974 for the fiscal year in question is not less than such amount for the preceding fiscal year. Part 3: Reports: Directs the Administrator, within 180 days after the end of a fiscal year for which funds are appropriated for this subtitle, to report to the President, the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate. Requires such report to: (1) describe the projects and activities for which each State spent funds received under part 1, and how each State coordinated these with projects and activities under specified Federal law; (2) summarize each project or activity which received part 2 funds, and evaluate their results; and (3) describe exemplary drug abuse education, prevention, and treatment projects and activities, particularly community-based juvenile delinquency prevention involving and assisting families of juveniles. Subtitle B: Program for Runaway and Homeless Youth - Directs the Secretary of HHS to make grants to public and private nonprofit agencies, organizations, and institutions for research, demonstration, and services projects for runaway and homeless youth, especially relating to illicit use of drugs. Includes among such projects: (1) individual, family, and group counseling; (2) peer counseling; (3) community education, including outreach to individuals; (4) rural area assistance, including community support groups; (5) information and training to individuals providing services to such youth, including information on increased susceptibility to communicable diseases; (6) research on the effects on such youth of their own or family members' drug abuse, and correlations between such use and suicide attempts; and (7) improved availability and coordination for such youth of local drug abuse services. Directs the Secretary to give grant priority to agencies and organizations with experience in providing services to such youth. Limits any such grant to three years' duration. Directs the Secretary, within 180 days after the end of a fiscal year for which funds are appropriated for this subtitle, to report to the President, the Speaker and the President pro tempore. Requires such report to describe: (1) the types of projects and activities funded; (2) the number and characteristics of the youth and families served; and (3) exemplary projects and activities funded. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991, but only if the aggregate amount appropriated to carry out title III of the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 for the fiscal year in question is not less than such amount for the preceding fiscal year. Subtitle C: General Provisions - Sets forth requirements for submission and contents of applications under this title. Sets forth provisions for review of such applications. Title VI: Drug Abuse Education for Participants in the Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children - Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to include: (1) drug abuse among health problems covered by such Act; (2) drug abuse education along with the nutrition education provided under such Act; and (3) drug abuse education and instruction relating to such education under specified requirements for State plans. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, within six months after enactment of this Act, to study appropriate methods of drug abuse education instruction. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 and succeeding fiscal years to carry out such study. Adds two members to the National Advisory Council on Maternal, Infant, and Fetal Nutrition. Requires that one such member be an expert in drug abuse education and prevention, and the other be an expert in alcohol abuse education and prevention. Title VII: Community-Based Volunteer Demonstration Projects for Drug Abuse Education and Prevention Services and Activities - Amends the Domestic Volunteer Service Act of 1973 to authorize the Director of the ACTION Agency (the Director) to make grants to public and nonprofit organizations for innovative, community-based volunteer demonstration projects which provide comprehensive drug abuse education and prevention services and activities to youths during the summer months. Allows such projects to include: (1) extending effective school-based programs, or other programs operated during the school year, to the summer months; (2) summer recreational, volunteer service, and youth development activities to provide positive alternatives to illicit drug use; and (3) incorporating drug abuse education and prevention activities in public and private programs serving youth during the summer months. Gives priority to projects that serve high-risk youths and provide opportunities for parent involvement. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. Title VIII: Amendments to the Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1986 - Amends the Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1986 to limit the amount which may be used for administrative expenses of the chief executive officer of the State under provisions for State and local programs. Allows up to ten percent of participants in innovative State programs under such Act to be individuals who are not high-risk youth, if the Secretary of Education determines that such individuals' participation will not significantly diminish the amount or quality of services provided to high-risk youth. Requires that drug-abuse education curricula, textbooks, and teaching materials, and the information from which such materials and textbooks are developed, be the most readily available, accurate, and up-to-date (under provisions for Federal, State, and local level development and other treatment of such materials). Title IX: Drug-Free Workplace - Requires recipients of any Federal contract, subcontract, or assistance to have, and to administer in good faith, a policy designed to ensure that all their workplaces are free from the illegal use, possession, manufacture, or distribution of controlled substances by their employees. Requires Federal agencies to make rules to carry out and enforce such condition. Title X: Miscellaneous - Sets forth definitions for purposes of this Act. Directs the Secretaries of Education and of HHS jointly to: (1) conduct a study to determine the effects of drug treatment programs carried out by grant and contract recipients with funds under Acts administered by their Departments; and (2) report a summary of study results to specified congressional officers within 180 days after funds for such study and report are appropriated. Authorizes appropriations. Sets forth congressional findings and the sense of the Congress that: (1) any proposal to legalize illicit drugs, as a method to combat their sale and use, should be rejected; and (2) the Congress should explore only those proposals which directly attack the supply of and demand for illicit drugs, such as proposals to strengthen and expand penalties for their sale and use, or encourage greater multinational cooperation in illicit drug eradication and interdiction, or promote educational awareness programs for young people.</summary>
</bill>
