<bill session="100" type="h" number="4891" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Commandant of the United States Coast Guard to make full use of all available and qualified resources, including the Coast Guard Auxiliary and individuals licensed by the Secretary pursuant to section 8904(b) of title 46, United States Code, in rendering aid in nonemergency cases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405855"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403266" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406148" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400440" joined="1988-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Coast Guard and Navigation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM01" subcommittee="Coast Guard and Navigation" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Marine safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Salvage"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1988--Introduced.
Amends Federal law concerning the Coast Guard's powers with regard to saving life and property to direct the Commandant of the Coast Guard to make full use of all available and qualified resources, including the Coast Guard Auxiliary and individuals licensed to operate towing vessels, in rendering aid in nonemergency cases. Amends the Coast Guard Authorization Act of 1982 to direct the Commandant to review policies and procedures for towing and salvage of disabled vessels to minimize Coast Guard competition or interference, other than by the Coast Guard Auxiliary, with private towing activities or other commercial enterprises. (Current law contains the same provision, but without reference to the Coast Guard Auxiliary.)</summary>
</bill>
