<bill session="100" type="h" number="4897" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Film Disclosure and Preservation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Act entitled "An Act to provide for the registration and protection of trade-marks used in commerce, to carry out the provisions of certain international conventions, and for other purposes", enacted July 5, 1946 (popularly known as the Lanham Act), to require certain disclosures relating to materially altered films and to establish a National Film Preservation Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409650" joined="1988-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authors and authorship"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/22/1988--Introduced.
Film Disclosure and Preservation Act of 1988 - Amends Federal copyright law to mandate the conspicuous disclosure at each public exhibition of a materially altered film (including colorized film and any promotional or rental activity relating to it): (1) that it has been materially altered from the form in which it was first released to the public; (2) the nature of such alteration; and (3) any objection raised by an aggrieved party to such alteration. Requires any person who proposes to exploit a materially altered film to notify specified persons by registered mail of such intent. Permits statutory and punitive damages, including attorney's fees, to a party aggrieved by violations of the notice and disclosure requirements. Preempts State laws respecting the material alteration of films. Establishes the National Film Preservation Commission to: (1) determine methods to encourage the restoration and preservation of films; (2) report annually to the Congress regarding the efficacy of the disclosure requirements under this Act; and (3) report to the Congress whether categories of audiovisual works other than films should be brought within the scope of such disclosure requirements.</summary>
</bill>
