<bill session="100" type="h" number="4900" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Defense Inspector General Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish as an independent establishment in the executive branch an Office of Defense Inspector General which shall be responsible for overseeing financial programs and activities of the Department of Defense and which shall be independent of the Secretary of Defense.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300011"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400987" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401310" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="401363" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1988-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300017" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="402600" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400109" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400580" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300037" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300038" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405524" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="405775" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="405939" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="406157" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406765" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406994" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407051" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400278" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407853" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400314" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408621" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400604" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409219" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="409632" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="409650" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400387" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" name="House Government Operations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Governmental investigations"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/1988--Introduced.
Independent Defense Inspector General Act - Establishes the Office of the Defense Inspector General (Office) as an independent establishment within the executive branch. Provides that such office shall be headed by an Inspector General appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Specifies that the Inspector General shall not report to, or be subject to supervision by, the Secretary of Defense. Provides that the Inspector General shall appoint an Assistant Inspector General for Auditing and an Assistant Inspector General for Investigations. Specifies the various duties and responsibilities of the Inspector General, including: (1) providing policy direction for, and conducting and supervising audits and investigations relating to, the programs and operations of the Department of Defense; and (2) being the principal adviser to the Secretary of Defense for matters relating to the prevention and detection of fraud, waste, and abuse in the programs and operations of the Department of Defense. Requires the Inspector General, in carrying out the duties and responsibilities established under this Act, to: (1) give regard to the activities of the Comptroller General with a view toward avoiding duplication and insuring coordination and cooperation; (2) report to the Attorney General whenever reasonable grounds exist to believe there has been a violation of criminal law; and (3) carry out such duties and responsibilities in a manner that avoids compromising or endangering the national security. Requires the Inspector General to prepare semiannual reports concerning the activities of the Office and to furnish such reports to the President, the Secretary of Defense, and the Committees on Armed Services of the Senate and the House of Representatives. Sets forth administrative provisions concerning: (1) the authorities of the Inspector General to have access to records and documents of the Department of Defense; (2) the obtaining of information and assistance from other Federal agencies; and (3) office space and equipment. Requires the Inspector General to report to the President, the Secretary of Defense, and the Armed Services Committees whenever any requested information or assistance is unreasonably refused. Authorizes the Inspector General to receive and investigate complaints or information from employees of the Department of Defense concerning violations of law, waste, mismanagement, or dangers to public health or safety. Prohibits the Inspector General from disclosing the identity of such an employee without the consent of the employee, unless the Inspector General determines such disclosure is unavoidable during the course of an investigation. Prohibits taking or threatening to take any action against any such employee as a reprisal for making a complaint or disclosing information to the Inspector General. Prohibits any person from serving as Inspector General if he or she has served as an officer of the armed forces or has been employed by a defense contractor during the five-year period prior to nomination. Prohibits any person who has served as Inspector General from accepting compensation from a defense contractor for a period of five years after leaving office. Sets forth similar rules for employees of the Office for periods of three years before and after employment with the Office. Terminates the Office of the Inspector General of the Department of Defense. Transfers all personnel, records, property and assets of such office to the Office established by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
