<bill session="100" type="h" number="4904" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-08">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology-Related Assistance for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Technology-Related Assistance for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Technology-Related Assistance for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program of grants to States to promote the provision of technology-related assistance to individuals with disabilities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300057"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401203" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402710" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404220" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400586" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404723" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404765" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405646" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406992" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400253" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407400" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408621" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408632" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400380" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411947" joined="1988-08-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-12">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Education and Labor.  Report No: 100-819.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 493.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-08-08" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Laid on Table in House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Other Measure S.2561 Passed House in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2561"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2561"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Medical technology"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/8/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Technology-Related Assistance for Individuals With Disabilities Act of 1988 - Title I: Grants to States - Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to States for consumer-responsive comprehensive statewide programs of technology-related assistance for individuals of all ages with disabilities. Lists functions and activities which may be included in the programs. Directs the Secretary to award to States three-year grants for statewide programs of technology-related assistance for individuals with disabilities. Provides for the number and amounts of the grants. Gives States receiving grants in one fiscal year priority in the availability of amounts appropriated in the next fiscal year. Directs the Secretary to award grants in a manner that is geographically equitable and that distributes them among States that have differing levels of development of programs of technology-related assistance. Sets forth information and assurances which must accompany an application. Authorizes the Secretary to award a two-year extension grant to any State that demonstrates significant progress of a statewide program of technology-related assistance under a grant provided for in this Act. Provides for the amounts of the extension grants and for priority for previously participating States. Specifies elements which must be included in an extension grant application. Requires each State that receives a grant under this title to submit an annual report to the Secretary. Sets forth specific requirements for reports with respect to extension grants. Directs the Secretary to establish a system to assess the extent to which States which receive grants under this title are making significant progress. Subjects any State which fails to comply with the requirements of this title to a corrective action plan. Declares that nothing in this title shall be construed to permit the State or any Federal agency to reduce medical or other assistance available or to alter eligibility under: (1) title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance), title V (Maternal and Child Health), title XVI (Supplemental Security Income), title XVIII (Medicare), title XIX (Medicaid), or title XX (Block Grants for States for Social Services) of the Social Security Act; (2) the Education of the Handicapped Act; (3) the Rehabilitation Act of 1973; or (4) laws relating to veterans' benefits. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993. Directs the Secretary to reserve from amounts appropriated one percent for provision to States of information and technical assistance. Authorizes the Secretary to reserve sums as necessary to cover the cost of on-site visits. Directs the Secretary, directly or by contract, to: (1) conduct a national evaluation of the grant program authorized by this title; and (2) report to the Congress not later than October 1, 1992. Directs the Secretary to work with the States to consider and develop an information system designed to report and compile a qualitative and quantitative description of the impact of the grant program. Title II: Programs of National Significance - Part A: Study on Financing of Assistive Technology Devices and Assistive Technology Services for Individuals with Disabilities - Requires the National Council on the Handicapped to: (1) conduct a study and make recommendations to the Congress and the President concerning financing and other aspects of technology-related assistance, devices, and services; and (2) appoint an advisory committee in accordance with the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 to assist the Council in carrying out the Council's duties under this part. Directs the heads of all Federal agencies, to the extent not prohibited by law, to cooperate with the Council. Authorizes the Council, with the consent of the agency involved, to use the resources of Federal, State, local, and private agencies, with or without reimbursement. Sets forth reporting requirements. Part B: National Information and Program Referral Network - Directs the Secretary to enter into any contract or cooperative agreement necessary in order to establish a national information and program referral network to assist States regarding such technology-related assistance, if the Secretary determines it appropriate to establish the network. Requires the contracts or agreements, if any, to be entered into before the end of 30 months after appropriations are enacted. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study of the feasibility and desirability of creating such a network and, if so, to determine the appropriate structure for the network. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into a contract or cooperative agreement necessary to conduct the study. Provides for the content and timetable of the study. Part C: Training and Public Awareness Projects - Directs the Secretary to enter into contracts or cooperative agreements concerning training with regard to the provision of technology-related assistance. Specifies eligible activities. Directs the Secretary to make grants to assist institutions of higher education to prepare personnel for careers relating to the provision of technology-related assistance. Sets forth priorities and specifies allowed uses of funds. Directs the Secretary to make grants or enter into contracts to carry out national projects that build awareness of the importance and efficacy of assistive technology devices and services for individuals of all ages with disabilities functioning in various settings of daily life. Sets forth allowed uses of the funds. Directs the Secretary to establish priorities for the grants and to publish the priorities, along with an explanation of how the priorities were determined, in the Federal Register. Part D: Demonstration and Innovation Projects - Directs the Secretary to make grants or enter into contracts or cooperative agreements to pay all or part of the cost of demonstration and innovation projects concerning technology-related assistance for individuals with disabilities. Sets forth allowed uses of the funds. Part E: Authorization of Appropriations - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993. Sets forth priorities depending on specified levels of appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
