<bill session="100" type="h" number="4912" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making a special supplemental appropriation for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1988, to enhance and speed up the war on illegal drugs and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410076"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400761" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402325" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403709" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400226" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400340" joined="1988-06-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/23/1988--Introduced.
Appropriates funds to the President for transfer to specified agencies and activities to enhance and speed up the war against the use of illegal drugs. Directs the President to transfer funds appropriated by this Act to various Government agencies and activities in such amounts as such agencies can use to more effectively fight the war against drugs, to treat addicts, and to cooperate with international agencies. Prohibits the use of such funds: (1) to engage in any activity prohibited by Federal laws or for which authority from the Congress was requested and denied; (2) except for purposes set forth in this Act, or under the authority of such agencies or activities authorized by law; and (3) to finance long-term or permanent facilities and equipment not primarily used for the war against drugs, other than for an interagency data system useful for other purposes. Declares that the war against illegal drugs constitutes a dire emergency. Directs that sums provided under this Act shall not be considered to be within the funding ceiling for a given function or section under any budgetary rule, resolution, or agreement previously adopted.</summary>
</bill>
