<bill session="100" type="h" number="4917" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Post-Employment Restrictions Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 207 of title 18, United States Code, relating to restrictions on post-employment activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400140"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400064" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402750" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403476" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="408097" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400370" joined="1988-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400386" joined="1988-06-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-06-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Clean Bill H.R.5043 Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee in Lieu.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/1988--Introduced.
Post-Employment Restrictions Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal criminal code to revise provisions regarding former Federal employees attempting to influence the Government. Prohibits a former officer or employee of the executive branch, for one year after Federal service ends, from representing or aiding and advising any person, with the intent to influence, regarding any trade negotiation: (1) which was actually pending under the official's responsibility within one year before the termination of Federal employment; or (2) in which the official participated personally and substantially within a period of one year before termination of employment. Prohibits senior officials in the executive branch (including the President) for one year after such service ends from representing any person with the intent to influence the Government. Prohibits former Members of Congress and elected officers of the Congress from representing others before or attempting to influence any Member, officer, or employee of the House in which the individual served for one year after that individual leaves office regarding any matter involving national policy. Exempts public speeches from such prohibition. Prohibits any former employee of a Senator or Representative, within one year after employment terminates, from representing others before or attempting to influence any of the following persons in connection with any matter involving national policy: (1) the Member for whom that person worked; or (2) any employee of the Member. Prohibits a former employee of a congressional committee, within one year after termination of such employment, from representing others before or attempting to influence any current employee of such committee with respect to any matter involving national policy. Establishes a one-year ban for former employees of the leadership staff of the House and Senate on representing others before or attempting to influence certain parties in the Congress. Declares that the prohibitions set forth in this Act apply only to acts done for compensation. Sets forth penalties for violations. Sets forth general exceptions to the prohibitions under this Act if the former employee or official is carrying out official duties as an elected official of a State or local government or as an employee of: (1) a State or local government; (2) an institution of higher learning; or (3) a tax-exempt hospital or medical research organization. Revises the authority of the Director of the Office of Government Ethics in designating separate agencies and bureaus. Authorizes the Attorney General to grant a waiver from restrictions under this Act if the proposed conduct would not be adverse to the security, trade, or other national interests of the United States. Authorizes the Attorney General, if it is reasonably believed that a person is engaging or is about to engage in conduct in violation of this Act, to petition an appropriate U.S. district court for an order prohibiting such conduct.</summary>
</bill>
