<bill session="100" type="h" number="4939" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-31">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lead Contamination Control Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Lead Contamination Control Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Lead Contamination Control Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Lead Contamination Control Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Safe Drinking Water Act to control lead in drinking water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409901"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1988-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-03">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-29">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Energy and Commerce.  Report No: 100-1041.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 612.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-05" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Senate Committee on Environment and Public Works discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-31" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-572" type="public" datetime="1988-10-31">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-572.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Lead poisoning"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Schools"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water purification"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Lead Contamination Control Act of 1988 - Amends the Safe Drinking Water Act to direct the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to consider drinking water coolers with lead-lined tanks as imminently hazardous consumer products which must be repaired, replaced, recalled, or refunded by their manufacturers and importers within one year of this Act's enactment. Requires the EPA to publish and distribute to the States: (1) a list identifying each brand and model of drinking water cooler which is not lead free, including each cooler which has a lead-lined tank; and (2) a guidance document and testing protocol to assist schools in determining the source and degree of lead contamination in school drinking water supplies and in remedying such contamination. Bans the manufacture or sale of listed drinking water coolers and any other drinking water cooler which is not lead free. Establishes criminal and civil penalties for violation of such ban. Requires the States to disseminate the water cooler list and the guidance document and testing protocol to local education agencies (LEAs), private nonprofit elementary or secondary schools, and day care centers. Directs each State to establish a program, within nine months of this Act's enactment, to assist LEAs in testing for, and remedying, lead contamination in school drinking water from coolers and from other sources of lead contamination. Requires that testing results be made available for public inspection in LEA administrative offices. Requires that listed coolers be repaired, removed, or rendered inoperable within 15 months of this Act's enactment, unless they are tested and found not to contribute lead to drinking water. Directs the EPA to make grants to States for such programs. Authorizes appropriations for such grant program through FY 1991. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to State and local governments for the initiation and expansion of community programs designed to: (1) screen infants and children for elevated blood lead levels; (2) assure referral for treatment of, and environmental intervention for, infants and children with such blood lead levels; and (3) provide education about childhood lead poisoning. Requires that grant priority be given to programs which will serve areas with a high incidence of elevated blood levels in infants and children. Directs the Secretary to report annually to the Congress on the effectiveness of such programs. Authorizes appropriations for such grant program through FY 1991. Directs the EPA to: (1) assure that drinking water testing laboratory certification programs certify only those laboratories which provide reliable accurate testing; and (2) publish a list of certified laboratories.</summary>
</bill>
