<bill session="100" type="h" number="4943" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Caribbean Regional Development Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote equitable and participatory development, national and regional economic integration, and food security and self-reliance in the Caribbean through responsive aid and development policies and programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="401585" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403695" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404002" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404856" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406277" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406740" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407282" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407960" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400306" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Women"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1988--Introduced.
Caribbean Regional Development Act of 1988 - Declares it to be the policy of the United States in providing development and other economic assistance to the Caribbean to: (1) help the poor to participate in the development of their societies; (2) support development that is environmentally sustainable; (3) promote Caribbean self-reliance; (4) increase food security; (5) promote the diversification of production; (6) advance the process of regional economic integration; (7) support national programs of economic adjustment that promote the policies of this Act; (8) avoid the displacement of traditional lines of small-scale production; (9) preserve and reinforce traditional Caribbean culture and social values; and (10) consult with the intended beneficiaries of U.S. economic assistance. Requires that priority in providing development assistance to the Caribbean shall be given to supporting indigenous Caribbean institutions (including farmers' unions, cooperatives, labor organizations, women's groups, and community organizations) that represent, work with, and benefit the poor. Specifies that Economic Support Fund assistance (ESF) shall be used for assistance for those nations in the Caribbean that are experiencing a scarcity of foreign exchange. Provides that priority in the use of such assistance shall be given to the purchase of: (1) critical commodity imports by small- and medium-sized industries, farms, and cooperatives that have limited access to foreign exchange; and (2) key consumer goods in critically short supply. Provides that preference in the purchase of commodity imports purchased with ESF funds or with local currencies shall be given to commodities within the Caribbean region. Specifies that in providing assistance to the Caribbean area priority in the allocation of funds provided for development assistance and through the ESF and in the allocation of local currencies shall be given to: (1) food self-sufficiency; (2) integrated rural development; (3) community-based agro-industries; (4) financial resources for small- and medium-sized farm and manufacturing enterprises; (5) expansion of tourism; (6) regional integration; (7) upgrading technical and managerial skills; and (8) enhancing the natural resource base. Prohibits the provision of any development assistance for: (1) any government or economic enterprise in the Caribbean that does not enforce internationally recognized worker rights; or (2) the construction of any physical infrastructure in the Caribbean for use by an economic enterprise that does not enforce internationally recognized worker rights. Requires the Agency for International Development (AID) to ensure that any physical infrastructure which is constructed using U.S. development assistance is not thereafter used by any economic enterprise that does not enforce internationally recognized worker rights. Requires AID to investigate (through public hearings) allegations that a government or economic enterprise in the Caribbean which receives such funds does not enforce internationally recognized worker rights. Prohibits AID from providing any assistance, directly or indirectly, for the use of any chemical or other substance in the Caribbean if such use: (1) is not permitted under the public health laws of that nation; or (2) would not be permitted in the United States under U.S. public health laws. Specifies that in the provision of development assistance to the Caribbean, emphasis shall be placed on ensuring the active participation of Caribbean women in the development process. Requires AID to: (1) consult with Caribbean organizations that work with the poor in all stages of the design and implementation of assistance policies; and (2) monitor socioeconomic conditions in the Caribbean and the effect of U.S. economic assistance programs and policies on those conditions. Requires the Office of Technology Assessment to conduct an evaluation of and report to the Congress on the performance of AID in carrying out this Act. Requires the Administrator of AID to report annually to the Congress concerning AID's efforts to implement the provisions of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
