<bill session="100" type="h" number="4979" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">SSI Improvements Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVI of the Social Security Act by extending eligibility for supplemental security income benefits, increasing such benefits, promoting the efficient administration of such program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409446"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401418" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="401526" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1988-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403314" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408313" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410889" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411948" joined="1988-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Birth defects"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Disability evaluation"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Supplemental security income program"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/6/1988--Introduced.
SSI Improvements Act of 1988 - Amends title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act to set the SSI income eligibility limit at the Federal poverty level and provide eligible individuals with the amount of SSI benefits needed to raise their income to such level. Increases the amount of resources individuals may possess before becoming ineligible for SSI benefits. Covers specially disadvantaged individuals who are not disabled, but meet at least two of the following criteria: (1) have attained age 50 and, throughout the five years preceding their application for SSI benefits, their earnings have been insufficient to represent substantial gainful activity; (2) are unable to read or write at at least the second grade level in their native language, or comprehend simple written instructions; (3) are homeless, or are chronically unable to function with others in a group setting and have a history of unreasonable hostility to others or the inability to obtain or hold employment due to erratic or unusual and inappropriate behavior; (4) use one or more drugs or alcohol to the ongoing detriment of their ability to obtain food, clothing, or shelter or participate in substantial gainful activity; or (5) have received SSI benefits or benefits under title IV (various family-related welfare programs) or XIX (Medicaid)) of the Act during at least 36 of the preceding 60 months. Extends the SSI program to Puerto Rico, the Virgin Islands, Guam, and American Samoa. Amends the Social Security Amendments of 1972 to repeal a program providing grants to such Territories for aid to the aged, blind, or disabled. Eliminates the one-third SSI benefit and eligibility level reductions applicable to an individual living in another person's household and receiving support and maintenance in kind from such person. Increases the SSI personal needs allowance for institutionalized recipients to $600 per year. Excludes from SSI income eligibility determinations: (1) the first $480 of an individual's annual income; (2) income earned in a month and received infrequently or irregularly, if such income does not excced $30 for the month; (3) assistance furnished for home energy conservation; (4) benefits received in kind; and (5) the first $100 of an individual's annual interest income. Treats State unemployment compensation benefits and Federal or State workers' compensation benefits as earned income for SSI purposes. Eliminates the Secretary of Health and Human Services' authority to apply the SSI benefits due to an individual for his or her first month of eligibility to the first two months of such eligibility. Provides for cost-of-living adjustments to SSI eligibility limits, income exclusions, and benefit amounts. Considers a child to be disabled, for SSI eligibility purposes if such child suffers from any medically determinable physical or mental impairment which severely interferes with activities of daily living. Establishes a presumption that any child born with a genetic or congenital condition which is extremely likely to result in disability is disabled until his or her third birthday, when a disability determination shall be made. Directs the Secretary to: (1) contract with the Institute of Medicine for the development of criteria for use in determining whether or not a child is disabled for SSI purposes; (2) publish revised child disability listings as a notice of proposed rulemaking; and (3) conduct an ongoing program of outreach to children who are potentially eligible for SSI benefits by reason of disability.</summary>
</bill>
