<bill session="100" type="h" number="4972" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-11-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the Patent and Trademark Office in the Department of Commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407899" joined="1988-06-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-30" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-05" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Received in the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Senate Committee on Judiciary discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-14" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>House Concurred, in Senate Amendments , with Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House to the Senate amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-11-19" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-703" type="public" datetime="1988-11-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-703.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Discharged" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust actions"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Consumer price indexes"/>
    <term name="Copyright"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electronic data processing"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Trademarks"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3689"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/20/1988--House agreed to Senate amendment with amendment.
(House agreed to Senate amendments with amendments) Title I: Patent and Trademark Office Authorizations - Authorizes appropriations to the Patent and Trademark Office for FY 1989 through 1991. Prohibits the Commissioner of Patents and Trademarks from increasing or establishing additional patent and trademark fees during FY 1989 through 1991. Allows cost-of-living adjustments according to the Consumer Price Index. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to report to the Congress regarding patent and trademark fee expenditures and collections, budget plans, and surplus fees. Repeals the prohibition against the imposition of a fee for the use of public patent and trademark search rooms and libraries. Directs the Commissioner to make U.S. patent and trademark information (and foreign patent documents) available for public search and retrieval. Prohibits the Commissioner from imposing fees for the use of such collections or for the use of public patent trademark search rooms or libraries. Authorizes the Commissioner to establish fees for public access to automated search systems of the Patent and Trademark Office. Provides for a limited amount of free access to all users of such systems for education and training purposes. Authorizes the Commissioner to waive fee payments by individuals upon a show of need or hardship if such waiver is in the public interest. Authorizes the Patent and Trademark Office to use fee revenues for its activities. Prohibits the Commissioner from: (1) entering during FY 1989 through 1991 into any agreement for the exchange of items or services related to automatic data processing resources; or (2) continuing existing agreements for such exchange after the date of enactment of this Act, except an agreement with a foreign government or an international intergovernmental organization. Title II: Patent Misuse Reform - Amends Federal patent law to permit a patent holder to: (1) refuse to license or use any rights to a patent; or (2) condition the license of any rights to the patent or its sale on the acquisition of the licensing rights in another patent or the purchase of a separate patent, unless, in the circumstances, the patent owner has market power in the relevant market for the patent or patented product on which the license or sale is conditioned.</summary>
</bill>
