<bill session="100" type="h" number="4985" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Agricultural Relief Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Agricultural Act of 1949 to provide drought relief, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300058"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Conservation Credit and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Cotton, Rice, and Sugar.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Livestock, Dairy, and Poultry.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Domestic Marketing, Consumer Relations, and Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Forest, Family Farms, and Energy.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Tobacco and Peanuts.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Wheat, Soybeans, and Feed Grains.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>See H.R.5015.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG01" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, and Rural Development" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG02" subcommittee="Cotton, Rice, and Sugar" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG03" subcommittee="Livestock, Dairy and Poultry" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG04" subcommittee="Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG05" subcommittee="Domestic Marketing, Consumer Relations, and Nutrition" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG06" subcommittee="Forests, Family Farms, and Energy" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG07" subcommittee="Tobacco and Peanuts" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG08" subcommittee="Wheat, Soybeans, and Feed Grains" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5015"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agribusiness"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Cotton"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Feed grain program"/>
    <term name="Feeds"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Fruit and fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Poultry"/>
    <term name="Rice"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Swine"/>
    <term name="Trees"/>
    <term name="Wheat"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/1988--Introduced.
Emergency Agricultural Relief Act of 1988 - Amends the Agricultural Act of 1949 to provide disaster payments for wheat, feed grains, rice, and upland cotton lost in 1988 to drought and other natural disasters. Provides disaster payments to nonprogram producers in specified drought or natural disaster-affected areas. Limits producer payments to not more than $100,000. Provides feed assistance (including transportation) for producers of livestock, poultry, and swine affected by drought or other natural disasters. Provides assistance to orchard owners who have lost trees as a result of the drought. Extends disaster payments to 1988 producers of wheat, feed grains, upland cotton, and rice who are located in counties eligible to receive disaster emergency loans and who did not purchase reduced crop yield insurance. Increases milk price support levels. Revises support level reduction provisions. Provides disaster emergency assistance to counties contiguous to a disaster-affected county under specified conditions. Permits haying and grazing on conservation reserve acreage during periods of drought. Provides for 1988 rural agribusiness disaster assistance. Makes food assistance available for Indian farmers and ranchers affected by drought. States that the chief executive officer of a State shall request the Secretary of Agriculture to make specified agricultural emergency determinations. Requires the Secretary to make such a determination within 25 days of receiving the request. Directs the Secretary to take into consideration the effects of the 1988 drought on a borrower's income when making specified agricultural loan restructuring determinations. Directs the Secretary to provide grain to alcohol fuel producers in times of shortage at prices and in quantities that will ensure the economic vitality of such industry. Directs the Secretary to prepare and submit to the appropriate congressional committees: (1) a drought relief contingency plan; and (2) a forward contracting report. Expresses the sense of the Congress regarding the importance of foreign trade to the domestic agricultural industry and the need to continue to expand such trade. Declares there should be no embargo on domestic agricultural commodities and no reduction in export promotion programs, except in the case of an extreme national emergency. Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to exclude payments under a special conservation reserve enhancement program from specified payment limitations.</summary>
</bill>
