<bill session="100" type="h" number="4984" updated="2014-03-22T09:52:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Health Corps Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish an International Health Corps.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406740"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400025" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="401446" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404213" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406473" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408618" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="409901" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400425" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>For Previous Action See H.R.3669.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Agency for International Development, Pe, ace Corp, HHS.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Reported to House by House Committee on Energy and Commerce. Report No: 100-1078 (Part I).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-15">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From AID.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-17">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From HHS.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-08">
      <text>Favorable Executive Comment Received From Peace Corps.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3669"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American technical assistance"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/1988--Introduced.
International Health Corps Act - Amends title III (General Powers and Duties of Public Health Service) of the Public Health Service Act to establish the International Health Corps (Health Corps), to consist of the International Health Development Corps (Development Corps) and the International Health Emergency Corps (Emergency Corps). Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services, on request of a foreign government, to assign members of: (1) the Development Corps to serve in the country to assist the country in meeting the long-term basic health care needs of its people; and (2) the Emergency Corps to provide short-term assistance in the country with regard to an ongoing medical emergency. Directs the Secretary to disseminate information on the Health Corps and request health care professionals to provide services to the Corps without compensation. Requires a health care professional to be considered, while providing uncompensated services to the Health Corps, an employee of the Public Health Service for purposes of provisions relating to defense of certain malpractice and negligence suits. Directs the Secretary to establish programs in which health professionals and health professions students agree to: (1) serve as members of the Development Corps for at least two years in return for payment by the Federal Government of not more than $20,000 of their educational loans for each year of service; or (2) provide uncompensated services to the Development Corps for at least six months in return for payment by the Federal Government of not more than $5,000 of their educational loans for each six months of service, subject to an aggregate limit. Makes provisions of the Public Health Service Act relating to the National Health Service Corps Loan Repayment Program, except as inconsistent, apply to these programs. Provides for non-duplication and coordination between these programs and the programs of other Federal agencies, other developed countries, and nonprofit private entities. Directs the establishment of a committee to advise the Secretary on policies concerning the activities of the Health Corps. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
