<bill session="100" type="h" number="5008" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Dire Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making dire emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural appropriations"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Black lung"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Cubans"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal assistance to prisoners"/>
    <term name="Legal services"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Prison labor"/>
    <term name="Prison riots"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prisons"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Small Business Administration"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/1988--Introduced.
Dire Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1988 - Title I: Program Supplementals - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to delay or forego foreclosure of Government loans, suspend payments of principal and interest, and make adjustments, on a case by case basis, to prevent bankruptcy or foreclosure due to the drought. Instructs the Secretary to request other creditors to make comparable adjustments. Appropriates FY 1988 supplemental funds to the Department of Agriculture for: (1) salaries and expenses of the Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation Service; and (2) watershed and flood prevention operations of the Soil Conservation Service. Derives the additional funds in both cases through fund transfers. Makes FY 1988 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Defense-Civil for emergency activities of the Army Corps of Engineers-Civil in connection with drought relief in the Mississippi River Basin. Directs the Secretary of the Army, through the Chief of Engineers, to undertake specific activities in this connection. Makes FY 1988 supplemental appropriations to the Department of Labor's Employment and Training Administration for State unemployment insurance and employment service operations. Makes this additional amount available for obligation from July 1, 1988, through June 30, 1989. Transfers funds from the Employment Security Administration's revolving fund as advances to the Black Lung Disability Trust Fund and for trade adjustment assistance. Transfers from the Business Loan and Investment Fund additional FY 1988 appropriations for salaries and expenses of the Small Business Administration. Limits FY 1988 outlays resulting from the use of these funds. Transfers monies from various funds within the Department of Transportation to provide supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to pay operating expenses of the Coast Guard. Makes these additional amounts available through FY 1989. Appropriates supplemental FY 1988 funds to the Department of Justice for the following activities associated with the Mariel Cuban prisoner riots: (1) legal activities in support of U.S. prisoners; (2) salaries and expenses of the Community Relations Service and of the Federal Prison System; and (3) buildings and facilities, specifically authorizing use of the funds for reconstruction of Federal Prison Industries plants. Title II: General Provisions - Prohibits obligation beyond FY 1988 of any funds appropriated in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
