<bill session="100" type="h" number="5028" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the amounts authorized for the Colorado River Storage Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-20">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior, DOE, EPA, USDA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII05" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/1988--Introduced.
Increases authorized appropriations to provide for completion of the Colorado River Storage Project, which provides water and power to the States of Arizona, Colorado, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming. Sets aside a specified amount for the Bonneville Unit of the Central Utah Project for an irrigation and drainage system. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to affect the construction of facilities for the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation under a deferral agreement between the United States, the Tribe, and the Central Utah Water Conservancy District (District). Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to enter into agreements with non-Federal entities for the design and construction of the Bonneville Unit Irrigation and drainage system. Lists certain features of the Bonneville Unit that are not to be funded. Directs the District to develop comprehensive water conservation plans for all systems of the Central Utah Project. Directs the Secretary to form an interagency task force to be known as the Central Utah Project Fish and Wildlife Task Force to review and coordinate accomplishment of the fish and wildlife mitigation program for the Central Utah Project. Sets forth the stream flows to be provided in the Uinta Basin and for the Bonneville Unit. Makes funds available for canal, reservoir, stream, and habitat improvements in the Uinta Basin.</summary>
</bill>
