<bill session="100" type="h" number="5027" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-26">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-26" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Aviation policy"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Board for International Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government ownership"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Railroad Retirement Board"/>
    <term name="Railroad facilities"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Social Security Administration"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/1988--Introduced.
Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1988 - Title I: Program Supplementals - Chapter I - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to the Department of Commerce for the Bureau of the Census. Appropriates supplemental FY 1988 amounts for activities of the Judiciary, including: (1) the Supreme Court; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; (3) the U.S. Court of International Trade; (4) the Courts of Appeals, district courts, and other judicial services; (5) the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; and (6) the Federal Judicial Center. Makes supplemental appropriations to the Department of Transportation's Maritime Administration. Amends the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriation Act, 1988 to revise appropriations to the Board for International Broadcasting. Makes supplemental appropriations for drug law enforcement activities of the Department of Justice and to the Judiciary for the processing of drug-related cases. Chapter II - Amends the Department of Defense Appropriations Act, 1988 to increase the amount that the Secretary of Defense is authorized to transfer among Department of Defense funds for military functions. Directs the Secretary to notify the Congress before making such transfers, which must not result in increased outlays during FY 1988. Chapter III - Makes additional FY 1988 appropriations, through transfers of funds, to the Department of Housing and Urban Development for operations of low-income housing projects. Appropriates supplemental FY 1988 amounts to: (1) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, derived through fund transfers; and (2) the Veterans Administration. Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1988 to repeal a provision limiting funds available for veterans' medical care. Chapter IV - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to: (1) the Department of Agriculture's Forest Service; and (2) the Department of Energy for clean coal technology. Chapter V - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to: (1) the Department of Labor's Employment and Training Administration, through fund transfers; (2) the Department of Health and Human Services for the Social Services Block Grant program; (3) the Department of Education for student financial assistance, with amounts made available by amendment of the Department of Education Appropriations Act, 1988; and (4) the Railroad Retirement Board. Rescinds amounts previously appropriated in connection with specified activities of: (1) the Department of Labor; (2) the Department of Education; (3) the Department of Health and Human Services; and (4) the National Institutes of Health. Rescinds, in addition, certain prior appropriations for health resources and services. Limits FY 1988 administrative expenses of the Social Security Administration. Chapter VI - Appropriates amounts to the House of Representatives for payments to specified widows of deceased Members of Congress. Chapter VII - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to the Department of Transportation for the Office of the Secretary. Reduces amounts available for airway science programs of the Federal Aviation Administration. Rescinds certain FY 1988 funds apportioned to the District of Columbia under the Federal-aid highway program. Makes available additional appropriations, to remain available through FY 1989, to the Federal Railroad Administration, including a transfer of funds, solely to purchase title to Washington Union Station. Appropriates funds to the Mass Transit Capital Fund of the Urban Mass Transportation Administration to pay obligations incurred in connection with a mandated bus testing program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to transfer the Coast Guard Cutter "Ingham" to the Intrepid Sea-Air-Space Museum in New York, New York, for use as a Coast Guard museum and display. Prohibits funds from being used in connection with specified highway facility projects. Title II: General Provisions - Limits the availability for obligation of these appropriations to the current fiscal year, unless expressly provided in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
