<bill session="100" type="h" number="5029" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ute Indian Water Settlement Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the amounts authorized to be appropriated for the Colorado River Storage Project, to settle Ute Indian water rights, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII05" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Colorado"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indian water rights"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="State government-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water storage"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
    <term name="Wyoming"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/1988--Introduced.
Ute Indian Water Settlement Act of 1988 - Increases authorized appropriations for construction of the Upalco Unit and Taskeech Dam of the Colorado River Storage Project which provides water and power to the States of Arizona, Colorado, New Mexico, Utah, and Wyoming. Authorizes appropriations for storage projects, irrigation improvements, and the Whiterocks Dam for the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation. Authorizes appropriations for and creates the Ute Indian Water Deferral Trust Fund with monies to be held by the Secretary of the Interior for the benefit of the Ute Indian Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation, Utah, as compensation for deferring the use and development of irrigable farmland and the related water diversion requirement. Restricts use of the deferred water to diversion directly from the Green River. Directs the Bureau of Reclamation to maintain certain stream flows and to transfer acreage at the proposed site of the Lower Stillwater Reservoir as a wildlife mitigation measure. Allocates funds for the Uintah Irrigation Project. Provides for: (1) non-Federal operation and construction of Project facilities; (2) water right losses for nonpayment of assessments; and (3) lease of available water. Ratifies, confirms, and approves the compact among the Ute Tribe of the Uintah and Ouray Reservation, the State of Utah, and the United States (the Ute Indian Water Compact).</summary>
</bill>
