<bill session="100" type="h" number="5030" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Business and Citizen School Volunteers of America Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Education to make grants to assist in the establishment and improvement of programs in elementary and secondary schools in the United States to use volunteers and to establish a national center for leadership in school volunteer and partnership programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400975"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400882" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403696" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400143" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404587" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300057" joined="1988-07-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406463" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406530" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406873" joined="1988-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Elementary, Secondary and Vocational Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED01" subcommittee="Elementary, Secondary, and Vocational Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Students"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/1988--Introduced.
Business and Citizen School Volunteers of America Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Education (the Secretary) to make grants to eligible partnerships to assist such partnerships in preparing, expanding, and carrying out programs designed to use volunteers in elementary and secondary schools. (Defines eligible partnership as a volunteer program development agreement between: (1) an elementary or secondary school, State educational agency (SEA), and/or local educational agency (LEA); and (2) a government agency, nonprofit organization, institution of higher education, or business concern.) Sets forth priorities in the grant approval process. Sets forth types of programs for which such grants may be made. Directs the Secretary, when issuing rules for such grants program, to consult with nonprofit organizations that operate nationwide and that have as primary purposes assisting: (1) elementary and secondary schools in organizing, promoting, and using school volunteers; and (2) older Americans, employees of business concerns, educators, and students in becoming school volunteers. Sets forth grant eligibility and application requirements. Requires annual reports by: (1) grant recipients to the Secretary; and (2) the Secretary to specified congressional officers. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Center for Leadership in School Volunteer and Partnership Programs, through grants to or contracts with a nonprofit organization described in this Act. Requires the Center to: (1) train volunteers; (2) provide technical assistance to an eligible partnership in developing or improving a volunteer program; (3) conduct an annual survey of volunteer programs; and (4) evaluate volunteer programs. Requires that at least 20 percent of funds under this Act in any fiscal year be used for Center activities. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993 to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
