<bill session="100" type="h" number="5040" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Standard Nuclear Reactor Development Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a standard nuclear reactor program to develop an inherently safe and economic nuclear reactor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411025"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1988-09-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-13">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy Research and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY06" subcommittee="Energy Research and Development" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2639"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2639"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Nuclear reactors"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/13/1988--Introduced.
Standard Nuclear Reactor Development Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish a standard reactor program to develop an inherently safe economic nuclear reactor to be available for the purchase of utilities by the year 2000. Establishes the Office of Standard Reactor Development in the Department of Energy to be headed by an Assistant Secretary of Energy for Standard Reactor Development. Directs the Secretary to submit a program implementation plan to the Congress within one year of enactment of this Act. Outlines the contents of such plan. Directs the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to establish a standard reactor project to: (1) assist the Secretary in the development of standard reactor designs; and (2) facilitate the licensing of reactors based on such designs. Requires the Commission to specify the tests and evaluations that a prototype or demonstration reactor based on a standard reactor design must undergo and to promulgate regulations governing standard reactor siting, design, construction, and operation. Mandates that the Commission submit quarterly reports to the Congress regarding standard reactor activities and promptly inform the Congress of any safety or licensing problems that could interfere with the objectives of this Act. Terminates the standard reactor office and the program 20 years after the date of enactment of this Act or when this Act's purposes have been fulfilled.</summary>
</bill>
