<bill session="100" type="h" number="5060" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Legislative Branch Fair Employment Practices Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend coverage under certain Federal labor laws to employees of the Congress, to provide for the enforcement of such coverage by the establishment of the Legislative Branch Employment Relations Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405236"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Personnel and Police.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSHA05" subcommittee="Personnel and Police" name="House Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative courts"/>
    <term name="Administrative law judges"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Age and employment"/>
    <term name="Age discrimination"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining in government"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employee-management relations in government"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government employee unions"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Industrial relations"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1988--Introduced.
Legislative Branch Fair Employment Practices Act - Title I: Application of Federal Labor Laws to Congress - Amends the following Federal laws to provide for coverage of legislative branch employees under: (1) the National Labor Relations Act; (2) the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (including provisions on minimum wages, overtime, and equal pay); (3) the Age Discrimination in Employment Act of 1967; (4) the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970; (5) title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 (equal employment opportunity provisions); and (6) the Rehabilitation Act of 1973 (employment of the handicapped provisions). Provides that such amendments shall not be construed to require: (1) any Member of Congress to employ in the legislative branch any individual who is not a domiciliary of the district or State such Member represents; or (2) any Member of Congress or congressional committee not to take political affiliation into consideration in hiring for the legislative branch. Title II: Enforcement Provisions - Part A: Conforming Amendments - Amends the Federal laws referred to in title I to provide that requirements applicable to legislative branch employees shall be enforced in accordance with this title II. Part B: Establishment of the Legislative Branch Employment Relations Board and the Office of the General Counsel for Employment Practices - Establishes the Legislative Branch Employment Relations Board. Directs the Board to: (1) establish and publish policies and guidelines for implementing and enforcing any law referred to in title I with respect to coverage of legislative branch employees; (2) review decisions of hearing examiners upon appeal under this title; and (3) maintain a registry of individuals to serve as such hearing examiners. Establishes the Office of the General Counsel for Employment Practices. Directs the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the majority leader of the Senate, in consultation with the minority leaders of each House, to appoint the General Counsel. Directs the General Counsel to appoint officers and employees to carry out the functions of the Office, including employees necessary to conduct inspections and investigations under any law referred to in title I. Part C: Complaints of Violations - Allows any individual who claims to be aggrieved by a violation of any law referred to in title I, or any employee or officer authorized to conduct inspections and investigations under such laws, to file a charge with the Office of the General Counsel for Employment Practices alleging such violation and stating a claim for relief authorized under this part. Sets forth provisions relating to: (1) filing of such charges; (2) investigations, determinations, appointments, and qualifications of investigating counsels; and (3) hearings and determinations of hearing examiners. Directs the hearing examiner, upon finding a violation, to issue and serve a cease and desist order. Allows such order also to require the defendant to take any of the following actions: (1) employment or reinstatement of the complainant under appropriate terms and conditions with specified exceptions; (2) payment of compensatory damages; (3) payment of up to two years' double backpay; (4) payment of up to two years' frontpay; and/or (5) payment of witnesses' fees and allowances and attorney's fees. Prohibits the Board from compelling any Member of Congress or Senator, or their staff members, to employ, reinstate, or modify terms and conditions of employment of any individual to any position on their staff. Requires any such ordered payments to be paid from the contingent fund of the House or the Senate, as appropriate. Directs examiners to dismiss a complaint if they determine that, upon the preponderance of the evidence, the defendant has not violated any such law. Sets forth provisions relating to subpoenas and service of process. Provides for review and enforcement of final orders. Provides for review by the Board of hearing examiners' orders, upon appeal. Provides for judicial review of final orders, upon appeal, in the U.S. Court of Appeals for the District of Columbia, with further review by the U.S. Supreme Court upon writ of certiorari or certification. Provides for court enforcement of administrative orders under this Act. Prohibits the intimidation of persons filing complaints or appearing as witnesses. Requires that decisions and orders of the Board and the Office under this Act be made public. Title III: General Provisions - Requires each congressional committee and office to cooperate with the Board, the Office, and specified congressional committees so that their functions and duties under this Act may be carried out.</summary>
</bill>
