<bill session="100" type="h" number="508" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">War Powers Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the War Powers Resolution to make rules governing certain uses of the Armed Forces of the United States in the absence of a declaration of war by the Congress.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408109"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1987--Introduced.
War Powers Act of 1987 - Amends the War Powers Resolution to rename the resolution the War Powers Act. Authorizes U.S. armed forces, in the absence of a congressional declaration of war, to be introduced into hostilities or into a situation where the imminent introduction of such forces into hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances only: (1) to repel an attack upon the United States, to take retaliatory actions in the event of such an attack, and to forestall the direct and imminent threat of such an attack; (2) to repel an attack against U.S. armed forces located outside the United States and to forestall the direct and imminent threat of such an attack; (3) to protect U.S. citizens while evacuating them from a country where they are being subject to a direct and imminent threat to their lives either sponsored by the country's government or beyond the power of such government to control, provided the President shall make every effort to terminate the threat without using U.S. armed forces and provided that the President shall where possible obtain the consent of the government before using U.S. armed forces; or (4) pursuant to specific statutory authorization. Requires the President to report to the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President of the Senate whenever U.S. armed forces are introduced into hostilities or into one of the other situations listed above. Requires the President to report to the Congress at least once every six months for as long as U.S. armed forces are engaged in hostilities outside the United States. Limits the length of time that U.S. armed forces may be used in hostilities or in such situations to 30 days unless the Congress enacts a law providing otherwise. Permits the Congress by law or joint resolution to terminate U.S. involvement before the expiration of the 30 days. Provides for expedited consideration of proposals to continue or terminate the use of U.S. armed forces in such situations. States that statutory authorization either for introducing U.S. armed forces into or for sustaining their use in hostilities or situations where imminent introduction of such forces into hostilities is clearly indicated by the circumstances shall not be inferred from: (1) any provision of law unless such provision specifically authorizes such introduction or use of the armed forces and states that it is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of this Act; or (2) any treaty unless the treaty is implemented by a law specifically authorizing such introduction or use of such armed forces and stating that it is intended to constitute specific statutory authorization within the meaning of this Act. Permits U.S. armed forces to participate jointly with members of military forces of other countries in high-level military commands that were established before enactment of this Act and pursuant to a treaty which was ratified before such enactment.</summary>
</bill>
