<bill session="100" type="h" number="5097" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Equal Employment Opportunity Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VII of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to prohibit discrimination based on race, color, religion, sex, handicap, national origin, or age in employment in the legislative branch of the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401203"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-27">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Personnel and Police.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-20">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSHA05" subcommittee="Personnel and Police" name="House Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Grievance procedures"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Party affiliation"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/27/1988--Introduced.
Congressional Equal Employment Opportunity Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to require that personnel actions affecting employees or applicants in the legislative branch of the Government other than units having positions in the competitive service be free from any discrimination based on race, color, national origin, religion, sex, handicap, or age. Allows Members of Congress to take into consideration an individual's domicile and political affiliation. Authorizes an aggrieved individual to file a written charge with the Joint Commission on Congressional Employment. Establishes the Commission in the legislative branch. Provides that the Commission be composed of Members of the House of Representatives and the Senate appointed by the Speaker of the House of Representatives and the President pro tempore of the Senate as requested by the majority and minority leaders of each body. Establishes procedures for the Commission to investigate, settle, hear, and determine the claims alleged. Requires the Commission, insofar as practicable, to make a determination not later than 180 days after receiving the charge. Provides that, if a violation is found, an order for relief may compel the defendant to: (1) employ or reinstate, with or without up to two years back pay, on terms and conditions as determined to be appropriate; (2) pay compensatory damages; or (3) cease and desist committing the violation. Makes the order final and not reviewable. Amends title VII (Equal Employment Opportunity) of the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to define "handicap" to have the meaning given it in the Rehabilitation Act of 1973.</summary>
</bill>
