<bill session="100" type="h" number="5096" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-26">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill making emergency supplemental appropriations for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>House Committee on Appropriations Reported an Original Measure. Report No: 100-799.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 487.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Origin, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Air bases"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Beach erosion"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Board for International Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Chemical industries"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Droughts"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Forests, forestry, trees"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Harbors"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Ice breaking operations"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Intermediate range ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Iowa"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="National Aeronautics and Space Administration"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Nature conservation"/>
    <term name="Navigation"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Ohio"/>
    <term name="Oklahoma"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Railroad Retirement Board"/>
    <term name="Railroad facilities"/>
    <term name="Railroad terminals"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Supplemental appropriations"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Synthetic fibers"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Waste water treatment"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watershed management"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Waterways"/>
    <term name="Widows"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/1988--Introduced.
Emergency Supplemental Appropriations Act, 1988 - Title I: Program Supplementals - Chapter I - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to the Department of Commerce for the Bureau of the Census. Appropriates supplemental FY 1988 amounts for activities of the Judiciary, including: (1) the Supreme Court; (2) the U.S. Court of Appeals for the Federal Circuit; (3) the U.S. Court of International Trade; (4) the Courts of Appeals, district courts, and other judicial services; (5) the Administrative Office of the United States Courts; and (6) the Federal Judicial Center. Makes supplemental appropriations to the Department of Transportation's Maritime Administration. Amends the Departments of Commerce, Justice, and State, the Judiciary, and Related Agencies Appropriation Act, 1988 to revise appropriations to the Board for International Broadcasting. Makes supplemental appropriations for drug law enforcement activities of the Department of Justice and to the Judiciary for the processing of drug-related cases. Chapter II - Provides for limited transfers of funds from Department of Defense accounts to the Federal Bureau of Investigation to fund increased work load relating to Intermediate-range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty implementation. Reduces amounts available for operation of a C-130E unit at McChord Air Force Base, Washington. Chapter III - Directs the Secretary of the Army, through the Chief of Engineers, to undertake specific activities to address the problems of the Mississippi River Basin. Appropriates supplemental FY 1988 amounts for: (1) water supply emergency relief in Louisiana; (2) the preparation of regional drought management plans; (3) various flood control projects; (4) general investigations; and (5) operation and maintenance. Revises a current navigation project for the Atchafalaya River and Bayous Chene, Boeuf, and Black, in Louisiana. Directs the Secretary of the Army to permit the city of Aberdeen, Washington, to operate the project for Wynoochee Reservoir, Wynoochee River, Washington, effective October 1, 1988, subject to prescribed conditions. Provides for the transfer of land at Sardis Lake, in Latimer County, Oklahoma. Authorizes the Army Corps of Engineers to exchange land located along the Snake River with the Port of Whitman County, Washington. Prohibits the use of any appropriations to initiate legal action with respect to recreational facilities at Arcadia Lake, Oklahoma. States the conditions under which the Santa Ana River project in California shall proceed. Provides funding for an icebreaking boat and equipment in connection with the Kankakee River project in Illinois. Directs the Secretary of the Army to: (1) construct flood reduction measures along specified shoreline of Lake Michigan in Chicago, Illinois; (2) undertake a project study of Buffalo Harbor, New York; (3) pursue projects in Waterloo, Iowa, Ste. Genevieve, Missouri (flood control), Sims Park, Euclid, Ohio (beach erosion control), Kissimee River, Florida (demonstration project), and Monroe County, Florida; (4) continue with the development of the Cross Florida National Conservation Area; and (5) resume construction on the Wallisville Lake project in Texas. Chapter IV - Makes additional FY 1988 appropriations, through transfers of funds, to the Department of Housing and Urban Development for operations of low-income housing projects. Exempts treatment works operated by Gulf Coast Waste Disposal Authority and its industrial users from certain Environmental Protection Agency pretreatment standards for the organic chemicals and plastics and synthetic fibers category of point sources. Prescribes conditions that must be met to qualify for the exemption. Appropriates supplemental FY 1988 amounts to: (1) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA); (2) the National Aeronautics and Space Administration, derived through fund transfers; and (3) the Veterans Administration. Restricts activities of the Director of FEMA with respect to flood insurance related issues pertaining to Sacramento, California. Amends the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1988 to repeal a provision limiting funds available for veterans' medical care. Chapter V - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to the Department of Agriculture's Forest Service. Chapter VI - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to: (1) the Department of Labor's Employment and Training Administration, through fund transfers; (2) the Department of Health and Human Services for the Social Services Block Grant program; (3) the Department of Education for student financial assistance, with amounts made available by amendment of the Department of Education Appropriations Act, 1988; and (4) the Railroad Retirement Board. Rescinds amounts previously appropriated in connection with specified activities of: (1) the Department of Labor; (2) the Department of Health and Human Services; and (3) the National Institutes of Health. Chapter VII - Appropriates amounts to the House of Representatives for payments to specified widows of deceased Members of Congress. Chapter VIII - Makes supplemental FY 1988 appropriations to the Department of Transportation for the Office of the Secretary. Reduces amounts available for airway science programs of the Federal Aviation Administration. Rescinds certain FY 1988 funds apportioned to the District of Columbia under the Federal-aid Highway program. Makes available additional appropriations, to remain available through FY 1989, to the Federal Railroad Administration, including a transfer of funds, solely to purchase title to Washington Union Station. Appropriates funds to the Mass Transit Capital Fund of the Urban Mass Transportation Administration to pay obligations incurred in connection with a mandated bus testing program. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to transfer the Coast Guard Cutter "Ingham" to the Intrepid Sea-Air-Space Museum in New York, New York, for use as a Coast Guard museum and display. Prohibits funds from being used in connection with specified highway facility projects. Title II: Special Supplemental Appropriation to Enhance and Speed up the War on Illegal Drugs - Appropriates to the President from unappropriated Treasury amounts, to remain available until expended, funds to be transferred to Federal departments and agencies for activities that combat the production, distribution, and use of illegal drugs, treat addicts, or foster international anti-drug cooperation. Restricts the use of these funds to anti-drug endeavors. Declares the war against illegal drugs to be a dire emergency. Exempts these amounts from funding limitations under budgetary rules, resolutions, and agreements. Title III: General Provisions - Limits the availability for obligation of these appropriations to the current fiscal year, unless expressly provided in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
