<bill session="100" type="h" number="5092" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Presidential Directives and Records Accountability Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide accountability in the use of presidential directives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401837"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-03">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" name="House Government Operations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidential records"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Records management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/26/1988--Introduced.
Presidential Directives and Records Accountability Act - Defines an "executive directive" to mean any written instrument, other than a Presidential proclamation or executive order, that: (1) is signed or endorsed by, or is issued at the direction of, the President or an appointee in the Executive Office of the President; and (2) establishes policy, directs the carrying out of law or policy, authorizes or requires the use of appropriated funds or other resources (including personnel), or otherwise asserts or appears to assert an authority of the President. Provides that an executive directive does not include a finding with respect to intelligence activities. Sets forth requirements for filing such directives with the Office of the Federal Register, the Archivist of the United States, the Speaker of the House of Representatives, and the President pro tempore of the Senate. Provides for informing employees in the Executive Office of the President or Vice President of the requirements of this Act. Establishes an Office of Records Management in the Executive Office of the President to be responsible for securing compliance with this Act. Declares that the Archivist has the final authority in the executive branch to determine what constitutes a record for records management purposes.</summary>
</bill>
