<bill session="100" type="h" number="5106" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 10, United States Code, to prohibit the use of certain inside information in the award of any contract with the Department of Defense, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405524"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400003" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="401363" joined="1988-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400542" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402454" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408342" joined="1988-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="411834" joined="1988-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civilian personnel positions"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Defense procurement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information leaking"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1988--Introduced.
Prohibits covered defense officials who are participating in procurement functions in connection with contracts of at least $25,000 to be awarded by the Department of Defense (DOD) from disclosing to any contractor: (1) any unauthorized information regarding the bids of competing contractors; or (2) any information concerning the proprietary data of competing contractors or which may afford a contractor an advantage over competing contractors. Prohibits a competing contractor from knowingly receiving such information. Prescribes civil and criminal penalties for such prohibited conduct. Requires the Secretary of Defense or the Secretary of the military department concerned to terminate any contract with any contractor who has been convicted for a violation of this Act, unless the Secretary of Defense determines that such termination would be inconsistent with national security interests. Directs the Secretary to award a contract for any work remaining to be done under a terminated contract to the most qualified offeror who submitted a bid in the original competition for such contract if: (1) such contract is terminated two years or less after the award of the contract; (2) the offeror is willing to carry out the work for such contract near the same cost and level of quality as proposed in the original competition; and (3) the award is consistent with national security interests.</summary>
</bill>
