<bill session="100" type="h" number="5108" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Kendall Square Project Redevelopment and Real Property Reconveyance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Cambridge Redevelopment Authority to acquire and redevelop land within the Kendall Square Urban Renewal Project Area for housing and accessory uses and to direct the Secretary of Transportation to reconvey certain disposable real property in the Project Area to the Cambridge Redevelopment Authority for such purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="Moderate income housing"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Urban renewal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1988--Introduced.
Kendall Square Project Redevelopment and Real Property Reconveyance Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to consent to an extension to August 30, 2000, of certain provisions of the Urban Renewal Plan and restrictions, agreements, and convenants of the deeds of conveyance applicable to certain property within the Kendall Square Urban Renewal Project Area conveyed to the United States by the Cambridge Redevelopment Authority of Massachusetts. Requires the Secretary, within six months of the enactment of this Act, to reconvey such disposable real property to the Authority. Directs the Authority to prepare and carry out a master plan for developing and reusing such property. Requires the plan to include the making of appropriate demolition, alterations, public improvements, and sale or lease of the property for housing and accessory uses. Provides that no less than 30 percent of the housing units shall be for low- and moderate-income persons and families who will pay no more than 25 percent of their annual incomes for yearly rental. Requires the Authority to pay the fair market value of such property to the Federal Government. Directs the Authority to cooperate with the Department of Transportation to secure additional space, if needed, for expansion of the Department's functions and facilities within the project area. Requires the Secretary to ensure that the current number of parking spaces continue to be made available to employees of the Department at the project area and that adequate facilities for the Department's warehousing, shipping, and receiving functions continue to be provided within the project area. Relieves the United States, upon reconveyance of the disposal real property, of all obligations to develop such property.</summary>
</bill>
