<bill session="100" type="h" number="5113" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cigarette Restrictions Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that the advertising and promotion of tobacco products and the sale of tobacco products in vending machines violates the Federal Trade Commission Act, to amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to authorize a continuing study of tobacco smoke, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406994"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400882" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="401231" joined="1988-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300011" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404006" joined="1988-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1988-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400611" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="411585" joined="1988-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health warnings"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1988--Introduced.
Cigarette Restrictions Act of 1988 - Declares that consumer sales promotion of tobacco products is an unfair or deceptive act or practice under the Federal Trade Commission Act. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to issue regulations defining such unlawful acts or practices. Prohibits the sale of tobacco products unless sold over the counter in an establishment in which is posted a sign stating the sale of cigarettes to minors is strictly prohibited. Repeals provisions of the Federal Cigarette Labeling and Advertising Act exempting cigarettes manufactured, imported, or packaged for export from the requirements of such Act. Requires the FTC to conduct a continuing study of the constituents of tobacco smoke, including: (1) random testing of cigarettes to determine the amounts of tar, nicotine, carbon monoxide, and other constituents; and (2) an analysis of the levels of cigarette smoke constituents when people change their smoking behavior to compensate for lower levels of nicotine. Directs the FTC to: (1) arrange for a laboratory of the Government or a private, non-profit laboratory with no connection to a tobacco company to conduct the study; (2) as a condition to the arrangement, require such laboratory to conduct similar studies for private non-profit groups; and (3) report annually to the Congress on the results. Declares that State tort systems should be allowed to treat cigarettes like any other product even though warning labels are required and States are prohibited from requiring additional warning labels. Provides that States are not prevented from regulating the sales, distribution, or promotion of cigarettes. Requires cigarette packages to bear a warning label stating that nicotine in cigarettes is addictive, with specified format requirements, and in both English and the language of any country in which an exporter reasonably expects the cigarette to be sold. Makes this Act applicable with respect to cigarettes manufactured after one year after the date of the enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
