<bill session="100" type="h" number="5110" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus McKinney Homeless Assistance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act to extend programs providing urgently needed assistance for the homeless, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404193"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-28">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-03">
      <text>House Incorporated this Measure in H.R.4352 as an Amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4352"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Census"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Hotels, motels, etc."/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interagency Council on the Homeless"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Minnesota"/>
    <term name="Mortgages"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Rent control"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Single family housing"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban areas"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1988--Introduced.
Omnibus McKinney Homeless Assistance Act of 1988 - Title I: General Provisions - Amends the Stewart B. McKinney Homeless Assistance Act (the Act) to require the Comptroller General to make annual audits of Federal emergency management food and shelter and housing assistance programs. Title II: Interagency Council on the Homeless - Amends the Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1990 for the Interagency Council on the Homeless. Extends such Council through FY 1990. Title III: Federal Emergency Management Food and Shelter Program - Amends the Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1990 for the Federal emergency management food and shelter program. Title IV: Housing Assistance - Amends the Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1990 for the emergency shelter grants program. Requires the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development (Secretary) to report annually to the Congress regarding the supportive housing demonstration program. Authorizes program appropriations through FY 1990. Authorizes appropriations through FY 1990 for supplemental assistance for facilities to assist the homeless. Increases budget authority for section 8 assistance (low-income housing) for single room occupancy dwellings. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress regarding the effect of rent control on urban homelessness. Title V: Identification and Use of Surplus Federal Property - Amends the Act to require the Secretary to identify Federal properties to use to aid the homeless within two months of collecting such information. Title VI: Revision and Extension of Programs of Health Care for the Homeless - Subtitle A: Categorical Grants for Primary Health Services and Substance Abuse Services - Amends the Public Health Service Act to limit Federal matching funds after the first fiscal year to 66-2/3 percent of service costs with regard to grants for health assistance for the homeless. (Current law provides for 75 percent Federal funding.) Authorizes the continued provision for up to 12 months of certain health (including mental health) services to former homeless persons currently living in permanent housing. Includes persons living in transitional housing within the definition of "homeless individual" for purposes of such grants. Authorizes appropriations for such grants through FY 1991. Subtitle B: Block Grant for Community Mental Health Services - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1991 for community mental health services block grants. Directs the Secretary to: (1) make grants to the States on a competitive basis if annual appropriations are insufficient for minimum allotments; and (2) make unallotted State funds available to public and private nonprofit agencies for mental health services to the homeless in such State. Makes Guam, the Virgin Islands, American Samoa, and the Northern Mariana Islands eligible for mental health services allotments. Sets minimum allotments at $50,000 for Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands. Subtitle C: Authorization of Appropriations for Community Demonstration Projects - Amends the Act to authorize additional appropriations through FY 1991 for mental health services for homeless persons with chronic mental illness. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1991 for alcohol and drug abuse treatment for homeless persons. Subtitle D: General Provisions - Sets forth effective dates for specified provisions of this title. Title VII: Education, Training, and Community Services Programs - Amends the Act to authorize appropriations through FY 1990 for the following programs for the homeless: (1) adult education; (2) education for children and youth; (3) exemplary education programs and related information dissemination; (4) job training, including a specified obligation for veterans' reintegration projects; and (5) the emergency community services homeless grant program. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1936 to make homeless women eligible for the special supplemental food program (WIC). Title VIII: Veterans Programs - Authorizes additional appropriations through FY 1990 for veterans' medical care, including specified amounts for domiciliary care and for chronically mentally ill homeless veterans. Title IX: Aid to Families With Dependent Children; Unemployment Compensation - Amends the Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1987 to extend through September 30, 1989, the prohibition on implementation of certain regulations proposed by the Secretary of Health and Human Services regarding the use of aid to families with dependent children (AFDC) funds to meet emergency AFDC family needs either through emergency assistance or special needs payments. Directs the Secretary to: (1) review policies governing the use of AFDC funds; and (2) report to the Congress by April 1, 1989, regarding improvements in AFDC's ability to respond to emergency needs of eligible families and the elimination of the use of AFDC funds in commercial or similar transient shelters (welfare hotels). Authorizes up to five demonstration projects to reduce the number of homeless AFDC families in such hotels and increase the use of transitional facilities to house such families. Title X: Technical and Conforming Amendments to Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 - Subtitle A: Housing Assistance - Amends the United States Housing Act of 1937 to prohibit owners from skipping over lower income families for purposes of assisted housing eligibility. Permits child care grants to be awarded to facilities near (as well as in) public housing projects. Restores certain section 8 rents that were reduced after April 15, 1987. Permits Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) funded housing counseling for owners of Veterans Administration guaranteed or insured homes. Amends the Housing and Community Development Amendments of 1978 to obligate funds from the flexible subsidy program for multifamily housing capital improvements. Requires 50 percent of funds recaptured from the refinancing of a State financed section 8 project to be used for very low income housing. Exempts a HUD contract with the Minneapolis Community Development Agency (Cedar Square West Project) from certain multifamily housing management provisions. Subtitle B: Preservation of Low Income Housing - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1987 to require an owner of certain low-income housing to submit his intent to prepay a mortgage and his plan of action for such prepayment to the tenants. Requires tenant consultation prior to plan approval. Provides incentives to extend low-income use only when low-income restrictions are extended through the mortgage term. Includes a limit on the amount of rent increases among the criteria necessary for approval of a plan of action. Subtitle C: Rural Housing - Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to repeal the provision limiting rent increases in the low-income rural rental housing program. Makes farm labor housing available for other low-income families in areas where there is no longer a need for farm labor housing. Subtitle D: Mortgage Insurance and Secondary Mortgage Market Programs - Amends the National Housing Act to permit an investor to refinance an insured single family mortgage if monthly mortgage payments are reduced (thus exempting such investor from certain occupancy requirements). States, with regard to procedures applicable to assumption of insured mortgages under the National Housing Act, that: (1) credit reviews shall be made starting from the date on which the mortgage is executed (currently from the date of endorsement). Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to direct the Secretary to: (1) accept Veterans Administration certificates of reasonable value for one or more properties in a subdivision as administrative approval for the entire subdivision for a one-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act; and (2) before the end of such period, report to the Congress regarding housing subdivision approval practices of the Veterans Administration, and HUD. Makes permanent the authority of the Federal National Mortgage Association and the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation to purchase multifamily second mortgages. Subtitle E: Community Development and Miscellaneous Programs - Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to repeal the provision requiring HUD to use 1980 census data to determine loss of entitlement status for metropolitan cities and urban counties. Permits the use of community development block grant funds to pay the assessments required of low and moderate income homeowners to recover the capital cost of public improvements.</summary>
</bill>
