<bill session="100" type="h" number="5128" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Western Hemisphere Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of a Western Hemisphere Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403695"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA02" subcommittee="International Operations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="International education"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
    <term name="Western Hemisphere"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/2/1988--Introduced.
Western Hemisphere Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange Act of 1988 - Requires the Director of the United States Information Agency to establish a Western Hemisphere Center for Cultural and Technical Interchange. Provides that the Center shall serve as an institution where western hemisphere scholars and students may meet, study, conduct research and seminars, and pursue other activities promoting the international educational, cultural, and related activities of the United States. Requires the Center to be organized in two branches: one located in Puerto Rico and devoted to the study of Spanish-speaking peoples of the western hemisphere; the second located in the Virgin Islands and devoted to the study of English-speaking people in the hemisphere. Requires the Director to provide grants, fellowships, and other payments to attract western hemisphere scholars and to enable students to study at the Center. Authorizes the Director to accept money and property from public and private sources to carry out the functions of the Center. Requires the Director to report annually to the Congress on the operation of the Center. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
