<bill session="100" type="h" number="513" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Coal Trade Equalization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to offset the competitive advantage which foreign producers have as a result of not having to meet environmental, health, welfare, and safety requirements of the kinds imposed on United States coal producers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400331"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401417" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406461" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400281" joined="1987-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="408632" joined="1987-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from State, Treasury, Commerce, Labor,, Interior, ITC, USTR.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Mining and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-13">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From ITC.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSII02" subcommittee="Mining and Natural Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Colombia"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1987--Introduced.
Coal Trade Equalization Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to investigate and report to the Congress on the relationship between coal imports and: (1) the management of the Federal coal leasing program; and (2) the economic condition of the U.S. coal industry. Directs the Secretary to include in such report appropriate legislative recommendations if coal imports are adversely affecting the management of the Federal coal leasing program and the economic condition of one or more sectors of the U.S. coal industry. Amends the Tariff Schedules of the United States to grant duty-free treatment of: (1) coal from any country that has historically imported more coal from the United States than it has exported to the United States; and (2) coal produced in Colombia and imported into Puerto Rico. Imposes a duty on coal imported from other countries. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to add coal subject to such duty to the list of articles which cannot be designated as eligible articles for the Generalized System of Tariff Preferences.</summary>
</bill>
