<bill session="100" type="h" number="5148" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for compensation with respect to former members of the Armed Forces of the United States for each day spent avoiding capture by hostile forces or as underground fighters while unattached to any regular unit of the Armed Forces during World War II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409534"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1988-10-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Guerrilla warfare"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/3/1988--Introduced.
Amends the War Claims Act of 1948 to authorize the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission of the United States to provide for the payment of claims filed by underground fighters. Defines an "underground fighter" as any individual who: (1) as a member of the U.S. armed forces between December 7, 1941, and August 16, 1945, served as a guerrilla fighter resisting forces hostile to the United States or concealed himself from a hostile force for more than ten days while in danger of capture or after escaping as a prisoner of war; (2) is, or was at death, a U.S. citizen, national, or permanent resident alien; and (3) was never separated from the U.S. armed forces, except under honorable conditions. Provides that the compensation allowed to any underground fighter shall be five dollars for each day he served as a guerrilla fighter or concealed himself from hostile forces. Provides that any claim allowed by the Commission shall be certified to the Secretary of the Treasury and paid by such Secretary. Declares that any claim must be filed with the Commission within one year after enactment of this Act. Requires the Commission to complete its determination for any such claim no later than one year after such claim is filed. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
