<bill session="100" type="h" number="5161" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Equality and Annuities for Claims Court Judges Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide to Claims Court judges pay equality with judges of the United States Tax Court, to provide retirement and survivors' annuities for Claims Court judges, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406191"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400043" joined="1988-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1988-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Cost of living adjustments"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Practice of law"/>
    <term name="Retirement"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1988--Introduced.
Pay Equality and Annuities for Claims Court Judges Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal judicial code to set the salary of U.S. Claims Court judges at the same rate, and in the same installments, as that of U.S. Tax Court judges. Initiates a retirement program for Claims Court judges aged 65 or older, basing annuities upon specified age and length of service criteria, as determined in accordance with this Act. Includes provisions to cover retirement due to disability and cost-of-living adjustments. Precludes judges who elect this new annuity program from receiving civil service retirement benefits. Sets forth the administrative features of the annuity plan, requiring withholding of three percent of salary, to be credited to the Claims Court Judges' Retirement Fund. Declares that any retired judge who practices law after retirement forfeits all rights to an annuity, except, if the judge files an irrevocable election to retire and practice law under certain conditions, the judge is entitled to an amount equal to his or her entitlement prior to the election. Permits lump-sum payments under certain circumstances. Establishes in the Treasury the Claims Court Judges' Retirement Fund and authorizes appropriations for its funding. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to invest Fund monies in U.S. securities. Initiates an annuity program for Claims Court judges under the civil service retirement system and sets forth administrative features of the program. Permits lump-sum payments under certain circumstances. Assures survivors' annuities with respect to survivors of Claims Court judges who retire under the new systems instituted in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
