<bill session="100" type="h" number="5165" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Airways Systems Specialists Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the recruitment and retention of airways systems specialists.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407816"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-12">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from OMB, OPM, DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Compensation and Employee Benefits.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Aviation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO02" subcommittee="Compensation and Employee Benefits" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO04" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW05" subcommittee="Aviation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1988--Introduced.
National Airways Systems Specialists Act of 1989 - Amends Federal law regarding merit systems principles to direct the Secretary of Transportation to take necessary action to ensure that a specified minimum number of airways systems specialists are employed by the Department of Transportation by certain deadlines. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress if such minimum requirements are not met, citing the reasons for such noncompliance, and the steps proposed to ensure compliance. Directs the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) to review within six months after enactment of this Act whether the Departments of Defense and Transportation are placing systems-specialist positions in classes and grades conforming to published standards and to take any corrective action necessary. Requires OPM to report to the Congress (and to the Secretaries of Transportation and Defense) the results of a mandated review of training and promotion procedures and special pay rates for airways systems specialists. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to ensure that at least 75 percent of all systems specialists employed by the Department by September 30, 1992, are at the journeyman level and to submit a written report to the Congress if such requirement has not been met. Mandates that: (1) the overtime hourly rate of pay for airways systems specialists equal one and one half times the hourly basic pay; (2) all such amount be premium pay; and (3) standby status entitle such specialists to premium pay at specified maximum levels. Directs OPM to prescribe regulations regarding home leave for airways systems specialists attending the Federal Aviation Administration Academy for specified lengths of stay. Prescribes a minimum per diem allowance for the training period at such Academy.</summary>
</bill>
