<bill session="100" type="h" number="5178" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Closed-Captioned Television Services for the Hearing-Impaired Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that certain Federal entities and certain non-Federal entities receiving Federal financial assistance provide television sets capable of displaying closed-captioning, to prohibit Federal funding of conferences held at certain places of public accommodation which do not provide guests with guest rooms furnished with televisions capable of displaying closed-captioning, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401585"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400527" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408621" joined="1988-08-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Veterans' Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Government Activities and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Select Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED04" subcommittee="Select Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO03" subcommittee="Government Activities and Transportation" name="House Government Operations"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSVR" name="House Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Convention facilities"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Educational television"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to vocational education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Hotels, motels, etc."/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intermediate care facilities"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Soldiers' homes"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Surveys"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/8/1988--Introduced.
Closed-Captioned Television Services for the Hearing-Impaired Act of 1988 - Amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act to permit participation in the Medicaid and Medicare programs only to hospitals which certify that each patient is provided, upon request, with a room furnished with a television capable of displaying closed-captioning and that notice of this service is given to the patient at the time of admission. Exempts hospitals that do not make televisions available to patients. Institutes comparable requirements for nursing care facilities and intermediate care facilities for the mentally retarded, requiring that televisions in common areas of the relevant facility be capable of displaying closed-captioning. Amends the Public Health Service Act and other Federal law to institute the same requirements for Public Health Service facilities and for hospitals, nursing homes, and domiciliary facilities under the direct jurisdiction of the Veterans Administration. Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to require institutions of higher education and vocational schools, in order to be eligible for student assistance programs, to certify that televisions capable of displaying closed-captioning are available for use in classrooms and common areas, unless the Secretary of Education determines that waiver or modification is appropriate. Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to require any local educational agency conducting programs that include television program viewing to certify that the televisions used are capable of displaying closed-captioning, unless the Secretary of Education determines that waiver or modification is appropriate. Directs all Federal entities that use television or video programming to provide public information or educational services to make reasonable efforts to caption the programming and make it available to the general public and to organizations that serve the hearing-impaired. Prohibits Federal funding of conferences, seminars, or similar activities held in a public lodging establishment that does not, upon request, provide guests with rooms furnished with televisions capable of displaying closed-captioning. Permits the Secretary of the Treasury to waive this prohibition if the entity sponsoring or funding the event certifies that the waiver would be appropriate. Requires federally funded or federally sponsored public service announcements to be closed-captioned.</summary>
</bill>
