<bill session="100" type="h" number="5172" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs Relocation Incentives Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a tax credit to corporations equal to 55 percent of the cost of relocating certain foreign operations to labor surplus areas in the United States, and to partially recover such tax benefits if relocated foreign operations is terminated with 5 years after commencement.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1988-10-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407432" joined="1988-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International corporations"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Location of industries"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1988--Introduced.
Jobs Relocation Incentives Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit an income tax credit to a corporation for qualified expenses incurred in discontinuing a wholly-owned foreign operation and relocating its activity to a U.S. labor surplus area within two years. Requires the business activity to employ at least 500 individuals full time. Permits a ten percent credit for the first taxable year and five percent for the nine succeeding years. Disallows the credit if bankruptcy results from the relocation or if employee numbers decrease to a specified threshold within five years of the new operation's commencement. Recaptures credit amounts if the corporation ceases operation of the new domestic enterprise within five years of its beginning. Terminates the credit five years after this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
