<bill session="100" type="h" number="5188" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Commerce to make grants for operation of export promotion vessels, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400440"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-19">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT, Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Merchant Marine.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM06" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal aid programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/9/1988--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of Commerce to make grants to operators of eligible vessels for export promotion and facilitation activities, including: (1) exhibition, promotion, and facilitation of sales in foreign countries; (2) establishment of dealer and distributor networks; (3) establishment and maintenance of a computerized directory of goods and services manufactured or produced in the United States; (4) maintenance of a team of technical and sales personnel to represent goods and services exhibited on the vessel; and (5) operation and maintenance of the vessel. Includes among eligibility criteria a requirement that a vessel have areas specifically designed for exhibitions, conferences, seminars, training activities, and workshop facilities. Prohibits using vessels for unrelated activities. Directs the Secretary to provide technical assistance to grant recipients. Provides for inspections of vessels.</summary>
</bill>
