<bill session="100" type="h" number="5195" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Excellence in Career Management Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to increase the productivity of the Government by promoting excellence in Federal career employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409650"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Post Office and Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Civil Service.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPO" name="House Post Office and Civil Service" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPO03" subcommittee="Civil Service" name="House Post Office and Civil Service"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Civil service system"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Rating of employees"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Excellence in Career Management Act - Amends Federal law to direct the Office of Personnel Management to establish a qualifications review board to certify the executive qualifications of candidates for initial appointment as career appointees. (Currently the Office has the authority to establish one or more such boards.) Authorizes an agency to pay from its appropriations a geographic relocation benefit to any career appointee reassigned to a Senior Executive Service position outside the career appointee's commuting area, if such individual agrees to serve in the Government for 12 months after such reassignment. Provides that any days (not to exceed a total of 60) during which a career appointee serves a detail or other temporary assignment apart from such appointee's regular position shall not be counted in determining the number of days that have elapsed from such individual's initial appointment. Directs the Office to provide appropriate informational services and otherwise encourage career appointees to take advantage of any opportunities relating to: (1) sabbaticals; (2) training; or (3) details or other temporary assignments in other agencies, State or local government, or the private sector. Changes from biennial to annual the report by the Office to the Congress on the Senior Executive Service. Requires the Office to include in such report information on applications for sabbaticals. Requires the head of an agency to establish a fellowship program for individuals pursuing post-secondary degrees in fields of study for which the agency requires proficiency or expertise. Sets forth general requirements, including work requirements, for participation in such program. Directs the Office to establish regulations for training programs for members of the Senior Executive Service, supervisors, and management officials. Provides for adjusting the presidential rank award amounts by percentage adjustments in the rates of pay under the General Schedule. Requires the Director to establish and periodically consult with: (1) a panel of career appointees recognized for their knowledge, interest, and experience with respect to matters of executive management, or for the excellence of their performance as senior executives; and (2) a panel of employees holding career appointments in the civil service and recommended by labor organizations or other organizations representing the interests of employees.</summary>
</bill>
