<bill session="100" type="h" number="5194" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide certain public and private entities with an opportunity for a waiver of the liability resulting from the sale of a medical facility with respect to which funds were received pursuant to title VI of the Public Health Service Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400552" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1988-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Municipal buildings"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Declares that, if the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies compliance with conditions of this title, provisions of the Public Health Service Act imposing liability in the nature of recovery by the Government of funds provided for the construction or modernization of medical facilities shall not apply to the sale of a specified facility in San Juan County, Utah, on November 26, 1986. Sets forth the conditions which must be met, including: that (1) the transferor county, a political subdivision of the State of Utah, establishes and administers an irrevocable trust to satisfy, with respect to such facility, its obligation under Federal laws and regulations to provide for adequate facilities to furnish needed services for persons unable to pay; and (2) the transferee corporation agrees to satisfy the obligation of the county to provide such services for persons unable to pay. Directs the Secretary to make such determination within 12 months after enactment of this Act and to certify the determination to the Congress. Directs the Secretary to monitor compliance and, if conditions are not met or either party fails to carry out its duties, to ensure that proceedings are commenced to recover the amounts as provided by current law.</summary>
</bill>
