<bill session="100" type="h" number="5205" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Biennial Budgeting Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Congressional Budget Act of 1974 to provide for a two-year budgeting cycle, to provide for separate and timely consideration of authorizing legislation, budget resolutions, and appropriations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408457"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400334" joined="1988-08-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Legislation and National Security.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSGO06" subcommittee="Legislation and National Security" name="House Government Operations"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget process"/>
    <term name="Entitlements"/>
    <term name="Federal budget process"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Government consultants"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Introduced.
Biennial Budgeting Act of 1988 - Amends the Congressional Budget Act of 1974, including provisions of the Congressional Budget and Impoundment Control Act of 1974, to revise the Federal and congressional budget processes by establishing a two-year budgeting and appropriations cycle and timetable, beginning in the 101st Congress. Defines the budget biennium as the two consecutive fiscal years beginning on October 1 of any odd-numbered year. Devotes the first session of any Congress to the budget resolution and to appropriations decisions, retaining current deadlines in most cases, specifying the year as the odd-numbered year. Changes relevant deadlines as follows to conform the congressional budget process to the biennial scheme: (1) from April 1 to March 31 for the Senate Budget Committee's report of the concurrent resolution on the budget; (2) from June 15 to September 30 for completion of congressional action on reconciliation legislation; and (3) from June 30 to September 30 for completion of congressional action on appropriations bills. Devotes each second session to authorization activity, subject to deadlines of: (1) May 15 for the submission of the Congressional Budget Office (CBO) report to the Budget Committees; and (2) the last day of the session for completion of congressional action on bills and resolutions authorizing new budget authority for the next biennium. Sets March 31 of this year as the deadline for revisions of the President's budget recommendations of the previous year. Changes from January 15 to February 15 of each year the date by which the CBO Director must submit to the Congress a report on authorizations. Applies current law with respect to each year in the biennium in connection with: (1) CBO duties; (2) committee allocations, including restrictions on points of order; (3) the requirement prohibiting consideration of legislation providing new budget authority, spending authority, or changes in revenues or of the public debt limit prior to agreement on the concurrent budget resolution; (4) revisions of budget resolutions; and (5) procedures for consideration of budget resolutions. Requires the Committee on Appropriations of the House of Representatives to report to the House by June 10 of any odd-numbered year all regular appropriations bills providing new budget authority for the biennium beginning on October 1 of that year. Applies this provision as of noon on January 3, 1991. Requires the Director of the CBO to issue four-year projections of congressional budget action. (Current projections are on a five-year basis.) Conforms to the biennial budget framework provisions concerning: (1) agreement of new budget authority, new spending authority, and revenue legislation with appropriate levels specified in the concurrent budget resolution; and (2) parallel agreement in connection with legislation providing entitlement authority. Revises the extent of projections to be included in CBO analyses of reported bills. Conforms provisions governing the President's budget, including maximum deficit amount requirements, to the biennial framework. Directs the President to transmit any budget revisions to the Congress by March 1 of each even-numbered year. Changes the due date for the President's report of estimated budget outlays and proposed budget authority, making the report due at the same time as the President's budget. Requires the Joint Economic Committee to submit its evaluation of these estimates by February 25 of each odd-numbered year. (The current annual deadline is March 1). Amends Federal law to conform to the biennial framework provisions relating to: (1) year-ahead requests for authorizing legislation; and (2) budget information on consulting services. Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to conform to the biennial framework.</summary>
</bill>
