<bill session="100" type="h" number="5213" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:10-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Equity Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide assistance to families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300029"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Dual-career families"/>
    <term name="Earnings"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Individual retirement accounts"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance premiums"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Married people"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Pension funds"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad retirement plans"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Retirement income"/>
    <term name="Saving and investment"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax exemption"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Introduced.
Family Equity Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual taxpayer a refundable income tax credit, in an amount based on adjusted gross income (minimum credit of $150), for each dependent below the age of compulsory school attendance in the State where the taxpayer resides. Sets the maximum credit amount as the total employee tax withheld from the taxpayer's wages during the year under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act. Increases to $2,900 the amount permitted as a deduction for personal exemptions. Repeals the employment-related dependent care tax credit as of tax year 1989. Revises the earned income tax credit to: (1) increase from $5,714 to $7,143 the amount of earned income subject to the credit; and (2) increase the credit percentage incrementally from 14 percent to 35 percent, adjusted annually for inflation, as the number of the taxpayer's dependent children increases from one to four or more. Repeals provisions of the Tax Reform Act of 1986 that eliminated the income tax deduction for two-earner married couples. Repeals provisions: (1) that limit the tax deduction for participation in certain pension plans; and (2) governing nondeductible contributions to individual retirement plans. Excludes from the gross income of an individual any amounts distributed out of an individual retirement plan that are: (1) used within 60 days of receipt to pay long-term care expenses of the taxpayer, spouse, or dependent; (2) used to pay the educational expenses of a student at an institution of higher education or postsecondary vocational school; or (3) used within 60 days of receipt by an individual in connection with the acquisition of a first principal residence. Permits an income tax deduction for expenditures of the taxpayer to provide otherwise uncompensated custodial care for a parent, grandparent, or dependent aged 65 or older. Excepts this deduction from the two percent floor limitation. Excludes all Social Security and Tier 1 railroad retirement benefits from taxable income for income tax purposes. Excludes from gross income any earnings and distributions in connection with any deposit of money with an institution of higher education intended to pay the educational expenses of a beneficiary attending the institution. Applies the exclusion only if payments or distributions are used within 60 days to pay these expenses.</summary>
</bill>
