<bill session="100" type="h" number="5214" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Low-Income Housing Revitalization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to promote the development and preservation of rental housing for low- and moderate-income families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400580"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400975" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404013" joined="1988-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="404190" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404376" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404752" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="405236" joined="1988-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400256" joined="1988-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408556" joined="1988-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1988-09-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409344" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1988-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400614" joined="1988-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business losses"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing codes"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Real estate investment"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Introduced.
Low-Income Housing Revitalization Act - Amends Internal Revenue Code (IRC) provisions relating to the low-income housing credit to: (1) increase the credit from four percent to nine percent with respect to new buildings that are federally subsidized; (2) reallocate unused credit amounts among other States for their housing credit agencies; and (3) permit carryover to the succeeding year of a housing credit amount, if it is reasonably likely that the building will be put into service then. Extends the low-income housing credit through 1991. Amends IRC accounting provisions to exempt low-income housing credit activities from limitations on passive losses. Revises the accelerated cost recovery system in connection with low-income residential rental property to reduce the applicable recovery period from 27.5 to 20 years. Disallows an income tax deduction for any expense relating to residential rental units that violate State or local building, health, or safety codes and are not brought into compliance. Requires the regulatory agency that notifies a taxpayer of the substandard conditions to file an information return with respect to affected taxpayers. Excludes deductions for business expenses, interest on indebtedness, and taxes from calculations to determine the passive loss limitation in connection with rental real estate activity relating to a qualified low-income housing project in which a noncorporate taxpayer actively or materially participates.</summary>
</bill>
