<bill session="100" type="h" number="521" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Free Political Broadcasting Act of 1985</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971, to provide free radio and television time to candidates for election to Federal office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410455"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Elections.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-02">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSHA08" subcommittee="Elections" name="House Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Congressional candidates"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Political advertising"/>
    <term name="Presidential candidates"/>
    <term name="Presidential elections"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio in politics"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television in politics"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1987--Introduced.
Free Political Broadcasting Act of 1985 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to require radio and television stations licensed under the Communications Act of 1934, community antenna television stations, and radio and television networks to provide free broadcast time to eligible candidates in congressional and presidential elections. Provides for determining the broadcast time allotments a candidate shall receive based upon the popular votes received by such candidate's party in the most recent general elections. Utilizes the popular vote counts to determine whether a party is a major, third, or minor party. Allots the most broadcast time to major party candidates and the least broadcast time to minor party candidates. Entitles an incumbent candidate of a third or minor party to the broadcast time allotment of a major party candidate. Sets forth restrictions on the use of free broadcast time. Requires such time to be available during the period beginning 30 days prior to an election and ending at the close of the day before such election. Requires 75 percent of such time to be available during prime air time. Declares that new program and public service program appearances at the invitation of the stations shall not be attributable to broadcast time allotments. Provides that the equal time rule shall not apply to the use of radio and television facilities for free broadcast time under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
