<bill session="100" type="h" number="5244" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Boxing Labor Standards Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 to provide for the establishment of an occupational safety and health standard applicable to boxing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411677"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409205" joined="1988-08-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor Standards.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and Safety.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED03" subcommittee="Labor Standards" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED05" subcommittee="Health and Safety" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism counseling"/>
    <term name="Athletes"/>
    <term name="Boxing"/>
    <term name="Career education"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse counseling"/>
    <term name="Drugs and athletes"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Professional sports"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Sports and Athletics"/>
    <term name="Sports and state"/>
    <term name="Sports injuries"/>
    <term name="Sports medicine"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Violence in sports"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Introduced.
Boxing Labor Standards Act - Directs the Secretary of Labor (the Secretary) to establish an advisory council on occupational safety and health respecting the safety of boxing. Directs the council to advise, consult with, and, within one year after enactment of this Act, make recommendations to the Secretary concerning a Federal occupational safety and health standard respecting the safety of boxing. Directs the Secretary to promulgate such standard pursuant to specified provisions of the Occupational Safety and Health Act of 1970 (the Act). Subjects any violation of such standard to specified penalties under the Act. Provides that such Federal standard shall not preempt a State standard if the State: (1) has a State Occupational Safety and Health Plan approved under the Act or has some other standard certified by the Secretary, either of which is more effective with respect to the safety of boxing than the Federal standard; (2) has a State boxing commission to regulate and enforce such standard; and (3) submits an inspection program to the Secretary for certification. Directs the Secretary to establish the Office of Boxing Standards Compliance within the Occupational Safety and Health Administration and appoint a Director of such Office. Grants such Office authority to enforce the Federal occupational safety and health standard relating to boxing, including authority to conduct inspections and investigations under the Act and to establish a passport system of boxer registration and tracking. Establishes a nonprofit corporation, the Fighters Institute for Support and Training, Incorporated (FIST) with a principal office in Washington, D.C., to: (1) provide counseling and financial support (to or for the benefit of prizefighters who lack the resources to obtain career and psychological counseling), educational scholarships, vocational training, substance abuse assistance, job placement counseling, or related assistance to prepare for and effect a successful transition to productive employment subsequent to boxing; (2) encourage, accept, and administer private donations and contributions of property or other assets to carry out the foregoing purposes; (3) make donations to, cooperate with, and assist other public or private entities and individuals who can provide such treatment, counseling, and so forth to boxers; (4) promote the education, economic, social, and physical welfare of retired prizefighters by encouraging their growth, development, readjustment, self-respect, and self-confidence; and (5) give retired boxers the opportunity to acquire the understanding and skills necessary to become productive, contributing community members. Provides for the FIST Board of Directors and its operation. Authorizes the Secretaries of Labor, Education, and Health and Human Services to award grants to FIST to assist in carrying out its purposes.</summary>
</bill>
