<bill session="100" type="h" number="5263" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-20">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Overseas Private Investment Corporation Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 with respect to the activities of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, and to make supplemental authorizations of appropriations for the Board of International Broadcasting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401585"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Reported to House by House Committee on Foreign Affairs.  Report No: 100-922.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 555.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-09-20" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="982">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 982.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Board for International Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Subsaharan Africa"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1988--Introduced.
Title I: Overseas Private Investment Corporation - Overseas Private Investment Corporation Amendments Act of 1988 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to update and increase the per capita income levels established for countries with respect to which the Overseas Private Investment Corporation is required to either give preferential consideration (the least developed countries) or restrict its activities (the higher income developing countries). Authorizes the Corporation to designate up to 25 percent of any loan from the Direct Investment Fund for use by a project sponsor in the development or adaptation in the United States of new technologies or new products or services that are likely to contribute to the economic or social development of less developed countries. Authorizes the Corporation to establish a four-year pilot program in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean Basin to assist eligible projects through the provision of limited equity capital. Requires the Corporation, in conducting such pilot project, to give preferential consideration to projects sponsored by or significantly involving U.S. small businesses or cooperatives. Authorizes the Corporation to establish a fund to be available solely for the purposes of such pilot project and to make a one-time transfer to such fund of a specified amount from its income and revenues. Requires the Corporation to undertake cooperative programs with the private insurance industry designed to enhance the private political risk insurance industry in the United States. Requires the Corporation to establish a group to advise the Corporation on the development and implementation of such cooperative programs. Requires the Corporation to include in its annual report to the Congress an assessment of such programs. Specifies the types of information to be included in such assessment. Increases the ceiling on the Corporation's investment guaranty authority. Extends the authority of the Corporation to issue investment insurance and guaranties until September 30, 1992. Removes Romania from the list of countries eligible for Corporation programs upon a finding that such programs in those countries would be in the national interest. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Corporation should continue to: (1) encourage U.S. small businesses to invest in the world's developing countries; and (2) encourage minority-owned U.S. small businesses to invest in the world's developing countries, as such businesses are well suited to the economic and social development needs of such countries. Specifies that prohibitions on U.S. assistance for Haiti during FY 1988 shall not be construed to apply with respect to the Corporation unless the prohibition specifically states that it does apply. Title II: Board for International Broadcasting - Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 to authorize appropriations to the Board for International Broadcasting for radio transmitter construction and modernization. Authorizes appropriations for the construction of a relay station in Israel.</summary>
</bill>
