<bill session="100" type="h" number="5287" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-11-19">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Panama Canal Commission Compensation Fund Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Panama Canal Commission Compensation Fund Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Panama Canal Commission Compensation Fund Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Panama Canal Commission Compensation Fund to provide for the accumulation of funds to meet the Panama Canal Commission's obligations under chapter 81 of title 5, United States Code, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400397"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404068" joined="1988-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Treasury, Labor, Panama Canal Comm.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf Discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.  Report No: 100-969.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 580.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-09-26" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Received in the Senate, read twice.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-11-10">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-11-19" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-705" type="public" datetime="1988-11-19">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-705.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Discharged" code="HSMM05" subcommittee="Panama Canal and Outer Continental Shelf" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5254"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Interoceanic canals"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal"/>
    <term name="Panama Canal Commission"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Panama Canal Commission Compensation Fund Act of 1988 - Establishes in the Treasury the Panama Canal Commission Compensation Fund (Compensation Fund). Requires the Panama Canal Commission to make deposits on a regular basis to the Compensation Fund, beginning on October 1, 1988, to accumulate an amount sufficient to cover the liability for workers' compensation benefits and other payments for the disability or death of employees of the Commission or its predecessor agencies on account of injuries sustained between October 1, 1988, and December 31, 1999. Provides for calculation of the amounts to be deposited and for investment of amounts in the Fund. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury, upon request of the Secretary of Labor, to transfer funds from the Compensation Fund to the Employees' Compensation Fund (Employees' Fund) to reimburse the Employees' Fund for the cost of such payments made on or after October 1, 1988. Directs the Secretary of Labor, upon the termination of the Commission, to make a final determination of the amounts estimated to be necessary to make such payments. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to transfer from the Compensation Fund to the Employees' Fund sufficient amounts to make such payments. Provides for handling deficiencies or surpluses in the Compensation Fund by making transfers from or to the Panama Canal Revolving Fund. Declares that specified provisions of Federal law relating to compensation for injuries for government employees continue to be the exclusive remedy for the disability or death of any employee of the Commission, or its predecessor agencies, for injuries while in the performance of duty. Amends the Panama Canal Act of 1979 to remove provisions stating that, in meetings of the Supervisory Board of the Panama Canal Commission, only one proxy may be valid at any one time. Prohibits, except as provided in the Act, funds available to the Commission from being: (1) made available to any other agency; or (2) authorized or appropriated for any function other than Commission activities.</summary>
</bill>
