<bill session="100" type="h" number="5297" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the reformulation of the Cedar Bluff Unit of the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program, Kansas, to provide for the amendment of water service and repayment contracts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII05" subcommittee="Water and Power Resources" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2678"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2678"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Aquaculture"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Kansas"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Missouri River development"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to reformulate the Cedar Bluff Unit of the Pick-Sloan Missouri Basin Program, Kansas, including reallocation of the conservation capacity of the Cedar Bluff Reservoir, to create: (1) a designated operating pool for fish, wildlife, and recreation purposes, and for groundwater recharge for environmental, domestic, municipal, industrial, and irrigation uses; and (2) a joint-use pool for flood control, water sales, fish, wildlife, and recreation purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with Kansas for the sale, use, and control of the designated operating pool (with the exception of water reserved for Russell, Kansas), and to allow Kansas to acquire use and control of water in the joint-use pool. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with Kansas for the acceptance of a specified payment and the State's commitment to pay a proportionate share of the annual operation, maintenance, and replacement charges for the Cedar Bluff Dam and Reservoir, as full satisfaction of the reimbursable cost associated with irrigation of the Cedar Bluff Unit. Requires, after the reformulation authorized by this Act, that any revenues in excess of operating expenses received from the sale of water from the Cedar Bluff Unit be allocated to pay the United States for the cost of the project. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer ownership of the fish hatchery facility at Cedar Bluff Dam and related water rights to Kansas for its use and operation. Authorizes the Secretary to transfer title to the Cedar Bluff Irrigation District headquarters located near Hays, Kansas, contingent upon the District's agreement to close down the irrigation system to the satisfaction of the Secretary at no additional cost to the United States, after which all easement rights shall revert to the owners of the land to which the easements are attached.</summary>
</bill>
