<bill session="100" type="h" number="5305" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National African-American Heritage Museum and Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of the National African-American Heritage Museum within the Smithsonian Institution and to establish a memorial to the African-American, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400240"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Libraries and Memorials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Buildings and Grounds.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA09" subcommittee="Libraries and Memorials" name="House Administration"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW04" subcommittee="Public Buildings and Grounds" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Black history"/>
    <term name="Blacks"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/1988--Introduced.
National African-American Heritage Museum and Memorial Act - Establishes in the Smithsonian Institution the National African-American Heritage Museum devoted exclusively to the history, art, and culture of African-Americans. Provides for the Museum to be directed by an independent board known as the Trustees of the National African-American Heritage Museum (Board). Requires the Board to provide for: (1) construction of the Museum; (2) its administration and maintenance; and (3) the acquisition, exhibition, and disposal of materials. Requires the Board to establish education and awareness programs, an affiliate program, and a museum management degree program. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989, 1990, and succeeding fiscal years to carry out the purposes of this Act. Declares the intent of the Congress that the Museum be completed within five years after the date of enactment of this Act. Establishes an Advisory Committee on the Museum to assist the Board in carrying out its duties.</summary>
</bill>
