<bill session="100" type="h" number="5321" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-06">PASS_OVER:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Motor Carrier Safety and Regulatory Reform Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to house">Motor Carrier Safety and Regulatory Reform Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Motor Carrier Safety and Regulatory Reform Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1984 to eliminate application of the commercial zone exemption to commercial motor vehicle safety regulations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400844"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="405006" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400189" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407772" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400299" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409442" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400374" joined="1988-09-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Hearings Held by Subcommittee on Surface Transportation Prior to Referral (Sept 16, 17, and 23, 87).  Hearings Printed:  H. Hrg. 100-28.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-27">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-27">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-27">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-29">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.  Report No: 100-1009.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-29">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 596.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-06" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1140">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1140.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>H.R. 5210 passed in Senate relating to this measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-18">
      <text>See H.R.5210.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agricultural marketing regulation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Food prices"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grocery trade"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="Liability (Law)"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle registration"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle safety"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Traffic regulations"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation insurance"/>
    <term name="Transportation safety"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Motor Carrier Safety and Regulatory Reform Act of 1988 - Title I: Motor Carrier Safety - Amends the Motor Carrier Safety Act of 1984 to prohibit the Secretary of Transportation from exempting any person or commercial motor vehicle from complying with any commercial motor vehicle safety regulation or from waiving application of such regulation solely on the grounds that the commercial carrier's operations take place entirely within a municipality or its commercial zone. (Grandfathers certain commercial motor vehicle operators who operated entirely within a municipality or its commercial zone during the one year period ending on the date of enactment of this Act.) Directs the Secretary to: (1) delay application of Federal safety regulations to foreign motor carriers in border commercial zones for a two-year period beginning on the date of enactment of this Act if certain conditions are met; and (2) report to the Congress on the need to continue such delayed application. Directs the Secretary to: (1) issue a final rule extending motor carrier safety regulations coverage to motor private carriers of passengers operating in interstate commerce; (2) implement an to education and enforcement program regarding compliance of motor private carriers of passengers with Federal motor carrier safety regulations when operating in interstate commerce. Directs the Secretary to: (1) study the hours of service regulations pertaining to commercial motor vehicle operators to determine any relationship among them, operator fatigue, and the frequency of serious accidents involving such vehicles; (2) report to the Congress regarding such study results; and (3) initiate a rulemaking proceeding regarding commercial motor vehicle operator compliance with the hours of service regulations (including the use of onboard monitoring devices to record speed, driving time, and other information). Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress any recommendations whether to make such onboard monitoring devices mandatory. Stipulates that any rule promulgated by the Secretary shall ensure that such devices are used solely for monitoring operator productivity rather than for harassment. Requires the Secretary to issue regulations establishing minimum uniform standards for a biometric identification system for commercial motor vehicle operators. Authorizes the Secretary to use specified funds to implement a pilot demonstration project using such a system. Directs the Secretary to initiate a rulemkaing proceeding regarding the use of flares as an alternative to bidirectional emergency reflective triangles. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress regarding: (1) the need for improved brake systems for commercial motor vehicle operation on the Federal-aid highway system; and (2) the results of a study on whether to make use of speed control devices mandatory for commercial motor vehicles. Directs the Secretary to: (1) initiate a rulemaking proceeding for the purpose of adopting a methodology ensuring the proper maintenance of commercial motor vehicle brake systems; and (2) issue regulations for the purpose of adopting such methodology. Authorizes the Secretary to extend for up to 24 more months the 60-month delay period granted to States before Federal pre-emption applies if a State requests such an extension to further consider adoption of safety regulations compatible with Federal law. Title II: Motor Carrier Regulatory Reform Amendments - Amends Federal motor carrier law to require foreign motor carriers to obtain a certificate of registration from the Interstate Commerce Commission (the Commission) as a condition of providing interstate transportation of property (including exempt property) in the United States. Requires a copy of such certificate to be in the carrier's vehicle any time it provides such transportation in the United States. Authorizes the Secretary to issue regulations permitting foreign motor carriers and foreign motor private carriers providing transportation of property under a registration certificate to meet Federal insurance requirements for financial responsibility only during those periods in which they provide such transportation in the United States. Repeals the requirement that the Commission report annually to the Congress on the extent to which cost savings resulting from direct sales at a food and grocery seller's shipping point are passed on to the ultimate consumer. Subjects general commodity freight forwarders to: (1) the same liability, and grants them the same limitation on liability, accorded common carriers; and (2) the same statutes of limitations for civil actions accorded common carriers.</summary>
</bill>
