<bill session="100" type="h" number="532" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Competitive Exchange Rate Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to stabilize international currency markets in support of fair global competition.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA08" subcommittee="International Finance, Trade and Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="International economic relations"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="National growth policy"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/1987--Introduced.
Competitive Exchange Rate Act of 1987 - Makes achievement of a competitive exchange rate for the dollar a top priority of the United States in international economic negotiations. Directs the President, through an international conference, to negotiate with other countries to: (1) review the existing international exchange rate system; (2) develop an agenda for reform of that system to provide for long-term exchange rate stability; and (3) recommend proposals for better coordination of macroeconomic policies of the major industrialized nations and greater stability in trade, current account balances, and the exchange rates. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to submit to the House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs and the Senate Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs a biannual report on changes in exchange rates. Sets forth specified information to be included in such reports. Directs each Committee to consult with the Secretary and report to its House on the Secretary's intended policies. Directs the Secretary to transmit to the Congress all official U.S. documents submitted to the International Monetary Fund in the course of any requested consultation with the United States and all Fund documents arising from that consultation.</summary>
</bill>
