<bill session="100" type="h" number="5369" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Bureau of Investigation First Amendment Protection Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate the conduct of the Federal Bureau of Investigation in certain matters relating to the exercise of rights protected by the first article of amendment to the Federal Constitution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403776"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1988-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1988-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Civil and Constitutional Rights.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU04" subcommittee="Civil and Constitutional Rights" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Constitution and Constitutional Amendments"/>
    <term name="Constitutional torts"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Freedom of the press"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Right of assembly"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/23/1988--Introduced.
Federal Bureau of Investigation First Amendment Protection Act of 1989 - Prohibits the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) from initiating or conducting any investigation that may involve the collection of information about the exercise by a U.S. person of first amendment rights, except as specified. Requires the Attorney General to issue guidelines for investigations covered by this Act. Sets forth standards to be followed by the FBI in the conduct of an investigation, the disposition of any records obtained, and the periodic review of open investigations. Provides a civil remedy for any person aggrieved by a violation of this Act. Waives the provisions of this Act with respect to background investigations conducted with the consent of the subject regarding: (1) nominees to judicial and executive branch positions requiring the advice and consent of the Senate; (2) employees of the Department of Justice; or (3) the granting or retention of security clearances.</summary>
</bill>
