<bill session="100" type="h" number="5388" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Utah-Federal Land Exchange Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve land ownership patterns and management of State and Federal lands in the State of Utah and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Utah"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1988--Introduced.
Utah-Federal Land Exchange Act of 1988 - Provides for a land exchange between the United States and the State of Utah, with the United States releasing to Utah certain Federal lands in exchange for State lands located within certain national parks, recreation areas, and Indian reservations. Requires the lands transferred to Utah to be used for: (1) commercial development, including public recreation for the economic benefit of the people of Utah and the Uniform School Fund; and (2) the protection of scenic, scientific, historic, cultural, and geological resources. Provides that certain land entitlement payments made by the United States to States on which Federal land is located shall cease to be made with regard to lands transferred to the State of Utah at the end of the second fiscal year after such land exchange is made. Provides that the United States shall make payments in lieu of taxes on lands acquired by the United States in such exchange, requiring such payments to be made to the Governor of Utah.</summary>
</bill>
