<bill session="100" type="h" number="5384" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Interstate Commerce Commission Sunset Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to abolish the Interstate Commerce Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400174"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Common carrier regulation"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Corporation directors"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Freight"/>
    <term name="Freight forwarders"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="Household moving"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Inland water transportation"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Motor transportation"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Railroad rates"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Railroads and state"/>
    <term name="Regulatory reform"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Shipping rates"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Sunset legislation"/>
    <term name="Trade regulation"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation and state"/>
    <term name="Trucking"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1988--Introduced.
Interstate Commerce Commission Sunset Act of 1988 - Amends the Interstate Commerce Act to terminate, as of October 1, 1990, the Interstate Commerce Commission (ICC) as an independent executive agency of the U.S. Government. Transfers to the Secretary of Transportation the functions, powers, and duties of the ICC relating to the regulation of rail transportation and to certain other surface transportation regulation. Prohibits any State or its political subdivison or any interstate or other political agency of two or more States from enacting or enforcing any law, rule, or standard relating to interstate or intrastate rates, routes, or services of motor carriers, motor private carriers, water carriers, freight forwarders, or transportation brokers. Authorizes the President to take certain action upon a determination that the government of a contiguous foreign country has engaged in unfair, discriminatory, or restrictive practices having a substantial adverse competitive impact upon certain U.S. transportation companies. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to submit to the Congress, two years from the effective date of this Act, a status report and evaluation concerning the implementation of the National Governors' Association Consensus Agenda on standards for uniform State regulation of interstate motor carriers. Transfers to the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) jurisdiction over certain regulation of motor carriers, water carriers, freight forwarders, and railroad passenger carriers. Grants to the FTC the exclusive power to enforce certain regulations governing the transport of household goods. Requires the FTC, within 120 days of this Act's enactment, to review and revise such regulations to eliminate unnecessary regulation and to ensure that shippers of household goods receive adequate protection in their dealings with carriers. Identifies the administrative procedure to govern such FTC rulemaking, including provisions for judicial review. Requires such rule review and revision to be completed within one year following its initiation. Requires that all U.S. departments and agencies conform their rules to those finally promulgated by the FTC within one year after such promulgation. Repeals statutory limitations on purchases by common carriers in cases of interlocking directorates.</summary>
</bill>
