<bill session="100" type="h" number="5390" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the suspension of duty-free treatment to wood products under the Generalized System of Preferences to beneficiary countries that do not implement appropriate reforestation programs; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Reforestation"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to require the President to suspend the designation as an eligible article for duty-free treatment under the Generalized System of Preferences of wood products from a beneficiary country unless such country, during each year: (1) commences a reforestation program for the equivalent forest area for such country; and (2) continues or completes such reforestation program begun in any previous year. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to: (1) determine those beneficiary countries that comply with such requirement; and (2) advise the President of those countries that do not. Sets forth an exception to such suspension. Directs the United States Trade Representative to use the Uruguay Round of Multilateral Trade Negotiations to promote reforestation in developing countries.</summary>
</bill>
