<bill session="100" type="h" number="5400" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate the disposal of certain medical equipment and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404750" joined="1988-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408109" joined="1988-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411725" joined="1988-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a marking and recordkeeping system tracking medical equipment from its manufacture or importation to its disposal. Prohibits the disposal or disinfection of medical equipment waste at a facility which is not licensed. Requires such facilities to post a bond with the Administrator to insure compliance with licensing regulations. Requires handlers of medical equipment to give EPA representatives or representatives of a State having an authorized medical waste program information and access to information concerning such waste. Imposes penalties for violations of medical equipment marking, recordkeeping, and disposal requirements. Prohibits the interpretation of this Act as precluding more stringent State or local medical equipment tracking or disposal requirements. Authorizes appropriations to the Administrator through FY 1991 for carrying out this Act's activities. Makes individuals who violate medical equipment tracking or disposal requirements liable for compensable damages caused by the disposal of such equipment. Sets forth defenses to such liability. Limits the time within which such actions may be brought. Reduces amounts payable to a plaintiff by the total of the relief or compensation they have previously received for such damages.</summary>
</bill>
