<bill session="100" type="h" number="5421" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Environment Research and Policy Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for development of a National Global Change Research Plan to coordinate oceanographic, atmospheric, terrestrial, and cryospheric research programs, and to establish the Council on Global Environmental Policy.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406148"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406974" joined="1988-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410496" joined="1988-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-29">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Scientific Cooperation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Space Science and Applications.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Science, Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Natural Resources, Agricultural Research, and Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, Interior, State, Treasury, National Science Foundation, DOE, USDA, Science and Technology Policy, DOT, CEQ, EPA, FEMA, NASA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oceanography.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM04" subcommittee="Oceanography" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY01" subcommittee="International Scientific Cooperation" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY02" subcommittee="Space Science and Applications" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY03" subcommittee="Science, Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY04" subcommittee="Natural Resources, Agricultural Research and Environment" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental research"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1988--Introduced.
Global Environment Research and Policy Act of 1988 - Title I: National Global Change Research Plan - Directs the Federal Coordinating Council on Science, Engineering, and Technology (Council) to develop a National Global Change Research Plan for a ten-year national research program on the processes and factors which contribute to global environmental change, including research on increases of global sea levels. Requires that such Plan allocate research responsibilities among Federal agencies in accordance with existing and appropriate additional agency missions and responsibilities. Requires that such Plan be submitted to the Congress within one year of this Act's enactment and revised and resubmitted at least once every three years. Directs the Council to: (1) oversee implementation of the Plan; (2) coordinate global change research and assessment activities among Federal agencies; (3) work with the National Research Council and other groups conducting such activities; (4) promote consistent, efficient, and compatible transfer and use of research data; and (5) cooperate with the Secretary of State in providing U.S. representation at international governmental meetings on global change. Requires each Federal agency to submit a report identifying each element of its proposed global change activities to the President and the Council when it submits its appropriations request to the President. Directs the President to give the Council an opportunity to review and comment on the budget estimate for each agency in the context of the Plan before submitting the annual budget to the Congress, and identify in such budget the portion of each agency's annual budget that is allocated to each element of that agency's global change activities. Sets forth Council reporting requirements. Title II: Council on Global Environmental Policy - Establishes a Council on Global Environmental Policy within the Executive Office of the President to advise the President regarding domestic and international policies, plans, and programs of the Federal Government related to global environmental change. Sets forth reporting requirements, including the requirement that the Council on Global Environmental Policy develop and submit to the Congress and the President, within five years of this Act's enactment, a comprehensive program to abate, mitigate, and adapt to the impacts of global environmental change. Requires that such program be updated periodically to incorporate the results of Plan research. Title III: Miscellaneous - Defines terms.</summary>
</bill>
