<bill session="100" type="h" number="5434" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Waste Act to Save the Environment</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that any solid waste exported from the United States to foreign countries is managed to protect human health and the environment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401585" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400585" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407673" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Introduced.
Waste Act to Save the Environment - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to establish as an objective of such Act the assurance that solid waste exports are managed in accordance with environmental standards no less strict than Federal standards in this country. Prohibits the export of solid waste except when there is an agreement between the United States and the receiving country which provides for the exchange of information regarding such export and its management, cooperation in the enforcement of the agreement, and biannual review of the agreement's effectiveness. Requires exporters of solid waste to register with and submit specified export and export management information to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency who shall annually submit a report to the Congress summarizing such information. Prohibits the export of a solid waste until the Administrator finds that the transportation, treatment, storage, and disposal of such export will be carried out in accordance with environmental standards no less strict than Federal standards in this country. Authorizes the Administrator to impose fees on exporters to defray the costs of administering this Act. Imposes criminal penalties against persons who knowingly violate this Act's requirements.</summary>
</bill>
