<bill session="100" type="h" number="5432" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation Recapitalization Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase the limitation on the amount of outstanding obligations of the Financing Corporation, impose a limitation on the amount of outstanding promissory notes issued by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400537"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401203" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411901" joined="1988-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Debt"/>
    <term name="Federal Home Loan Bank Board"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Introduced.
Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporaton Recapitalization Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Federal Home Loan Bank Act to increase the limitation on outstanding obligations of the Financing Corporation. Repeals the annual limitation on net new borrowing by the Corporation after its first year. Amends the National Housing Act to limit the aggregate outstanding balance on promissory notes issued by the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation (FSLIC). Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Federal Home Loan Bank Board should rely primarily on raising funds through the Financing Corporation to provide assistance through the FSLIC to resolve cases of failed or failing thrift institutions.</summary>
</bill>
