<bill session="100" type="h" number="5435" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Comprehensive Environmental Risk Management Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to maximize protection of human health and the environment by requiring the submission to Congress of an annual report to assist the oversight and appropriation process, with the objective of providing an assessment which weighs the achieved or anticipated reduction in environmental risk through implementation of the Environmental Protection Agency's statutory authorities against the Agency's budgetary expenditures and the societal costs of reducing those risks.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409251"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400572" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="400165" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="406746" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407069" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411224" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411585" joined="1988-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Commerce, Interior, EPA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oceanography.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG04" subcommittee="Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM04" subcommittee="Oceanography" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW02" subcommittee="Water Resources" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Carcinogens"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Law and legislation"/>
    <term name="Risk assessment"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Introduced.
Comprehensive Environmental Risk Management Act of 1988 - Expresses the U.S. policy regarding Federal environmental protection activities administered by the Environmental Protection Agency, including that such activities shall attain the greatest risk reduction possible with the resources available. Requires the Administrator of EPA to act to protect human health and the environment on the basis of careful assessment of risks and evaluation of control options for their management. Requires the development of risk assessment guidelines covering specified elements, including mutagenicity assessment, carcinogenicity assessment, exposure estimates, reproductive risks, and ecological effects. Requires guidelines to include hazard determinations, dose response assessments, exposure assessments, and risk characterizations. Requires a report to the Congress projecting the net risk reduction and costs that would result from control and abatement of environmental hazards in accordance with this Act. Requires inclusion of a list of human and environmental risks with which the EPA is concerned and the potency, exposure, and other information for each risk. Requires recurring reports every four years. Requires an annual report to the Congress projecting the net risk reduction and costs that would result from the implementation of each of the Agency's abatement and control programs. Requires a report on the status of risk assessment within the Federal Government, to include a review of risk assessment activities presently being carried out within Federal agencies with a mandate to protect the public health, specifying under which legislative authority they are and are not being carried out, and the limitations under such authorities which prevent the full utilization of risk assessment. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
