<bill session="100" type="h" number="5454" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Thomas Cole National Historic Site in the State of New York and the Thomas Cole Advisory Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on National Parks and Public Lands.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII01" subcommittee="National Parks and Public Lands" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Artists"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Painting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1988--Introduced.
Establishes the Thomas Cole National Historic Site in Catskill, New York. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by donation land, improvements thereon, and associated personal property within such Site. Directs the Secretary to administer the Site in accordance with laws applicable to national historic sites. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the State of New York and other public and private entities to further the purposes of this Act. Requires the Secretary, in consultation with a group of historians, scholars, and other experts, to report to specified House and Senate committees on issues related to such Site and other historic sites in the Hudson River Valley no later than two years after enactment of this Act. Establishes the Thomas Cole Advisory Commission to advise the Secretary on the management and development of the Site. Requires the Secretary, no later than five years after enactment of this Act, to submit to specified House and Senate committees a general management plan for the preservation and use of the Site and other historic sites in the Hudson River Valley. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
