<bill session="100" type="h" number="5453" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer the administration of the District of Columbia Department of Corrections from the District Government to a Special Federal Administrator in the Justice Department of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408490"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on District of Columbia.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Judiciary and Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSDT" name="House District of Columbia" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSDT03" subcommittee="Judiciary and Education" name="House District of Columbia"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU03" subcommittee="Courts, Civil Liberties, and the Administration of Justice" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Correctional personnel"/>
    <term name="Corrections"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal-city relations"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1988--Introduced.
Mandates that, notwithstanding any other law, the Department of Corrections of the District of Columbia be administered by a Special Federal Administrator appointed by and under the direction of the U.S. Attorney General. Directs the Attorney General to make the first such appointment not more than 30 days after enactment of this Act. Sets forth transitional provisions and certain powers and responsibilities of the Administrator. Applies Federal laws governing the administration of Federal penal and correctional institutions to the District of Columbia Department of Corrections, except as determined by the Attorney General. Prohibits this Act from being construed: (1) as an assumption by the Federal Government of the financial responsibility for incarceration of individuals; or (2) to require use of Federal penal or correctional institutions. Directs the Administrator, directly or by contract, to conduct a study of alternative sentencing in the District of Columbia.</summary>
</bill>
