<bill session="100" type="h" number="5461" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Powerplant Standardization Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to encourage the development and use of standardized plant designs and improve the nuclear licensing and regulatory process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400548"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-01">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF03" subcommittee="Energy and Power" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1988--Introduced.
Nuclear Powerplant Standardization Act of 1988 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require the Nuclear Regulatory Commission to establish procedures, standards, and criteria permitting the approval of standardized designs and facility sites for production or utilization facilities or discrete subsystems of such facilities. Mandates that such procedures provide an opportunity for a public hearing prior to the issuance of a design approval or site permit. Prohibits the NRC from modifying a final determination on an issue made in a permit or license proceeding unless it determines, based on significant new information, that a modification is required to protect and enhance the public safety or common defense and security. Authorizes the Commission to issue a combined construction permit and operating license for a production or utilization facility based upon an approved standardized design if certain conditions are met. Requires the Commission to specify in any such license the emergency preparedness requirements that shall apply and the standards for meeting such requirements. Requires the Commission to publish in the Federal Register a notice of intended operation no later than 60 days prior to commencement of the operation of a licensed facility.</summary>
</bill>
