<bill session="100" type="h" number="5486" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intergenerational Library Literacy Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of Education to establish a program to make grants to local public library systems to establish demonstration projects using older adult volunteers to provide intergenerational library literacy programs to children during afterschool hours.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300091"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1988-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Postsecondary Education.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED07" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED08" subcommittee="Postsecondary Education" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary school students"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Literacy programs"/>
    <term name="Older workers"/>
    <term name="Secondary school students"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Introduced.
Intergenerational Library Literacy Act - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to local public library systems to establish demonstration projects using older adult volunteers to provide intergenerational library literacy programs for school children during afterschool hours. Limits the aggregate amount of grants under this Act to a local public library system. Sets forth requirements for such demonstration projects relating to: (1) new programs; (2) multiple locations; (3) afterschool hours; (4) older adult volunteers; (5) older adult role models; (6) one-year duration; and (7) an evaluation and report to the Secretary. Sets forth requirements for applications and for selection of grant recipients. Directs the Secretary, within three years after first making a grant under this Act, to report to the Congress on such deomonstration projects, including any recommendations on the establishment of a permanent program to develop intergenerational library literacy programs in local public library systems. Directs the Secretary to issue regulations to carry out this Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 for such grants under this Act, in a specified amount to be appropriated from any unobligated amounts appropriated to carry out title II of the Library Services and Construction Act.</summary>
</bill>
