<bill session="100" type="h" number="5488" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">William C. Redfield Export Award Establishment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the William C. Redfield Export Award.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300156"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Introduced.
William C. Redfield Export Award Establishment Act of 1988 - Establishes the William C. Redfield Export Award to be given to companies in the United States which have applied for the award and demonstrated leadership in the U.S. export trade. Mandates that the award be evidenced by a medal bearing an inscription as prescribed by the Secretary of Commerce. Provides for the criteria for selection, applications and qualifications, categories and numbers of awards, and the presentation of the award. Directs the Secretary to: (1) develop and publish selection criteria; (2) appoint a board of examiners; and (3) appoint a board of overseers to make recommendations for the improvement of the award program. Authorizes the Secretary to seek and accept gifts from public and private sources to carry out the award program and, if additional sums are needed, directs the Secretary to impose fees on applicants. Sets forth reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
