<bill session="100" type="h" number="5487" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require any conservator of a Federal association and the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, in such Corporation's capacity as conservator, receiver, or custodian of any insured institution, to provide notice to any depositor in such institution whose deposits exceed the insured amount that such depositor has uninsured deposits.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410589"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA07" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Deposit insurance"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Home Owners' Loan Act of 1933 to require any conservator appointed for a federally insured savings and loan association by the Federal Home Loan Bank Board to notify each insured member whose deposits in such association exceed the amount of available deposit insurance that such member has uninsured deposits. Amends the National Housing Act to require the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation, when appointed as the conservator, receiver, or custodian of an association, to notify each insured member whose deposits in such association exceed the amount of available deposit insurance that such member has uninsured deposits.</summary>
</bill>
