<bill session="100" type="h" number="5498" updated="2016-06-29T08:44:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Corruption Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18 of the United States Code to punish corruption.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400544"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1988-10-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2793"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="2793"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/1988--Introduced.
Anti-Corruption Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal criminal code to prescribe criminal penalties to be imposed upon anyone who uses any facility of, or affects, interstate or foreign commerce to deprive or defraud the inhabitants of a State or political subdivision of: (1) the honest services of a government official or employee; or (2) a fair and impartially conducted election process through the use of fraudulent ballots or voter registration forms or the filing of fraudulent campaign reports. Imposes criminal penalties upon anyone who deprives or defrauds the inhabitants of the United States of the honest services of a public official. Imposes criminal penalties upon any official who, in order to carry out or conceal any scheme or artifice to defraud, discriminates, harasses, or takes adverse action against any employee or official of the United States or any State or political subdivision. Authorizes such an adversely affected employee or official to obtain relief through a civil action, provided such person did not participate in the scheme or artifice. Amends mail fraud provisions to: (1) include within the definition of a "scheme or artifice to defraud" any scheme or artifice to deprive an organization of the intangible rights of honest services in which the defendant received or attempted to receive anything of value or in which the defendant intended loss or harm to the organization; and (2) prohibit use of any facility of interstate or foreign commerce in the execution of a scheme or artifice to defraud.</summary>
</bill>
