<bill session="100" type="h" number="5504" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to increase Federal payments in lieu of taxes to units of general local government, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300037"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from Interior.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Energy and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSII" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSII06" subcommittee="Energy and the Environment" name="House Interior and Insular Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental fiscal relations"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Payments in lieu of taxes"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Real property tax"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/1988--Introduced.
Amends Federal law to revise the formula used, in connection with Bureau of Land Management (BLM) holdings, to determine the amount of payments the Secretary of the Interior must make to local governments in lieu of taxes, permitting a payment option equal to three-fourths of one percent of the fair market value of the entitlement land, up to the amount that would be due if the land were subject to local property tax. Directs the Secretary, not later than July 1, 1990, and at least every five years thereafter, to appraise all entitlement lands to determine fair market value. Requires indexing of per acre formulas used to determine payments in lieu of taxes with respect to both BLM and National Wildlife Refuge System lands. Amends the Refuge Revenue Sharing Act to appropriate rather than authorize the appropriation of funds to the Refuge Revenue Sharing Fund whenever receipts are less than aggregate required payments. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to reduce payments (based on fair market value) in lieu of taxes in connection with National Wildlife Refuge System lands that exceed amounts that would be due if the land were subject to local property tax.</summary>
</bill>
