<bill session="100" type="h" number="5501" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Nurse Shortage Relief Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish programs to increase the supply of professional nurses and provide educational assistance to nurses and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400003"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration, Refugees, and International Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU01" subcommittee="Immigration, Refugees, and International Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/1988--Introduced.
Emergency Nurse Shortage Relief Act of 1988 - Amends title VIII (Nurse Education) of the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants and contracts for programs to: (1) promote nursing as a career, including promotion in public secondary schools; (2) identify and provide internships to students in such schools who show an interest in health care; and (3) recruit nursing students from groups not traditionally well represented in the profession. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and contracts for programs to: (1) encourage and assist non-practicing nurses to reenter the profession; (2) train nurses as nurse practitioners or nurse midwives or in areas of needed specialized nursing skills; and (3) provide tuition assistance to students in educational programs designed to facilitate reentry. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and contracts for programs to: (1) increase the attractiveness of nursing as a career through changes in wage structures, employment options and benefits, and the role of nurses in health care facilities; and (2) demonstrate innovative methods of providing for career advancement and encourage nurses and nurse assistants to continue nursing education. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a program to insure educational loans to individuals with a degree as a registered nurse for educational expenses related to training nurses as nurse practitioners or nurse midwives or in areas of needed specialized nursing skills. Makes provisions of the Federal Program of Insured Loans to Graduate Students in Health Professions Schools, established by current law in the Public Health Service Act, apply to this program except as inconsistent. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with eligible individuals to assist in repaying specified amounts of their eligible educational loans. Sets forth criteria for an individual to be eligible to receive assistance, including a requirement that the individual agree to work full-time as a registered nurse in a nursing crisis area. Sets forth a schedule for loan repayment by the Secretary to the holder of the loans based on the number of years of work completed as agreed. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow C corporations a tax credit for 20 percent of the amount paid or incurred as qualified nursing scholarships. Directs the Attorney General to extend for at least one additional year the status of nonimmigrant alien for those aliens admitted under specified provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act who perform services as registered nurses in a nursing crisis area, provided the Secretary of Labor has certified that the continuing employment of the aliens will not adversely affect the wages and working conditions of U.S. registered nurses. Amends title VIII (Nurse Education) of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to designate areas that have: (1) a severe shortage in the number of nurses as nursing crisis areas; and (2) a shortage of practicing nurses with specialized nursing skills as areas of needed specialized nursing skills. Directs the Secretary to review and, if necessary, redesignate such areas at least annually.</summary>
</bill>
