<bill session="100" type="h" number="5505" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Waste End Revenue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 38 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish new environmental taxes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403581"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/1988--Introduced.
Waste End Revenue Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a per ton tax on: (1) the exportation of hazardous waste from the United States (liability for the tax is on the exporter); and (2) the receipt of hazardous waste at a qualified hazardous waste management unit (liability is on the owner or operator of the unit) or for transport from the United States for ocean disposal (liability is on permittee). Sets the initial (1989) rate of the tax at $27.00 for land disposal (increasing annually to a maximum of $43.00 for 1993 and thereafter), and $2.70 ($3.00 in 1993) for any other taxable event. Establishes exceptions to the tax, including hazardous waste received at a U.S.-owned facility or at any waste treatment unit, unless the unit requires corrective action that has not been completed. Provides for reduced tax liability when the waste has already been subjected to the waste management tax or to the tax on waste generation. Permits as a credit or refund any waste management tax paid in connection with: (1) hazardous waste incinerated on land or a battery recycled within 90 days after receipt at the waste management site; or (2) waste used by a producer of a qualified chemical fuel or solvent to be sold for industrial or commercial use. Imposes a per ton waste generation tax on hazardous waste that has been neither received for proper disposal nor exported within 270 days of being generated. Applies the same rates as those of the hazardous waste management tax. Places liability for the tax on the producer of the waste. Permits some of the same exemptions established in connection with the waste management tax, as well as exemptions for generators of small amounts of waste and waste legally disposed of in publicly owned treatment works. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to provide for other exemptions. Describes reporting requirements with respect to the hazardous waste management tax. Imposes penalties on persons who fail to report or who underpay environmental excise taxes because of negligence or disregard of rules and regulations.</summary>
</bill>
