<bill session="100" type="h" number="5511" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on the Importation of Japanese Semiconductors and Integrated Circuits Establishment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Commission on the Importation of Japanese Semiconductors and Integrated Circuits, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSM" name="House Small Business" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Integrated circuits"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Semiconductor industry"/>
    <term name="Semiconductors"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/1988--Introduced.
Commission on the Importation of Japanese Semiconductors and Integrated Circuits Establishment Act of 1988 - Establishes the Commission on the Importation of Japanese Semiconductors and Integrated Circuits. Directs the Commission to: (1) determine whether any Japanese act, policy, or practice with respect to the export of semiconductors and integrated circuits to the United States is unreasonable; and (2) transmit a report to the Congress and the President. Requires the Commission further to determine whether such act, policy, or practice burdens or restricts U.S. commerce if it is determined to be unreasonable. Terminates the Commission in the event its determinations are negative. Directs the Commission, if its determinations are affirmative, to impose an additional duty on imported Japanese electronic products. Establishes in the Treasury the National Manufacture of Semiconductors and Integrated Circuits Trust Fund. Sets forth the purposes of the Fund. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress with regard to such fund. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Small Business Administration to make direct loans to assist small businesses in financing plant construction, conversion, expansion, including acquisition of land for such plant, or startup, and the acquisition of equipment to enable such business to manufacture semiconductors or integrated circuits.</summary>
</bill>
