<bill session="100" type="h" number="5523" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alternative Fuels Incentive Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow an investment tax credit for vehicles fueled by clean-burning substances, for converting vehicles to be so fueled, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400882"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control equipment"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy tax credits"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Investment tax credit"/>
    <term name="Liquefied petroleum gas"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1988--Introduced.
Alternative Fuels Incentive Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit a 20 percent income tax credit for investments in qualified clean-burning (natural gas or alcohol) motor vehicle fuel property. Applies the credit to depreciable property that is: (1) equipment designed either to modify a motor vehicle so that it will be propelled only by a clean-burning fuel or to assist in delivering such fuel into such vehicles; or (2) a motor vehicle propelled by clean-burning fuel. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to make credit-equivalent payments to States and to local governments in connection with qualified property. Provides for the recapture of credit amounts if the relevant property ceases to be eligible for the credit. Earmarks at least 25 percent of amounts transferred or credited to the Mass Transit Account in the Highway Trust Fund for grants to State and to local governments for clean-burning motor vehicle fuel property.</summary>
</bill>
