<bill session="100" type="h" number="5545" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Drug Treatment and Crime Reduction Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act by establishing an entitlement program, to be financed by raising the level described in section 230 of such Act of wages and self-employment income subject to certain taxes, under which certain treatment services shall be provided to persons suffering from drug or alcohol addiction.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400387"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Social Security.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM01" subcommittee="Social Security" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical records"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Narcotic addiction"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/1988--Introduced.
Drug Treatment and Crime Reduction Act of 1988 - Adds a new title XXI to the Social Security Act: Addiction Treatment Services. States that each U.S. citizen and permanent resident is entitled to have payment made for addiction treatment services designed to reduce or eliminate physical or psychological dependence on controlled substances. Bases payment amounts on the individual's ability to pay. Describes the addiction services covered, including detoxification, drug maintenance therapy, and vocational skills training. Lists entities eligible for payment and establishes a prospective payment system for services. Creates the Addiction Treatment Services Trust Fund and appropriates to it amounts which are attributable to the increase in the contribution and benefit base under the Social Security Act resulting from amendments made by this Act. Requires an annual estimate of the fund's surplus or deficit. Provides for the use of copayment and reductions in payment limits and the use of the annual or cumulative surpluses to eliminate any deficits. Establishes in the fund a separate cumulative account of surpluses and deficits. Provides for confidentiality of records of patients under this title. Prohibits the use of records for criminal investigative or prosecutorial purposes except under court order. Makes special provision for coordination of regulations regarding records of veterans suffering from alcohol abuse or alcoholism. Requires providers of services to submit annual reports on the effectiveness of treatment programs. Provides for an increase in the contribution and benefit base for purposes of determining the amount of wages or self-employment income subject to certain taxes under the Social Security Act. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to contract with the National Academy of Sciences to conduct a study of the clinical and cost effectiveness of various drug addiction treatment methods and services. Requires a study and report to the Congress on the costs and benefits of expanding the addiction treatment services program of this Act to provide funding for treatment services for alcohol and nicotine addiction.</summary>
</bill>
