<bill session="100" type="h" number="5546" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Integrity in Post Employment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 207 of title 18, United States Code, to prohibit Members of Congress and officers and employees of any branch of the United States Government from attempting to influence the United States Government or from representing or advising a foreign entity for a proscribed period after such officer or employee leaves Government service, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404170"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Personnel and Police.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-24">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Administrative Law and Governmental Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-14">
      <text>See H.R.5043.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA05" subcommittee="Personnel and Police" name="House Administration"/>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU02" subcommittee="Administrative Law and Governmental Relations" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5043"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Ex-Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Lobbying"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Partnerships"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/1988--Introduced.
Integrity in Post Employment Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal criminal code to revise provisions regarding former Federal employees attempting to influence the Government. Makes it unlawful, within one year after employment or service has ceased, for: (1) former senior officials to lobby their former employing agency; (2) former top level officials (Cabinet Secretaries and Deputy Secretaries) to lobby any executive or independent agency or any Member of Congress; and (3) former Members of Congress to lobby any entity of the legislative branch or any top level official of the executive branch. Prohibits any senior or top level official, within 18 months after employment has ceased, from being employed by, representing, or advising a foreign entity for compensation, financial gain, or other remuneration. Prohibits any person from acting as an agent and communicating on behalf of such former officials and Members of Congress. Includes as exceptions to such prohibitions: (1) any person who is engaging solely in the solicitation or collection of funds and contributions within the United States to be used only for medical assistance, food, or clothing to relieve human suffering; or (2) any person who is providing a statement based on that person's special knowledge, provided that no compensation is received for such statement other than that regularly provided by law for witnesses. Increases the criminal and civil penalties for violations of this Act. Prohibits the partner of a Member, officer, or employee of the legislative branch in a partnership for the provision of professional services from acting as an agent or attorney for, or otherwise representing, any other person other than the United States in lobbying activities in either House of Congress. Provides for the imposition of penalties upon any Member of Congress who: (1) affiliates with a firm, partnership, association, or corporation for the purpose of providing professional services for compensation; (2) permits the use of the Member's name by such firm, partnership, association, or corporation; or (3) practices a profession for compensation. Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit Members of Congress from converting excess campaign funds to their personal use. Title II: Fairness in Personal Campaign Expenditures - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to prohibit any candidate for Federal office who makes expenditures from personal funds or the personal funds of the candidate's immediate family to the candidate's campaign committee, or makes a loan from such funds to such committee, from using any other contributions made after the election to such candidate or committee to repay such expenditure or loan.</summary>
</bill>
