<bill session="100" type="h" number="5556" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to control hazardous air pollutants.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400110"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to publish a list, within one month of this Act's enactment, of all categories and subcategories of major sources of listed air pollutants and simultaneously designate 50 percent of such the categories for emission regulation. Requires that the remaining major stationary sources which present risks warranting regulation be designated for regulation within five years of this Act's enactment. Permits the Administrator to designate other stationary sources as warranting regulation. Establishes a schedule for the promulgation of emission standards applicable to designated categories or subcategories of pollutant sources. Requires the Administrator, within seven years of promulgating emission standards for a source category, to evaluate public health risks remaining after application of such standards and make such standards more stringent if risks remain significant. Provides for variances from, and extensions of, the implementation of such standards. Prohibits the construction of a new source or modification of an existing source, or emissions from a major source which is subject to emission standards unless such activity is conducted in compliance with a permit issued by the Administrator or an approved State permit program. Requires that such permits be for a fixed term not exceeding ten years. Directs the Administrator to establish and maintain an air toxics clearinghouse, control technology center, and risk information center to assist States in reducing air pollutant emissions. Authorizes the Administrator to make grants to a State for the development and implementation of a permit program. Authorizes the President to exempt a source from compliance with emission standards if the means of complying with such standards are unavailable and the source is required for national security purposes.</summary>
</bill>
