<bill session="100" type="h" number="5581" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Economic Set-Aside Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Commission on Economic Set-Asides and a uniform Federal policy concerning economic set-asides.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403695"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Government Operations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSGO" name="House Government Operations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Black colleges"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Minority education"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/22/1988--Introduced.
Economic Set-Aside Act of 1988 - Title I: Economic Set-Aside Policy of United States Government - Requires each Federal agency to award not less than ten percent of its contract funds to: (1) business concerns owned and operated by socially and economically disadvantaged individuals; and (2) historically Black colleges and universities, colleges and universities having a student body in which more than 40 percent of the students are Hispanic, and private and voluntary organizations controlled by individuals who are economically disadvantaged. Requires each Federal agency to award not less than ten percent of its contract funds to business concerns owned and operated by females. Requires Federal agencies to establish policies and procedures to implement such requirements. Title II: Commission on Economic Set-Asides - Establishes the Commission on Economic Set-Asides to enforce title I of this Act, assist Federal agencies in meeting title I requirements, and inform business concerns that may be eligible for the award of contracts under such Act of the benefits provided by title I. Requires the Commission to make annual reports to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
