<bill session="100" type="h" number="562" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ocean Dumping Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title I of the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405775"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300019" joined="1987-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404752" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400533" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400359" joined="1987-06-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT, EPA, CEQ, Commerce, Justice, Interior, Army Corps of Engineers, Marine Mammal Comm.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Oceanography.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-27">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-27">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From DOT.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-20">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From Justice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Executive Comment Received From State.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-08">
      <text>Field Hearings Held in Ocean City, New Jersey.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSMM04" subcommittee="Oceanography" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/1987--Introduced.
Ocean Dumping Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to prohibit after December 31, 1986, the issuance of any permit for the dumping of municipal sludge unless: (1) the applicant is in compliance with all the requirements of the Federal Water Pollution Control Act pertaining to pretreatment standards for the introduction of pollutants into treatment works; and (2) there is not available any land-based alternative to the ocean disposal of the sludge. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to periodically monitor the effects of dumping at sites, if necessary, and to estimate the extent of such dumping every three years. Directs the Administrator to limit, suspend, or terminate dumping if a site is no longer suitable for such purpose. Makes it mandatory for the Administrator to collect ocean dumping permit processing fees. Requires the Administrator and the Secretary of the Army to establish information quality assurance programs for the permitting process. Directs the Administrator to develop, after public hearings, and report to the Congress within three years on a New York Bight Apex Restoration Plan for improving the overall water quality and marine resources of the Apex. Sets forth various activities which must be covered by the plan. Directs the Administrator to submit to the Congress, within six months, a schedule for completing the plan and an estimate of the cost for developing and, where possible, implementing the plan. Directs the Administrator to report to the Congress, within one year, on the economic and technical feasibility of establishing and implementing quality standards for the disposal of municipal sludge through ocean or land-based methods. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 and 1988 to EPA for purposes of preparing the New York Bight Apex Restoration Plan. Creates criminal penalties for certain violations of this Act. Prohibits the ocean dumping of all harmful municipal sludge 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act. Defines "harmful municipal sludge" as municipal sludge which fails to meet EPA's environmental impact criteria. Extends United States authority over ocean dumping to a specified exclusive economic zone.</summary>
</bill>
