<bill session="100" type="h" number="586" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hart-Scott-Rodino Antitrust Procedure Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 7A of the Clayton Act to extend the waiting periods and to expand the applicability of the notification requirement; to make subject to such section persons who, while acting in concert, acquire voting securities or assets of another person; to require such notification to include an economic impact statement; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409344"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="401417" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402114" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400080" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403031" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403364" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403689" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403776" joined="1987-01-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="405687" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400210" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400211" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406191" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400216" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400223" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408052" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400539" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="410066" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="410076" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information disclosure (Securities law)"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tender offers"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/1987--Introduced.
Hart-Scott-Rodino Antitrust Procedure Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Clayton Act to eliminate the 15-day waiting period (and thus require a 30-day waiting period) following notification of a proposed acquisition in the case of a cash tender offer. Requires the 30-day acquisition waiting period to be extended for an additional 30 days (or 60 days if, after the acquisition, the U.S. assets or probable annual U.S. sales of the acquiring person would exceed $1,000,000,000) if the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) or the Attorney General requires submission of additional information or documentary material concerning the proposed acquisition. Extends premerger notification requirements to any situation where any voting securities or assets of a person with annual net sales or total assets of $100,000,000 or more are being acquired by any person with total assets or annual net sales exceeding $1,000,000 (currently, $10,000,000). Includes within the definition of an acquiring person for purposes of such notification and waiting period requirements two or more separate persons acting in concert. Directs the FTC to require that a premerger notification disclose: (1) whether the acquiring person intends to sell or close any facility or to terminate or alter any operation as a result of the acquisition; (2) the number of jobs likely to be lost as a result of such acquisition over each of the subsequent five years; (3) the revenue to government entities likely to be lost over each of the subsequent five years; (4) the aggregate liabilities and equities the acquiring person has before, and is likely to have after, such acquisition; and (5) each asset of the person to be acquired that is likely to be used in any way to obtain credit or financing to carry out the acquisition. Directs the Assistant Attorney General and the FTC to make such economic impact statement available to the public immediately after such a notification is filed.</summary>
</bill>
