<bill session="100" type="h" number="595" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Highway Beautification Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, relating to the control of outdoor advertising along the Federal-aid primary and Interstate highway systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400369"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Highway beautification"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Outdoor advertising"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/1987--Introduced.
Highway Beautification Act of 1987 - Requires States and Federal agencies to control, according to prescribed guidelines, the erection and maintenance of outdoor advertising in rural areas adjacent to the Federal-aid primary and the Interstate systems. Provides that a State shall be deemed as failing to provide effective control of outdoor advertising if the State allows vegetation located on State rights-of-way for Interstate or primary system highways to be altered or removed if the purpose of such alteration is to improve the visibility of certain outdoor advertising. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to provide for rights-of-way areas on the Federal-aid primary and Interstate systems in which informational signs may be erected according to national standards. Sets deadlines for the removal of nonconforming signs. Authorizes the Secretary to approve payments out of certain apportionments for sign acquisition and removal by a State. Repeals, effective September 30, 1989, Federal law enacted prior to this Act regarding outdoor advertising in areas adjacent to the Interstate and primary systems. Provides for the payment of outdoor advertising bonus claims submitted by a State before such effective repeal date.</summary>
</bill>
