<bill session="100" type="h" number="598" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that each State must establish a workfare program, and require participation therein by all residents of the State who are receiving benefits or assistance under aid to families with dependent children, food stamp, and public housing programs, as a condition of the State's eligibility for Federal assistance in connection with those programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410097"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Housing and Community Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-08">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Domestic Marketing, Consumer Relations, and Nutrition.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Employment Opportunities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.1720.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG05" subcommittee="Domestic Marketing, Consumer Relations, and Nutrition" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA04" subcommittee="Housing and Community Development" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED06" subcommittee="Employment Opportunities" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="916"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food stamps"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Manpower policy"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public housing"/>
    <term name="Public service employment"/>
    <term name="Rent subsidies"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/8/1987--Introduced.
Requires that each State establish and maintain an approved workfare program as a condition of its eligibility for Federal payments or other assistance under the: (1) program under part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Social Security Act; (2) food stamp program under the Food Stamp Act of 1977; and (3) public housing and assisted housing programs under the United States Housing Act of 1937. Requires that such State workfare program shall require every State resident applying for or receiving aid under such Federal public assistance programs to perform work in return for, and as a condition for, such aid. Directs the appropriate Federal agencies to promulgate guidelines for approval, supervision, and oversight of such State workfare programs. Exempts from required participation in such programs those who are: (1) under age 18 or over age 65; (2) disabled; (3) regularly employed for at least 40 hours a week; or (4) primarily responsible for the care of a child less than three years old (or for the care of a child more than two but less than six years old if suitable child care is not available at reasonable cost). Requires that each State workfare program must provide that if any individual who is required to participate in such program refuses to accept a bona fide offer of qualified employment or to perform qualified employment, in any month, neither such individual nor any other person in the family or household of which such individual is a member shall be eligible to receive any aid under such Federal public assistance programs for that month. Requires that State workfare programs include provision for job counseling, assistance in obtaining employment outside the program, and job search activities. Provides for: (1) Federal matching funds to cover administrative costs of such State programs; (2) Federal cut-offs of funds to State agencies for failure to comply with this Act; and (3) Federal agency reports to the Congress on such State programs. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
