<bill session="100" type="h" number="61" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to commemorate the Bicentennial of the Constitution of the United States with exhibits and programs relating to the history of democracy and by the establishment of Democracy Hall.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401363"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Libraries and Memorials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA09" subcommittee="Libraries and Memorials" name="House Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Anniversaries"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Exhibitions"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Library of Congress"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Secretary of the Smithsonian Institution, in consultation with the Commission on the Bicentennial of the United States Constitution, to develop exhibits and programs depicting and explaining democratic philosophy and practices throughout history. Requires that these exhibits be housed in a Smithsonian Institution building from July 4, 1987, to December 31, 1997, in a location to be designated as Democracy Hall. Directs the Librarian of Congress to establish, for the same period of time, a room in the Library of Congress containing information on the history of democracy. Directs the Commission to make recommendation to the Congress on: (1) which of the exhibits and facilities should continue beyond 1997; (2) their permanent location; and (3) potential sources of financial support for these exhibits and facilities and for a permanent building to house Democracy Hall after 1997.</summary>
</bill>
