<bill session="100" type="h" number="663" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Investment Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to stimulate savings and to lower the cost of money for farmers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406799"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Conservation Credit and Rural Development.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAG01" subcommittee="Conservation, Credit, and Rural Development" name="House Agriculture"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Certificates of deposit"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Savings bonds"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Agricultural Investment Act of 1987 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax exclusion for up to $1,000 ($2,000 for a joint return) of interest earned each year on an agricultural savings certificate. Defines an agricultural savings certificate as a certificate issued by a qualified savings institution in a specified denomination ranging from $10 to $1,000 which matures in 10, 15, or 20 years. Requires institutions to: (1) use the proceeds of such certificates to purchase U.S. agricultural savings bonds; or (2) pay a penalty. Revokes the tax exclusion of interest on any certificate redeemed or used as loan security before its maturity date. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to issue agricultural savings bonds. Requires the proceeds from the sale of such bonds to be credited to the Farm Trust Fund established by this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to prescribe how such a bond may be issued to a taxpayer in lieu of a refund check for overpayment of taxes. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make loans from such Fund to certain lending institutions, with priority given to those institutions with the higher percentages of loans outstanding to bona fide farmers. Requires such institutions to loan the amount received to bona fide farmers meeting specified financial criteria and to return the portion not loaned within 60 days or incur a penalty. Limits the annual interest rate on such loans to farmers to nine percent. Defines a bona fide farmer as any individual 50 percent of whose annual gross income is directly attributable to the raising or cultivating of livestock or agricultural commodities.</summary>
</bill>
