<bill session="100" type="h" number="685" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:31-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Securities, Safety, and Soundness Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide a moratorium on hostile corporate takeovers financed by "junk" securities, to prohibit federally insured institutions from holding "junk" securities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409205"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Telecommunications and Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF01" subcommittee="Telecommunications and Finance" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate mergers"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Junk bonds"/>
    <term name="National banks"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Savings banks"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Securities, Safety, and Soundness Act of 1987 - Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to prohibit any person from acquiring certain equity securities in 1987, if: (1) such person would then be entitled to cast 15 percent or more of the securities holders' votes in an election of directors of the issuer; (2) such acquisition is disapproved by a majority of those members of the issuer's board of directors who are not issuer officers or employees; and (3) 20 percent or more of the acquisition is financed by the issuance of takeover securities the proceeds from which exceed $25,000,000. Defines "takeover securities" as certain low-rated or unrated bonds or preferred stock, other debt instruments subordinated in right of payment to the payment of any substantial amount of unsecured indebtedness, or equity or quasi-equity instruments other than common or preferred stock. Prohibits any insured bank or institution from purchasing non-investment grade securities. Directs the Federal Deposit Insurance Corporation and the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation to prevent insured institutions from carrying non-investment grade securities as loans.</summary>
</bill>
