<bill session="100" type="h" number="704" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare and Medicaid Patient and Program Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Social Security Act to protect beneficiaries under the health care programs of that Act from unfit health care practitioners, and otherwise to improve the antifraud provisions of that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-18">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.1444.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM02" subcommittee="Health" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1444"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicaid fraud"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Medicare fraud"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Patients' rights"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="White collar crime"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Medicare and Medicaid Patient and Program Protection Act of 1985 - Amends part A (General Provisions) of title XI of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to exclude from participation in programs under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act any individual or entity: (1) convicted of a criminal offense related to the delivery of an item or service under title XVIII or under titles XIX (Medicaid), V (Maternal and Child Health Block Grant), or XX (Block Grants to States for Social Services) of such Act; or (2) convicted of a criminal offense related to neglect or abuse of patients in connection with the delivery of a health care item or service. Authorizes the Secretary to exclude from Medicare participation any individual or entity: (1) convicted of fraud with respect to any Federal, State, or locally financed health care program; (2) convicted of interfering with the investigation of health care fraud; (3) convicted of manufacturing, distributing, or dispensing a controlled substance; (4) whose health care license has been suspended or revoked; (5) suspended or excluded from participation in a Federal health care program; (6) claiming excessive charges or providing unnecessary services; (7) committing certain acts prohibited under title XI; (8) owned or controlled by an individual convicted of health care related crimes, fined for health care abuses, or excluded from Medicare or a State health care program; and (9) failing to supply certain information. Authorizes the Secretary to exclude any hospital failing to comply with corrective action required under title XVIII. Sets forth provisions relating to notice requirements, judicial review, and period of exclusion. Directs the Secretary to promptly notify each appropriate State agency administering or supervising the administration of a State health care program of each exclusion and the period of exclusion. Permits an excluded individual or entity to apply, following a period of exclusion, to the Secretary for reinstatement. Sets forth provisions providing for civil and criminal penalties for acts involving Medicare or State health care programs abuse, including penalties for physician misrepresentations. Requires a State, as a condition of Medicaid plan approval, to provide for the following: (1) a system of reporting any type of adverse action concluded against any health care practitioner or entity by the State or a local licensing authority; and (2) such access to documents as may be necessary by the Secretary. Requires the Secretary to provide suitable safeguards for the confidentiality of such information. Requires any health care provider providing health care services for which payment may be made under the Act to assure that services or items furnished: (1) will be provided economically and only when, and to the extent, medically necessary; (2) will be quality services which meet professionally recognized standards of health care; and (3) will be supported by evidence of medical necessity and quality in such form and fashion and at such time as may reasonably be required by a reviewing peer review organization in the exercise of its duties and responsibilities. Permits a State to exclude from Medicaid participation any individual or entity excluded under Medicare pursuant to the patient and program protection provisions. Requires a State in order to receive Federal payments with respect to a health maintenance organization (HMO) to exclude any HMO that: (1) could be excluded because of the conviction of the owners or managers of certain crimes; or (2) contracts with any individual or entity convicted of such crimes. Prohibits Federal payments with respect to any amount expended for items or services furnished with respect to any individual or entity excluded from Medicaid participation because of the patient and program protection provisions. Prohibits a State under title V from making payments to any individual or entity excluded from participation pursuant to the patient and program protection provisions. Prohibits Federal payments with respect to any amount expended for items or services furnished with respect to any individual or entity excluded from Medicare because of the patient and program protection provisions of part A of title XI. Prohibits using a grant under title XX for payment for any item or service furnished by a person excluded from title XX participation because of the patient and program protection provisions of title XI. Revises disclosure requirements under part A of title XI. Revises Medicare provisions concerning agreements with providers. Modifies the Medicaid moratorium provisions of the Deficit Reduction Act of 1984 to consider a State's Medicaid plan to include any plan change submitted to the Secretary either before or after the enactment of that Act and whether or not approved or disapproved by the Secretary.</summary>
</bill>
