<bill session="100" type="h" number="717" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">America's Living Standard Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Computer Software and Videotape Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Council on Industrial Competitiveness Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Future Teacher Training Corps Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Science Foundation Engineering Research Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Scientific Research Fellows Program Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">State Job Bank Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">University Research Facilities Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Work Opportunities and Retraining Compact (WORC) of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote economic competitiveness in the United States, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400572"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Economic Stabilization.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Science Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Provisions of Measure Incorporated Into H.R.1720.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA05" subcommittee="Economic Stabilization" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY03" subcommittee="Science, Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM03" subcommittee="Public Assistance and Unemployment Compensation" name="House Ways and Means"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSWM04" subcommittee="Trade" name="House Ways and Means"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1720"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Graduate education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Industrial policy"/>
    <term name="Industry"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="National Science Foundation"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Retirement"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technology assessment"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Trends"/>
    <term name="Video tape recording"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/22/1987--Introduced.
America's Living Standard Act of 1987 - Title I: Establishment of an Office of Technology Assessment in Certain Foreign Nations to Catalogue, Abstract, Translate, and Report on Scientific and Technological Developments - Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to direct the Secretary of Commerce, in consultation with the Secretary of State, to establish an Office of Technology Assessment within the U.S. Embassy in five foreign nations which maintain a high level of scientific and technological development. Requires such offices to: (1) participate in the scientific and technical community of the host nation and issue a monthly catalogue of activities; (2) monitor, select, abstract, and translate important articles from scientific and technical journals of the host nation; and (3) prepare an annual analysis of technological trends and a directory listing government and private sources of information about scientific and engineering developments of the host nation. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988. Title II: Office of Technology Assessment, Forecast and Outreach - Establishes within the Department of Commerce the Office of Technology Assessment, Forecast and Outreach, headed by a Director to be appointed by the Secretary of Commerce. Requires the Office to: (1) identify emerging areas of technology throughout the world; (2) analyze the sources of new technology; (3) develop and administer a program involving the identification of the ownership of U.S. patents, including by country and firm; (4) determine trends in patent behavior throughout the world; (5) assure regular reviews by relevant industry sector advisory committees; and (6) assure broad private sector knowledge of, and access to, findings, data, and other information made or acquired by the Office. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and subsequent fiscal years. Title III: National Science Foundation Engineering Research Assistance - National Science Foundation Engineering Research Assistance Act - Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 1988 to the National Science Foundation for engineering research centers. Amends the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 to direct the National Science Foundation, in cooperation with participating institutions of higher education, to seek methods of excluding from participation in engineering research activities foreign corporations which do not allow reciprocal participation by U.S. corporations in similar research activities. Title IV: Scientific Research Fellows Program - Scientific Research Fellows Program Act - Amends the National Science Foundation Act of 1950 to direct the National Science Foundation to award up to 500 scientific leadership fellowships in each fiscal year to outstanding graduate students who pursue studies which give promise to contribute significantly to the efficiency, economic productivity, and international competitiveness of the United States. Directs the Foundation to give special consideration to applicants who demonstrate competence in the foreign language of one of identified foreign countries and who intend to perform at least two years research in such foreign country. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992. Title V: University Research Facilities Fund - University Research Facilities Act of 1987 - Requires the Director of the National Science Foundation to establish a University Facilities Division within the Directorate for Science and Engineering Education of the Foundation. Establishes a University Research Facilities Fund in the Treasury. Provides that awards from the Fund made under this title shall be used by institutions of higher education for the Federal share of the cost of acquiring, replacing, renovating, upgrading, or constructing facilities and equipment to be principally used for scientific research or laboratory instruction. Sets forth provisions for applications for such awards and for review of such applications. Sets forth a matching requirement. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1997 to be deposited in the Fund. Title VI: Future Teacher Training Corps - Future Teacher Training Corps Act - Amends title V (Teacher Corps and Teacher Training Programs) of the Higher Education Act of 1965 to establish a new part F program of Future Teacher Training Corps Fellowships. Directs the Secretary of Education to allot program grant funds to each State on the basis of school-age population. Directs State Governors to appoint Selection Review Panels to select fellowship recipients. Requires that recipients be interested in teaching careers and agree to teach in areas of the State where there is a shortage of elementary or secondary school teachers or in fields of study where there is a shortage of such teachers. Sets forth guidelines for selection procedures. Sets forth program grant application requirements for States. Limits each such fellowship to not more than: (1) $5,000 for each year of graduate education in preparation to become an elementary or secondary school teacher; and (2) two years of such graduate education. Sets forth fellowship conditions. Requires fellowship repayment in cases of noncompliance with fellowship agreements, with specified exceptions. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991 to carry out this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to award up to 5,000 fellowships during each of those fiscal years. Title VII: Computer Software and Videotape Assistance - Computer Software and Videotape Assistance Act - Directs the Secretary of Education (through the National Institute of Education) and the National Science Foundation to provide advice and technical assistance to State and local educational agencies on expenditures for acquisition of suitable computer software and videotapes by performing specified evaluation, dissemination, and development activities. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. Directs the National Science Foundation to foster research and experimentation on, and dissemination of, models of instruction in the operation and use of computers and videotapes. Requires the Director of the Foundation to report annually to the Congress on the results of such research and experimentation. Requires the Director, in conjunction with the National Institute of Education, to disseminate information concerning such results to local educational agencies. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. Directs the National Science Foundation to arrange for specified entities to develop and operate institutes in the use of computers for computer education instruction and other educational programs in schools. Provides that such institutes shall be for preservice or inservice training of teachers, supervisors, or trainers of teachers. Provides for stipends for attendance at such institutes. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. Title VIII: Work Opportunities and Retraining Compact - Work Opportunities and Retraining Compact (WORC) of 1987 - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require AFDC applicants and recipients to register with a State agency for employment counseling, training, and assignment. Authorizes AFDC recipients to refuse employment which results in a net loss in their income. Directs an agency of each State to: (1) establish a single intake and registration process for AFDC applicants and recipients; (2) determine whether training or education is needed to prepare registered applicants and recipients for employment and then provide counseling regarding prospects and needs; (3) arrange for their participation in one or more of the work-related programs established under title IV of the Act or other Federal law, while coordinating such programs to enhance the availability and efficiency of services provided; and (4) develop an employment plan for each AFDC applicant or recipient. Requires the State agency to provide AFDC applicants and recipients assigned to employment, training, or education programs with child care and transportation services. Sets the Federal contribution to education, training, and assignment costs at 70 percent and the Federal share of administrative and support service costs at 50 percent. Increases, by five percent in any fiscal year after FY 1987, the Federal share of education, training, and assignment costs, provided a State meets certain performance standards to be developed by the Office of Technology Assessment. Provides that such standards shall measure a State's success in reducing welfare costs and helping AFDC recipients achieve self-sufficiency, while accounting for differing conditions among the States. Title IX: State Job Bank Systems - State Job Bank Assistance Act of 1987 - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act to add provisions for State job bank systems. Directs the Secretary of Labor to make funds available through the U.S. Employment Service for the development and implementation of job bank systems in each State. Requires that such systems be designed to use computerized electronic data processing and telecommunications systems. Authorizes appropriations. Directs the Secretary of Labor, within six months after the enactment of this title, to commence a study: (1) of the feasibility of providing portability for pensions and health benefits of dislocated workers; and (2) evaluating the benefits of providing early retirement benefits without penalty for older dislocated workers. Requires a report of such study to be submitted to the Congress within 18 months after such enactment. Authorizes appropriations. Title X: Council on Industrial Competitivenesss - Council on Industrial Competitiveness Act - Establishes in the executive branch an independent agency to be known as the Council on Industrial Competitiveness. Requires the Council to: (1) gather and analyze information regarding the competitiveness of U.S. industries; (2) create an institutional forum where national leaders will identify economic problems inhibiting the competitiveness of industries, develop long-term strategies to address those problems, and create broad consensus in support of those strategies; and (3) make recommendations on issues crucial to the development of coordinated industrial strategies. Directs the Council to examine and make available to the public all international agreements on foreign trade that have been agreed to by the United States. Directs the Council to monitor, and maintain public records regarding, the effect of imports on domestic industries. Requires the Council, not later than one year after the date of enactment of this title, to transmit a report to the Congress and the President containing recommendations for changes in any Federal policy necessary to implement effective industrial strategies. Requires the Council to make annual reports concerning the major industrial development priorities of the United States. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988.</summary>
</bill>
