<bill session="100" type="h" number="765" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Natural Wetlands Inventory and Evaluation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to classify and inventory wetland resources, to measure wetlands degradation, to evaluate the environmental contribution of natural wetlands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402463"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Merchant Marine and Fisheries.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-02">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from CEQ, EPA, DOD, Interior, Army Corps of Engineers.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-02">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSMM" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSMM02" subcommittee="Fisheries and Wildlife Conservation and the Environment" name="House Merchant Marine and Fisheries"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Wetland conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/27/1987--Introduced.
Natural Wetlands Inventory and Evaluation Act - Directs the Secretary of the Interior to formulate and carry out a continuous program which: (1) classifies and inventories the Nation's wetlands; (2) measures the degradation and loss of wetlands; and (3) evaluates the contribution of wetlands to fish and wildlife conservation, land and water conservation, and the quality of the human environment. Directs all departments and agencies of the Government to furnish information concerning the extent of destruction, alteration, and uses of wetlands under their respective programs. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with educational institutions, State fish and wildlife agencies, and private organizations to collect and analyze data for the purposes of this Act. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
