<bill session="100" type="h" number="926" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bank and Thrift Branch Closure Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require national banks and federally chartered thrift institutions to provide advance notice of any proposal to close a branch of such bank or thrift institution to the Comptroller of the Currency or the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, as the case may be, and to customers of such branch, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404422"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400906" joined="1987-02-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400035" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400126" joined="1987-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405256" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400238" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407471" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407672" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="408023" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400333" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410145" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400612" joined="1987-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA07" subcommittee="Financial Institutions Supervision, Regulation and Insurance" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Branch banking"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="National banks"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1987--Introduced.
Bank and Thrift Branch Closure Act of 1987 - Requires any national bank, District bank, or Federal savings and loan association to provide written notice to the Comptroller of the Currency or, in the case of a savings and loan, the Federal Home Loan Bank Board, between 90 and 180 days before closing any branch. Includes among notice requirements: (1) a detailed justification of such action; (2) a financial analysis of deposit and loan activity at such branch for the previous three years and projected activity if the branch were to remain open; (3) a detailed map of the area served by the branch showing the location of all other branches of depository institutions; and (4) a description and the location of any limited or full-service facility planned for such area. Requires such a bank or savings and loan to provide notice of such proposed action to branch customers by: (1) posting a general notice in a conspicuous place on branch premises at least 90 days before the branch is to be closed; and (2) inserting a notice in at least one of any periodic statements mailed to account holders during the period beginning 180 days and ending 90 days before the branch is to be closed. Directs the Comptroller or the Board to determine whether the closing of such branch will result in a significant reduction in the availability of depository institution services in the area and, if so, to consult with leaders in the area and appropriate depository institutions to explore the feasibility of replacing the branch with adequate banking facilities, including a community development credit union.</summary>
</bill>
