<bill session="100" type="h" number="934" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bus Regulatory Reform Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, relating to the abandonment of intrastate bus transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300083"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300017" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403726" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404422" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404602" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="406873" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400595" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407669" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="400331" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409593" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409966" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410097" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="411585" joined="1987-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Public Works and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Surface Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-01">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOT, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-26">
      <text>Unfavorable Executive Comment Received From DOT.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSPW" name="House Public Works and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSPW03" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="House Public Works and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Common carrier regulation"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor bus lines"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Sparsely populated areas"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/3/1987--Introduced.
Bus Regulatory Reform Act Amendments of 1987 - Requires the Interstate Commerce Commission (the Commission), when considering a petition for the discontinuance of bus transportation within on State, to take into account the extent to which interstate and intrastate revenues are less than the variable costs of transportation (currently it has to accord great weight to such revenues). Requires the Commission, when considering such a petition, to accord great weight to whether the transportation is the last motor carrier of passenger service to such point, and whether a reasonable alternative to such service is available. Requires the Commission, when making any findings related to the public interest concerning public transportation certification, to accord great weight to the recommendations of each State in which the transportation to be authorized will be provided. Declares that it is the Federal transportation policy to coordinate State and Federal regulatory actions to ensure bus service to rural communities which have no other means of public transportation. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Commission, the States, and national associations representing governmental agencies should cooperate in developing innovative regulatory approaches to ensure the preservation of bus service in areas which are threatened with the total loss of public transportation service.</summary>
</bill>
