<bill session="100" type="h" number="94" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the establishment of, and the deduction of contributions to, housing savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402675"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400551" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400028" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="402763" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403178" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400104" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403769" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400169" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="405448" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400192" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400596" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407432" joined="1988-03-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="408190" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400601" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409618" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400365" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409887" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400409" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411178" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400428" joined="1987-02-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400435" joined="1987-02-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Ways and Means.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSWM" name="House Ways and Means" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax incentives"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individual taxpayers who have attained the age of 18 an income tax deduction for contributions (cash or readily tradeable securities) to a savings account established for the exclusive purpose of financing the taxpayer's first principal residence. Limits the aggregate amount allowable as a deduction under this Act to any individual for any taxable year to 15 percent of such individual's adjusted gross income. Provides that the amount allowable as a deduction to all taxpayers for amounts paid or transferred to a house savings account may not exceed $1,500 ($3,000 for accounts of married couples). Provides for a $15,000 maximum lifetime deduction ($30,000 for joint returns), with annual inflation adjustments. Limits to ten years the period during which deductible contributions may be made to housing savings accounts. Prohibits any individual from being a beneficiary of more than one account. Excludes distributions from a housing savings account from the gross income of its beneficiary if such distributions are used exclusively for the purchase of a principal residence. Exempts a housing savings account from taxation. Provides for the forfeiture of such exemption where the taxpayer uses the account for certain prohibited purposes. Imposes a penalty on distributions from an account which are used for a prohibited purpose. Requires the trustee of a housing savings account to file a report on the maintenance of the account. Imposes a penalty for the failure to file any required report. Imposes: (1) a six percent excise tax on excess contributions to a housing savings account; and (2) a five percent excise tax on amounts connected with any prohibited transaction with respect to such an account.</summary>
</bill>
