<bill session="100" type="h" number="981" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain flammable liquid storage facilities to have overflow alarm systems, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404856"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and Safety.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED05" subcommittee="Health and Safety" name="House Education and Labor"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1987--Introduced.
Requires storage tank facilities which contain flammable liquids to be equipped with high level alarm systems designed to activate upon the threat of an overflow. Subjects plans and specifications to the approval of the Assistant Secretary of Labor for Occupational Safety and Health prior to installation. Requires the Assistant Secretary to inspect such installations for compliance with this Act. Requires an alarm system to have a distinctive sound signal audible to all personnel in the event of specified occurrences. Requires any high level alarm system at an unattended facility to prevent the flow of flammable liquid in the event of a power failure. Requires systems installed prior to enactment of this Act to be inspected by the Assistant Secretary. Requires fire and emergency plans for facilities to be filed with the appropriate fire department. Directs the Assistant Secretary to assess civil penalties against owners or operators of noncomplying terminals at a certain sum per day.</summary>
</bill>
