<bill session="100" type="hc" number="102" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:08-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for the fiscal years 1988, 1989, and 1990.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410641"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402435" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404097" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404723" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407519" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407558" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407721" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409165" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="400414" joined="1987-04-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Budget.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1987--Introduced.
Sets forth the concurrent resolution on the budget for FY 1988 and the appropriate budgetary levels for FY 1989 and 1990. Sets forth levels and amounts of Federal revenues, new budget authority, budget outlays, and deficits for FY 1988 through 1990 for purposes of determining whether the maximum defict amounts set forth in the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) have been exceeded. Recommends levels of Federal revenues of $672,000,000,000 for FY 1988, $712,000,000,000 for FY 1989, and $776,700,000,000 for 1990. Sets the amount by which the aggregate levels of Federal revenues should be increased at $12,000,000,000 for FY 1988, $11,600,000,000 for FY 1989, and $12,600,000,000 for FY 1990. Designates the following amounts of Federal revenues for Federal Insurance Contributions Act revenues: (1) $59,700,000,000 for FY 1988; (2) $63,900,000,000 for FY 1989; and $68,900,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets the appropriate levels of total new budget authority at $902,700,000,000 for FY 1988, $957,400,000,000 for FY 1989, and $995,700,000,000 for FY 1990. States that the appropriate levels of total budget outlays are $836,100,000,000 for FY 1988, $875,500,000,000 for FY 1989, and $914,900,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets the amount of the deficit at $164,400,000,000 for FY 1988, $163,500,000,000 for FY 1989, and $138,200,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets the appropriate levels of the public debt at $2,580,400,000,000 for FY 1988, $2,810,900,000,000 for FY 1989, and $3,014,000,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets forth the appropriate levels of total Federal credit activity as follows: (1) $33,205,303,000 for new direct loan obligations and $149,583,221,000 for new primary loan guarantee commitments for FY 1988; (2) $31,907,373,000 for new direct loan obligations and $150,748,217,000 for new primary loan guarantee commitments for FY 1989; and (3) $30,617,576,000 for new direct loan obligations and $158,306,087,000 for new primary loan guarantee commitments for FY 1990. Sets forth the levels of budget authority, budget outlays, new direct obligations, and new primary loan guarantee commitments for each major functional category for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires all standing committees of the House of Representatives to make recommendations for FY 1988 for programs within their jurisdiction necessary to carry out proposed reductions in the deficit of $30,000,000,000 and submit such recommendations to the House Budget Committee. Directs the House Committee on Ways and Means to report changes in the law within the jurisdiction of that committee sufficient to increase revenues in FY 1988 by $12,000,000,000 and submit its recommendations to the House Budget Committee. Requires the House Committee on Government Operations to recommend proposed legislation to eliminate any constitutional defects in the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act). Directs the Committee on the Budget to report to the House a reconciliation bill or resolution carrying out such recommendations. Directs the Congressional Budget Office to review such recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
