<bill session="100" type="hc" number="16" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Congressional Regulatory Oversight Improvements Resolution of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution to provide improved structures and procedures for congressional oversight of the Federal regulatory process and for congressional review of agency rules, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional joint committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government regulation"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Law libraries"/>
    <term name="Legislative reference services"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Congressional Regulatory Oversight Improvements Resolution of 1987 - Title I: Establishment and Responsibilities of Joint Committee - Establishes the Joint Committee on Regulatory Affairs to monitor on a continuing basis the rulemaking activities of Federal agencies. Authorizes the joint committee to investigate agency rules on its own initiative or at the request of a Member of either House. Expresses the sense of the Congress that agencies should cooperate with any investigation. Title II: Regulatory Oversight and Review - Authorizes the joint committee to report identical concurrent resolutions disapproving an agency rule on one or more specified grounds, accompanied by a report specifying the basis for disapproval. Sets forth rules of procedure for consideration of the resolution. Prohibits, after adoption of such resolution, either House from considering legislation making or continuing appropriations for the agency in question. Authorizes the joint committee, after adoption of such resolution, to report joint resolutions requiring the agency in question to revise, repeal, or not promulgate the pertinent rule. Title III: Administrative Provisions - Requires the joint committee to adopt rules of procedure consistent, where practicable, with the rules of each House. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the committee should utilize a consolidated, nonpartisan staff. Requires the joint committee to report as soon as practicable in the 100th Congress on its activities during the preceding Congress and make recommendations necessary to improve the functions of such committee. Directs the Postmaster of the House of Representatives to operate a regulatory library to provide reference material relating to administrative law and regulatory affairs.</summary>
</bill>
