<bill session="100" type="hc" number="396" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution concerning the promotion of the environment and human rights in Malaysia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400536" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="400231" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="408407" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411426" joined="1988-10-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on International Economic Policy and Trade.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Asian and Pacific Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA04" subcommittee="International Economic Policy and Trade" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA05" subcommittee="Asian and Pacific Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Detention of persons"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest management"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="Malaysia"/>
    <term name="Opposition (Political science)"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Tropical forests"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/21/1988--Introduced.
Expresses the concern of the congress over the October 1987 arrests of 43 Sarawak tribal people. Encourages the Malaysian Government and the State of Sarawak to: (1) consult with the indigenous groups of the forest of Sarawak who are concerned with the future of the forest; (2) release all those imprisoned for the expression of their views and lift all restrictions on the rights of those detained for their opposition to the environmental and public policies of the Government of Malaysia; and (3) cease attacks on the independence of the Malaysian judiciary. Calls upon the President to: (1) encourage the importation into the United States of only hardwood harvested in a sustainable manner, and urge other countries to adopt similar practices; (2) encourage Malaysia and all countries marketing tropical hardwood to promote sustainable forestry practices; and (3) urge the Malaysian Government and the Government of the State of Sarawak to release those imprisoned for the expression of their views, lift restrictions on the rights of those detained for opposition to governmental public policies, and cease attacks on the Malaysian judiciary. Urges the President to communicate to the International Tropical Timber Organization that the United States: (1) advocates that the interests of indigenous peoples play a key role within the Organization; (2) encourages the Organization to develop environmentally sound policies; and (3) condemns imports of tropical hardwood from logging concession areas where activities cause environmental damage, are not managed for sustained use, or endanger the way of life of the inhabitants of the forest.</summary>
</bill>
