<bill session="100" type="hc" number="71" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of the Congress that the Federal Government take immediate steps to support a National STORM Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409353"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Artificial satellites"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Hurricanes"/>
    <term name="Meteorological research"/>
    <term name="Meteorological satellites"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Space"/>
    <term name="Storms"/>
    <term name="Weather"/>
    <term name="Weather and Climate"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/10/1987--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Federal Government should take immediate steps to support funding for a National Storm-Scale Operational and Research Meteorology Program (STORM) under the leadership of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration, with the cooperation of other Federal agencies. Provides that, on or before August 1, 1988, and each fifth year thereafter, the President shall transmit to the Congress a plan for the National STORM Program and its budgetary requirements, specifying the activities to be conducted and the Federal agency which will conduct them. Directs the President, on or about January 1, 1989, to transmit to the Congress a progress report on implementing the National STORM Program. Directs the Administration to: (1) place a high priority on reinstating the two geostationary operational environmental satellite (GOES) system; (2) compensate for the absence of a second GOES satellite by taking actions such as increasing hurricane reconnaissance flights; and (3) undertake an immediate analysis of how best to maintain a two GOES system.</summary>
</bill>
