<bill session="100" type="hc" number="93" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:07-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-24">CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution setting forth the congressional budget for the United States Government for the fiscal years 1988, 1989, and 1990.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404752"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Budget.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Committee on Rules Granted a Modified Closed Rule Providing Six Hours of General Debate; Waiving all Points of Order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Rules Committee Resolution H.Res.139 Reported to House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08">
      <text>Rule Passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08">
      <text>Called up by House by Rule.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08">
      <text>Considered by House Unfinished Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>House Agreed to Amendments Adopted by the Committee of the Whole.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Resolution Agreed to in House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-21" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="98">
      <text>Received in the Senate. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 98.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Senate struck all after the Enacting Clause and substituted the language of S.CON.RES. 49 amended.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="97" datetime="1987-05-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate in lieu of S.CON.RES. 49 with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Yea-Nay Vote. 56-42. Record Vote No: 97.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Senate insisted on its amendments, requested a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>House Disagreed to Senate Amendments by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>House Conferees Instructed  by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>House Agreed to Request for Conference and Speaker Appointed Conferees: Gray (PA), Foley, Lowry (WA), Derrick, Miller (CA), Frost, Fazio, Russo, Oberstar, Espy, Latta, Gradison, Mack, Goodling, Denny Smith (OR), Buechner, Houghton.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and held at desk:. House agrees to request for conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Senate appointed conferees Chiles; Hollings; Johnston; Sasser; Riegle; Exon; Domenici; Armstrong; Kassebaum; Boschwitz.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-13">
      <text>Conference held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Rules Granted a Rule Providing One Hour of Debate for the Consideration of the Conference Report; Waiving All Points of Order.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Conference report S. Rept. 100-76 filed in Senate by Senator Chiles under the authority of the order of Jun 18, 87 on the disagreeing votes of the two Houses on the amendment of the Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-19">
      <text>Conference papers, Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Conference Report 100-175 Filed in House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-23">
      <text>Rule Passed House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-23">
      <text>House Agreed to Conference Report by Yea-Nay Vote: 215 - 201 (Record Vote No: 204).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-23">
      <text>Conference papers, Senate report and managers' statement and message on House action held at the desk.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Motion to commit to Senate Committee on Finance made in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Motion to commit to Senate Committee on Finance tabled in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 56-43. Record Vote No: 155.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>A point of order was raised that the conferees exceeded the scope of their authority.  The Chair ruled that the point of order was not well taken.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Ruling of the Chair sustained by Yea-Nay Vote. 54-45. Record Vote No: 156.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="conference" roll="157" datetime="1987-06-24" where="s" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Yea-Nay Vote. 53-46. Record Vote No: 157.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Senate receded from its amendment to the title. By Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-25">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBU" name="House Budget" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="rule" session="100" type="hr" number="139"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="sc" number="49"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Catastrophic health insurance"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Corporation taxes"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Deficit financing"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government spending reductions"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Tax rates"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h30"/>
    <amendment number="h31"/>
    <amendment number="h32"/>
    <amendment number="h33"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>6/18/1987--Conference report filed in Senate.
(Conference report filed in Senate, S. Rept. 100-76) Sets forth the concurrent resolution on the budget for FY 1988 and the appropriate budgetary levels for FY 1989 and 1990. Sets forth levels and amounts of Federal revenues, new budget authority, budget outlays, and deficits for FY 1988 through 1990 for purposes of determining whether the maximum deficit amounts set forth in the Balanced Budget and Emergency Deficit Control Act of 1985 (Gramm-Rudman-Hollings Act) have been exceeded. Recommends levels of Federal revenues of $692,300,000,000 for FY 1988, $732,300,000,000 for FY 1989, and $779,800,000,000 for 1990. Sets the amount by which the aggregate levels of Federal revenues should be increased at $21,150,000,000 for FY 1988, $24,950,000,000 for FY 1989, and $26,100,000,000 for 1990. Designates the following amounts of Federal revenues for Federal Insurance Contributions Act revenues: (1) $59,700,000,000 for FY 1988; (2) $63,850,000,000 for FY 1989; and (3) $68,950,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets the appropriate levels of total new budget authority at $912,700,000,000 for FY 1988, $956,100,000,000 for FY 1989, and $974,300,000,000 for FY 1990. States that the appropriate levels of total budget outlays are $836,200,000,000 for FY 1988, $868,200,000,000 for FY 1989, and $888,300,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets the amount of the deficit at $144,000,000,000 for FY 1988, $135,800,000,000 for FY 1989, and $108,500,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets the appropriate levels of the public debt at $2,565,100,000,000 for FY 1988, $2,777,100,000,000 for FY 1989, and $2,964,200,000,000 for FY 1990. Sets forth the appropriate levels of total Federal credit activity as follows: (1) $34,600,000,000 for new direct loan obligations, $156,700,000,000 for new primary loan guarantee commitments, and $100,600,000,000 for new secondary loan guarantee commitments for FY 1988; (2) $33,550,000,000 for new direct loan obligations, $150,550,000,000 for new primary loan guarantee commitments, and $97,600,000,000 for new secondary loan guarantee commitments for FY 1989; and (3) $32,450,000,000 for new direct loan obligations, $158,300,000,000 for new primary loan guarantee commitments, and $94,600,000,000 for new secondary loan guarantee commitments for FY 1990. Sets forth the levels of budget authority, budget outlays, new direct obligations, new primary loan guarantee commitments,and new secondary loan guarantee commitments for each major functional category for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires the following Senate Committees to report changes in the laws within their jurisdiction and to make recommendations sufficient to reduce budget authority and outlays by specified amounts for FY 1988 through 1990: (1) Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry; (2) Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs; (3) Commerce, Science, and Transportation; (4) Energy and Natural Resources; (5) Environment and Public Works; (6) Finance; (7) Governmental Affairs; (8) Labor and Human Resources; and (9) Veterans' Affairs. Requires the following House Committees to report changes in the laws within their jurisdiction and to make recommendations sufficient to reduce budget authority and outlays by specified amounts for FY 1988 through 1990: (1) Agriculture; (2) Merchant Marine and Fisheries; (3) Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs; (4) Education and Labor; (5) Energy and Commerce; (6) Interior and Insular Affairs; (7) Post Office and Civil Service; (8) Veterans' Affairs; and (9) Ways and Means. Directs the Senate Committee on Finance and the House Committee on Ways and Means to report changes in laws within the jurisdiction of such committees which are sufficient to increase revenues by specified amounts in FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Senate Finance Committee on report changes in laws to increase the statutory limit on the public debt to an amount not to exceed $2,565,100,000,000. Earmarks a specified amount of new budget authority and budget outlays for FY 1988 through 1990 for funding for defense and interest. Directs the Senate Committee on Finance and the House Committee on Ways and Means to report legislation to: (1) establish a deficit reduction account in the Treasury; (2) ensure that revenues deposited in such account would not be available for appropriation; and (3) provide that such revenues be used to retire the national debt. Expresses the sense of the Congress that from time to time the U.S. Government should sell assets to non-government buyers. Describes the budgetary treatment of legislation authorizing the prepayment of certain loans. Establishes a reserve fund for: (1) the child care and job training initiative; and (2) the Medicare catastrophic health insurance initiative. Assumes that the Senate Committee on Finance and the House Committees on Ways and Means, and Energy and Commerce would achieve Medicare savings without increasing premiums or deductibles or delaying eligibility or otherwise raising beneficiary out-of-pocket costs. Expresses the sense of the Senate that the increase of revenue levels provided for this Act will not be achieved by either raising or delaying the individual or corporate income tax rates provided in the Tax Reform Act of 1986. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the special needs of rural hospitals should be taken into account in enacting legislation to reconcile Medicare Program expenditures with those under the congressional concurrent resolution on the budget for FY 1988 and subsequent years.</summary>
</bill>
