<bill session="100" type="hj" number="102" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-12">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-02-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution making emergency additional funds available by transfer for the fiscal year ending September 30, 1987, for the Emergency Food and Shelter Program of the Federal Emergency Management Agency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411587"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Placed on Union Calendar No: 4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22">
      <text>Reported to House by House Committee on Appropriations.  Report No: 100-4.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="13" datetime="1987-01-27" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House by Yea-Nay Vote: 296 - 79 (Record Vote No: 13).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-01-28">
      <text>Received in the Senate and read twice and referred to the Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Committee on Appropriations. Reported to Senate by Senator Stennis with amendments. With written report No. 100-5.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-29">
      <text>Motion to waive the Budget Act with respect to to the bill agreed to in Senate by Yea-Nay Vote. 67-22. Record Vote No: 10.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="12" datetime="1987-01-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Yea-Nay Vote. 78-5. Record Vote No: 12.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-02-03">
      <text>Unanimous Consent Request to Take from the Table and to go to Conference Rejected in House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-02-04" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:HOUSE">
      <text>House Agreed to Senate Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1987-02-04">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1987-02-04">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1987-02-12" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-6" type="public" datetime="1987-02-12">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-6.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSAP" name="Senate Appropriations" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional salaries and pensions"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive impoundment of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Federal Emergency Management Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Mental care facilities"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
    <term name="Veterans' rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s7"/>
    <amendment number="s9"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/29/1987--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended, roll call #12 (78-5)) Rescinds specified disaster relief funds under the Department of Housing and Urban Development-Independent Agencies Appropriations Act, 1987 and made available by Public Laws 99-500 and 99-591. Transfers a specified amount from previously appropriated FY 1987 Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) disaster relief funds to the emergency food and shelter program. Transfers from such funds a specified amount to the Veterans Administration (VA) for treatment of chronically mentally ill veterans as provided for by this Act. Amends Federal law to authorize the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to contract for care, treatment, and rehabilitative services in halfway houses, therapeutic communities, psychiatric residential treatment centers, and other community-based treatment facilities of eligible veterans suffering from chronic mental illness disabilities. Includes within such coverage homeless veterans with such disabilities. Requires the Administrator to approve the quality and effectiveness of such program before entering into a contract for such care. Requires the Administrator to designate a VA employee to provide case management services for each veteran provided care and services under this provision. Sets forth the order of priority for providing such care to eligible veterans. Authorizes the Administrator to contract to provide in-kind assistance under this provision. Requires the VA to receive full reimbursement from the contract facility for any such in-kind assistance provided. Directs the Administrator, no later than three years after the enactment of this Act, to report to the Senate and House Veterans' Affairs Committees concerning the provision of such services. Disapproves the recommendations of the President relating to pay rates of Members of Congress, Federal judges, and Federal officials under the Executive Schedule. Disapproves a proposed deferral (D87-33) of budget authority for the Department of Agriculture's temporary emergency food assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
