<bill session="100" type="hj" number="185" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to provide for a settlement to the Long Island Rail Road labor-management dispute.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406746"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406994" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="407457" joined="1987-03-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Automobile repair"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Lockouts"/>
    <term name="Maintenance and repair"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1987--Introduced.
Requires parties to the Long Island Rail Road labor-management dispute to take all necessary steps to restore or preserve the conditions out of which the dispute arose as such conditions existed on January 17, 1987. Declares that the report and recommendations of the advisory board established under Public Law 100-2 to provide for a temporary prohibition of strikes or lockouts with respect to the Long Island Rail Road labor-management dispute shall be binding on the parties, except that nothing in this joint resolution prevents a mutual written agreement by the parties different from those established by this joint resolution. Prohibits the parties to the dispute from taking action with respect to the issue of repair and maintenance of a certain motor vehicle fleet until the next conference between such parties under the Railway Labor Act. Directs the parties to consider such issue in the conference.</summary>
</bill>
