<bill session="100" type="hj" number="433" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to authorize the National Committee of American Airmen Rescued by General Mihailovich to erect a monument to General Draza Mihailovich in Washington, District of Columbia, or its environs, in recognition of the role he played in saving the lives of more than five hundred United States airmen in Yugoslavia during World War II.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400085"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on House Administration.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Libraries and Memorials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSHA" name="House Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSHA09" subcommittee="Libraries and Memorials" name="House Administration"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="sj" number="182"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="sj" number="182"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
    <term name="Yugoslavia"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/1987--Introduced.
Authorizes the National Committee of American Airmen Rescued by General Mihailovich to establish a monument to General Draza Mihailovich in the District of Columbia or its environs in recognition of the role he played in saving the lives of more than 500 U.S. airmen in Yugoslavia during World War II. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to select, with the approval of the National Commission of Fine Arts and the National Capital Planning Commission, a suitable site on public grounds for such memorial. Subjects the design and any plans for the memorial to the approval of the Secretary, the National Commission of Fine Arts, and the National Capital Planning Commission. Declares that, except for specified items, neither the United States nor the District of Columbia shall bear any expense in the establishment of such memorial. Directs the Secretary to permit groundbreaking for construction of the monument only after determining that sufficient funds are available for completion of the monument. Directs that the maintenance and care of the monument shall be the responsibility of the National Committee of American Airmen Rescued by General Mihailovich.</summary>
</bill>
