<bill session="100" type="hj" number="44" updated="2014-03-22T09:53:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution relating to Federal budget procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on The Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Monopolies and Commercial Law.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>See H.J.Res.321.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSJU" name="House Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSJU05" subcommittee="Monopolies and Commercial Law" name="House Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="hj" number="321"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Constitution and Constitutional Amendments"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="National income"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Requires the Congress, prior to each fiscal year, to adopt a statement of receipts and outlays for that year in which total outlays are not greater than total receipts. Permits the Congress in such statement to provide for a specific excess of outlays over receipts by a three-fifths vote. Requires the President and the Congress to ensure that actual outlays do not exceed the outlays set forth in such statement. Prohibits total receipts for any fiscal year set forth in such statement from increasing by a rate greater than the increase in national income in the last calendar year, unless a bill directed solely to approving specific additional receipts is enacted. Permits the Congress to suspend the provisions of this Act for any fiscal year in which the Congress has declared war. Declares that total receipts shall include all receipts of the United States, except those derived from borrowing, and total outlays shall include all outlays of the United States except those for repayment of debt principal.</summary>
</bill>
