<bill session="100" type="hj" number="514" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Assistance for the Nicaraguan Democratic Resistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing emergency assistance for the Nicaraguan democratic resistance.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400882" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402435" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402463" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400081" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404002" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404520" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404733" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405209" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405855" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406554" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="406682" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407399" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400286" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408621" joined="1988-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="409442" joined="1988-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Intelligence (Permanent).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Appropriations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Executive Comment Requested from DOD.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Investigations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Western Hemisphere Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HLIG" name="House Intelligence (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAP" name="House Appropriations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSAS" name="House Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSAS06" subcommittee="Investigations" name="House Armed Services"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA07" subcommittee="Western Hemisphere Affairs" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Air defenses"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Auditing"/>
    <term name="Central America"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Reagan Doctrine"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1988--Introduced.
Emergency Assistance for the Nicaraguan Democratic Resistance Act - Transfers to the President a specified sum of unobligated funds to provide humanitarian assistance to the Nicaraguan democratic resistance and transportation for such assistance. Earmarks a specified amount of such assistance for the purchase, repair, and transportation of communications equipment. Provides that such transferred funds shall remain available until March 31, 1989. Declares it to be U.S. policy to assist all groups within the resistance which are committed to work for democratic national reconciliation in Nicaragua and which respect international standards of conduct. Prohibits assistance for groups violating human rights or engaging in drug smuggling, or the significant misuse of public or private funds. Directs the President to use authority under this Act to encourage the resistance to broaden its representative base, increase the responsiveness of military forces to civilian leadership, and continue to participate in the diplomatic process. Requires the President to make a determination and report to the Congress on certain actions taken by the resistance such as willingness to participate in the diplomatic effort, efforts to eliminate human rights abuses, and measures assuring accountability of funds, before such funds may be used. Makes the Secretary of State responsible for policy guidance, coordination, and supervision of Government activities under this Act. Requires the establishment of standards, procedures, and controls to ensure accountability of funds. Sets limitations on the activities of U.S. Government personnel in Nicaragua. Directs the Secretary of Defense to make available through March 31, 1989, passive air defense equipment to assure the safety of transportation provided under this Act. Provides that, after a ceasefire is negotiated between the Government of Nicaragua and the resistance, delivery of the remaining assistance shall be made in accordance with the terms of the ceasefire agreement. Welcomes proposals by the President to the Congress for bilateral and multilateral action to: (1) provide additional economic assistance to the democratic countries of Central America; (2) facilitate the growth of their economies; (3) provide a more realistic plan to assist such countries in managing their foreign debt; (4) develop these initiatives in concert with democratic allies; and (5) lift the embargo on trade and other transactions against Nicaragua, and include Nicaragua as eligible for assistance, if it is in compliance with the Guatemala Accords. Sets forth: (1) time periods during which the President may request additional assistance for the resistance, after consultation with the Congress; and (2) congressional priority procedures for taking up such requests.</summary>
</bill>
