<bill session="100" type="hj" number="637" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to provide for a temporary prohibition of strikes or lockouts with respect to, and, if necessary, a resolution of, the railway labor-mangement dispute between the Chicago and North Western Transportation Company and certain of its employees represented by the United Transportation Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400604"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF07" subcommittee="Transportation, Tourism, and Hazardous Materials" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Labor injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Lockouts"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Extends a temporary prohibition of strikes or lockouts, under specified provisions of the Railway Labor Act, with respect to the Chicago and Northwestern Transportation Company labor-management dispute referred to in a specified Executive Order. Provides for a resolution of such dispute if it is not resolved by agreement by September 19, 1988. Directs such Company and the United Transportation Union to then resolve the dispute by implementing, without any work stoppage, the recommendations submitted by a specified Presidential Emergency Board. Makes obligations imposed by such implementation enforceable in U.S. district court by the Attorney General.</summary>
</bill>
