<bill session="100" type="hj" number="646" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Commission on Human Resources Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution establishing the National Commission on Human Resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400425"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406765" joined="1988-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="409644" joined="1988-08-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Science, Space, and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Rights and International Organizations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Science, Research and Technology.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSED07" subcommittee="Human Resources" name="House Education and Labor"/>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA06" subcommittee="Human Rights and International Organizations" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
    <committee code="HSSY" name="House Science, Space and Technology" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSSY03" subcommittee="Science, Research and Technology" name="House Science, Space and Technology"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Manpower"/>
    <term name="Manpower policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Introduced.
National Commission on Human Resources Act - Establishes a National Commission on Human Resources. Directs the Commission to: (1) advise the Congress, the President, and the U.S. public on policies and programs designed to facilitate the attainment of fuller human potential; (2) solicit views from the public on the role of the individual, family, community, and government in researching, educating, and implementing techniques designed to increase human potential in body, mind, and spirit; (3) identify private and foundation financial resources to fund the Commission's operation; (4) establish a scientific advisory panel to assist in the evaluation of technologies and procedures calculated to develop fuller human potential; and (5) after consultation with the Secretary of State, communicate with foreign governments and international organizations on the establishment of counterpart commissions, and prepare for an international meeting of such commissions (if they are established) prior to the preparation of its final report. Directs the Commission to prepare and transmit to the President and the Congress: (1) a report on its activities and recommendations within 18 months after the effective date of this joint resolution; and (2) a proposal for implementation of its recommendations within 24 months after such effective date. Sets forth provisions for Commission members. Directs the President and specified congressional officers to appoint such members, from representatives of an appropriate executive department, both Houses of the Congress, the field of extraordinary human performance research, physicians, the field of higher education, the clergy, organized labor, business management, retired individuals, high school students, and the general public. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
