<bill session="100" type="hj" number="678" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">War Powers Amendments of 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to amend the War Powers Resolution to remove the requirement that U.S. Armed Forces be withdrawn in the absence of congressional authorization for certain deployments abroad and to establish new procedures for congressional action with respect to such deployment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401847"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/1988--Introduced.
War Powers Amendments of 1989 - Amends the War Powers Resolution to repeal provisions requiring the President to terminate any use of U.S. armed forces: (1) within 60 days after such use is required to be reported to the Congress unless the Congress authorizes their continued use or the President is unable to meet such deadline as a result of an armed attack on the United States; or (2) if the Congress so directs by concurrent resolution. Revises provisions concerning congressional action under the War Powers Resolution. Allows the President to continue the use of U.S. armed forces for an additional 30 days beyond that required by a joint resolution enacted by the Congress providing for the withdrawal of U.S. armed forces if the President certifies that unavoidable military necessity respecting the safety of U.S. armed forces requires the continued use of such armed forces in the course of bringing about a prompt removal of such forces. Sets forth expedited procedures for the consideration of joint resolutions concerning the use of U.S. armed forces. Repeals provisions relating to concurrent resolutions. Makes certain conforming amendments. Repeals provisions of the Department of State Authorization Act, FY 1984 and 1985 relating to expedited procedures for joint resolutions and bills requiring the removal of U.S. armed forces from hostilities.</summary>
</bill>
