<bill session="100" type="hr" number="119" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to authorize certain investigations by the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct and to amend the Code of Official Conduct of the Rules of the House of Representatives to prohibit any Member, officer, or employee of the House from discriminating against any qualified handicapped person with respect to employment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Standards of Official Conduct.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
    <committee code="HSSO" name="House Standards of Official Conduct" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Personnel management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/11/1987--Introduced.
Amends rule X of the Rules of the House of Representatives to authorize the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to investigate the official conduct of a Member, officer, or employee upon notification from an employee of an officer in accordance with the adverse personnel action review procedure as promulgated by the Committee on the House Administration. Amends rule XLIII to prohibit discrimination against an individual with respect to employment because such individual is a qualified handicapped person. Describes a qualified handicapped person as an individual who: (1) has an impairment which substantially limits one or more of such individual's major life activities, or has a record of such impairment; and (2) with or without reasonable accommodation, can perform the essential functions of the position without endangering the health and safety of the individual or others, and who meets the requirements for such position.</summary>
</bill>
