<bill session="100" type="hr" number="229" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to impose certain limitations on the use of continuing resolutions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409618"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401383" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="401526" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="401874" joined="1987-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="403242" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403545" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404009" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404325" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="400174" joined="1987-07-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="405580" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="408190" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410010" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="410529" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410574" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Appropriations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Legislative resolutions"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/22/1987--Introduced.
Amends rule XXI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to provide that no appropriation shall be reported in any joint resolution continuing appropriations, or amendment thereto, for any expenditure not previously authorized by law, except to continue appropriations for public works and objects which are already in progress. Declares that this provision shall only be applicable for FY 1989 or any subsequent fiscal year. Makes it out of order in the House to consider any joint resolution continuing appropriations, or amendment thereto, which covers a period of more than 90 calendar days. Declares that an item of appropriation set forth in any joint resolution continuing appropriations shall not be for an amount exceeding 90 percent of the amount that represents a continuation of the rate of appropriation for such item under current law. Prohibits any provision of this Act from being waived other than by a two-thirds vote of the Members present and voting.</summary>
</bill>
