<bill session="100" type="hr" number="277" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to human rights abuses in Afghanistan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410147"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="411948" joined="1987-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-14">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-10-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Resolution Agreed to in House (Amended) by Yea-Nay Vote: 411 - 0 (Record Vote No: 365).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="hj" number="25"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="Underground movements"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/20/1987--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended, roll call #365 (411-0)) Declares that the House of Representatives hereby: (1) renews its condemnation of the continued Soviet invasion and occupation of Afghanistan; (2) finds that past Soviet representations concerning Soviet troop withdrawal have been a sham; (3) finds that recent Soviet offers of a ceasefire and national reconciliation fail to provide the framework for a settlement as long as Soviet troops continue to occupy Afghanistan; (4) believes that the only acceptable formula for a settlement in Afghanistan is one that results in a government representative of the Afghan people; and (5) renews its commitment to support the Afghans through the provision of material support. Urges the Secretary of State to take specified actions to encourage Soviet military withdrawal and a peaceful settlement of the situation in Afghanistan. Urges: (1) the Soviet Union to present a timetable for the withdrawal of its forces at any session of U.N.-sponsored indirect negotiations with Pakistan; and (2) the Government of Pakistan to resist Soviet pressure to accept less than such a timetable for withdrawal of such forces.</summary>
</bill>
