<bill session="100" type="hr" number="301" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the House of Representatives that monetary policy should stabilize the domestic economy, not exchange rates.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408109"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Banking, Finance and Urban Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Domestic Monetary Policy.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSBA" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSBA03" subcommittee="Domestic Monetary Policy" name="House Banking, Finance, and Urban Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="hc" number="210"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Federal reserve system"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/1987--Introduced.
Urges the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System and the Federal Open Market Committee to: (1) conduct monetary policy independently of any international agreements or understandings reached by the Department of the Treasury; (2) refrain from conducting monetary policy primarily for the purpose of maintaining exchange rates for the dollar at any particular level or within any particular range; (3) devote monetary policy to the stabilization of the domestic economy along a path of steady, sustainable and noninflationary growth, even if such stabilization entails significant changes in exchange rates; and (4) take into account the behavior of the dollar on the foreign exchange market in their deliberations, but only as one of many factors affecting the domestic economy.</summary>
</bill>
