<bill session="100" type="hr" number="30" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution amending Rule XLVI of the Rules of the House to require greater economy in mass mailing and other uses of the frank by Members of the House, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404325"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Franking privilege"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (House)"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Postal rates and revenues"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/7/1987--Introduced.
Amends rule XLVI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require that Members of the House of Representatives prepare franked mail (and mass mailings) to qualify for the lowest first-class rate practicable. Prohibits a Representative from using the equivalent priority mail rate for franked mail unless the mail is inherently time sensitive. Decreases, after April 30, 1986, the amount of franked mail to which Representatives are entitled. Provides a formula to count against limitations on the use of the frank, mail matter for the period beginning on May 1, 1986, and ending on December 31, 1986, that relates to a Representative's notice of appearance or scheduled itinerary. Provides a formula, for the period beginning on May 1, 1986, and ending on September 30, 1986, to limit the amount of franked mail a Representative may mail that is not in direct response to an inquiry or request.</summary>
</bill>
