<bill session="100" type="hr" number="330" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-10">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution relating to the termination of the affairs of the Select Committee to Investigate Covert Arms Transactions With Iran.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404996"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402484" joined="1987-12-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-10">
      <text>Called up by House by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-10">
      <text>Resolution Agreed to in House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="hr" number="329"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Iran-Contra affair"/>
    <term name="National Archives and Records Administration"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Public records"/>
    <term name="Reagan Doctrine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/10/1987--Introduced.
Requires the Select Committee to Investigate Covert Arms Transactions with Iran: (1) to terminate on March 1, 1988; (2) not to undertake any activities unrelated to the closing of its affairs between the date of adoption of this resolution and the date of the Select Committee's termination, other than receiving materials in response to requests made before the date of adoption of this resolution; and (3) upon termination, to transmit its records to the Clerk of the House of Representatives for storage in the National Archives. Grants members of the Select Committee access to the records which are in the National Archives upon request. Allows any other member, or staff, of the House of Representatives, or of any joint committee of the Congress, access to such records only upon approval by the Permanent Select Committee on Intelligence in accordance with its rules and the rules of the House of Representatives.</summary>
</bill>
