<bill session="100" type="hr" number="401" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the House of Representatives with respect to implications of the Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty for the military security of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization and with respect to other arms control issues.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401986"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Foreign Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Arms Control, International Security and Science.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Europe and the Middle East.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSFA" name="House Foreign Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA01" subcommittee="Arms Control, International Security and Science" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSFA03" subcommittee="Europe and the Middle East" name="House Foreign Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Collective security agreements"/>
    <term name="Conventional weapons"/>
    <term name="Europe"/>
    <term name="Intermediate range ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Military policy"/>
    <term name="NATO countries"/>
    <term name="NATO military forces"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/14/1988--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the House of Representatives that the President should: (1) continue to provide a credible nuclear deterrent based in Europe for the security of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO); (2) provide leadership in achieving modernization of conventional NATO forces; (3) seek to achieve a U.S.-Soviet agreement for verifiable conventional arms reductions in Europe; (4) discuss with other NATO member nations how NATO can best develop a comprehensive strategy for arms control and nuclear and conventional defense modernization in the post-Intermediate-Range Nuclear Forces (INF) Treaty period; (5) halt the elimination of U.S. missile systems under the Treaty and take other appropriate measures if the Soviets materially violate the Treaty; and (6) create specific procedures to resolve existing and future Soviet arms control violations.</summary>
</bill>
