<bill session="100" type="hr" number="419" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution amending the Rules of the House of Representatives with respect to preservation of, and access to, noncurrent records of the House.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Subcommittee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Forwarded by Subcommittee to Full Committee.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Committee Consideration and Mark-up Session Held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Ordered to be Reported (Amended).</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Reported to House (Amended) by House Committee on Rules.  Report No: 100-1054.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Placed on House Calendar No: 238.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Archives"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1988--Reported to House amended.
(Reported to House from the Committee on Rules with amendment, H. Rept. 100-1054) Amends rule XXXVI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to revise its provisions concerning the preservation of noncurrent records of the House. Requires each congressional officer (Clerk, Sergeant-at-Arms, Doorkeeper, Postmaster, and Chaplain) to transfer to the Clerk any noncurrent records made or acquired in the course of such officer's duties. Declares that such records deposited at the National Archives and Records Administration are the permanent property of the House and remain subject to this rule and the orders of the House. Provides for the public disclosure of such records. Amends rule XI to require each committee to include in its rules standards for availability of records of the committee delivered to the Archivist under rule XXXVI. Requires such standards to include a requirement that nonavailability of a record for a period longer than the period otherwise applicable under that rule shall be approved by a separate vote of the committee. Authorizes the Committee on House Administration to report at any time on matters relating to preservation and availability of noncurrent records of the House under rule XXXVI.</summary>
</bill>
