<bill session="100" type="hr" number="418" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to make technical amendments in the Rules of the House of Representatives, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400600"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/29/1988--Introduced.
Amends rule XI of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require each House committee to publish its rules in the Congressional Record not later than 30 days after the committee is elected (currently, not later than 30 days after the Congress convenes). Exempts the Committee on House Administration from the prohibition against committee meetings while the House is reading a measure for amendment under the five-minute rule. Removes certain restrictions on the three-day layover for committee reports. Provides that the prohibition against professional committee staff engaging in any work other than committee business applies to such staff's congressional working hours. Amends rule XXI to specify the authority of the Committee on the Budget to report reconciliation bills. Amends rule XXII to require that the referral of bills and resolutions be made in accordance with such rule. Amends rule XXIV to specify that the call of committees on Calendar Wednesday begins again in a new Congress. Amends rule XLI to make the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct responsible for administering such rule, which concerns the qualifications of officers and employees of the House. (Currently, the Committee on House Administration has such responsibility.) Repeals certain obsolete rules provisions. Amends the Legislative Reorganization Act of 1946 to repeal its obsolete provision on congressional adjournment.</summary>
</bill>
