<bill session="100" type="hr" number="47" updated="2014-03-22T09:50:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">House Scheduling Reform Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend House Rules to require that the Speaker announce a legislative program each session, to require the early election and organization of committees, and to restrict the use of the suspension of the rules procedure.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300069"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rules of the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSRU01" subcommittee="Rules of the House" name="House Rules"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional Record"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional sessions"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Government spending"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="House rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Legislative calendars"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
House Scheduling Reform Amendments of 1987 - Amends rule I of the Rules of the House of Representatives to require the Speaker, at the beginning of each session, to announce a legislative program for the session which includes: (1) target dates for the consideration of specified major budgetary, authorization, and appropriations bills; (2) an indication of those full, five-day work weeks during which the House will be in session for committee and floor business; (3) those weeks set aside for district work periods, holidays, and recesses; and (4) the target date for adjournment of the session. Amends rule X to require standing committees to hold organizational meetings not later than three days after their election. Amends rule XXVII to declare that it shall not be in order to suspend the rules to consider any measure or matter unless by direction of the committee of jurisdiction, or unless the chairman and ranking minority member of such committee files a written request with the Speaker asking for its consideration under suspension of the rules. Makes it out of order to suspend the rules to consider any measure or matter that would enact new budget or spending authority in excess of $50,000,000 for any fiscal year. Makes it out of order to suspend the rules to consider any joint resolution which proposes to amend the Constitution. Makes it out of order to suspend the rules to consider any measure or matter unless notice is placed in the Congressional Record of its scheduled consideration. Requires such notification to include the numerical designation of the matter, its short title, the text of any amendments, and the date the matter is scheduled for consideration.</summary>
</bill>
