<bill session="100" type="hr" number="526" updated="2014-03-22T09:51:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to amend the Rules of the House of Representatives to establish a Public Review Board and an Inspector General, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403476"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401947" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400100" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400140" joined="1988-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="404869" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400205" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406463" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407306" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400378" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300155" joined="1988-10-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411247" joined="1988-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="HSRU" name="House Rules" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (House)"/>
    <term name="Congressional ethics"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="House of Representatives"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Rules of the House of Representatives to add rule LI to establish a Public Review Board. Sets forth requirements for the six members of the Board. Prohibits more than three members from being of the same political party. Prohibits a member from being: (1) a Member or ex-Member of Congress; (2) a relative of a Member of Congress; (3) an officer or employee of any government; or (4) a registered lobbyist or foreign agent within the previous five years. Authorizes the Board to: (1) recommend to the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct such actions as it deems appropriate to establish or enforce standards of official conduct for House Members, officers, and employees; (2) investigate any alleged violation of the Code of Official Conduct and recommend to the Committee any action deemed appropriate; and (3) report to the appropriate Federal or State authorities, with the approval of the House, any substantial evidence of a violation of any law which may have been disclosed in an investigation. Requires an affirmative vote of a majority of the members of the Board before the Board makes any report or recommendation or undertakes an investigation. Sets forth administrative procedures for the Board in response to written complaints. Adds rule LII, which establishes the position of Inspector General of the House of Representatives. Describes the duties of the Inspector General, to include: (1) providing policy direction for the financial operations of the House; (2) recommending policies to promote efficiency in the administration of, and the prevention and detection of fraud and abuse in, House operations; (3) notifying the Board of any evidence of fraud or violations of standards of official conduct; (4) notifying the Board of evidence of fraud or other deficiencies with respect to House financial operations; and (5) preparing an annual report on its activities. Amends rule X and rule XLIV to revise the duties of the Committee on Standards of Official Conduct to conform to provisions under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
