<bill session="100" type="s" number="10" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Emergency Medical Services and Trauma Care Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Emergency Medical Services and Trauma Care Improvement Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve emergency medical services and trauma care, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1988-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-07-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-05-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1988-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, HUD, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-504.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-13" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="928">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 928.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-504.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Commerce by unanimous consent until the close of business October 3, 1988.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Senate Committee on Commerce discharged. Pursuant to the order of September 30, 1988.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1059">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1059.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Communication in medicine"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Highway planning"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio frequency allocation"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Labor and Human Resources with amendment, S. Rept. 100-504) Emergency Medical Services and Trauma Care Improvement Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for the establishment and operation of a National Clearinghouse on Emergency Medical Services. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 or for the first three fiscal years for which funds are appropriated. Amends the Public Health Service Act to revise the application procedure for Preventive Health and Health Services Block Grants to provide the State officer responsible for the administration of the State highway safety program an opportunity to participate in the development of any plan relating to emergency medical services as such plan relates to highway safety. Allows the State official responsible for the provision of emergency medical services the opportunity to participate in the development of the State highway safety program as such program relates to emergency medical services. Amends the Public Health Service Act and the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to allow certain grant allotments to be used for the purchase of communications equipment. Requires the Federal Communications Commission to: (1) study the availability of radio frequency channels for emergency medical services communications; (2) establish a plan to ensure that the needs of emergency medical services communications are provided for in the allocations of frequencies for public safety; and (3) submit a report to committees of the Congress containing such study and plan. Establishes a Trauma Care Block Grant program. Sets forth requirements for the distribution of allotments, including requiring: (1) non-Federal matching contributions, in cash or in kind, at a specified minimum ratio; and (2) reserving, on request, amounts for Indian tribes or tribal organizations. Sets forth permissable uses of allotments, including requiring that hospital emergency departments, within their capability, if an indidual appears and requests examination and treatment: (1) examine for the existence of an emergency medical condition or active labor and, if such a condition or labor exists, treat the individual until stable, subject to exception; and (2) transfer such individual to other facilities only according to stated criteria. Sets forth application requirements. Requires each State, beginning in FY 1989, to annually submit the trauma care component of the State emergency medical services plan to the Secretary. Sets forth requirements regarding the plan and directs the Secretary to issue regulations governing the establishment by States of standards and guidelines relating to certain aspects of trauma care. Allows the Secretary, on request of a State, to waive one or more of the standards. Directs the Secretary to study and, no later than one year after enactment of this Act, report to the appropriate committees of the Congress regarding the long-term economic effects of trauma. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989.</summary>
</bill>
