<bill session="100" type="s" number="1008" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for State regulation of the transportation of high level radioactive waste.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408937"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit a person from transporting nuclear waste or spent nuclear fuel without a license from the Nuclear Regulatory Commission. Sets forth the application requirements and mandates the inclusion of an emergency response and mitigation plan outlining procedures to be taken in the event of a release or potential release of radioactive waste. Requires the Commission to prepare an environmental analysis according to specified guidelines prior to issuing a radioactive waste transportation license. Sets forth the conditions under which the Commission is authorized to issue such a license. Requires specified Federal bodies, in consultation with the States and affected Indian tribes, to determine the emergency response capabilities of corridor States and affected Indian tribes. Mandates the development and exercise of such emergency response plans within 12 months after a transportation license is issued. Proscribes any shipments unless such plans are developed and periodically exercised. Identifies the types of regulations which the States and Indian tribes may impose. States that such nuclear waste transportation restrictions are inapplicable if the Commission certifies that there are compelling reasons of public safety or national security which necessitate the immediate transportation of the waste to another site or facility.</summary>
</bill>
