<bill session="100" type="s" number="101" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles XVIII and XIX of the Social Security Act to provide that a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist may, in collaboration with a physician, certify or recertify the need for certain services, to provide for coverage of certain items and services furnished by a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-12-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Intermediate care facilities"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends titles XVIII (Medicare) and XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to provide that a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist may, in collaboration with a physician, certify and recertify a patient's need for skilled nursing or intermediate care facility services. Authorizes skilled nursing facilities to satisfy certain Medicare requirements by having such nurses, in collaboration with physicians, supervise patient care and be available for patient emergencies. (Currently, a physician must make need certifications, supervise patient care, and be available for patient emergencies.) Provides Medicare coverage for 100 percent of the reasonable cost of items and services furnished by a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist in a skilled nursing facility. Provides Medicaid coverage for services furnished by such nurses, in collaboration with a physician, in an intermediate care or skilled nursing facility.</summary>
</bill>
