<bill session="100" type="s" number="1016" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Literacy Corps Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide financial assistance for the establishment and operation of literacy corps programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-05-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-04-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-24">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="College students"/>
    <term name="Community and college"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers in education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/1987--Introduced.
Literacy Corps Assistance Act of 1987 - Authorizes the Secretary of Education to make grants to institutions of higher education to carry out literacy corps programs. Permits funds under this Act to be used for grants to institutions of higher education for: (1) the costs of their participation in the literacy corps program; and (2) stipends for student coordinators engaged in the literacy corps program. Permits such funds to also be used for technical assistance, collection and dissemination of information, and evaluation. Sets forth grant application requirements. Requires the institution to establish one or more courses for instruction for academic credit designed to combine the training of undergraduate students with experience as tutors. Requires individuals, as a condition of receiving credit in such course, to perform at least six hours of voluntary, uncompensated service each week of the academic term in a public community agency as a tutor in such agency's educational or literacy program. Sets forth provisions for technical assistance and coordination contracts. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989.</summary>
</bill>
