<bill session="100" type="s" number="1036" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Michigan Wilderness Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain public lands in the State of Michigan as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-19">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture. Ordered favorably reported H.R. 148 in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="148"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/10/1987--Introduced.
Michigan Wilderness Act of 1987 - Designates the following lands in Michigan as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) the Nordhouse Dunes Wilderness in the Manistee National Forest; (2) the Sylvania Wilderness in the Ottawa National Forest; (3) the Sturgeon River Gorge Wilderness in the Ottawa National Forest; (4) the Rock River Canyon Wilderness in the Hiawatha National Forest; (5) the Big Island Lake Wilderness in the Hiawatha National Forest; (6) the Mackinac Wilderness in the Hiawatha National Forest; (7) the Horseshoe Bay Wilderness in the Hiawatha National Forest; (8) the Round Island Wilderness in the Hiawatha National Forest; and (9) the McCormick Wilderness in the Ottawa National Forest. Provides that the RARE II (second roadless area review and evaluation) final environmental statement (dated January 1979) with respect to national forest system lands in Michigan shall not be subject to judicial review. Releases national forest system lands in Michigan which were reviewed in the RARE II program from further review by the Department of Agriculture, pending the revision of initial national forest management plans. Releases lands in Michigan reviewed in the RARE II program and not designated as wilderness from management as wilderness areas. Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from conducting any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of national forest system lands in Michigan without express congressional authorization.</summary>
</bill>
