<bill session="100" type="s" number="1053" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to waive certain time limitations imposed under the Trade Adjustment Assistance Program for certain workers whose employment terminated between 1981 and 1986, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-04-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to waive certain time limitations governing eligibility for trade adjustment assistance with respect to workers who became totally or partially separated from adversely affected employment between August 13, 1981, and April 7, 1986. Provides that such workers who are otherwise eligible for a trade readjustment allowance may receive payments only if they: (1) are enrolled in a training program approved by the Secretary of Labor; (2) have completed a training program approved by the Secretary; or (3) have received a written statement certifying that the Secretary finds that it is not feasible to approve a training program for them. Prohibits the payment of trade readjustment allowances to a worker if the Secretary of Labor determines that he has: (1) failed to begin or to complete the training program in which he enrolled; and (2) there is no justifiable cause for such failure. Requires the Secretary, if he finds it is not feasible to approve a training program for a worker, to submit to the worker a written statement certifying such finding. Requires the Secretary to provide written notice by mail of the trade adjustment assistance benefits available to each worker whom he has reason to believe is covered by a certification of eligibility for such assistance: (1) at the time the certification is made, if the worker is partially or totally separated from the adversely affected employment before such certification; or (2) at the time of separation of the worker. Requires the Secretary to publish notice of the benefits available to workers covered by each certification in newspapers of general circulation in the areas where such workers reside. Requires the Secretary to publish notice of the benefits made available under this Act in newspapers of general circulation in areas where workers who are likely beneficiaries reside.</summary>
</bill>
