<bill session="100" type="s" number="1063" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Administration Tort Claims and Hospital Cost Collections Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to make certain improvements in the administering of tort claims and hospital cost collections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 9 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2013"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2013"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="9"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Collection of accounts"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Malpractice"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/21/1987--Introduced.
Veterans Administration Tort Claims and Hospital Cost Collections Amendments of 1987 - Title I: Hospital Cost Collections - Amends Federal veterans' benefits provisions relating to recovery by the United States of the cost of care and services provided to veterans for non-service-connected disabilities to provide a six-year statute of limitations for the bringing of a recovery action (measured from the last day on which such services were provided). Title II: Tort Claims - Excludes from immunity from suit (thereby allowing tort claims to be brought against) a negligent or wrongful act or omission of a person while exercising duties in or for the Veterans Administration's Department of Medicine and Surgery. Authorizes the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to settle any claims arising under the Federal Tort Claims Act to the extent delegated by the Attorney General, within specified limitations.</summary>
</bill>
