<bill session="100" type="s" number="1071" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Care Public-Private Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for expanding private sector initiatives in child care services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR06" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Loans"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1987--Introduced.
Child Care Public-Private Partnership Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to establish a demonstration program of grants to local private nonprofit organizations to improve and expand child care services in the community by establishing and administering community funds for child care, in partnership with private for-profit businesses. Requires such grants to community child care funds to be used for: (1) scholarships for low-income families in child care programs; and (2) loans and grants for start-up or renovation costs for community child day care services. Limits the Federal share of such assistance. Requires any organization desiring a grant under this Act to submit to the Secretary an application, which must include among its contents assurances that: (1) for-profit private businesses will supply at least half of the matching funds required for the community child care fund; (2) the organization will establish an appropriate local advisory board; and (3) funds will be used in accordance with certain requirements. Directs the Secretary, in considering applications for approval, to: (1) ensure an equitable geographic and rural/urban distribution of assistance; and (2) give special consideration to nonprofit groups serving significant populations of low-income children in communities lacking licensed day care facilities. Requires each grant recipient to submit an annual report to the Secretary concerning the extent and effects of its program. Requires the Secretary to evaluate and audit community child care funds each year. Authorizes FY 1988 through 1990 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
