<bill session="100" type="s" number="1077" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Handicapped Transportation Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 to prohibit implementation of the provisions of certain regulations thereunder which discriminate against mentally handicapped individuals and which place a limit on required expenditures to eliminate discrimination against handicapped persons and to provide a private right of action for violations of certain handicapped anti-discrimination regulations and laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation and the physically handicapped"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1987--Introduced.
Handicapped Transportation Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 to prohibit the enforcement or implementation of minimum criteria for the provision of transportation services to handicapped individuals by recipients of certain Federal transportation assistance in such a way as to: (1) limit the category of handicapped individuals to those who are physically, rather than mentally, unable to use public bus systems; or (2) limit the expenditures which a recipient is required to make during any specified period. Authorizes individuals aggrieved by violations of certain handicapped transportation provisions to bring actions in Federal district court to enforce compliance with Federal provisions.</summary>
</bill>
