<bill session="100" type="s" number="1072" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parkinsons Disease Amelioration Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a commission for the amelioration of Parkinsonism.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-04-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, GAO.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Brain research"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1987--Introduced.
Parkinsons Disease Amelioration Act - Establishes the Commission for the Amelioration of Parkinsonism Disease which shall: (1) conduct a study of the medical and social management of parkinsonism; (2) determine whether there is an appropriate balance between basic brain research and clinical research on parkinsonism and other ailments; (3) investigate and make recommendations concerning the proper roles of Federal, State, and local governments and public and private agencies in the research, prevention, and identification of Parkinson's disease and the treatment and rehabilitation of persons with Parkinson's disease; and (4) develop a national plan for the control of parkinsonism. Sets forth operating and related provisions. Requires the Commission to make a final report to the President and each House of Congress within six months. Terminates the Commission 30 days after submission of the final report.</summary>
</bill>
