<bill session="100" type="s" number="1088" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airline Consumer Protection Powers Transfer Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide the Federal Trade Commission with authority to regulate the advertising of commercial airlines, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-03-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Unfair or deceptive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/23/1987--Introduced.
Airline Consumer Protection Powers Transfer Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to transfer from the Department of Transportation to the Federal Trade Commission jurisdiction over unfair, deceptive, or anticompetitive practices within the airline industry. Declares that it shall be an unfair method of competition or deceptive practice affecting commerce for an air carrier (or a foreign air carrier) to: (1) change the rules of a frequent flier program to the detriment of the participants without reasonable advance notice; or (2) prevent such participants from using accumulated credits during a period of time after a change in rules has become effective. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (the Commission) to prescribe rules to prevent deceptive advertising by such air carriers. Cites the disclosure requirements of such rules. Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to repeal the authority of the Department of Transportation to investigate unfair methods of competition by air carriers. Requires the Commission to issue regulations regarding unfair methods of competition and deceptive advertising practices by air carriers within 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
