<bill session="100" type="s" number="1098" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rail Safety Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the Federal licensing of railroad conductors, engineers, and other appropriate personnel, to further the safety of railroad transportation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad freight operations"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Traffic accidents and safety"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1987--Introduced.
Rail Safety Improvement Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (the Secretary) to promulgate rules establishing a Federal licensing system, including minimum standards and requirements for testing, ensuring the fitness of all railroad personnel engaged in train operations. Requires railroad personnel to obtain and maintain licenses in order to engage in train operations. Requires license applicants to authorize the provision of information regarding their motor vehicle records and National Driver Register records. Requires the Secretary to promulgate regulations regarding written certification of railroad maintenance, tests, and inspections, including the assessment of civil penalties against a railroad or its employees for specified violations of the certification requirements. Amends the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to raise from $2,500 to $25,000 the maximum civil penalty imposed for violation of any railroad safety rule. Directs the Secretary to establish a system to record and classify all safety defects violating Federal railroad safety laws and regulations. Directs the Secretary to consult with railroad carriers and labor organizations regarding the feasibility of establishing a schedule of permitted absences for employees for safety reasons if there is impairment caused by alcohol or drug use. Directs the Secretary of Labor to promulgate regulations: (1) prohibiting any railroad carrier from discriminating against an employee for engaging in protected activities (whistle blowing); and (2) defining such protected activities. Sets forth a grievance procedure for employees alleging discrimination for engaging in protected activities. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to establish a Northeast Corridor Safety Committee comprised of certain representatives for consultation on safety improvements in the Northeast Corridor. Requires such Secretary to promulgate regulations that require the use on the Northeast Corridor of: (1) automatic train control devices on all freight and passenger trains; and (2) event recorders on all freight trains. Directs the Secretary to: (1) convene a meeting of Northeast Corridor rail carriers for the purpose of reducing through freight traffic on Northeast Corridor passenger lines; and (2) report to the Congress on the status of efforts to improve safety in the Northeast Corridor. Amends the Railroad Revitalization and Regulatory Reform Act of 1976 to specify required improvements on certain systems operating within the Northeast Corridor.</summary>
</bill>
