<bill session="100" type="s" number="1101" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "Foreign Primary Dealer and Bank National Treatment Act of 1987".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1987-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="International banking"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Reciprocity"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities industry"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1987--Introduced.
Expresses congressional findings, including that U.S. firms seeking to compete in Japan face discriminatory barriers which effectively preclude fair competition for Japanese business. Prohibits the Board of Governors of the Federal Reserve System or the Federal Reserve Bank of New York from designating, or permitting continued designation of, any person of a foreign country as a primary dealer in Government debt instruments if U.S. companies are denied equal access in the acquisition of government debt instruments issued by such country. Allows exceptions to such requirement for countries involved in or negotiating bilateral agreements with the United States as of January 1, 1987. Amends the International Banking Act of 1978 to allow Federal banking agencies to deny any application or disapprove any notice by a foreign bank or bank holding company if the country in which such bank or bank holding company is chartered or incorporated does not accord to U.S. banks and holding companies equality of competitive opportunity with domestic banks and bank holding companies.</summary>
</bill>
