<bill session="100" type="s" number="1115" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Home and Preventive Health Services for Older Americans Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to provide financial assistance for home services for frail older Americans and for preventive health services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Aging (Labor and Human Resources).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from OMB, GAO, Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR05" subcommittee="Aging" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Old age assistance"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/30/1987--Introduced.
Home and Preventive Health Services for Older Americans Act of 1987 - Amends title III (Grants for State and Community Programs on Aging) of the Older Americans Act of 1965 to direct the Commissioner on Aging to implement programs making grants to States for the provision of: (1) in-home services to frail older individuals; and (2) periodic preventive health services to older individuals at senior centers or other appropriate sites. Excludes from the preventive health services covered by this Act those services covered under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act. Authorizes appropriations for both grant programs for FY 1988 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
