<bill session="100" type="s" number="1111" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Motor Fuel Sales Competition Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Antitrust laws in order to preserve and promote wholesale and retail competition in the retail gasoline market and to protect the motoring safety of the American public.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Antitrust, Monopolies and Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU01" subcommittee="Antitrust, Monopolies and Business Rights" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Fuel storage"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Service stations"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1987--Introduced.
Motor Fuel Sales Competition Improvement Act of 1987 - Prohibits any oil producer or refiner from: (1) requiring any retail motor fuel dealer to purchase more than 70 percent of its monthly retail sales of motor fuel from such producer or refiner; or (2) prohibiting such a dealer from converting a fuel storage tank or dispenser for the sale of fuel supplied by another producer or refiner. Prohibits any dealer at a service station displaying a name or other identifying symbol of a refiner or producer from selling fuel not provided by such refiner or producer without providing notice at the point of sale. Prohibits any large integrated refiner from operating any service station in the United States. Permits such refiner to own all or part of a service station, provided it does not engage in selling fuel at such service station through any employee, agent, or representative. Provides for the enforcement of this Act. Provides that this Act shall not supersede any comparable State law to the extent that compliance with the State law can be accomplished consistent with this Act.</summary>
</bill>
