<bill session="100" type="s" number="1120" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Coal Leasing and Utilization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920 to improve the administration of the Federal Coal Leasing Program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1987-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-04">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG05" subcommittee="Mineral Resources Development and Production" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information leaking"/>
    <term name="Mining royalties"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural electrification"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/1/1987--Introduced.
Federal Coal Leasing and Utilization Act of 1987 - Makes certain statutory coal production requirements inapplicable to coal deposit leases: (1) which have been determined by the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to have had all recoverable reserves mined out; and (2) which are being held in order to comply with reclamation requirements. Prohibits the disclosure of coal-tract value data by Department of the Interior personnel to anyone not associated with the Department. Establishes criminal penalties for disclosure violations. States that a logical mining unit may include certain noncontiguous areas determined by the Secretary to be incorporated into a single operation under the effective control of a single operator. Repeals the requirement that an approved mining plan must include production and operation standards which assure that the entire unit reserves will be mined within 40 years. Provides that no logical mining unit shall be approved by the Secretary if the total Federal acreage exceeds 25,000 acres (current law combines both Federal and non-Federal acreage). Provides for automatic royalty readjustments at specified percentages for surface-mined coal and for coal recovered by underground mining operations under leases issued before August 4, 1976, or in the case of special bituminous coal mines meeting certain requirements. Provides for royalty readjustments on a reasonable basis, taking into consideration specified factors, for that portion of any pre-August 4, 1976, lease from which income is derived from a supply agreement with any nonprofit rural electric cooperative association. Terminates at the end of ten years and 15 years, 20-year leases that are not producing coal in commercial quantities unless the tenth or fifteenth lease year is extended through annual payment of advance royalties. Sets guidelines for the assessment of such royalties. Authorizes the Secretary to suspend the condition of continued operation upon the payment of continued operation advance royalties. Sets guidelines under which such royalties may be accepted in lieu of continued operation.</summary>
</bill>
