<bill session="100" type="s" number="1135" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:13-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 to allow individuals to direct that part or all of their income tax refunds be contributed to a trust fund established for the relief of domestic and international hunger, and to establish a commission to oversee the distribution of such contributions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300031"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="81"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="81"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Charities"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Hunger"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/1987--Introduced.
Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust Act of 1987 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow individuals to direct that all or part of their income tax refunds be contributed to the Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust. Establishes within the Treasury such Hunger Emergency Assistance and Relief Trust (trust fund) to distribute hunger relief funds to qualified nonprofit hunger relief services organizations. Appropriates to the trust fund revenues equivalent to those designated for such purpose by individual taxpayers. Sets forth standards and procedures for the distribution of trust fund monies. Limits the amount that recipient organizations can pay for administrative expenses to ten percent of amounts received from the trust fund. Prohibits organizations receiving funds from: (1) failing to match payment; (2) failing to use payments properly; (3) incurring excessive administrative expenses; and (4) not complying with certain Hunger Commission requests. Authorizes the Hunger Commission to inform State attorneys general of possible State law violations by organizations. Requires the Hunger Commission to submit to specified congressional committees an annual report detailing trust fund expenditures. Establishes a Hunger Commission to administer the distribution of funds to qualified hunger relief services organizations on a matching grant basis. Permits a maximum award of $100,000 to any single qualified organization in any fiscal year. Requires that: (1) at least 50 percent of amounts received into the trust fund in any year be paid to qualified organizations; and (2) monies in the trust fund be distributed within 180 days of their receipt in the fund. Sets forth: (1) criteria governing Commission organization and membership; and (2) powers of the Commission, including the power to hold hearings, to issue subpoenas, and to grant immunity. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
