<bill session="100" type="s" number="1138" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nevada Wilderness Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to designate certain lands in the State of Nevada as wilderness, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Agriculture Department. Favorable.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Forest roads"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grazing"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="National forests"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Snowmobiles"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1987--Introduced.
Nevada Wilderness Protection Act of 1987 - Designates the following lands in Nevada as components of the National Wilderness Preservation System: (1) the Alta Toquima Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (2) the Arc Dome Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (3) the Boundary Peak Wilderness in the Inyo National Forest; (4) the East Humboldts Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (5) the Jarbidge Wilderness Additions in the Humboldt National Forest; (6) the Mt. Moriah Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (7) the Mt. Rose Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (8) the Quinn Canyon Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (9) the Ruby Mountains Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest; (10) the Mt. Charleston Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; (11) the Table Mountain Wilderness in the Toiyabe National Forest; and (12) the Grant Range Wilderness in the Humboldt National Forest. Provides that the RARE II (second roadless area review and evaluation) final environmental statement (dated January 1979) with respect to national forest system lands in Nevada shall not be subject to judicial review. Releases national forest system lands in Nevada which were reviewed in the RARE II program from further review by the Department of Agriculture, pending the revision of initial national forest management plans. Releases lands in Nevada reviewed in the RARE II program and not designated as wilderness from management as wilderness areas. Prohibits the Department of Agriculture from conducting any further statewide roadless area review and evaluation of national forest system roadless lands in Nevada which are less than 5,000 acres in size and other specified areas. Permits livestock grazing in such wilderness areas, subject to mandatory review by the Secretary of Agriculture. Directs the Secretary to report to the appropriate committees on such grazing at least every five years. Permits snowmobiles in a specified corridor of Mt. Rose.</summary>
</bill>
