<bill session="100" type="s" number="1142" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Mowa Band of Choctaw Indians Recognition Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal recognition of the Mowa Band of Choctaw Indians of Alabama.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300089"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-07-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3107"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3107"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Alabama"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1987--Introduced.
Mowa Band of Choctaw Indians Recognization Act - Extends Federal recognition and associated services and benefits to the Mowa Band of Choctaw Indians of Alabama. Restores Federal rights and privileges abrogated by earlier statutes. Provides that nothing in this Act shall diminish any rights or privileges of the Band that existed prior to its enactment and that nothing in this Act alters any obligations: (1) with respect to property; (2) under any contract; or (3) to pay a tax levied before the date of enactment. Transfers all interests in lands held by the Band to the United States to be held in trust for the benefit of the Band. Requires the Band to transfer to the United States any interest in lands acquired after enactment of this Act. Provides that such lands shall constitute the Band's reservation. Authorizes the Band to adopt a constitution that will take effect only after being filed with the Secretary of the Interior. Limits membership in the Band, until a constitution is adopted, to every individual who: (1) is named in the tribal membership roll in effect on the date of enactment of this Act; or (2) is a descendant of any such individual. Provides that membership will be determined according to the constitution after its adoption.</summary>
</bill>
