<bill session="100" type="s" number="1157" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:14-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family-School Partnership Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make demonstration grants to local educational agencies eligible to receive assistance under title I of the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965, as modified by chapter 1 of the Education Consolidation and Improvement Act of 1981, in order to strengthen the educational partnership between the family and the school, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1987-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-05-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Parent-school relationships"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/6/1987--Introduced.
Family-School Partnership Act - Establishes a demonstration grant program in the interest of encouraging local educational agencies (LEAs) to increase the involvement of families in the improvement of the educational achievement of their children. Authorizes the Secretary of Education (Secretary) to make demonstration grants to eligible LEA applicants for the development of innovative family-school educational partnership activities designed to: (1) support family efforts to work with children in the home; (2) train families, teachers, and other school personnel to work effectively as partners; and (3) evaluate the family participation activities of the schools and ways in which to increase involvement in such activities. Suggests possible uses for the grants, including: (1) regular conferences for families of students; (2) training of appropriate educational personnel to foster communication among families, students, and educators; and (3) provision of complementary curriculum materials to families and assistance in implementing home-based education activities. Establishes within the Department of Education a National Center for Family-School Partnerships in Education (Center). Directs the Secretary, through such Center, to collect and disseminate information and to serve as a clearinghouse with respect to relevant successful programs. Authorizes FY 1988 through 1992 appropriations. Designates a specified percentage of such funds for provisions related to the Center.</summary>
</bill>
