<bill session="100" type="s" number="1207" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Rural Health Services Transition Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to establish a program of grants, funded from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund, to assist small rural hospitals in modifying their service mixes to meet new community needs and in providing more appropriate and cost-effective health care services to medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1987--Introduced.
Medicare Rural Health Services Transition Act of 1987 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a program providing grants to small rural hospitals to assist such hospitals in modifying the type or extent of health care services they provide so that their services more closely approximate the changing needs of rural communities and are integrated with other community health care services. Requires rural hospitals wishing to participate in the program to submit an application specifying the nature of the hospital's proposed grant project and a timetable (of no more than two years) for its completion to the State Governor, who shall transmit it to the Secretary within 30 days with his or her comments on such application. Directs the Secretary to consider such comments, each project's objectives, and each project's effect in reducing expenditures under part A (Hospital Insurance) of the Medicare program in choosing among applicants for such grants. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989.</summary>
</bill>
