<bill session="100" type="s" number="1206" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Services in the Home Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish a program for the provision of health care services in the home for individuals who are suffering from a catastrophic or chronic illness.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404444" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-27">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, GAO, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/14/1987--Introduced.
Health Care Services in the Home Act of 1987 - Amends title XIX (Block Grants) of the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary) to make allotments to States, according to a specified formula, to be used for home health care services, including: (1) compensating physicians, nurses, and social workers in planning, managing, or providing home health care; (2) identifying and locating individuals in need of such care; (3) developing standards and quality assurance mechanisms; (4) coordinating home health care services with other social services; (5) coordinating long-term care services; and (6) training health professionals other than physicians, nurses, and social workers. Allows States to use allotments for the home health care of eligible individuals through grants to health care organizations, subject to certain conditions. Restricts the portion of the amount paid to States which may be used for activities other than compensation for the services of physicians, nurses, and social workers in planning, managing, or providing home health care. Limits the amount a State may use for any individual in a year for certain services. Sets forth application procedures for such allotments. Makes applicable to this Act provisions of existing law relating to adjustments in payments to States, annual reports and audits, withholding of payments for cause, nondiscrimination, and penalties for false statements. Requires annual reports to include an analysis of cost effectiveness. Directs the Secretary to conduct evaluations of services provided and activities carried out with payments to States under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
