<bill session="100" type="s" number="1217" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-15">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arctic Coastal Plain Public Lands Leasing Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Mineral Leasing Act of 1920 to authorize the Secretary of the Interior to lease, in an expeditious and environmentally sound manner, the public lands within the Coastal Plain of the North Slope of Alaska for oil and gas exploration, development, and production.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404444" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300159" joined="1987-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300154" joined="1987-09-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1987-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, Environmental Protection Agency, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-13">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Arctic and polar regions"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum in submerged lands"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/15/1987--Introduced.
Arctic Coastal Plain Public Lands Leasing Act of 1987 - Amends the Mineral Lands Leasing Act of 1920 to direct the Secretary of the Interior to implement a competitive oil and gas leasing program on the public lands of the Coastal Plain (in Alaska) in order to assure expeditious exploration, development, and production of the area's oil and gas resources. Delineates the elements of the Coastal Plain leasing program. Mandates deposit of the receipts from such leasing program in the Treasury. Requires that activities be conducted to achieve the reasonable protection of wildlife resources, the environment, and subsistence users. Directs the Secretary to provide impact aid to affected communities to ensure the availability of public services necessitated by the leasing program. Authorizes the Secretary of State to initiate discussions with the Canadian Government regarding mutual planning for the development and transportation of crude oil and natural gas resources in the Arctic region under the respective jurisdiction of each country, both onshore and offshore.</summary>
</bill>
