<bill session="100" type="s" number="1250" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Criminal and Juvenile Justice Partnership Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Criminal and Juvenile Justice Family Violence Prevention Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Criminal Justice Information Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the criminal justice partnership between the States and the Federal Government.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-13">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Church property"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Compensation for victims of crime"/>
    <term name="Conspiracy"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Crimes against minorities"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information systems"/>
    <term name="Criminal statistics"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Domestic relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Missing children"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Narcotics and crime"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Racial violence"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Religion and Clergy"/>
    <term name="Religious liberty"/>
    <term name="Runaway children"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1987--Introduced.
Criminal and Juvenile Justice Partnership Act of 1987 - Title I: Drug Law Enforcement - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out program grants for drug law enforcement. Prohibits the distribution of grant funds to recipients who have been provided such funds for four years. Title II: Juvenile Justice - Subtitle A: Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act Reauthorization - Amends the Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out the purposes of such Act. Subtitle B: Runaway and Homeless Youth Act Reauthorization - Amends the Runaway and Homeless Youth Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out the purposes of such Act. Subtitle C: Missing Children's Assistance Act Reauthorization - Amends the Missing Children's Assistance Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out the purposes of such Act. Title III: Law Enforcement - Subtitle A: Justice Assistance Act Reauthorization - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control Act of 1968 to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out the functions of the: (1) Bureau of Justice Statistics; (2) National Institute of Justice; (3) Bureau of Justice Assistance; and (4) Office of Justice Programs. Subtitle B: Criminal and Juvenile Justice Family Violence Prevention Act of 1987 - Criminal and Juvenile Justice Family Violence Prevention Act of 1987 - Amends the Omnibus Crime Control and Safe Streets Act of 1968 to authorize the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to States for the purpose of improving the criminal justice system's response to domestic and family violence. Directs the Attorney General to include in the uniform crime reports data that indicates the age of the victim and the relationship of the victim to the offender for specified crimes. Requires the Director of the Bureau of Justice Statistics to collect and publish data that more accurately measures the extent of domestic violence in America. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 through 1992 for such purposes. Subtitle C: Multijurisdiction Criminal Conspiracy Information and Targeting Grants - Establishes a multijurisdiction criminal conspiracy information and targeting grant program. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out such program. Subtitle D: Public Safety Officers' Death Benefits Improvement - Increases from $50,000 to $100,000 the basic level of public safety officers' death benefits, and provides for annual adjustment of the benefits level. Removes the requirement that parent beneficiaries be dependents. Authorizes the use of appropriated funds to assist the families of public safety officers who have died in the line of duty. Subtitle E: Criminal Justice Information Improvement - Criminal Justice Information Improvement Act of 1987 - Establishes a grant program to improve criminal justice information compiled and maintained by States and local criminal justice agencies. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 to carry out such program. Subtitle F: College and Railroad Police Information - Amends the Federal judicial code to direct the Attorney General to exchange criminal records and information with railroad and college police departments. Subtitle G: The Racial and Religious Violence Information - Directs the Attorney General to include in the uniform crime reports information regarding crimes: (1) involving religious property; and (2) committed to express racial, ethnic, or religious prejudice. Subtitle H: Victim Compensation and Assistance - Amends the Victims of Crime Act of 1984 to allow deposits to be made into the Crime Victims Fund through September 30, 1992. Title IV: Assistance to State and Local Courts - Amends the State Justice Institute Act of 1984 to authorize appropriations through FY 1992 to carry out the purposes of such Act. Title V: National Academy of Sciences - Directs the Attorney General to provide for a study, to be conducted by the National Academy of Sciences, of policies and programs at the State and local levels to reduce violent and property crime by drug users. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
