<bill session="100" type="s" number="1251" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Quality Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to establish a National Quality Award, with the objective of encouraging American business and other organizations to practice effective quality control in the provision of their goods and services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-07-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408420" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Quality of products"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1987--Introduced.
National Quality Improvement Act of 1987 - Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to establish a National Quality Award, to be evidenced by a medal. Directs the President (on the basis of recommendations received from the Secretary of Commerce) or the Secretary of Commerce to periodically make the award to companies and other organizations which have substantially benefited the economic or social well-being of the United States through improvements in the quality of their goods and services resulting from the effective practice of quality management. Sets forth categories in which the award may be given and qualification criteria. Directs the Secretary to appoint a board of overseers to make suggestions for improvements in the award process. Directs the Director of the National Bureau of Standards to provide information about the awards and about the successful quality improvement strategies and programs of the award winners to all participants and to other appropriate groups. Provides that funding for the award program shall be through gifts from public and private sources and fees imposed upon organizations applying for the award. Directs the Secretary to prepare and submit to the President and the Congress a report on the progress, findings, and conclusions of activities conducted with respect to the award, along with recommendations for possible modifications.</summary>
</bill>
