<bill session="100" type="s" number="1273" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 and to provide authorizations for the Appalachian Highway and Appalachian Area Development Programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1987-05-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-07-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409580" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Appalachia"/>
    <term name="Appalachian Regional Commission"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1987--Introduced.
Appalachian Regional Development Act Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 to include as a purpose of such Act public investment in severely distressed and underdeveloped counties or areas lacking resources for basic services. Authorizes appropriations for the Appalachian Regional Commission for FY 1988 through 1992. Permits the Commission to lease office space through FY 1992. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992 for construction of the Appalachian development highway system and local access roads. Increases from 70 percent to 80 percent the maximum Federal share of such highway construction costs. Allows for Federal supplements to the Federal grant-in-aid programs to continue through FY 1992. Removes the restriction on financial assistance for the cost of industrial facilities. Requires that energy enterprise development loan funds established with grants previously approved by the Commission be made available for authorized purposes. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992. Terminates specified provisions of the Appalachian Regional Development Act of 1965 on October 1, 1992.</summary>
</bill>
