<bill session="100" type="s" number="1271" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Day Care for Working Families Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide comprehensive Federal assistance for day care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407663"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Labor. Hearings held at Toledo, OH. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-195.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSHR03" subcommittee="Labor" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR06" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/21/1987--Introduced.
Day Care for Working Families Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Labor to establish a demonstration matching grant program in the interest of increasing the availability of affordable high quality day care services, especially to low-income families. Limits the Federal share of such grants to 50 percent. Authorizes grant awards to employer-community day care councils comprising representatives of private employers, child care programs, parents, local government, and other community institutions. Lists permissible grant fund uses, including: (1) the provision of affordable high quality day care services, especially for low-income families; (2) the start-up and operation of day care resource and referral programs; (3) support of day care services for handicapped children; and (4) the establishment, renovation, and expansion of day care facilities. Authorizes FY 1988 appropriations. Amends the Social Security Act to increase the authorization for certain block grants to be allotted to the States for social services for FY 1988 and thereafter. Reserves a specified amount of such allotments for child care services. Amends the Small Business Act to authorize the Small Business Administration (SBA) to make loans, up to a $30,000,000 fiscal year maximum, to assist child care providers in constructing and renovating space to be used for child care. Directs the SBA to: (1) give priority to projects in areas with the greatest need and to organizations serving significant numbers of children of low-income families; (2) establish an outreach program to advise and assist prospective day care providers; and (3) report to the Congress on its program with respect to day care providers. Precludes any State from receiving certain funds unless the Secretary of Health and Human Services determines that the State has established specified minimum requirements for day care centers. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study and to report to the Congress, within one year of this Act's enactment, concerning: (1) the availability of day care services for school age children in each State; and (2) the need for such services.</summary>
</bill>
