<bill session="100" type="s" number="1282" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-05-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-05-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Deterrence of State-Sponsored Terrorism Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the imposition of sanctions against countries supporting international terrorism, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1987-05-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-05-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-15">
      <text>Subcommittee on Terrorism, Narcotics &amp; Int. Oper. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFR04" subcommittee="Terrorism, Narcotics and International Communications" name="Senate Foreign Relations"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign tax credit"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Shipping agreements"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/28/1987--Introduced.
Deterrence of State-Sponsored Terrorism Act of 1987 - Requires the Secretary of State to prepare and transmit annually to the Congress a report setting forth a list of countries repeatedly providing support for acts of international terrorism (terrorist list). Requires that certain sanctions be imposed upon the countries named in such terrorist list within 30 calendar days unless the President transmits a written determination to the Congress that the national interests of the United States or humanitarian interests dictate otherwise. Provides that the Congress may disapprove of the President's determination by enactment of a joint resolution within 30 legislative days. Specifies that such sanctions shall go into effect as of the date of enactment of such joint resolution. Authorizes the President to remove such sanctions upon a determination that it is in the national interest or in humanitarian interests to do so unless the Congress passes a joint resolution disapproving of such determination. Allows the President to remove such sanctions either partially or completely upon a certification to certain committees of the Congress that an emergency situation exists. Specifies that such sanctions shall consist of: (1) termination of all U.S. assistance to such country; (2) termination of the importation of technology and goods which are produced, grown, or manufactured in such country or the imposition of additional duties on such imports; (3) denial to all products of such country of duty-free tariff treatment under the Generalized System of Preferences; (4) termination of any air or sea transportation agreement in effect between the United States and such country; (5) U.S. opposition to any loan or other use of funds for that country by international financial institutions; (6) a presidential prohibition on the transfer out of the United States of any property or credit in which such country or a national has a financial interest; and (7) the denial of any income tax credits for the amount of any income, war profits, and excess profits taxes paid or accrued to such country by taxpayers of the United States. Expresses the sense of the Congress that in any case in which such a sanction is imposed against a country, the President should try to obtain the imposition of similar sanctions by U.S. allies. Specifies the procedure for congressional review of presidential determinations required by this Act for the consideration and enactment of joint resolutions of disapproval of such determinations.</summary>
</bill>
