<bill session="100" type="s" number="1312" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Interagency Coordinating Committee on Federal Participation in Sematech Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Federal Participation in Sematech, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402495"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Semiconductors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1987--Introduced.
Interagency Coordinating Committee on Federal Participation in Sematech Act of 1987 - Establishes the Interagency Coordinating Committee on Federal Participation in Sematech and an Advisory Council on Federal Participation in Sematech. Defines "Sematech" as a consortium of U.S. semiconductor manufacturers, materials manufacturers, equipment manufacturers, academic institutions, and Federal agencies, established for the purpose of: (1) conducting research concerning advanced semiconductor manufacturing techniques; and (2) developing techniques to adapt manufacturing expertise to a variety of semiconductor products. Requires the Committee, within 120 days after enactment of this Act, to report to the Congress its recommendations about whether the Federal Government should participate in Sematech. Specifies the contents of a favorable report. Outlines the duties of the Committee should a majority vote to support Federal participation. Requires the provision of grants and other financial assistance to Sematech in such an event but limits the Federal share of costs to 50 percent. Makes the Committee a liaison between Federal agencies and private participants in Sematech. Directs the Committee to require Sematech to submit annual reports and provide for biennial audits. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1993.</summary>
</bill>
