<bill session="100" type="s" number="1311" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Areas Mental Health Services Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 504(f) of the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for demonstration projects for mental health services and related services for residents of rural areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-06-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child mental health services"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1987--Introduced.
Rural Areas Mental Health Services Act of 1987 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to States and private nonprofit agencies for the development, improvement, and demonstration of State and local systems for the provision of mental health services and related services to residents of rural areas. Limits the grants to no more than three consecutive one-year periods, subject to waiver. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990 for such grants and for grants under existing provisions relating to mental health services demonstration projects for the improvement of community services for chronically mentally ill individuals, seriously mentally disturbed children, elderly individuals, and homeless chronically mentally ill individuals.</summary>
</bill>
