<bill session="100" type="s" number="1315" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Professional Liability Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for Federal incentive grants to encourage State health care professional liability reform.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-11-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Administration of justice"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Malpractice"/>
    <term name="Medical malpractice insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1987--Introduced.
National Professional Liability Reform Act of 1987 - Establishes a program to provide development and incentive grants to States for enacting medical malpractice liability reforms. Sets forth the reforms which must be in effect for States to receive incentive grants, including: (1) requiring that future damage awards exceeding $100,000 be made by periodic payments; (2) limiting damages for noneconomic losses to $250,000; and (3) requiring that attorney fees be in accordance with a provided schedule. Allows the Secretary of Health and Human Services to require additional or alternative reforms. Requires each State receiving an incentive grant to prepare and transmit a report to the Secretary every two years describing: (1) State liability reforms enacted, adopted, or in effect; (2) activities conducted by the State with grants received under this Act; and (3) any current problems with respect to health care professional liability or health care professional liability insurance. Requires the Secretary to transmit periodic reports to the Congress summarizing the information provided by the States. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
