<bill session="100" type="s" number="1320" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Solar Development Initiative Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide adequate funding levels for solar energy research and development, to encourage Federal procurement of solar energy systems, to encourage Federal loans for solar energy equipment, to enhance the international competitiveness of the solar industry, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-06-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources and, pursuant to Rule XXV (1)(o)(1),  if and when reported, to the Committee on Small Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Energy Department, OMB, Defense Department (Sec.6), Export-Import Bank of the United States (Sec.7), Overseas Private Investment Corporation (Sec.8), Small Business Administration (Sec.9).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on Research and Development. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-06">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Defense Department. Favorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Export-Import Bank of the United States. Unfavorable.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Research and Development" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy development"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Solar energy industries"/>
    <term name="Solar heating and cooling"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/3/1987--Introduced.
Solar Development Initiative Act of 1987 - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the authorizations provided by this Act indicate the minimum levels for a solar research effort that is sensitive to both the Federal deficit and to the growth of the domestic solar energy industry. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990 for specified Federal solar energy research and development programs. Directs the Secretary of Energy to include in the FY 1989 budget the funding necessary to implement a solar and renewable energy research program which: (1) has near-term commercial applications; and (2) enhances the international competitiveness of the solar and renewable energy industries. Directs the Secretary of Energy to establish an information-dissemination program for Federal procurement and loan officers regarding the application of solar heating and cooling technology in Federal buildings. Directs the Committee on Renewable Energy, Commerce, and Trade to continue to coordinate Federal programs affecting commerce in renewable energy products and services. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the renewable energy technologies programs established by the Secretary of Commerce should be funded in FY 1988 through 1990 through the Department of Energy at a specified minimum level. Amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to direct the President to take into account, when determining whether to designate a beneficiary country, the degree to which it undertakes self-help measures to promote energy self-sufficiency using locally available renewable resources. Mandates that the design for new Federal facilities for specified agencies include consideration of energy systems using solar energy or other renewable energy forms. Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to mandate that a specified percentage of loan authority be available only for solar and renewable energy loans. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to prohibit the use of administrative funds for incentives, grants, and studies for renewable energy and other small business activities. Amends the Small Business Act to: (1) repeal provisions regarding loans to small business concerns for solar energy and energy conservation measures; (2) mandate that a certain percentage of loan authority be used only for small business energy measures; and (3) direct the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to give due consideration to the export potential of solar and renewable energy products, and to include a list of solar and renewable energy loan guarantees in an annual report to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
