<bill session="100" type="s" number="1327" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent United States involvement in hostilities in the Persian Gulf.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-06-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1987-07-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-25">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Reported to Senate. With written report No. 100-102.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="China"/>
    <term name="Embargo"/>
    <term name="Flags of convenience"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iran-Iraq War"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Neutrality"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Shipping agreements"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Tankers"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/7/1987--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Foreign Relations with amendment, S. Rept. 100-102) Declares that the Congress: (1) reaffirms U.S. neutrality in the war between Iran and Iraq; (2) supports the use of U.S. naval forces to protect the right of American vessels under international law to free passage through the international waters of the Persian Gulf; and (3) supports U.S. participation in collective efforts by the Western allies and other neutral nations to protect such neutral rights. Urges the President to: (1) take steps through the United Nations Security Council to obtain a cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq War; and (2) seek a U.N. Security Council arms embargo and economic sanctions against any combatant which fails to cooperate in the establishment of a negotiated cease-fire. States that the United States should use its influence with the People's Republic of China (including leverage provided by the sale of advanced fighters aircraft avionics equipment) to stop Chinese arms sales to Iran. Prohibits, for one year, the use of any appropriated or other funds to enter into or implement any agreement with any country bordering on the Persian Gulf under which any vessel owned by a country or by a national of such a country is registered under the United States flag.</summary>
</bill>
