<bill session="100" type="s" number="1334" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restrict certain U.S. contributions to international organizations until certain actions to eliminate abuses of the United Nations system are undertaken by the United Nations Secretary General.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-07-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
    <term name="United Nations officials and employees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/5/1987--Introduced.
Prohibits the obligation of 50 percent of the funds made available for FY 1988 for payment of the U.S. contribution to the United Nations until the President certifies to the Congress that the Secretary General of the United Nations has investigated: (1) the use of salary remission arrangements by nationals of member states serving as employees of the United Nations Secretariat or any of its specialized agencies; (2) the excessive use of secondment by member states in a way that prevents nationals of such states from becoming regular career employees of the United Nations; and (3) the blatant control of nationals of member states serving as employees of the United Nations Secretariat or the specialized agencies.</summary>
</bill>
