<bill session="100" type="s" number="1347" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">International Child Abduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to facilitate implementation of the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409917"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="1987-12-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-07-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1987-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2673"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2673"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Custody of children"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Kidnapping"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Parental kidnapping"/>
    <term name="State courts"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/1987--Introduced.
International Child Abduction Act - Title I: Provisions Implementing the Convention - Grants State courts, the courts of the District of Columbia and the territories and possessions of the United States, and U.S. district courts original jurisdiction with regard to actions arising under the 1980 Hague Convention on the Civil Aspects of International Child Abduction (Convention) and this Act. Sets forth requirements with regard to notice and burden of proof for such actions. Allows any court exercising jurisdiction over a petition filed pursuant to the Convention or this Act to take provisional measures under Federal or State law to protect the well-being of the child or prevent the child's removal or concealment. Prohibits any court from ordering the provisional removal of a child from the person having physical control unless the applicable requirements of State law are satisfied. States that any application submitted to the Central Authority for the United States or petition submitted in accordance with the terms of the Convention shall be admissible in court without regard to the need for legalization or authentication. Directs the President to designate a Federal agency to serve as Central Authority for the United States for the purpose of: (1) issuing regulations to implement the Convention and this Act; (2) obtaining information from the Federal Parent Locator Service; and (3) collecting, maintaining, and disseminating information for purposes relating to the Convention and this Act. Directs the Secretary of State, the Secretary of Health and Human Services, and the Attorney General to designate Federal employees and private citizens to serve as an interagency coordinating group to monitor the operation of the Convention and provide advice on its implementation. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the purposes of the Convention and this Act. Title II: Amendments to Other Laws - Amends the Social Security Act to provide the Central Authority for the United States access to the services of the Parent Locator Service. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to permit the disclosure of tax returns and return information to Federal, State, and local child support enforcement agencies for the purpose of locating individuals in connection with the abduction or wrongful restraint or retention of a child.</summary>
</bill>
