<bill session="100" type="s" number="1348" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:17-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Office of Comprehensive School Health Education Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish in the Department of Education an Office of Comprehensive School Health Education, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-06-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2728"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2728"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="School health programs"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/10/1987--Introduced.
Office of Comprehensive School Health Education Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Education to establish within the Department of Education an Office of Comprehensive School Health Education. Makes it the function of such Office to: (1) encourage State and local educational agencies to provide comprehensive school health education to elementary and secondary school students; (3) provide technical support to State and local educational agencies for health education programs and curricula; (3) make grants to State and local educational agencies; (4) provide an annual report on the progress of the Office and the status of school health education in the Untied States; (5) cooperate with other Federal agencies carrying out school health education programs to ensure coordination of such programs; and (6) advise the Secretary on school health education policy. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to State and local educational agencies to pay the Federal share of the cost of establishing and improving comprehensive school health education programs. Sets forth authorized uses of such grants and application requirements. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992.</summary>
</bill>
