<bill session="100" type="s" number="1358" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 11, United States Code, the Bankruptcy Code, to clarify the transfer provisions.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bankruptcy"/>
    <term name="Contracts"/>
    <term name="Debtor and creditor"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/11/1987--Introduced.
Amends Federal bankruptcy provisions to provide that a debtor shall have received reasonably equivalent value through any transfer to a person who acquires an interest of the debtor in an asset pursuant to a regularly conducted, noncollusive foreclosure sale or execution of a power of sale for the acquisition or disposition of the interest of the debtor upon default under a mortgage, deed of trust, land sale contract, or security agreement. Makes nonvoidable any termination of a lease or contract pursuant to the terms of the lease or contract and permitted by applicable nonbankruptcy law. Specifies that any interest of a debtor in an asset acquired pursuant to a regularly conducted foreclosure sale or other procedure permitted by law for acquiring a debtor's interest upon default under a security agreement shall be deemed to be taken for new value and not in consideration of an antecedent debt.</summary>
</bill>
