<bill session="100" type="s" number="1367" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill authorizing the Secretary of the Interior to preserve certain wetlands and historic sites in the St. Johns River Valley, Florida, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402495"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1987-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/1987--Introduced.
Title I: Fort Caroline National Memorial - Provides that the Fort Caroline National Memorial shall serve as the principal interpretive center and administrative facility for the ecological, historic, and prehistoric resources of the historic settlement of Fort Caroline, Saint Johns Bluffs, Florida. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to construct and maintain museum facilities. Title II: Preservation of St. Johns River Valley Ecological Area and Protection of Significant Historic Assets - Establishes the Timucuan (Timucuan Indians) Ecological and Historic Preserve in St. Johns River Valley, Florida, including the Theodore Roosevelt Preserve. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire lands within the Preserve by donation, purchase, or exchange. Requires that the Preserve be managed to preserve its natural ecology. Authorizes the Secretary to acquire by donation or purchase with donated funds historic sites or properties in Duval County, Florida. Provides for the integrated administration and interpretation of the Preserve with the Memorial.</summary>
</bill>
