<bill session="100" type="s" number="1369" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Technology Literacy Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the technological literacy of the Nation through demonstration programs of technology education.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Curriculum planning"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Scientific education"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Technical education"/>
    <term name="Technology and civilization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/16/1987--Introduced.
Technology Literacy Act of 1987 - Defines "technology education" as a comprehensive educational process designed to develop a population that is knowledgeable about technology and its evolution, systems, techniques, utilization in industry and other fields, and cultural significance. Directs the Secretary of Education, subject to the availability of appropriations under this Act, to establish a program of grants to local educational agencies (LEAs), State educational agencies (SEAs), and institutions of higher education for up to ten demonstration programs in technology education for secondary schools. Sets forth grant application requirements. Directs the Secretary to consider equitable geographic distribution in making such grants. Permits such grants to be used to develop a model demonstration program for technology education with specified components. Includes among such components research and development of curriculum materials, a program to develop teacher capabilities in technology education, and multidisciplinary teacher workshops for interfacing mathematics, science, and technology education. Limits the Federal share to 75 percent of the costs of programs or projects assisted under this Act. Directs the Secretary to disseminate the results of such programs or projects so as to improve the training of educational personnel. Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act for FY 1988 and 1991.</summary>
</bill>
