<bill session="100" type="s" number="1366" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Planning Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Family Planning Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise and extend the programs of assistance under title X of the Public Health Service Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408420" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409580" joined="1987-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-07-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-06-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-29">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-11-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-02-18">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with amendments. With written report No. 100-286. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-02-18" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="539">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 539.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Abortion, Birth Control, and Family Planning"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Contraceptives"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2622"/>
    <amendment number="s2623"/>
    <amendment number="s2624"/>
    <amendment number="s2625"/>
    <amendment number="s2626"/>
    <amendment number="s2627"/>
    <amendment number="s2628"/>
    <amendment number="s2629"/>
    <amendment number="s2630"/>
    <amendment number="s2631"/>
    <amendment number="s2632"/>
    <amendment number="s2633"/>
    <amendment number="s2634"/>
    <amendment number="s2635"/>
    <amendment number="s2636"/>
    <amendment number="s2637"/>
    <amendment number="s2638"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>2/18/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Labor and Human Resources with amendment, S. Rept. 100-286) Family Planning Amendments of 1987 - Amends title X (Population Research and Voluntary Family Planning Programs) of the Public Health Service Act to remove, from provisions relating to project grants and contracts for family planning services, provisions allowing the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary), at the request of a grant recipient, to reduce the amount of the grant by the value of supplies or equipment furnished by the Secretary. Authorizes appropriations for such grants and contracts for FY 1988 through 1991. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991 for technical assistance and personnel training. States that such training shall include clinical training for obstetric-gynecologic nurse practitioners and training for educators and counselors. Repeals existing formula grant provisions. States that research grants and contracts may be made for evaluation as well as for development of contraceptives, and to improve clinical management and direct delivery of family planning services. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct, make grants, and enter into contracts for applied research into the development, evaluation, and bringing to the marketplace of contraceptive devices, drugs, and methods. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. States that amounts appropriated under this provision are in addition to amounts allocated under a specified provision for the National Institute of Child Health and Human Development. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants or enter into contracts for community-based information and education programs regarding sexuality, pregnancy, parenthood, and sexually transmitted diseases. Directs the Secretary to conduct, or make grants and enter into contracts for, training and technical assistance for such programs. Directs the Secretary to make grants and enter into contracts for the development, evaluation, and dissemination of educational and informational materials consistent with the objectives of such programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. Requires not more than ten percent of amounts appropriated to be available for training and technical assistance and for educational and informational materials. Directs the Secretary to collect data annually on: (1) the number of low-income and marginal-income individuals and adolescents at risk of unintended pregnancies; (2) the sources of funding available for family planning services in the United States; (3) the numbers and age, gender, race, and family income of persons who receive family planning services; and (4) the types of services chosen by individuals receiving services. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants and enter into contracts for such data collection. Requires the information to be made available to the public. Requires an annual report, currently required to be submitted by the Secretary to the Congress regarding family planning matters, to be based on the data collected.</summary>
</bill>
