<bill session="100" type="s" number="1379" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the imposition of further sanctions against drug-transiting countries unless such countries curtail corruption and cooperate with the United States to combat drug trafficking.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408252" joined="1987-06-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation agreements"/>
    <term name="Bribery"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Tariff agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to provide additional sanctions against a foreign country determined to be a drug-producing or drug-transit country that has failed to cooperate with the United States in combatting drug trafficking. Specifies such sanctions as: (1) limiting by one-half the number of non-immigrant visas that may be issued for aliens born in that country; (2) curtailing air transportation between the United States and that country; and (3) the mandatory withdrawal of the United States from participation in any arrangement with that country for the pre-clearance of customs by visitors between the United States and that country. Sets forth procedures for the curtailment of air transportation. Includes the taking of the legal and law enforcement steps necessary to eliminate corruption by government officials (with particular emphasis on the elimination of bribery) as a factor to be considered in the determination of whether a foreign country has failed to cooperate.</summary>
</bill>
