<bill session="100" type="s" number="1388" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Onshore Oil and Gas Leasing Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Act of February 25, 1920, to reform Federal onshore oil and gas leasing procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407622"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-18">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered favorably reported an original bill (S. 1730) in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG05" subcommittee="Mineral Resources Development and Production" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1730"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/18/1987--Introduced.
Federal Onshore Oil and Gas Leasing Act of 1987 - Amends Federal law regarding competitive leasing of oil and gas for onshore Federal lands to increase from 640 acres to 2,560 acres the units of land open to competitive leasing. Mandates that lease sales be conducted by oral bidding. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to accept the highest bid which is at least one dollar or greater per acre, and to reject all bids for less than such amount. Makes lands available for leasing without competitive bidding if no bids have been received, or such bids are for less than the minimum amount. Requires lease sales to be held at least quarterly in each State, and conditions such a lease upon the payment of specified royalties. Describes circumstances under which certain lands may be leased without competitive bidding. Increases the primary lease term from five to ten years. Authorizes the Secretary to disapprove partial assignments of less than 640 acres outside of Alaska, or of less than 2,560 acres within Alaska. Amends the Alaska National Interest Lands Conservation Act to make leasing in Alaska consistent with that in the lower 48 States. Repeals provisions regarding: (1) determination of favorable petroleum geological provinces; and (2) suspension of noncompetitive leasing. Establishes an interim period during which certain pending lease applications will be processed as they would have been prior to the date of enactment of this Act. Establishes civil penalties for persons who willfully and knowingly misrepresent the value of lands and leases under this Act. Grants to the States concurrent civil and criminal jurisdiction for violations of this Act. States that actions taken by the Secretary to develop regulations and procedures for a competitive oil and gas leasing program (or to hold particular lease sales) shall not be subject to requirements of the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969 regarding environmental impact statements.</summary>
</bill>
