<bill session="100" type="s" number="1419" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-24">INTRODUCED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ground Water Safety Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prevent ground water contamination by pesticides.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1987-06-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1988-06-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-06-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-24">
      <text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Agriculture; Environment and Public Works by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide pollution"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticide residues"/>
    <term name="Potable water"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/24/1987--Introduced.
Ground Water Safety Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Insecticide, Fungicide, and Rodenticide Act (FIFRA) to require a pesticide registrant or reregistrant to submit information to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) regarding the pesticide's potential for groundwater leaching. (Directs the Administrator, upon such registration, to determine a pesticide's leaching potential.) Requires registrants, in the case of a positive leaching potential, to: (1) develop management practices to minimize such leaching; (2) disseminate such management information to applicators; and (3) conduct groundwater monitoring. Requires a registrant, upon detection of groundwater contamination, to notify EPA, the State, the owner of the property, and any other person(s) relying on the underground source for drinking water or household needs. States that if such contamination reaches or is likely to reach 25 percent of the EPA-established groundwater residue guidance level, the Administrator shall amend the registration to impose further restrictions on the pesticide's use. Authorizes the Administrator to consider the health effects of alternative pesticides in setting such restrictions. States that if contamination reaches 50 percent of the groundwater residue guidance level, the Administrator shall notify and provide relevant information to the affected State(s). Directs the Administrator, if an affected State fails to act, to prohibit the pesticide's use in the vicinity of the underground source of drinking water. Directs the Administrator to: (1) collect and make available to the public information on groundwater pesticide contamination; (2) provide technical assistance to States for groundwater protection programs; (3) conduct research activities to monitor the presence of pesticides in the unsaturated zone; and (4) enter into agreements with the Departments of Agriculture, Commerce, and the Interior to develop information systems for State and local officials, farmers, and applicators regarding soil, climate, and hydrology at specific pesticide use sites. Authorizes FY 1988 through 1992 appropriations. Requires States to develop and submit for EPA approval pesticide water pollution prevention programs. Authorizes: (1) the Administrator to provide financial assistance; and (2) FY 1988 through 1992 appropriations. Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize the Administrator to issue groundwater residue guidance levels for FIFRA-registered pesticides.</summary>
</bill>
