<bill session="100" type="s" number="1426" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Small Business Retirement and Benefit Extension Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage small businesses to extend retirement and fringe benefits to all employees, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408939"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1988-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Private Retirement Plans and IRS. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFI05" subcommittee="Private Retirement Plans and Oversight of the Internal Revenue Service" name="Senate Finance"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2793"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2793"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employee ownership"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Profit sharing"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Tax-deferred compensation plans"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt organizations"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/25/1987--Introduced.
Small Business Retirement and Benefit Extension Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code (IRC) to cease, as of 1988, the application of special rules for employee benefit plans that are top-heavy. (A top-heavy plan is one in which the value of plan benefits for specified "key" employees exceeds 60 percent of those for all employees under the plan.) Establishes, as a component of the general business credit against income tax, a credit for the administrative costs incurred by an employer having 100 of fewer employees in maintaining a qualified employee pension plan. Limits such credit to a maximum of $3,000 ($4,500 in the case of a defined benefit plan). Reduces the amount of the credit when the average number of employees during a relevant period exceeds 50. Amends the Tax Reform Act of 1986 and the IRC to: (1) apply nondiscrimination rules for coverage and benefits to certain employee benefit plans as of 1991 (currently 1988); (2) extend from 1987 to 1989 the effective date of amendments relating to the definition of "compensation" with respect to pension, profit-sharing, and stock bonus plans; (3) render nontaxable any annuities purchased for employees by a nongovernmental tax-exempt entity; (4) repeal certain restrictions on distributions of contributions under salary reduction arrangements; (5) delay the effective date for the application of nondiscrimination requirements to tax-sheltered annuities; and (6) repeal the 15 percent tax imposed on excess distributions from qualified retirement plans. Amends the Employee Retirement Income Security Act of 1974 to provide, for the administrator of an employee benefit plan having fewer than 100 participants, simplified reporting requirements with respect to supplying plan descriptions and annual reports to plan participants and beneficiaries. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the required Government forms currently in use with respect to qualified retirement plans are not designed so that a person with no experience in the area of employee benefits could complete them. Directs the Secretaries of the Treasury and of Labor to: (1) redesign such forms as they pertain to plans having fewer than 100 participants; and (2) report to the Congress on their actions in this regard. Amends the IRC to provide that if an employer does not operate an on-premises eating facility for employees, 50 percent of the employer's share of an off-premises meal furnished to an employee shall be treated as a de minimis fringe benefit (not includible in the employee's income) provided that: (1) the employer pays no more than one-third of the cost of the meal; (2) a maximum of one meal per working day is provided; and (3) the meal is furnished during normal business hours.</summary>
</bill>
