<bill session="100" type="s" number="1435" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize certain elements of the Yakima River Basin Water Enhancement Project, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403920"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-26">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Water and Power.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Energy Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Water and Power. Hearings held at Yakima, Washington.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG03" subcommittee="Water and Power" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2814"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2814"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Dams"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Reservoirs"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/1987--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to design, construct, operate, and maintain the following features of the Yakima River Basin Water Enhancement Project: (1) modification of existing radial gates at Cle Elum Dam; (2) a Kachess Lake to Keechelus Lake pipeline; (3) a reregulating reservoir of the Roza Division; and (4) facilities to automate and otherwise improve canal operations of the Sunnyside Division and the Wapato Indian Project; (5) facilities to automate the headgate, wasteways, and trashrack of the Chandler Power Canal to maintain operating controls for the Kennewick Irrigation District; and (6) storage facilities at the Cabin Creek site pending a preliminary analysis, a specified report to the Congress, and secretarial approval. Directs the Secretary to develop and submit a plan to the Congress for water conservation measures by recipients of irrigation water from the Yakima Enhancement Project. Authorizes appropriations. Requires non-Federal interests to fund 35 percent of construction costs. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for a feasibility study of certain other potential elements of the Yakima Enhancement Project.</summary>
</bill>
