<bill session="100" type="s" number="143" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Compassionate Pain Relief Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a temporary program under which parenteral diacetylmorphine will be made available through qualified pharmacies for the relief of intractable pain due to cancer.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-06-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-05-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1987-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-05-01" withdrawn="1987-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB, GAO.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Drug safety and regulation"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Drugstores"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Narcotics"/>
    <term name="Pain"/>
    <term name="Terminal care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Compassionate Pain Relief Act - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a 60-month program under which parenteral diacetylmorphine shall be made available through hospital and other prescribed pharmacies for the relief of pain from terminal cancer (as defined by this Act). Directs the Secretary to provide for the manufacture of such drug. Permits physicians registered under the Controlled Substances Act to prescribe such drug. States that for purposes of such program the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act and titles II and III of the Comprehensive Drug Abuse Prevention and Control Act of 1970 shall not apply with respect to: (1) the importing of opium; and (2) the manufacture, distribution, and dispensing of parenteral diacetylmorphine. Requires: (1) the Secretary to make program reports to specified congressional committees; and (2) the Comptroller General of the United States to make a program report to such committees 56 months after the program is established. Requires the Secretary to report to specified congressional committees concerning: (1) the extent of research activities in the management of pain which have received funds through the National Institutes of Health; (2) the ways in which the Federal Government supports the training of health personnel in pain management; and (3) recommendations for expanding and improving the training of health personnel in pain management. Permits the Secretary at any time six months after implementation of the program to modify or terminate the program.</summary>
</bill>
