<bill session="100" type="s" number="1449" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Transport Regulatory Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the process for filling vacancies which occur on the Interstate Commerce Commission, the Federal Maritime Commission, and the National Transportation Safety Board.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400692"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional reorganization"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Federal Maritime Commission"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="National Transportation Safety Board"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/1987--Introduced.
Transport Regulatory Reform Act of 1987 - Establishes within the legislative branch a 15-member Transportation Regulatory Commissions Nominating Commission. Requires the President to notify the Commission's chair of any vacancy occurring on the Interstate Commerce Commission, the Federal Maritime Commission, or the National Transportation Safety Board. Requires the Commission to submit a list of at least three qualified individuals within 90 days of notification. Enumerates qualification requirements of nominees. Requires the President to nominate an individual for a vacancy within 90 days. Provides for a default to the first name on the Commission list if the President fails to make a nomination within the required time period. Provides for expedited committee consideration of nominees. Requires Commission membership to be drawn from transportation carriers and their organizations. Requires the Commission to submit nomination reports to the President of the Senate and biannual evaluations to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
