<bill session="100" type="s" number="1441" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-06">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Health Service Act Infant Mortality Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Public Health Service Act Infant Mortality Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Public Health Service Act Infant Mortality Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce the incidence of infant mortality.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-03">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment. With written report No. 100-137.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-08-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="282">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 282.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-08-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Boundaries"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Family medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to nursing education"/>
    <term name="Gynecology"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical residents"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Osteopathy and osteopaths"/>
    <term name="Pacific area"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="Sudden infant death syndrome"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s666"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/6/1987--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Public Health Service Act Infant Mortality Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to increase the FY 1988 authorization of appropriations for existing provisions relating to health centers which provide services to migratory and seasonal agricultural workers and their families. Increases the FY 1988 authorization of appropriations for existing provisions relating to community health centers. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services (Secretary), in making grants to community health centers, to give special consideration to the needs of frontier areas. Requires that, if amounts appropriated for community health centers for FY 1988 exceed a specified amount, the excess shall be available for grants to community health centers for prenatal services to decrease infant mortality and perinatal coordination projects to develop and coordinate referral arrangements between community health centers and other agencies. Directs the Secretary, in making grants from such excess appropriations, to give priority to community health centers in areas in which there is a high or increased incidence of infant mortality. Directs the Secretary to enter into contracts with schools of medicine and osteopathy for area health education center programs which include training of personnel to offer maternal and child health services in underserved areas, giving priority to programs which train personnel to provide services in areas along the border between the United States and Mexico, in frontier areas, in areas of the Pacific Basin Region, and in areas in which the rate of infant mortality and low birthweight are disproportionately higher than for the State in which such area is located. Requires schools participating in such programs to provide for active participation by the schools' administrative personnel in each of the departments of pediatrics, obstetrics and gynecology, and family medicine. Exempts schools participating in such programs from existing requirements that not less than ten percent of undergraduate medical or osteopathic clinical education of the school be conducted in an area health education center and locations under the sponsorship of such center. Requires programs to conduct a medical residency program in obstetrics and gynecology enrolling at least six individuals in first year positions. Requires area health education centers to involve nurse midwives in their interdisciplinary training (current provisions require involvement of physicians, physician assistants, and nurse practitioners). Increases the authorization of appropriations for FY 1988. Requires, of amounts appropriated for FY 1988, a specified amount to be available for contracts for area health education center programs under this Act. Amends part A (Special Projects) of title VIII (Nurse Training) of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary to make grants to public or nonprofit private schools of nursing, public health, or medicine for fellowship programs for the education of nurse midwives and pediatric, family, obstetric, and gynecologic nurse practitioners. Directs the Secretary, after consultation with educational, nursing, and medical organizations, to prescribe guidelines for the fellowship programs. Specifies minimum requirements to be included in the guidelines. Requires the fellowships to cover, for each year awarded, 100 percent of costs of tuition, books, reasonable living expenses (including stipends), reasonable moving expenses, and transportation expenses. Requires individuals receiving fellowships to be registered nurses. Requires schools of nursing, in awarding fellowships, to give priority to applicants employed in and recommended by a facility serving underserved populations. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988.</summary>
</bill>
