<bill session="100" type="s" number="1455" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-06-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require certain drug-producing or drug transiting countries to implement bilateral narcotics agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402495"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Extradition agreements"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/30/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to make ineligible for a presidential waiver of the limitations on foreign economic assistance to countries determined to be major illicit drug producing or drug transit countries any such country which has not agreed to an applicable bilateral narcotics agreement with the United States. Describes a bilateral narcotic agreement as an agreement between the United States and a foreign country whereby that country agrees to: (1) take specific actions in order to reduce drug production, drug consumption, and drug trafficking within its territory; (2) cooperate with U.S. drug enforcement officials; and (3) participate in extradition treaties, mutual legal assistance provisions directed at money laundering, sharing of evidence, and other initiatives for cooperative drug enforcement.</summary>
</bill>
