<bill session="100" type="s" number="1479" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-04">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farm Credit System Loan Restructuring Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide funds and assistance to Farm Credit System institutions, to protect borrower stock, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401611"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1987-07-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-08-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Agricultural Credit.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-11-04" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 1665 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSAF03" subcommittee="Agricultural Credit" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1665"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Farm Credit Administration"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreclosure"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/9/1987--Introduced.
Farm Credit System Loan Restructuring Act - Amends the Farm Credit Act of 1971 to authorize the Central Reserve Fund Board (established by this Act) to issue up to $4,000,000,000 in federally guaranteed bonds. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to assist in the interest payments on such bonds for five years. Establishes the Central Reserve Fund Board. Provides for Federal assistance to Farm Credit System institutions. Permits the use of Central Reserve Fund moneys to pay System institutions to enable them to redeem stock at par value and to otherwise remain financially viable. Requires the board of directors of a farm credit district to have a certain plan in place in order for any System institution in its district to be eligible. Requires a recovery plan to be submitted within 60 days of the enactment of this Act. Requires a plan to: (1) establish a special credit team in the district to review on a case-by-case basis the nonaccrual and high risk loans; (2) describe how the team plans to restructure rather than foreclose on troubled loans whenever it is cheaper for the institution to do so; and (3) describe how the district will reduce its operating costs at least ten percent below their 1985 levels. Requires that: (1) the restructuring of each loan be done by the System institution that holds the loan; and (2) the district have in place a system for monitoring restructured loans to determine whether the restructuring has been successful. Sets forth a procedure for determining whether a loan should be restructured or foreclosed. Requires the Farm Credit Administration to report quarterly to the Central Reserve Fund Board on the adherence of the districts to their filed plans. Directs the Board, on the basis of such reports, to determine whether or not a district should receive, or continue to receive, Federal assistance. Provides for protection of borrower stock. Declares that during the five year period following enactment of this Act, in the case of any System institution loan to a borrower that is secured by borrower stock: (1) if the stock is retired, it shall be paid at par value; (2) if the borrower defaults on the loan, the stock may be canceled; or (3) under other specified circumstances, the stock may be otherwise disposed of. Terminates the Farm Credit System Capital Corporation and transfers all of its assets and liabilities to the Central Reserve Fund.</summary>
</bill>
