<bill session="100" type="s" number="1474" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:20-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require that any United States Government support for military or paramilitary operations in Angola be openly acknowledged and publicly debated.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1988-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-10">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Angola"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Reagan Doctrine"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/8/1987--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that the U.S. Government should not provide any support for military or paramilitary operations in Angola until the President has informed the Congress and the public that such support is important to the national security and the Congress has approved such support. Authorizes any U.S. agency, during FY 1987 and 1988, to use its funds to conduct military or paramilitary operations in Angola or to provide aid to any group engaged in such operations only if such use of such funds is the openly acknowledged U.S. policy. Provides that such policy is considered openly acknowledged only if: (1) the President determines that U.S. support for such operations is important to national security and requests the Congress to approve support for such operations; and (2) the Congress enacts a joint resolution approving support for such operations.</summary>
</bill>
