<bill session="100" type="s" number="1487" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-16">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-06-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Program Support Authorization Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to consolidate and authorize program support and certain ocean and coastal programs and functions of the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration under the Department of Commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1987-06-16" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-10">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hollings. With written report No. 100-107.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-10" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="236">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 236.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Coastal zone"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Ecology"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Geodesy"/>
    <term name="Maps"/>
    <term name="Marine pollution"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/1987--Introduced.
National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Program Support Authorization Act - Title I: Program Support - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 to the Department of Commerce for the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) to carry out: (1) executive direction and administration; (2) marine services; and (3) aircraft services. Title II: Selected Ocean and Coastal Programs - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 to the Department of Commerce for the purpose of enabling NOAA to carry out its duties in: (1) mapping, charting, and geodesy; (2) observations and assessment activities; and (3) ocean and coastal management. States that the authorization for ocean and coastal management is in addition to moneys authorized under the Coastal Zone Management Act of 1972. Title III: Ocean Research - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 to the Department of Commerce to enable NOAA to carry out its duties regarding ocean and Great Lakes programs. States that such authorization is in addition to moneys authorized under the National Sea Grant College Program Act. Title IV: Global Environmental Change - Authorizes appropriations for 1988 and 1989 to the Department of Commerce to enable NOAA to carry out a program to be established by the Secretary of Commerce to study global environmental change. Title V: Reduction of Marine Debris - Directs the Secretary of Commerce to ensure that efforts to reduce marine plastic debris and its adverse impact on ocean, coastal, and Great Lakes resources receive priority attention in the Department of Commerce.</summary>
</bill>
