<bill session="100" type="s" number="148" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Shipping Act, 1916, to provide for jurisdiction over common carriers by water engaging in foreign commerce to and from the United States utilizing ports in nations contiguous to the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Common carriers"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Shipping rates"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Shipping Act, 1916 to redefine the term "common carrier by water in foreign commerce" to include those engaged as common carriers in specified ocean transportation of property who: (1) advertise, solicit, or arrange, within the United States, for such transportation; and (2) transport such property between a point within the United States and a port in a nation contiguous to the United States. Directs such common carriers to file their tariffs with the Federal Maritime Commission within 90 days of enactment of this Act. Sets forth the effective dates of such tariffs. Declares that nothing in this Act shall be construed to: (1) require such common carriers to reveal, in tariffs filed with the Commission, the portion of such tariffs attributable to inland transportation; (2) require such common carriers to reveal any information with regard to such inland transportation; or (3) extend to the Commission any jurisdiction over or authority to regulate rail carriers.</summary>
</bill>
