<bill session="100" type="s" number="1484" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide permanent authorization for White House Conferences on Rural Development and the Family Farm.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-09-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-08-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-09-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-16">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Rural Development, Electrification.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSAF05" subcommittee="Rural Development and Rural Electrification" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Family farms"/>
    <term name="Farmers"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural conditions"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="White House conferences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/10/1987--Introduced.
Directs the President to call and conduct, once during each presidential term, a National White House Conference on Rural Development and the Family Farm, bringing together State, regional, and Federal representatives for the purpose of preserving and stimulating economic and cultural vitality in rural communities. Mandates, to the extent practicable, State and regional conferences, at least one in each State, to be held as preparatory to the National Conference. Limits participation in these local conferences to participants in the National Conference and to residents of farms or of small rural communities who have a vested interest in rural community life. Directs the National Conference to examine such topics of rural concern as: (1) the delivery of essential services to rural communities; (2) the role of the family farm in these communities; (3) economic development, including job opportunities for displaced farmers; (4) the maintenance and development of the rural infrastructure; and (5) the interrelationship among Federal, State, and various local levels of government. Names the Secretary of Agriculture (Secretary) as the administrator of the National Conference and directs the heads of Federal departments and agencies to provide support and assistance as necessary. Directs the Secretary to assist in implementing the State and regional conferences. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into contracts with public agencies, private organizations, and academic institutions to carry out this Act. Makes participants responsible for their own National Conference expenses. Authorizes the President to appoint and compensate an executive director and other personnel for the National Conference. Requires: (1) the National Conference to submit a final report to the President and to the Congress not later than six months after convening; and (2) the Secretary of Agriculture and the Director of the Extension Service, after submission of the National Conference report, to submit annual reports to the Congress on the status and implementation of the National Conference's findings and recommendations. Authorizes appropriations, to remain available until expended. Prohibits Department of Agriculture funds not so specifically appropriated from being used for this Act's implementation.</summary>
</bill>
