<bill session="100" type="s" number="1488" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pediatric Emergency Medical Services Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for the establishment of a National Center for Pediatric Emergency Medical Services and regional centers for the provision of such services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Emergency medicine"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1987--Introduced.
Pediatric Emergency Medical Services Act of 1987 - Amends part B (Federal-State Cooperation) of title III of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make a grant for FY 1988 for a feasibility study on establishing and operating a National Center for Pediatric Emergency Medical Services (National Center). Directs the Secretary to request the Institute of Medicine of the National Academy of Sciences to submit an application for the grant and, if the Institute submits an acceptable application, to make the grant to the Institute. Directs the Secretary, in the absence of an acceptable application from the Institute, to request an application from one or more nonprofit private entities and to make the grant to the entity submitting the best acceptable application. Directs the Secretary, after reviewing the report prepared under such grant and consulting with the American Academy of Pediatrics and the American College of Emergency Physicians, if a National Center is feasible, to make grants for FY 1989 and each succeeding fiscal year for the establishment and operation of a National Center. Requires the National Center, with regard to pediatric medical emergencies, to: (1) develop and disseminate standards and quality assurance mechanisms; (2) facilitate training of health professionals; and (3) develop and disseminate information for the public on the prevention of, and responses to, such emergencies. Directs the Secretary to make grants to States, public and nonprofit private entities, and academic institutions for the development, establishment, and operation of regional centers for pediatric emergency medical services. Requires such centers to: (1) train health professionals; (2) provide for the appropriate use of bilingual personnel; (3) conduct research on prevention and treatment; and (4) conduct activities relating to prevention, including dissemination of information to the public. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Repeals a provision of the Public Health Service Act relating to emergency medical services for children.</summary>
</bill>
