<bill session="100" type="s" number="1498" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-15">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-05-15"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arms Control and Disarmament Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Arms Control and Disarmament Act to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1988 for the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1987-05-15" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations ordered to be reported an original measure in lieu of S. 859.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Pell. With written report No. 100-112.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="240">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 240.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-22">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-22">
      <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 2689 as an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-22">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 2689 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-22">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2689"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="859"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Antimissile missiles"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms Control and Disarmament Agency"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/15/1987--Introduced.
Arms Control and Disarmament Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends the Arms Control and Disarmament Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 for the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency. Earmarks specified amounts of appropriated funds for: (1) expenses of arms control negotiations conducted with the Soviet Union on strategic arms reductions, intermediate-range nuclear forces, and space and defensive weapons; (3) the Reduced Enrichment in Research and Test Reactors program; (4) the program for visiting scholars in the field of arms control and disarmament. Requires the President to submit to the Congress an annual report by the U.S. Commissioner on the activities of the United States-Union of Soviet Socialist Republics Standing Consultative Commission established under the Treaty on the Limitation of Anti-Ballistic Missile Systems. Revises the requirements for the annual report concerning arms-control compliance to require the inclusion of information on actions taken by the Soviet Union with regard to the size, structure, and disposition of its military forces in order to comply with existing arms control agreements. Requires the Director of the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency to submit an annual report to the Congress setting forth a comprehensive list of research, development, and other studies relating to arms control and disarmament issues concluded during the previous calendar year by Government agencies or for Government agencies by private or public institutions or persons.</summary>
</bill>
