<bill session="100" type="s" number="1518" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:21-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-14">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Methanol and Alternative Fuels Promotion Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Alternative Motor Fuels Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Methanol and Alternative Fuels Promotion Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Methanol and Alternative Fuels Promotion Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Alternative Motor Fuels Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act to provide for the appropriate treatment of methanol and ethanol, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400927" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1988-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="408420" joined="1987-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-10-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409580" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-07-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Consumer. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-271.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-12-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="514">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 514.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-04-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-04-15" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-04-18">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Called up by House by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-06-28" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>House Struck all After the Enacting Clause and Substituted the Language of H.R.3399 (Amended).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>House Insisted on its Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>House Requested a Conference and Speaker Appointed Conferees: Dingell, Sharp, Bruce, Lent, Moorhead.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and held at desk: House amendment to Senate bill and House requests a conference.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06">
      <text>Senate disagreed to the House amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06">
      <text>Senate agreed to request for conference. Appointed conferees. Hollings; Gore; Rockefeller; Danforth; McCain. From the committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-06">
      <text>Senate appointed conferees Glenn; Levin; Roth from the committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-15">
      <text>Conferees agreed to file conference report.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16">
      <text>Conference Report 100-929 Filed in House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Conference papers: official papers held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Conference report considered in Senate. By Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="conference" datetime="1988-09-20" where="s" result="pass" state="CONFERENCE:PASSED:SENATE">
      <text>Senate agreed to conference report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>House Agreed to Conference Report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-14" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-494" type="public" datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-494.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM03" subcommittee="Consumer" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3082"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3082"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3399"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Automobile fuel consumption"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Gasoline tax"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Liquefied petroleum gas"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Methanol"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="h778"/>
    <amendment number="h779"/>
    <amendment number="s1950"/>
    <amendment number="s1951"/>
    <amendment number="s1952"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/16/1988--Conference report filed in House.
(Conference report filed in House, H. Rept. 100-929) Alternative Motor Fuels Act of 1988 - Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to direct the Secretary of Energy to ensure that beginning in FY 1990 the maximum practicable number of Federal passenger automobiles and light duty trucks be: (1) alcohol-powered vehicles; (2) dual energy vehicles; (3) natural gas-powered vehicles; or (4) natural gas dual energy vehicles. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study regarding such vehicles' performance, fuel economy, safety, and maintenance costs. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress the results of a feasibility study concerning the disposal of such alternative-fueled Federal vehicles. Provides for alcohol fuel to be made available to the public at locations where the Federal vehicles are fueled. States that appropriations for Federal vehicle acquisition shall apply only to that portion of the cost of alcohol-powered (or dual energy) vehicles which exceeds the cost of comparable conventional fueled vehicles. Provides that: (1) such vehicles shall not be counted in any average fuel economy calculation of the Federal passenger automobile fleet acquired in any fiscal year; and (2) the incremental cost of such vehicles over the cost of comparable conventional fueled vehicles shall not be applied to any calculation regarding the maximum cost of individual Federal vehicles. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1990 through 1993 for such alternative-fueled vehicles. Requires the Secretary to establish a commercial application program to study alcohol and natural gas fuel use in heavy duty trucks. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY 1990 through 1992. Directs the Secretary (in cooperation with Federal agencies regulating motor vehicles for safety and environmental purposes) to assist State and local governmental agencies in testing the environmental and safety aspects of alcohol and natural-gas powered buses in urban settings. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1990 through 1992. Establishes the Interagency Commission on Alternative Motor Fuels to develop and coordinate efforts to implement a national alternative motor fuels policy. Requires the Commission chairperson to establish a United States Alternative Fuels Council to report to the Commission about alternative motor fuels matters. Requires the Commission to submit interim reports to the Congress and a final report no later than September 30, 1992. Terminates the Commission and the Council upon submission of its final report. Directs the Secretary to study and report to the Congress regarding the cost and practicability of methanol plants. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to submit to specified congressional committees biennial reports on a comprehensive analysis of the air quality, global climate change, and other environmental impacts associated with the use of alternative motor fuels under this Act. Requires the reports to include extended reasonable forecasts of environmental effects. Authorizes appropriations. Precludes the voiding of any guaranty or warranty with respect to any federally acquired passenger automobile or light-duty truck after October 1, 1989, on the grounds that such vehicle is operated with nonstandard fuels. Amends the Motor Vehicle Information and Cost Savings Act to set forth fuel efficiency standards for: (1) alcohol-powered automobiles; (2) dual energy automobiles; (3) natural gas-powered automobiles; and (4) natural gas dual energy automobiles. Prescribes guidelines for calculation of the fuel economy of alternative-fueled vehicles at increasing rates for model years 1993 through 2004. Expands the definition of "automobile" to include vehicles powered by alcohol or natural gas. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to report to the Congress the results of a study regarding the need to promulgate additional or amended regulations to stimulate the introduction of electric vehicles into commerce. Sets forth fuel economy labeling guidelines for alcohol or natural gas powered automobiles, and dual energy or natural gas dual energy automobiles. Requires the Secretary of Energy to report to certain congressional committees on whether the fuel economy prescriptions and the amendments made by this Act are likely to increase residential energy costs significantly.</summary>
</bill>
