<bill session="100" type="s" number="1553" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide that any liability of a Federal employee for a breach of any fiduciary responsibility under the Federal Retirement Thrift Investment Management System shall be payable by the United States if the liability relates to action taken in good faith and within the scope of the individual's official duties.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Employees' Retirement System Act of 1986 to provide that any liability of a Federal employee for a breach of fiduciary responsibility with respect to the Thrift Savings Fund shall be payable by the United States if the liability relates to action taken in good faith and within the scope of the individual's official duties. Repeals provisions which allow for an assessment of Federal agencies for contributions to the Thrift Savings Fund for the purchase of insurance to cover potential liability of persons who serve in a fiduciary capacity with respect to such Fund. Requires repayment of agency contributions to the Fund which are not spent or obligated for the purchase of fiduciary liability insurance.</summary>
</bill>
