<bill session="100" type="s" number="1558" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Railroad Safety Authorization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406190"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1774"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1774"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1987--Introduced.
Federal Railroad Safety Authorization Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989. Confers jurisdiction upon the district courts to issue orders requiring immediate compliance with a subpoena, order, or directive issued by the Secretary of Transportation (the Secretary). Precludes specified documents from being admitted into evidence or used for any purpose in lawsuits for damages arising out of railroad accidents or incidents. Declares it is unlawful for individuals who perform certain safety-sensitive railroad functions to fail to comply with rules or standards prescribed by the Secretary. Increases from $2,500 to $10,000 the maximum civil penalty for railroad safety violations (including a maximum civil penalty of $25,000 for violations that have created an especially egregious safety hazard). Authorizes the Secretary to prohibit a person from serving in a safety-sensitive capacity in the rail industry if such person's violation of a safety regulation is shown to make that person unfit for safety sensitive functions. Defines the term "railroad" to include all forms of nonhighway ground transportation that run on rails or electromagnetic guideways, except for rapid transit operations within an urban area that are not connected to the general railroad system of transportation. Repeals specified railroad safety laws. Prescribes guidelines under which the Secretary is required to establish a fee schedule for railroads, and to assess and collect such fees for each fiscal year for the purpose of approximating the costs of administering Federal laws regarding railroad safety and railroad noise control.</summary>
</bill>
