<bill session="100" type="s" number="1555" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Construction Labor Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Davis-Bacon Act by increasing the coverage threshold to $100,000 for non-military contracts and $1,000,000 for military contracts, and to amend the Copeland Act compliance provision, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/28/1987--Introduced.
Construction Labor Reform Act of 1987 - Amends the Davis-Bacon Act by increasing the contract coverage threshold to $100,000 (or $1,000,000 in the case of Department of Defense contracts). Provides that mechanics and laborers employed on contracts pursuant to such Act shall be paid no less often than twice a month (rather than once a week). Prohibits division of a project into smaller contracts to avoid Davis-Bacon Act coverage. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor, where such a division has occurred, to require: (1) retroactive incorporation of all the provisions which would have been required; and (2) compensation for payment to each affected laborer and mechanic of the difference in wage rates, with interest. Removes specified authority of the Comptroller General from such Act. Provides that, in accordance with specified regulations issued by the Secretary of Labor, wages found to be due laborers and mechanics under such Act shall be paid directly to them from accrued payments withheld under the contract. Provides that any sums due to laborers or mechanics under such Act and not paid because of inability to do so within three years, shall revert to or be deposited into the Treasury. Directs the Administrator of General Services to distribute a list to all departments of the Government giving the names of persons or firms that the Secretary of Labor has found to have disregarded their obligations to employees and subcontractors. Applies the $100,000 contract coverage threshold to federally assisted construction under related Acts requiring a Davis-Bacon wage determination. Amends the Copeland Act to require submission at least twice per month of a statement of compliance with labor standards provisions of applicable law, certifying the payroll of employees during the preceding period, and coverage each week any contract work is performed. Makes specified provisions of the Federal Trade Commission Act, relating to the attendance of witnesses and the production of books, papers, and documents, applicable to the jurisdiction, powers, and duties of the Secretary of Labor.</summary>
</bill>
