<bill session="100" type="s" number="1554" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-11">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Renewable Energy and Energy Conservation Technology Competitiveness Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Technology Competitiveness Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal assistance and leadership to a program of research, development and demonstration of renewable energy and energy conservation, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-10-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-07-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-09-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-10-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-07-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Research and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Energy Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on Research and Development. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 100-523.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="958">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 958.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG01" subcommittee="Research and Development" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy industries"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Geothermal resources"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government lending"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Industrialized building"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Mobile homes"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Ocean energy resources"/>
    <term name="Ocean thermal energy conversion"/>
    <term name="Photovoltaic power systems"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Solar heating and cooling"/>
    <term name="Solar thermal power generation"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wind power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1988--Indefinitely postponed in Senate.
(Measure indefinitely postponed in Senate) Renewable Energy and Energy Efficiency Technology Competitiveness Act of 1988 - Sets forth specified national goals for the current wind, photovoltaics, and solar thermal energy programs. Requires the President's budget requests for FY 1991 to contain the recommendations of the Secretary of Energy for specified Department of Energy research and development programs for 1995, including biofuels energy systems, solar buildings energy systems, ocean energy systems, and geothermal energy. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1990 through 1992 for: (1) the wind energy research program; (2) the photovoltaic energy systems program; (3) the solar thermal energy systems program; (4) the biofuels energy systems program; (5) the solar buildings energy systems program; (6) the ocean energy systems program; and (7) the geothermal program. Mandates that the President's budget requests for FY 1992 include the Secretary's recommendations or proof of concept proposals for certain renewable energy projects. Requires the Secretary to submit an options analysis to the Congress regarding the accelerated commercialization of specified renewable energy technologies. Requires the President's budget requests for FY 1991 and 1992 to include the Secretary's recommendations of amounts to be set aside for energy efficiency research and development and demonstration initiatives. Authorizes appropriations for specified energy efficiency research and development programs for FY 1991 through 1992. Directs the Secretary to establish joint research and development ventures in specified energy technologies and to report to the Congress on the implementation of such plans. Directs the Secretary to establish the following advisory bodies: (1) Advisory Committee on Photovoltaic Village Energy Systems; (2) Advisory Committee on Wind Energy Village Energy Systems; (3) Advisory Committee on Solar Thermal Community Total Energy Systems; (4) Advisory Committee on Energy Performance in Factory-Made Housing; (5) Advisory Committee on Advanced District Cooling Technology; and (6) Advisory Committee on Energy Conservation and Renewable Energy Technology Exports. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1990 through 1992 for such joint ventures. Requires the Secretary to evaluate and report to the Congress on the efforts of the Committee on Renewable Energy, Commerce and Trade to promote renewable energy technology exports. Authorizes appropriations for such Committee activities for FY 1990 through 1992. Amends the National Energy Conservation Policy Act to direct the Secretary to establish an information dissemination program for Federal procurement and loan officers on the benefits of solar heating and cooling technology, including site visits and technical briefings. Amends the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act to direct the President to take into account the degree to which a country promotes energy self-sufficiency using locally available renewable resources when he determines whether to designate it as a beneficiary country entitled to duty-free treatment for trade purposes. Amends the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945 to mandate that a specified percentage of its loan authority be available solely for solar and renewable energy loans. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to authorize the Overseas Private Investment Corporation to include among its special projects incentives, grants, and studies for renewable energy and other small business activities. Amends the Small Business Act to repeal provisions concerning loans to small business concerns for solar energy and energy conservation measures. Authorizes the Administrator of the Small Business Administration to assist small businesses engaged in providing certain energy services. Prohibits the use of such loans for research and development. Directs the Administrator to give due consideration to the export potential of solar and renewable energy products, and to include a list of solar and renewable energy loan guarantees in annual reports to the Congress. Requires the Secretary to make annual reports to the Congress regarding the research programs and ventures under this Act. Requires each annual submission of the National Energy Policy Plan to be accompanied by a three-year strategic plan for energy technology research, development, and demonstration, including energy conservation and renewable energy technologies.</summary>
</bill>
