<bill session="100" type="s" number="1569" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">High Level Waste Repository Water Pollution Control and Guarantee Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to guarantee the control and safety of polluted high level waste repository water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Compensation (Law)"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Interstate compacts"/>
    <term name="Liability for nuclear damages"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive contamination of soils"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution of water"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/30/1987--Introduced.
High Level Waste Repository Water Pollution Control and Guarantee Act - Amends the Nuclear Waste Policy Act of 1982 to grant congressional consent to an interstate compact which provides that: (1) if water in any State is polluted by leakage from a high level nuclear waste repository, every State signatory (whether or not it generates nuclear waste) shall provide a pro rata share of its water resources to fully replace the lost water resources; (2) if residential, commercial, or agricultural land becomes effectively unusable due to high level waste leakage, each State signatory shall provide equivalent land on a pro rata basis; and (3) each State signatory agrees to designate a member to, and comply with the orders of, the Polluted High Level Waste Repository Water State Compensation Commission (established by this Act). Establishes such Commission and makes it responsible for allocating land and water pursuant to this Act. Prohibits the shipment of high level radioactive waste to any repository authorized under this Act unless: (1) the compact is consented to by at least 40 States; and (2) the State in which such waste originated is a signatory to such compact. Provides a Federal guarantee that: (1) any land pollution loss that is not fully compensated under this Act shall be compensated at full value by the United States; and (2) any physical facilities needed for replacement water transportation shall be immediately constructed by the United States upon a determination of need for such facility by the Commission.</summary>
</bill>
