<bill session="100" type="s" number="1564" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Bipartisan Commission on Comprehensive Health Care Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a United States Bipartisan Commission on Comprehensive Health Care.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402495"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-07-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2654"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2654"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Comprehensive health care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/29/1987--Introduced.
United States Bipartisan Commission on Comprehensive Health Care Act - Establishes the United States Bipartisan Commission on Comprehensive Health Care. Sets forth its duties and membership. Authorizes it to appoint and determine the compensation of staff and procure the services of consultants. Details its powers. Requires the Commission to submit a report to the Congress, no later than six months after enactment of this Act, containing findings and recommendations regarding comprehensive long-term care services for the elderly and disabled, and including recommendations for legislative initiatives. Requires the Commission to submit a report to the Congress, no later than one year after enactment of this Act, containing findings and recommendations regarding comprehensive health care services for the elderly and disabled and comprehensive health care services for all individuals in the United States, and including recommendations for legislative initiatives. Terminates the Commission 30 days after the date of submission of such second report. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
