<bill session="100" type="s" number="1579" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-26">PASS_BACK:HOUSE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the block grant program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-07-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-07-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-08-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-09-23">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-167.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="325">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 325.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-02-03" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-02-16">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-16">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Energy and Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Health and the Environment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-07-26" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-08-02">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and held at desk: House amendments to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05">
      <text>Senate disagreed to House amendments, requested a conference and appointed conferees. Kennedy; Pell; Adams; Hatch; Quayle.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>House Disagreed to Senate Amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>House Agreed to Request for Conference and Speaker Appointed Conferees: Dingell, Waxman, Scheuer, Lent, Madigan.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Conference Report 100-1055 Filed in House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>House Agreed to Conference Report by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Conference papers: message on House action held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Conference papers: Senate report and managers' statement held at the desk in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-11-04">
      <text>For Further Action See S.2889.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSIF" name="House Energy and Commerce" activity="Referral"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="HSIF04" subcommittee="Health and Environment" name="House Energy and Commerce"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4915"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2889"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Breast cancer"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Cholesterol"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Diseases"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Emergency communication systems"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Sexually transmitted diseases"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Vaccination"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1988--Conference report filed in House.
(Conference report filed in House, H. Rept. 100-1055) Title I: Revisions and Extension of Certain Programs with Respect to Preventive Health and Health Services - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 for preventive health and health services block grants. Amends provisions specifying the uses for such grants to include grants related to elevated serum cholesterol, chronic diseases, immunization services, communications equipment for emergency medical services systems, and uterine and breast cancer. Requires that the annual application mandated by current law include a statement of the public health objectives expected to be achieved through the use of the payments. Specifies additional information and evaluations which must be included in the annual report mandated by current law. Allows grants for demonstration projects for emergency medical services for children to be for not more than a two-year period, subject to annual evaluation by the Secretary of Health and Human Services. (Current law limits such grants to a one-year period and makes no reference to an evaluation.) Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991. Repeals provisions authorizing the Secretary to make grants to States with regard to: (1) health information and health promotion; and (2) identification of needs for block grants relating to preventive health and health services. Title II: Revision and Extension of Certain Programs with Respect to Sexually Transmitted Diseases, Health Information, and Health Promotion - Revises provisions of the Public Health Service Act relating to grants concerning acquired immune deficiency syndrome and sexually transmitted diseases. Authorizes appropriations for sexually transmitted disease projects and programs for FY 1989 through 1991. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 to carry out the provisions of title XVII (Health Information and Health Promotion) of the Public Health Service Act. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, not later than 18 months after enactment of this Act, to develop model programs through which employers in the public sector and employers that are small businesses can provide for their employees a program to promote healthful behaviors and discourage unhealthful behaviors. Directs the Secretary to provide related technical assistance. Title III: General Provisions - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
