<bill session="100" type="s" number="1608" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:22-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Claims Court Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28 of the United States Code as it pertains to the structure of the United States Claims Court.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Judicial compensation"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Judicial reform"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/6/1987--Introduced.
United States Claims Court Improvement Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal judicial code with respect to the salaries and benefits of judges of the U.S. Claims Court (making such salaries and benefits equal those of U.S. Tax Court judges) and the administration of such court (allowing the Claims Court to contract for certain services and granting such court the same subpoena and incidental powers as the U.S. Tax Court). Deems the clerk, court executive (to be appointed by the chief judge of the Claims Court), and all employees of the Claims Court to be officers and employees of the judicial branch of the Federal Government. Sets forth provisions permitting the recall of eligible persons to serve as senior Claims Court judges.</summary>
</bill>
