<bill session="100" type="s" number="1633" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Transplant Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to revise and extend the program of assistance to organ procurement organizations, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404679"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Blood"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Donation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
Organ Transplant Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to authorize grants under existing provisions for consolidation as well as for establishment, initial operation, and expansion of organ procurement organizations. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for special projects designed to increase the number of organ donors. Directs the Secretary, in making the grants, to give special consideration to proposals from existing organ procurement organizations. Prohibits grants from exceeding a specified amount in a year. Revises organ procurement organization provisions concerning organ procurement and distribution. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Requires that the Organ Procurement and Transplantation Network: (1) establish medical criteria for allocating organs and provide a periodic opportunity for public comment on the criteria; (2) assist organ procurement organizations in the distribution of organs (current provisions require the Network to assist procurement organizations in the distribution of organs which cannot be placed within the service areas of the organizations); (3) prepare and distribute samples of blood sera from potential recipients, to the extent practicable, on a national as well as a regional basis; and (4) carry out studies and demonstration projects regarding organ procurement and allocation procedures. Directs the Secretary to establish procedures for considering comments received from interested persons relating to how the Network is carrying out its duties. Requires the Secretary to maintain an identifiable administrative unit in the Public Health Service regarding organ procurement through FY 1990. (Current provisions require such a unit through FY 1988.) Revises specified reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
