<bill session="100" type="s" number="1647" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Former Presidents Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the laws relating to former Presidents.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402495"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Federal Spending, Budget, Account. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-726.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSGA02" subcommittee="Federal Spending, Budget, and Accounting" name="Senate Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3282"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3282"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Political activities"/>
    <term name="Presidential allowances"/>
    <term name="Presidential compensation"/>
    <term name="Presidential protection"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Protection of officials"/>
    <term name="Secret service"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Transfer of employees"/>
    <term name="Vice Presidents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
Former Presidents Act of 1987 - Title I: Former Presidents - Changes the amount of the annual allowance to which the surviving spouse of a deceased former President is entitled from $20,000 to two-thirds of the allowance to which a former President is entitled. Repeals the requirement that the spouse must waive the right to any other Government annuity or pension to qualify for such allowance. Authorizes the Administrator of General Services to provide to each former President, upon request: (1) one office; (2) compensation, without an aggregate ceiling, for members of an office staff who shall be subject to certain provisions of civil service laws; (3) payment for the travel and subsistence allowances for specified office employees; (4) communications services; (5) printing and binding expenses; and (6) appropriate equipment for such office. Allows any Federal employee to be detailed to the office staff of a former President with the consent of the employee's agency head. Declares that the cost of providing transportation by Government aircraft to former Presidents shall be paid from appropriations for such purpose. Authorizes the Administrator to provide a former Vice President with necessary services and facilities for concluding his or her office affairs which are similar to the services and facilities provided to a former President under this title. Prohibits the use of funds provided for necessary services and facilities of a former President or Vice President for partisan political activities or income generating activities. Prohibits the expenditure of such funds for a former President any time beyond 90 days after the former President dies. Requires each former President to submit to the Congress an annual report concerning activities carried out with the assistance of such funds. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the provisions of this title concerning the services and facilities to be provided for former Presidents and Vice Presidents. Repeals specified provisions of the Presidential Transition Act of 1963. Title II: Protection of Former Presidents and Former Vice Presidents - Prohibits the United States Secret Service from protecting a former President, former Vice President, or the spouse, widow, widower, or child of a former President, except as authorized under this title. Authorizes the Secret Service to protect: (1) a former President for five years after the individual becomes a former President; (2) the spouse or child of a former President for two years after the individual becomes a former President, and after such period to the extent that such protection is incidental to the protection of the former President; and (3) the widow or widower and each child of a former President for six months after the former President dies, or for any time remaining in the two-year period, if applicable. Permits the Secretary of the Treasury to reinstate the Secret Service protection of a former President for one year and of a spouse or minor child for six months after the original protection has been terminated upon finding that a threat warranting such protection exists. Authorizes additional extensions of such periods of protection if the Secretary has submitted a request for an extension to the Congress and 60 days of continuous session have expired after the date of such request. Authorizes the President to direct the Secret Service to protect a former President, or a spouse or child of a former President, if a threat warrants emergency action. Permits the Secretary to authorize Secret Service protection for a former Vice President for a period beginning on the last day of the individual's term and ending on the last day of the fiscal year in which the term expires, and upon finding that a threat exists which warrants such protection.</summary>
</bill>
