<bill session="100" type="s" number="164" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Institute of Mental Health Transfer Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer the National Institute of Mental Health to the National Institutes of Health.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB, GAO.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical research"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health planning"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Suicide"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
National Institute of Mental Health Transfer Act of 1987 - Amends the Public Health Service Act to transfer the National Institute of Mental Health (Institute) from the Alcohol, Drug Abuse, and Mental Health Administration to the National Institutes of Health. Sets forth the general purpose of the Institute. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services, through the Director of the Institute, to make grants for demonstration projects for the planning, coordination, and improvement of community services for chronically mentally ill individuals, seriously mentally disturbed children, and elderly individuals, and to conduct research concerning such services. Authorizes appropriations for such grants. Authorizes the Secretary, through the Director, to make grants to States for the purpose of developing State comprehensive mental health plans. Requires the Director to develop and publish information respecting the causes and means of preventing suicide. Allows the Secretary, through the Director, to make grants to and enter into agreements with public and nonprofit private entities for research on mental illness.</summary>
</bill>
