<bill session="100" type="s" number="1653" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Junk Bond Limitation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the amount of "junk" securities that can be held by federally insured institutions and to amend the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to provide that debt securities issued by shell corporations are subject to the margin restrictions regulations.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporate reorganizations"/>
    <term name="Corporations"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Junk bonds"/>
    <term name="National banks"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Savings banks"/>
    <term name="Securities"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Tender offers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
Junk Bond Limitation Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Deposit Insurance Act to prohibit an insured bank from investing in noninvestment grade securities the proceeds of which will be used to purchase or carry margin securities if such an investment would be prohibited for a similarly situated national bank. Prohibits an insured bank from investing in noninvestment grade securities if its primary capital is less than six percent of its total assets. Amends the National Housing Act to prohibit an insured institution from investing in noninvestment grade securities the proceeds of which will be used to purchase or carry margin securities if such an investment would be prohibited for a similarly situated Federal savings and loan association. Prohibits an insured institution from investing in noninvestment grade securities if its primary capital is less than six percent of its total assets. Amends the Securities Exchange Act of 1934 to apply the margin restrictions prescribed by the Federal Reserve Board to any lender that purchases any debt securities by a shell corporation the proceeds of which will be used to purchase or carry margin stock in the context of a tender offer or any acquisition of securities which would require the filing of a report under the Securities Exchange Act of 1934.</summary>
</bill>
