<bill session="100" type="s" number="1656" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">COCOM Compliance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to restrict foreign military sales and military assistance to certain countries which are not members of COCOM or which are not complying with export controls under COCOM.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300154"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
COCOM Compliance Act of 1987 - Prohibits the extension of foreign military sales credits and the furnishing of military assistance to any country which: (1) is not a member of the Coordinating Committee of countries that cooperate in restricting strategic exports to Communist countries (COCOM); and (2) in the previous fiscal year received an aggregate of more than $150,000,000 in such credits and assistance. Requires the President to annually determine and certify to the Congress: (1) which members of COCOM have not complied with the export controls agreed upon by the COCOM member countries; and (2) for each such country, the value in dollars of the estimated damage to the United States which was incurred as a result of such noncompliance. Limits the amount of foreign military sales credits and military assistance received by a country identified by such determination.</summary>
</bill>
