<bill session="100" type="s" number="1661" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the establishment of, and a credit for contributions to, education savings accounts but to provide that the earnings of such accounts will be taxable.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1987-08-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="College costs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax deferral"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual a 15 percent nonrefundable income tax credit for contributions made to a savings account established to pay the educational expenses (tuition, supplies, meals, and lodging) of an individual at an institution of higher education or a vocational school. Limits the credit to $150 per year per account. Adjusts this limit annually for inflation. Provides that no account may have more than one beneficiary and that no individual may be a beneficiary of more than one account. Disallows the credit for contributions to an account maintained for any individual who, during the relevant taxable year, either attains age 21 or begins attending an eligible educational institution. Identifies the criteria and requirements applicable to an education savings account. Permits the exclusion from the gross income of the taxpayer-contributor of payments and distributions from an education savings account as long as such amounts: (1) are used exclusively for the educational expenses of the eligible beneficiary; (2) are rolled over into another education savings account; or (3) are distributions of excess contributions before the due date of the tax return. Provides that for the ten tax years beginning when the beneficiary attains age 25, ten percent of the amount paid or distributed from an education savings account to pay the educational expenses of that individual shall be included in his or her gross income each year. Establishes a 15 percent tax on the investment income of an education savings account unless it ceases to be a proper education savings account because either the contributor-taxpayer engages in prohibited transactions or the account's beneficiary pledges the account as security. (In such cases, regular capital gains tax rates would apply.) Establishes penalties in the form of additional tax when account funds or distributions are used for other than educational purposes. Requires that the trustee of an education savings account report to the Secretary of the Treasury and to the account's beneficiary on the maintenance of the account. Establishes a six percent excise tax on excess contributions to an educational savings account. Provides that contributions to an education savings account shall not be subject to gift tax. Establishes a five percent excise tax on amounts connected with any prohibited transaction with respect to an education savings account. Establishes a penalty for failure to file required reports concerning the education savings account. Excludes from the gross income of an individual any distributions from an education savings account used exclusively for that individual's educational expenses (deferring taxation of these amounts until the beneficiary attains age 25).</summary>
</bill>
