<bill session="100" type="s" number="1664" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-08-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to extend authorizations of appropriations for programs under the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act and the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act of 1978, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300157"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-08-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-14">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR06" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Child abuse"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Family violence"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child welfare"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/7/1987--Introduced.
Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Amendments of 1987 - Title I: Amendments Concerning Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment - Amends the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment Act with respect to the National Center on Child Abuse and Neglect. Repeals a requirement that the Center's information clearinghouse include information on all child abuse prevention and treatment programs showing promise of success. Repeals a requirement that Center reports on coordination efforts of responsible agencies and organizations be given annually. Provides for the Secretary of Health and Human Services' discretionary grants and contracts for demonstration or service programs and projects. Includes activities addressing family violence related to child abuse. Requires that a specified minimum amount be available to States for certain programs for disabled infants with life-threatening conditions. Repeals a deadline connected with a requirement that services for such infants be in place. Adds the Commonwealth of the Northern Mariana Islands to the definition of State for purposes of demonstration or service programs or projects. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Reserves 55 percent of such funds for grants to States and 45 percent for specified activities of the Secretary and the National Center on Child Abuse and Neglect. Title II: Amendments to Related Programs - Amends title II of the Child Abuse Prevention and Treatment and Adoption Reform Act of 1978 to provide that such title (with its adoption opportunities program) may be cited as the Adoption Opportunities Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990 to carry out the adoption opportunities program. Repeals specified provisions of Federal law containing authority for Federal challenge grants to States to establish and maintain funding mechanisms to support child abuse and neglect prevention activities. Title III: Effective Date - Sets forth the effective date of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
