<bill session="100" type="s" number="1696" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Agricultural Nitrogen Education Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to minimize the impact of agricultural nitrogen on ground water and surface water quality by establishing a nationwide educational program aimed at American farmers, to urge the adoption of agricultural best management practices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-09-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural chemicals"/>
    <term name="Agricultural education"/>
    <term name="Agricultural pollution"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Farm management"/>
    <term name="Farmland protection"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/1987--Introduced.
Agricultural Nitrogen Education Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an Agricultural Nitrogen Best Management Practices Task Force to: (1) develop agricultural best management practices to minimize nitrogen losses from all potential agricultural sources and practices; (2) develop and disseminate to American farmers educational and training materials with respect to such practices; and (3) report to the Congress in two years on the progress of its efforts. Authorizes appropriations. Amends the Federal Water Pollution Control Act (Clean Water Act) to require that any State assessment report or management report be developed in consultation with the task force. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to consult with the task force in preparing annual reports and final reports to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
