<bill session="100" type="s" number="1700" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:24-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Assessment of Educational Progress Improvement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the provisions relating to the National Assessment of Educational Progress, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Educational accountability"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Educational statistics"/>
    <term name="Educational surveys"/>
    <term name="Educational tests"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/17/1987--Introduced.
National Assessment of Educational Progress Improvement Act - Amends the General Education Provisions Act (GEPA) to revise provisions relating to the National Assessment of Educational Progress (NAEP). Provides that the NAEP shall be carried out by grants, contracts, or cooperative agreements with a qualified organization or institution. Requires that NAEP data be collected and reported on a national, regional, and State basis at least every two years in the areas of reading, science, and mathematics, and at least every six years in the areas of writing, history, geography, and civics. Replaces a reference to the basic skill of communication with a reference to the basic skills of writing, science, history, geography, and civics, under provisions for technical assistance on the use of NAEP objectives. Replaces the Assessment Policy Committee with a National Assessment Governing Board authorized to design and supervise the conduct of the national assessment. Provides that the Board shall be considered an advisory committee for the purpose of the Federal Advisory Committee Act. Makes the Board independent of the Secretary of Education (the Secretary) and the other offices and officers of the Department of Education. Grants the Board final authority on the appropriateness of cognitive items. Requires that participation in assessments made on a State basis be on a voluntary basis. Directs the Secretary to enter into agreements with States which desire to carry out such assessments. Requires such States to participate in the assessment and to pay the non-Federal share of participation from non-Federal sources or from funds paid to the State under specified provisions of GEPA. Sets the Federal share at 80 percent. Permits the non-Federal share of such payments to be in cash or in kind. Directs the Secretary, within six months after the enactment of this Act, to publish a report setting forth plans for the collection of State representative data for the 1990 assessment. Requires such report to be submitted to the Congress and made available the public. Extends through FY 1993 the authorization of appropriations to carry out provisions relating to the Office of Educational Research and Improvement (including the NAEP) and the Center for Education Statistics. Increases the minimum amount reserved for purposes of the NAEP.</summary>
</bill>
