<bill session="100" type="s" number="1728" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-09-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aircraft Collision Avoidance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to require the installation and use of collision avoidance systems in aircraft, to require the Federal Aviation Administration to complete research on and development of the TCAS-III collision avoidance system as soon as possible, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411762"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-09-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Avionics"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/29/1987--Introduced.
Aircraft Collision Avoidance Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to complete development of the collision avoidance system known as TCAS-II so that it will be operable under visual and instrument flight rules and will be upgradable to the performance standards applicable to the collision avoidance system known as TCAS-III. Requires the Administrator to: (1) implement a development and certification schedule resulting within 18 months after the date of enactment of this Act in the completion of TCAS-II certification; (2) report monthly to the Congress on TCAS-II development and certification; (3) require that civil aircraft with a maximum passenger capacity of more than 30 seats have an operational TCAS-II within 30 months after the certification of such system; and (4) require that automatic pressure altitude-encoding equipment be operated on certain civil aircraft operating in a high traffic density area. Requires the Administrator to complete as soon as possible research, development, and certification of the TCAS-III collision avoidance system. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
