<bill session="100" type="s" number="1723" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Indian Regional Museum Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of certain regional exhibition facilities as part of the Museum of the American Indian, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-12-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 1722 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1722"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/25/1987--Introduced.
(Reported jointly to Sen. from the Sel. Comm. on Indian Affairs; and Rules &amp; Admin., amended, S.Rept.100-494) American Indian Regional Museum Act of 1987 - Authorizes the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution, at such time as the United States acquires the Museum of the American Indian, to establish as part of such Museum permanent regional exhibition facilities in various geographic regions of the United States. Directs that each facility provide exhibit space and serve as an educational center, highlighting the historic, artistic, and cultural achievements of the Indian people of the region. Requires each facility to sponsor and coordinate a variety of traveling representative exhibits to schools and local communities in each region. Directs the Board to appoint an Advisory Council within each region to work with the Institution to establish museum policy, to oversee museum curation and acquisitions, and to provide technical assistance for the regional facility. Grants preference to American Indians and Alaskan Natives for membership on such Councils. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
