<bill session="100" type="s" number="1722" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-13">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-04-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National American Indian Museum and Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">National American Indian Museum and Memorial Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the establishment of the National Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation within the Smithsonian Institution, and to establish a Memorial to the American Indian, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300159" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409456" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-09-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-25">
      <text>Read twice and referred jointly to the Committees on Rules; Indian Affairs by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-12">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-12">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-18">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-13" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-04-13">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs incorporated provisions of related measures S. 1723 in reported measure.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-19">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Jointly reported to Senate by Senator Inouye under the authority of the order of Aug 11, 88 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 100-494.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-25">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Jointly reported to Senate by Senator Inouye under the authority of the order of Aug 11, 88 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 100-494.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="916">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 916.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1723"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaskan natives"/>
    <term name="Anthropology"/>
    <term name="Archaeology"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Cultural centers"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Ethnology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Foundations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Religion"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
    <term name="Social life and customs"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3739"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/25/1987--Introduced.
National American Indian Museum and Memorial Act - Title I: Establishes within the Smithsonian Institution a memorial to the American Indian people to be known as the National Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation, to provide for the study, research, collection, and exhibition of aboriginal Americans and their culture. Designates a specified area in the District of Columbia as the site of the Museum. Authorizes the Smithsonian to accept the transfer of all assets of the Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation, in New York City. Provides for the construction of a building for the Museum at the District of Columbia site, a Museum Support Center in Suitland, Maryland, and a permanent exhibition facility in New York City. Provides that the Heye Foundation's collection will not be merged with the Smithsonian's collection. Provides that the proceeds from the sale of property acquired through the transfer of the Foundation's assets will be maintained for the exclusive benefit of the Museum. Establishes the Trustees of the National Museum of the American Indian, Heye Foundation, to assist the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian on matters relating to the Museum. Grants the Trustees sole authority to: (1) dispose of and acquire additional Museum property; and (2) determine the policy for displaying artifacts. Requires the Trustees to submit annual reports to the Board of Regents and the Congress. Requires the Foundation's employees serving at the time of the transfer to be offered employment by the Smithsonian. Pledges that the United States will provide the funds needed to maintain and operate the Museum. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Establishes a memorial within the Museum to commemorate the contributions of Indians and Alaska Natives to the United States and to house certain skeletal remains. Expresses the intent of the Congress that the memorial and Museum be completed within five years of the enactment of this Act. Requires the Secretary of the Smithsonian to determine the tribal origin of all skeletal remains of Indians and Alaska Natives under the control of the Smithsonian. Requires the Secretary to inter in the memorial all skeletal remains of Indians and Alaska Natives covered by a written statement to the Congress certifying that such remains: (1) have not been identified as being associated with a specific Indian tribe or group of Alaska Natives; or (2) have been identified as being associated with a specific Indian tribe or group of Alaska Natives which requests the interment of such remains in the memorial; and (3) are not likely to be the subject of any Indian claim or dispute. Requires the Museum to establish a Board of Design for the memorial, the majority of whose members shall be of American Indian or Alaska Native ancestry. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
