<bill session="100" type="s" number="1727" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:25-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-09-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">National Deafness and Other Communications Disorders Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">National Deafness and Other Communications Disorders Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to establish within the National Institutes of Health a National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1988-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1988-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-03-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-05-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-12-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1988-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-12-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1988-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1988-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-09-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Senate Committee on Labor and Human Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-13" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-28" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-553" type="public" datetime="1988-10-28">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-553.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3361"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3361"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Continuing education"/>
    <term name="Deafness"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hearing"/>
    <term name="Hearing disorders"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="National Institutes of Health (NIH)"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Peer review organizations (Medicine)"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Speech disorders"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3626"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/7/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) National Deafness and Other Communications Disorders Act of 1988 - Amends title IV (National Research Institutes) of the Public Health Service Act to establish the National Institute on Deafness and Other Communication Disorders (Institute) as an agency of the National Institutes of Health (NIH). Removes communicative disorders from the title and purpose of the National Institute of Neurological and Communicative Disorders and Stroke. Requires the Director of the Institute, with the advice of the Institute's advisory council, to establish a National Deafness and Other Communications Disorders Program (Program). Requires the Director to prepare and transmit to the Director of NIH a plan to initiate, expand, intensify, and coordinate activities of the Institute respecting disorders of hearing, balance, voice, speech, language, taste, and smell. Describes the minimum activities of the Program. Requires the Director to establish a National Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Data System for the collection, storage, analysis, retrieval, and dissemination of data and a National Deafness and Other Communication Disorders Information Clearinghouse. Requires the Director, after consultation with the advisory council, to provide for the development, modernization, and operation of new and existing centers for studies of disorders of hearing and other communication processes. Sets forth requirements for the centers, including conducting research and training programs and information and continuing education programs for health professionals, and public information programs. Authorizes centers to provide stipends for health professionals in their training programs. Describes other programs the centers may undertake. Requires the Director to provide for an equitable geographical distribution of centers and to give appropriate consideration to the need for centers for the elderly and for children. Limits support of a center to seven years, with one or more additional periods of not more than five years, if recommended by a peer review group established by the Director, with the advice of the advisory council. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish in the Institute the National Deafness and Other Communications Disorders Advisory Board to review, evaluate, update, and give advice regarding the Institute's activities plan. Sets forth reporting requirements. Requires the Advisory Board to be established not later than 90 days after enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to establish the Deafness and Other Communications Disorders Interagency Coordinating Committee to coordinate, with respect to deafness and other communication disorders, the activities of the national research institutes and all Federal health programs. Sets forth transitional and savings provisions.</summary>
</bill>
