<bill session="100" type="s" number="1740" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Chronically Ill and Disabled Children Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to permit States the option of providing comprehensive medical assistance to chronically ill and disabled children with a family income meeting a particular income standard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1987--Introduced.
Medicaid Chronically Ill and Disabled Children Amendments of 1987 - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to authorize States to make medical assistance available to chronically ill or disabled children under the age of 18 with family incomes below specified percentages of the poverty line and meeting other requirements. Sets forth requirements regarding: (1) the determination and redetermination of eligibility; (2) the imposition of premiums, deductions, cost sharing, or other charges; (3) the development of a written health care management plan for each individual; (4) the provision of comprehensive health care case management services; (5) assistance for part or all of the cost of home or community-based services; and (6) the application of resource and income standards and the method of determining family income.</summary>
</bill>
