<bill session="100" type="s" number="1749" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">a bill to authorize the Smithsonian Institution to provide for additional facilities for the Cooper-Hewitt Museum, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2815"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2815"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to museums"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Smithsonian Institution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/2/1987--Introduced.
Directs the Board of Regents of the Smithsonian Institution to construct, expand, and renovate facilities at the Cooper-Hewitt Museum in New York, New York, in accordance with the master plan for such project. Limits the total cost of the project (taking into account funding from all sources). Authorizes appropriations to the Board for FY 1989 and subsequent fiscal years in an amount equal to one-half the total cost of the project. Prohibits any such appropriations from being used for any purpose until the Comptroller General determines that an amount equal to one-half of the total cost of the project is available to the Board from non-Federal sources. Provides for transfer of any portion of such funds to the General Services Administration to carry out such project. Provides that the Cooper-Hewitt Museum shall also be known as the National Museum of Design.</summary>
</bill>
