<bill session="100" type="s" number="1763" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">An Act to Reduce Fires Caused by Cigarettes</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to promulgate fire safety standards for cigarettes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1988-03-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1987--Introduced.
An Act to Reduce Fires Caused by Cigarettes - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue by rule a fire safety standard for cigarettes. Prohibits stockpiling of cigarettes between the issuing and effective dates of the standard. Provides for judicial review of the rule. Prohibits the manufacturing or importing of a cigarette unless the cigarette is in compliance with a standard issued under provisions of this Act. Declares violation of the prohibition to be a violation of provisions of the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. States that this Act does not preempt any law of a State which prescribes a more stringent fire safety standard for cigarettes. Prohibits, in any civil action for damages, admitting compliance with the standard as a defense.</summary>
</bill>
