<bill session="100" type="s" number="1765" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nursing Manpower Shortage Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide payment for direct graduate medical costs related to nurse clinical training, to establish demonstration projects to provide payment on a prepaid capitated basis for community nursing and ambulatory care furnished to medicare beneficiaries, to amend titles XVIII and XIX of such Act to provide coverage for certain nursing services, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407786"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Coinsurance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Intermediate care facilities"/>
    <term name="Kidney diseases"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Midwives"/>
    <term name="Nurse practitioners"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/7/1987--Introduced.
Nursing Manpower Shortage Act of 1987 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide for payment of the reasonable costs of hospitals for approved postgraduate nurse clinical training programs. Sets forth formulae for determining the amount to be paid and related amounts. Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with no fewer than seven eligible organizations to conduct three-year demonstration projects to provide payment on a prepaid, capitated basis for community nursing and ambulatory care furnished to any individual, other than individuals with end-stage renal disease, entitled to benefits under part A (Hospital Insurance) and enrolled under part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of Medicare. Directs the Secretary to determine, for each 12-month period in which a demonstration project is conducted, a per capita payment rate for each class of qualified individuals, according to a specified formula. Directs the Secretary to develop alternate capitation-based reimbursement rates to be applied in determining per capita rates for at least one eligible organization conducting a project. Requires payments relating to the demonstration projects to be made from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund. Restricts the premium rate and the actuarial value of deductibles, coinsurance, and copayments charged in connection with the demonstration projects. Requires that coverage for additional services, if any, be optional for the members of the eligible organization. Restricts the premium rate and the actuarial value of the deductibles, coinsurance, and copayments charged for additional services. Directs the Secretary to contract with a private, nonprofit entity to assist in designing, implementing, and evaluating the projects. Amends title XVIII and title XIX (Medicaid) to authorize, in addition to physicians, a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist working in collaboration with a physician to: (1) certify or recertify certain services under the Medicare or Medicaid programs; and (2) fulfill, for skilled nursing facilities, requirements regarding the supervision of the health care of every patient and the provision of emergency medical care. Amends the definition of "medical and other health services" under Medicare to include institutional nursing services. Defines "qualified institutional nursing services" for Medicare to include items and services furnished by a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist in a skilled nursing facility. Authorizes payments under Medicare from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund for qualified institutional nursing services in the amount of 80 percent of the reasonable charge. Includes qualified institutional nursing services in the definition of "medical assistance" under the Medicaid program. Defines "qualified institutional nursing services" for Medicaid purposes to include items and services furnished by a nurse practitioner or clinical nurse specialist in a skilled nursing facility, including an intermediate care facility. Amends the definition of "medical and other health services" under Medicare to include certified nurse-midwife services and certified pediatric nurse practitioner services. Authorizes payments under Medicare from the Federal Supplementary Medical Insurance Trust Fund for certified nurse-midwife services and certified pediatric nurse practitioner services. Directs the Secretary to contract with a private, nonprofit entity to study: (1) the effect on the supply of nurses in hospitals and nursing homes of the current reimbursement system under Medicare and regulations issued under Medicare and Medicaid; and (2) the case mix of patients for whom nurses provide services as compared to the case mix of patients at the same site for whom physicians provide the same services. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes payments for the contract from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
