<bill session="100" type="s" number="1772" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">White House Conference on International Trade in Services Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a White House Conference on International Trade in Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International trade"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="White House conferences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/1987--Introduced.
White House Conference on International Trade in Services Act - Directs the President to conduct a White House Conference on International Trade in Services to provide for an aggregation of effort by academics, professionals, government, and congressional representatives for the purpose of assisting the United States Trade Representative and the Secretary of the Treasury in formulating U.S. priorities for international negotiations on trade in services. Requires the Conference to provide for an exchange of information and views on specified topics related to international trade in services. Requires the President to select participants for the Conference from the private sector of the economy, trade associations, the Congress, Federal agencies, advisory bodies, commissions, and congressionally chartered private organizations with a mandate to study services trade negotiations. Requires the Conference to submit a final report to the President which shall include a review of international negotiations on trade in services, the negotiating positions of the United States and other countries, and recommendations for improving the U.S. position in such negotiations. Sets forth administrative provisions with respect to the functioning of the Conference. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989.</summary>
</bill>
