<bill session="100" type="s" number="1779" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Jimmy Carter National Historic Site and Preservation District in the State of Georgia, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404277"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408252" joined="1987-10-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Ex-presidents"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Georgia"/>
    <term name="Historians"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="History"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/9/1987--Introduced.
Establishes the Jimmy Carter National Historic Site in Plains, Georgia. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to acquire lands as specified. Establishes the Jimmy Carter National Preservation District, which includes the historic site and other specified lands. Authorizes the Secretary to assist in the interpretation of properties within such district. Requires the Secretary to administer the historic site and preservation district. Requires the Secretary to convene historians 25 years after enactment of this Act to examine the life of President Carter and to make recommendations on the interpretations and preservation of the areas. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory commission to advise on the interpretation of the site. Requires the Secretary to develop and submit to the Congress within three years a general management plan. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the State of Georgia and the town of Plains for specified purposes. Authorizes appropriations. Limits the use of appropriated funds for restoring Plains High School.</summary>
</bill>
