<bill session="100" type="s" number="1778" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Educational Opportunities Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for a rural educational opportunities program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-10-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-10-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Department of Education, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Regional educational laboratories"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural schools"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/8/1987--Introduced.
Rural Educational Opportunities Act - Establishes a rural educational opportunities program. Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to, or enter into contracts with, institutions of higher education or public or private nonprofit agencies (including regional educational laboratories), or combinations of such institutions or agencies to pay all or part of the cost of establishing and operating ten regional rural assistance centers. Requires each such center to provide technical assistance, consultation, training, and other assistance to State and local educational agencies in the region to improve the quality of education to educationally disadvantaged children participating in chapter 1 programs (under the Education Consolidation and Improvement Act of 1981) who reside in rural areas or attend small schools. Directs the Secretary to give priority to certain applications in carrying out this Act. Sets forth center coordination and dissemination requirements. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1993.</summary>
</bill>
