<bill session="100" type="s" number="1787" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Agent Orange Disabilities Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to prescribe certain presumptions in the case of veterans who performed active service during the Vietnam era.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-17">
      <text>Committee on Veterans requested executive comment from VA, OMB, Defense Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Veterans received executive comment from VA.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3486"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3486"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Agent Orange"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Dioxins"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Lung cancer"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/1987--Introduced.
Veterans' Agent Orange Disabilities Act of 1987 - Creates a non-rebuttable presumption that, for the purposes of wartime disability compensation for Vietnam veterans, the following diseases shall be considered to have been incurred in, or aggravated by, active military, naval, or air service in Vietnam during the Vietnam era: (1) non-Hodgkin's lymphoma; (2) lung cancer becoming manifest within 25 years of service; and (3) a disease that, in accordance with this Act, is determined to be reasonably associated with damage to or suppression of the immune system resulting from exposure to dioxin or any other toxic herbicide used in Vietnam and that is listed in regulations prescribed by the Administrator of Veterans Affairs. Requires the Administrator to enter into an agreement with an appropriate nonprofit private scientific organization to: (1) conduct a survey of all scientific studies of the effects of dioxin and other toxic herbicides used by the United States in Vietnam on humans or animals; and (2) determine what (if any) diseases are reasonably associated with damage to or suppression of the human immune system as a result of exposure to such herbicides. Designates the National Academy of Sciences (NAS) as the appropriate nonprofit organization, unless: (1) the NAS does not enter into such an agreement with the Administrator; (2) the Administrator has notified the veterans' committees of an alternative organization; and (3) 90 days have elapsed since such notification. Requires that the scientific organization report to the Administrator and the veterans' committees on the name of each disease determined to be reasonably associated with human immune system damage or suppression within one year after enactment of this Act. Directs the Administrator to prescribe regulations listing each such disease within 90 days of receipt of such report, unless a disease is specifically excluded by law. Directs the Administrator to periodically (but not less than annually) survey additional completed studies to determine whether any diseases should be added to the list. Requires that the Administrator: (1) compile and analyze, on a continuing basis, all clinical data obtained by the VA in connection with physical examinations and treatment furnished after November 3, 1981, to veterans who were exposed to dioxin or any other such toxic substance; and (2) submit to the Senate and House of Representatives' Committees on Veterans' Affairs a semiannual report containing such compilation and analysis, along with a discussion of the disabilities identified or treated by the VA, the Administrator's explanation for the incidence of such disabilities, and other reasonable explanations for the incidence of such disabilities.</summary>
</bill>
