<bill session="100" type="s" number="1794" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Advanced Superconducting Transportation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish, within the Department of Transportation, the High-Speed Ground Transportation Office; to develop the technology for a magnetically levitated superconducting transportation system; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-11-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Highspeed ground transportation"/>
    <term name="Magnetic levitation vehicles"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Superconductivity"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Transportation research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/1987--Introduced.
Federal Advanced Superconducting Transportation Act - Expresses the intent of the Congress that the development of a magnetic levitating superconducting technology for the purpose of constructing a national super high-speed transportation system in certain geographical corridors shall be implemented through a specified four-phase approach. Establishes within the Department of Transportation the High-Speed Ground Transportation Office (to be headed by a Director), whose functions shall be to establish uniform standards and regulate the design and construction for such technology, as well as recommend funding mechanisms. Mandates that such Office conduct a prescribed feasibility study regarding such high-speed transportation system. Authorizes appropriations to the National Aeronautics and Space Administration and to the High-Speed Ground Transportation Office to implement this Act.</summary>
</bill>
