<bill session="100" type="s" number="1808" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:26-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Reclassification of Transitional Devices Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Classification of Transitional Devices Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to determine the appropriate regulatory classification of the transitional devices of the Medical Device Amendments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-10-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-12-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-10">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Department of Health and Human Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-588.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-06" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1119">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1119.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Drug safety and regulation"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Optical instruments and optical trade"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Labor and Human Resources with amendment, S. Rept. 100-588) Classification of Transitional Devices Amendments Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to publish a notice in the Federal Register stating whether each transitional medical device shall remain in class III (devices requiring premarket approval) or be reclassified into class I (devices requiring general controls) or class II (devices requiring performance standards). Requires the manufacturers of devices that are to be classified in class I or II to submit to the Secretary any adverse safety and effectiveness information not previously reported. Requires the Secretary, within one year after enactment of this Act, to promulgate a regulation classifying each such device as class I or II, or providing that each such device shall remain in class III. Authorizes the Secretary to extend the one year period for classification for any such device for a period not to exceed one year. Prohibits the Secretary from retaining any nonhydrophilic plastic contact lens in class III unless such lens: (1) is used in supporting human life or preventing impairment of human health; or (2) presents an unreasonable risk of illness or injury.</summary>
</bill>
