<bill session="100" type="s" number="1813" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Safe Food Standards Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce foodborne disease, to improve the inspection of meat, poultry, and fish, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Feed contamination"/>
    <term name="Fish inspection"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Food adulteration and inspection"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food contamination"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Meat inspection"/>
    <term name="Meat packing industry"/>
    <term name="Poultry inspection"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Seafood"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/1987--Introduced.
Safe Food Standards Act of 1987 - Title I: Testing and Inspection of Certain Products - Amends the Federal Meat Inspection Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to administer a program to detect contamination in statistically selected samples of meat and meat food products that have already passed inspection. Requires the Secretary to monitor a slaughtering house during a review period whenever a sample from such house is found to contain a pathogenic microorganism in excess of the established standards. Directs the Secretary to publish the identity of, issue a warning to, and exact fines from an establishment exceeding standards during the review period. Withholds inspection services from establishments failing to pay assessed fines or persistently exceeding standards during the monitoring period. Provides for administrative and judicial review of decisions not to provide inspection services. Requires the Secretary to develop sampling procedures, baselines of contamination by pathogenic microorganisms harmful to humans, and procedures to identify the sources of slaughtered cattle, sheep, and swine. Permits exemptions to the identification requirement under specified circumstances. Amends the Poultry Products Inspection Act to direct the Secretary to administer a similar program for poultry products. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to establish a similar program for seafood. Provides waivers for seafood monitored by established alternative methods and when water quality monitoring is taken into account. Authorizes the Secretary to establish a water quality monitoring program. Prohibits monitored establishments from participating in the voluntary seafood inspection program established under the Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish and administer a similar program to test statistically selected samples of animal feed intended for poultry, sheep, cattle, or swine to be slaughtered, including contamination by toxic chemicals as well as pathogenic microorganisms. Excludes persistent violators from participation in the voluntary animal feed inspection program. Title II: Miscellaneous - Provides for consumer education about food safety through various channels, including a toll-free food safety hotline, cooperative agricultural extension services, and demonstration project grants to States. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to establish an animal feed improvements program, including maintaining a toll-free hotline. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY 1988 through 1992. Directs the Secretary to establish a research program to develop methods to reduce foodborne illnesses in the United States. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1989. Directs the Secretary to conduct pilot studies on the effectiveness of labeling fresh meats and poultry with handling and cooking instructions. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1989. Requires the Secretary to report to the appropriate congressional committees on such studies. Authorizes civil actions by persons aggrieved by the Secretary's failure to enforce the Federal Meat Inspection Act or the Poultry Products Inspection Act. Prohibits discrimination against whistle-blowers.</summary>
</bill>
