<bill session="100" type="s" number="1814" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">NTL-5 Gas Royalty Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide clarification regarding the royalty payments owed under certain Federal Onshore and Indian oil and gas leases, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-11-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1987-11-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-10-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-29">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Department of the Interior, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Interior Department. Favorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-02">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered favorably reported H.R. 3479 in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG05" subcommittee="Mineral Resources Development and Production" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3479"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/23/1987--Introduced.
NTL-5 Gas Royalty Act of 1987 - Sets forth a royalty calculation for certain Federal onshore oil and gas leases and for certain Indian leases (for the period from January 1, 1982, through July 31, 1986), under which the value of gas production shall be determined in accordance with specified lease terms and Federal regulations in effect at the time of production. Prescribes guidelines for the refund of previously paid royalties. Applies this Act only to leases for which documentation shows that the lessee or royalty payor received less than the highest applicable price under the Natural Gas Policy Act as a result of market conditions or considerations. Requires the Secretary of the Interior to notify the affected lessees and royalty payors of the provisions of this Act and to publish such notification in the Federal Register. Sets forth procedures for case-by-case audits of such leases by the Secretary to determine the amount of refunds due and payable under this Act. Mandates that the Secretary report to each Indian tribe holding specified Indian oil or gas leases regarding the difference between royalties computed under a certain Notice (NTL-5) and royalties computed in accordance with this Act. Requires lessees and payors to maintain records related to the value of gas production to which this Act applies for the period January 1, 1982, through July 31, 1986.</summary>
</bill>
