<bill session="100" type="s" number="1824" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airport Capacity Levels Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to require that capacity levels be established at certain airports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/27/1987--Introduced.
Airport Capacity Levels Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to require the Secretary of Transportation to establish a list of airport capacity levels for takeoffs and landings at each airport at which 5,000,000 passengers or more are annually enplaned. Requires such list to be published in the Federal Register. Authorizes the Secretary to modify such levels as needed. Requires the Secretary to monitor takeoffs and landings at each airport for which a capacity level is established to ensure that it is not exceeded. Authorizes the Secretary to take enforcement action to ensure compliance with such capacity levels. Prohibits the Secretary from allowing air carriers to buy and sell operating rights at any airport where such rights were impermissible prior to August 1, 1987. Requires the Secretary to report biannually to the Congress regarding implementation of this Act. Repeals this Act upon the expiration of the ten-year period following its date of enactment. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress regarding the administration of this Act, together with recommendations for extension, before the expiration of the nine-year period following the date of its enactment.</summary>
</bill>
