<bill session="100" type="s" number="1837" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Election Fraud Prevention Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to strengthen the enforcement of laws against fraud, corruption, and other illegal acts in connection with Federal, State, and local elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="Radio"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Telegraph"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/1987--Introduced.
Election Fraud Prevention Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal criminal code to increase penalties for mail fraud and for fraud involving wire, radio, or television. Provides that such fraud includes any scheme to violate Federal or State election laws. Increases the penalties for vote buying and vote selling and for intimidating or interfering with voters in Federal elections and in State and local elections involving offices that receive Federal benefits in excess of $1,000 in any year. Declares that this Act does not prohibit or make unlawful any Act by any officer or employee of a Federal, State, or local agency to enforce State or Federal election laws, including any protective measures requested by a candidate to prevent violations of election laws at or near polling places. Increases the penalties for fraud, including election fraud, involving interstate or foreign commerce. Increases the penalties for promising employment or other benefit for any political activity.</summary>
</bill>
