<bill session="100" type="s" number="1839" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Adult Day Health Care Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide for coverage of adult day health care under the medicare program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1988-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-11-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-03-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-06-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Day care centers for the aged"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mentally handicapped"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/1987--Introduced.
Medicare Adult Day Health Care Amendments of 1987 - Amends part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide for the establishment of adult day health care programs providing certain medically supervised health services furnished by an adult day health care center in an ambulatory group care setting on a less than 24-hour basis to individuals who are 18 years of age or older and: (1) have a medical or mental impairment that, but for the provision of adult day health care, would require the provision of care in a hospital or in a skilled or intermediate care facility; or (2) cannot perform on a daily basis certain activities of daily living. Sets forth standards for such a center. Sets forth matters which, as a condition of payment, must be certified by an existing State program which determines eligibility under title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act or by a State-administered preadmission screening program meeting certain minimum requirements. Makes deductibles inapplicable to adult day health care, requiring only the payment of a specified coinsurance amount. Provides for the evaluation of plans of correction submitted by centers found not to meet the conditions of participation and for sanctions against such centers, in lieu of cancellation of certification, including civil fines and suspensions of payments. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue regulations regarding adult day health care programs. Requires the Secretary to adopt the standards established by the National Institute of Adult Day Care as the minimum standards for qualifying as a provider of such care.</summary>
</bill>
