<bill session="100" type="s" number="1838" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Colonia Water and Sewage Service Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide grants and loans to enable areas near the international border separating the United States from Mexico to develop plans for the construction and improvement of, and to construct and improve, water and waste disposal facilities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3524"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="3524"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Southwest (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/3/1987--Introduced.
Colonia Water and Sewage Service Act - Amends the Consolidated Farm and Rural Development Act to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants to public bodies and private nonprofit organizations for the installation or improvement of the operation or maintenance of facilities (and necessary related equipment) for the storage, treatment, purification, or distribution of water, and the collection, treatment, or disposal of waste, in rural areas in the United States within 30 miles of the Mexican border. Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to direct the Secretary of Housing to make loans, grants, and combined loans and grants to eligible very-low income families or persons (including the nonelderly) in rural areas in the United States within 30 miles of the Mexican border for the cost of repairs, improvements, and additions to provide sanitary waste facilities and convenient and sanitary water supplies. Authorizes appropriations for such purposes.</summary>
</bill>
