<bill session="100" type="s" number="1833" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Nursing Practice and Patient Care Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make grants from amounts appropriated from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under title XVIII of the Social Security Act to test the cost-effectiveness of innovative nursing practice models under the medicare program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-11-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-03-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-03-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Cost effectiveness"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/30/1987--Introduced.
Medicare Nursing Practice and Patient Care Improvement Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into contracts with hospitals and nursing homes which provide services to individuals eligible to receive benefits under title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to provide grants for demonstrating and evaluating the cost-effectiveness of innovative nursing practice models. Requires such models to include: (1) the integration of case management and patient care; (2) the testing of innovative payment structures for nurses; and (3) the improvement of work schedules and other benefits for nurses. Authorizes appropriations from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for FY 1989 through 1991. Sets forth information and reporting requirements.</summary>
</bill>
