<bill session="100" type="s" number="1848" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Minority Business Development Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize a Minority Business Development Administration in the Department of Commerce.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-12-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-11-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-03">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-615.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business education"/>
    <term name="Capital formation"/>
    <term name="Corporate finance"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Joint ventures"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Securities regulation"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/4/1987--Introduced.
Minority Business Development Act of 1987 - Redesignates the Minority Business Development Agency in the Department of Commerce as the Minority Business Development Administration. Requires the President to appoint an Administrator to head the Administration. Requires the Secretary of Commerce to report to the Congress on the organizational structure within the Administration and its organizational position in the Department of Commerce. Title I: Market Development - Empowers the Administration to: (1) assist disadvantaged businesses in penetrating domestic and foreign markets by making available to such businesses management and technological assistance, a skilled labor pool, and financial and marketing services; and (2) encourage disadvantaged firms to establish joint ventures and projects to increase their share of the market. Authorizes the Administration to provide financial assistance to public and private sector organizations to carry out this Act. Requires the Administration to consult with State and local governments for the purpose of leveraging local resources, and recommending local administrative and legislative initiatives, to promote the position of disadvantaged businesses. Authorizes the Administration to provide financial assistance to States and cities and to allocate such assistance on the basis of relative populations of disadvantaged individuals, numbers of disadvantaged businesses, and unemployment rates of disadvantaged individuals. Requires the Administration, at least 120 days before the beginning of each fiscal year, to publish in the Federal Register the actual or anticipated amount of financial assistance that will or may be available in the immediately succeeding fiscal year. Requires the Administrator, at least 60 days before the beginning of each fiscal year, to publish its response to comments received and any change in the allocation methodology. Title II: Capital Formation - Authorizes the Administration to defray all or part of the costs of pilot projects which are conducted by public or private organizations and designed to assist disadvantaged businesses in obtaining equity capital. Requires the Securities and Exchange Commission to cooperate with the Administration to promote access to securities markets for disadvantaged businesses. Establishes within the Treasury a revolving fund to be available to the Administration to provide financial assistance to qualified disadvantaged businesses through the purchase of equity investments in such businesses. Permits the Administration to provide such assistance to qualified businesses only after determining that: (1) such assistance is unavailable on reasonable terms from other sources; (2) the assistance will permit a concern to operate profitably in a reasonable period of time; (3) the proceeds will be used in a reasonable period of time for plant construction, to finance the acquisition of equipment, or to supply working capital; (4) the terms under which the assistance is provided will not be breached by the business; and (5) salaries paid by the business are reasonable. Limits the amount of equity investments that may be purchased by the Administration and be outstanding at any one time. Title III: Management Educational Development - Requires the Administration to: (1) encourage universities, business leaders, and other public and private entities, to offer scholarships, sponsor seminars, and provide internships for the benefit of disadvantaged individuals; and (2) accelerate curriculum design in support of disadvantaged business development. Title IV: Research and Information - Requires the Administration to submit to the Congress a report describing the resources needed to advance and represent disadvantaged businesses in all levels of the economic system in numbers that would have existed were it not for past discrimination. Authorizes the Administration to: (1) provide financial assistance to public and private organizations to assist the Administration in collecting data on the causes for success and failure of disadvantaged businesses and in conducting research on how economic conditions affect the development of such businesses; (2) develop and maintain a data bank on disadvantaged businesses; and (3) establish an information clearinghouse for data pertinent to disadvantaged business. Title V: Administrative and Miscellaneous Powers of the Administration - Sets forth the administrative powers of the Administration. Permits the Administrator, the Inspector General of the Department of Commerce, and the Comptroller General to examine records of each recipient of assistance. Requires the Comptroller General to review and report to the Congress on programs authorized by this Act not later than July 1, 1988. Requires the Administrator to submit an annual report on the Administration's activities to the President and specified congressional committees. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
