<bill session="100" type="s" number="1862" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to provide for an immunosuppresive drug therapy block grant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-11-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404444" joined="1987-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-11-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-11-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-04">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Drug safety and regulation"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Immunosuppressive drugs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/12/1987--Introduced.
Amends title XIX (Block Grants) of the Public Health Service Act to establish an Immunosuppressive Drug Therapy Block Grant program to provide drugs to patients for the prevention of rejection of transplanted organs and tissues. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Provides formulae for the allotment of appropriated funds to the States. Establishes a minimum allotment of $50,000 for each State. Authorizes, in the event a State does not submit an allotment application or notifies the Secretary of Health and Human Services that it does not intend to use the full amount of the allotment, an organ transplant center in the State to apply for the amount of the allotment not allocated to the State. Enumerates the purposes for which the States may use such allotments. Details the application procedures and grant requirements. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress on the impact of this Act. Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to authorize States to provide immunosuppressive drugs to individuals who have received organ transplants.</summary>
</bill>
