<bill session="100" type="s" number="1870" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-29">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the use and distribution of funds awarded the Wisconsin Band of Potawatomi in docket 28 of the United States Claims Court.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408937"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Wisconsin"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1987--Introduced.
Allocates funds appropriated in satisfaction of a specified judgment awarded to the Wisconsin Band of Potawatomi Indians to the Hannahville Indian Community and the Forest County Potawatomi. Declares such funds to be held in trust by the United States. Requires such funds to be invested by the Secretary of the Interior for the benefit of such Indian tribe. Makes such funds available to the governing body of the tribe, on a budgetary basis and subject to the approval of the Secretary of the Interior, for tribal, social, and economic development programs for the tribe. Exempts such trust funds, and funds made available under this Act for programs or for distributions under any programs, from Federal, State, or local income taxes. Precludes such funds (or their availability) from being considered as income or resources, or otherwise utilized as the basis for denying or reducing the financial assistance or other benefits to which any household or individual would otherwise be entitled under the Social Security Act or, except for per capita payments in excess of $2,000, any other Federal or federally assisted program.</summary>
</bill>
