<bill session="100" type="s" number="1871" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pediatric Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS) Resource Centers Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants for the establishment of pediatric acquired immunodeficiency resource centers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-04">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="AIDS (Disease)"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Communicable diseases"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to child health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/17/1987--Introduced.
Pediatric Acquired Immunodeficiency Syndrome (AIDS) Resource Centers Act of 1987 - Amends part B (Federal-State Cooperation) of title III (General Powers and Duties of Public Health Service) of the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to hospitals to support the development and establishment in hospitals of pediatric acquired immunodeficiency syndrome resource centers. Requires the centers to: (1) provide care and treatment for children infected with the human immunodeficiency virus and who have contracted the syndrome; and (2) conduct research relating to the provision of such care and treatment. Provides for priorities in making grants and states authorized uses for grant funds. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
