<bill session="100" type="s" number="1882" updated="2016-06-29T08:46:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-19">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-11-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Product Safety Commission Authorization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Consumer Product Safety Commission Authorization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the Consumer Product Safety Commission, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404679"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-11-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1988-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-11-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-11-19" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings with amendments. With written report No. 100-273.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-12-21" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="517">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 517.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Accident prevention"/>
    <term name="Accidents"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="All terrain vehicles"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Cellulose"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child safety"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Consumer Product Safety Commission"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Independent regulatory commissions"/>
    <term name="Indoor air pollution"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Recreation and Recreational Facilities"/>
    <term name="Recreational vehicles"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Swimming pools"/>
    <term name="Thermal insulation"/>
    <term name="Toys"/>
    <term name="Wounds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/1987--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation with amendment, S. Rept. 100-273) Consumer Product Safety Commission Authorization Act of 1987 - Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act to require the President, when making appointments to the Consumer Product Safety Commission, to consider individuals with consumer product safety backgrounds. States that, at any time during FY 1988 through 1990 when there are two vacancies on the Commission, two Commission members shall constitute a quorum. Lists additional Commission personnel which must be appointed by the Commission Chairman with the approval of the Commission. Requires Commission approval for the removal of such personnel. Requires the Commission to establish an agenda and priorities for Commission actions at least 30 days before the beginning of each fiscal year. Amends the Consumer Product Safety Act, the Federal Hazardous Substances Act, and the Flammable Fabrics Act to permit any "interested party" to petition the Commission for review of any voluntary safety standard based upon a showing that: (1) the voluntary standard is inadequate to address a risk of injury associated with the product, substance, or material; or (2) the development of the voluntary standard is not proceeding in a timely manner. Makes certain procedural changes with respect to Commission reliance upon voluntary consumer product safety standards. Requires the Commission to issue proposed consumer product safety rules within 12 months after the publication of the advance notice of proposed rulemaking (unless the Commission determines that the proposed rule is not likely to eliminate or reduce the risk associated with the product). Directs the Commission to devise procedures to monitor compliance with any voluntary standards. Permits the disclosure of Commission-held information to Commission contractors. Repeals the Cellulose Insulation Safety Standards. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Repeals the safety standard for swimming pool slides issued by the Commission. Directs the Commission to enter into discussions with distributors of all-terrain vehicles (ATVs) regarding corrective actions to reduce the risk of injury and death associated with ATVs. Directs the Commission, if an agreement is reached within 60 days after the enactment of this Act, to file an action in U.S. district court, together with the proposed agreement in settlement of the action. Requires the court to file an "imminent hazards" action in such court if agreement is not reached within such time. Directs the Commission to promulgate a final rule regarding ATVs within one year after enactment of this Act, addressing: (1) uniform user controls; (2) education and training of users; (3) warning labels; and (4) performance requirements. Requires the Commission to review its activities (to determine whether additional action or requirements are necessary) regarding: (1) indoor air pollutants; (2) sleepwear flammability; and (3) the sale of articles which present a choking, aspiration, or ingestion hazard to children. Directs the Commission to report the results of each review to the Congress. Directs the Commission to revoke the current exemption which permits the sale of lawn darts for adult use, unless the Commission finds that such products do not have the potential for causing puncture wound injury.</summary>
</bill>
