<bill session="100" type="s" number="1896" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:28-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the Vietnam Women's Memorial Project, Inc., to construct a statue in honor and recognition of the women of the United States who served in the Vietnam conflict.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-12-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-12-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-11-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-12-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-11-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-03">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="Vietnam veterans"/>
    <term name="Women soldiers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/20/1987--Introduced.
Authorizes the Vietnam Women's Memorial Project, Inc., to construct a statue of a woman Vietnam veteran within the Vietnam Veterans Memorial site in Washington, D.C., to honor and recognize the women of the U.S. armed forces who served in the Vietnam conflict. Expresses the sense of the Congress that after the addition of such statue, no further additions to the site should be authorized or undertaken. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to select a site for the statue within the Memorial with the approval of the Commission of Fine Arts and the National Capital Planning Commission. Makes the design proposal subject to the approval of the Secretary and such Commissions. Prohibits the United States or the District of Columbia from paying any expense of constructing the statue. Requires that the construction of such statue be commenced within five years of the date of enactment of this Act, and that funds sufficient to insure completion are certified to be available by the Secretary prior to groundbreaking, or the authority provided by this Act shall lapse. Grants the Secretary the responsibility for the statue's maintenance and care.</summary>
</bill>
