<bill session="100" type="s" number="19" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Educational Achievement Incentive Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide grants to State and local educational agencies for dropout prevention programs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB, GAO.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Educational Achievement Incentive Act of 1987 - Amends the Elementary and Secondary Education Act of 1965 to provide for dropout prevention programs. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991. Directs the Secretary of Education to reserve a specified amount for State programs. Provides for distribution of grant funds on a competitive basis to local educational agencies. Reserves certain amounts for special needs grants to large local educational agencies with high dropout rates. Sets forth factors for special consideration in distribution of grant funds. Sets forth grant application requirements. Includes among authorized program activities: (1) early intervention programs; (2) use of counselors; (3) parental involvement; (4) tutorial services; (5) coordination with local institutions of higher education; (6) the combination of vocational and technical career training with basic academic skills, and with part-time work options; (7) communication networks for guidance and career advice from business and professional organizations; (8) referral to community programs addressing the noneducational needs of the dropout or potential dropout; and (9) model high school equivalent education programs. Requires the Secretary to review programs and projects. Sets forth provisions for withholding payments. Directs the Secretary to report annually to the Congress. Sets forth program auditing and reporting requirements. Requires that grant funds supplement, not supplant, other funds.</summary>
</bill>
