<bill session="100" type="s" number="1928" updated="2016-06-29T08:46:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Food, Drug, and Device Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to improve the regulation of medical devices, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408970"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-15">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Antibiotics"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Drug safety and regulation"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Electronics"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food industry"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Milk"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/1987--Introduced.
Food, Drug, and Device Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Federal Food, Drug, and Cosmetic Act to combine into a single class I those medical devices currently in class I (for which general controls are sufficient) and class II (for which performance standards are required). Redesignates current class III devices (devices for which premarket approval is required) as class II. Revises procedures for establishing medical device performance standards. Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish performance standards for any medical device regardless of its classification. (Under present law, the Secretary may establish performance standards only for class II devices.) Authorizes the Secretary to establish standards by informal notice-and-comment rulemaking in consultation with an appropriate advisory committee. Allows the Secretary to obtain injunctions against the manufacture and distribution of counterfeit drugs and the making, selling, or concealing of the equipment used to make them. Repeals the requirement that the Secretary, upon request of a manufacturer, certify batches of antibiotics for conformity to applicable standards of identity, strength, quality, and purity. Amends the Public Health Service Act to repeal requirements that the Secretary: (1) study and report to the Congress on State and Federal control of health hazards from electronic product radiation; and (2) submit an annual report on the administration of the electronic product radiation control program. Repeals the Filled Milk Act.</summary>
</bill>
