<bill session="100" type="s" number="1926" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to expedite reconciliation of inconsistent decisions of customs officers within the same customs region.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408420"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/8/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to require immediate review and reconciliation by the regional commissioner of customs of inconsistent decisions made by customs officers in any district or port of entry within the same customs region in regard to: (1) the appraised value of merchandise; (2) the classification and rate and amount of duties; (3) all charges within the Secretary of the Treasury's jurisdiction; (4) the exclusion of merchandise from entry or delivery; (5) the liquidation or reliquidation of an entry; and (6) the refusal to pay a claim for drawback or to reliquidate an entry. Authorizes an importer, customs broker, or port authority located in a customs region where such inconsistent decisions have been made to submit a petition to the regional commissioner requesting immediate review of such decisions. Requires the regional commissioner, within 72 hours after a petition is filed, to: (1) make a determination which reconciles the inconsistent decisions; and (2) provide written notice of such determination to the district and area administrators and area directors within the petitioner's customs region and to the petitioner. Provides that if a regional commissioner fails to make a determination within 72 hours after a petition is filed, each district and area director shall apply to merchandise the decision involved that results in the lowest applicable rate of duty.</summary>
</bill>
