<bill session="100" type="s" number="1935" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Communications Transfer Fee Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for the assessment and collection of a fee on the transfer of spectrum licenses and the establishment of a trust fund for public broadcasting.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Communications. Hearings held. Hearings printed: S.Hrg. 100-708.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM02" subcommittee="Communications" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fairness doctrine"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Public broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television broadcasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/9/1987--Introduced.
Communications Transfer Fee Act of 1987 - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to require the Federal Communications Commission, prior to the transfer of a construction permit or broadcast station license, to assess and collect from the transferor a charge of two percent of the selling price or of the fair market value, whichever is greater. Increases the charge to three percent if the transferor has violated the Fairness Doctrine. Increases such charge to four percent (five percent if the transferor has violated the Fairness Doctrine) if the Commission finds that the transferor has not operated the station for more than three years, unless: (1) the application involves only an FM translator station or FM booster station; (2) the application involves a pro forma assignment or transfer of control; (3) the transferor has made an affirmative factual showing that because of materially changed circumstances subsequent to the acquisition of the license or permit, a change in ownership will serve the public interest; or (4) the disposal of the permit or license was authorized in accordance with regulations concerning minority ownership of broadcast stations. Prohibits the Commission from waiving or deferring such charge. Provides that moneys received from such charge shall be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury until September 30, 1989, and thereafter in the Public Broadcasting Trust Fund, to be established by the Secretary of the Treasury. Provides that such Fund shall be used solely: (1) by the Secretary of Commerce for the planning and construction of public telecommunications facilities; and (2) for the Public Broadcasting Fund to provide financial support for public broadcasting. Requires the Commission, in establishing the fair market value of a construction permit or license that is disposed of, to include the price of the permit or license and all items of value disposed of, without regard to whether the disposition of such items occurs between the same persons or in the same transaction. Authorizes appropriations of a specified amount for FY 1989, and of a specified percentage of the Public Broadcasting Trust Fund for fiscal years after FY 1989, for the planning and construction of public telecommunications facilities. Limits to a specified portion of the Public Broadcasting Trust Fund the appropriations authorized for the Public Broadcasting Fund for fiscal years after FY 1990. Requires broadcast licensees to provide reasonable opportunity for the discussion of conflicting views on issues of public importance, consistent with the Commission's rules in effect on January 1, 1987.</summary>
</bill>
