<bill session="100" type="s" number="1988" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-07">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Merchant Marine Act of 1920.</title>
    <title type="official" as="amended by senate">A bill to amend the Merchant Marine Act, 1920, and for other purposs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300012"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1988-01-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300159" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1988-01-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on Merchant Marine. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-03-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings under the authority of the order of Apr 27, 88 with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 100-327.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-04" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="648">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 648.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-05-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-24">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-05-24" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-05-24">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-05-26">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-05-26">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-06-07" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-329" type="public" datetime="1988-06-07">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-329.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM06" subcommittee="Merchant Marine" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="82"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Buy American"/>
    <term name="Coastwise shipping"/>
    <term name="Dredging"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Offshore structures"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Territorial waters"/>
    <term name="Tugboats"/>
    <term name="Vessel documentation"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1920 to modify the penalty for transportation of merchandise between points in the United States in other than domestically built or rebuilt and documented vessels to permit the imposition of a penalty in the amount of the actual cost of the transportation provided, if that penalty is greater than the currently-imposed penalty of forfeiture of the merchandise or its value. Applies such provision to the transportation of valueless material, or any dredged material, regardless of whether it has commercial value, from a point in the United States, or on the high seas within the Exclusive Economic Zone (EEZ), to another point in the United States or on the high seas within the EEZ. Declares that the transportation of any platform jacket in or on a launch barge between two points in the United States, at one of which there is an installation or other device attached to the seabed in connection with exploring for, developing, or producing resources therefrom, as described in specified provisions of the Outer Continental Shelf Lands Act, shall not be deemed transportation which is subject to this provision if the barge meets certain requirements, including having a launch capacity of 12,000 long tons or more. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to develop, maintain, and update an inventory of launch barges which have a launch capacity of less than 12,000 long tons and which meet other criteria. Amends Federal law to make applicable to the towing of a vessel transporting valueless material, and any dredged material, from a point in the United States or on the high seas within the EEZ to a point in the United States or on the high seas within the EEZ current provisions prohibiting the towing of vessels by vessels not owned by a citizen of the United States and documented under provisions of Federal law. Permits a documented vessel to transport municipal sewage sludge provided such vessel, regardless of where it was built, as of enactment of this Act, is in use by or under contract with a municipality for the transportation of sewage sludge. Declares that, for purposes of a provision of the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 regarding forbidden practices in coastwise service, a vessel documented under U.S. laws and under contract with a municipality for the transportation of sewage sludge as of enactment of this Act is not a vessel engaged in domestic intercoastal or coastwise service. Provides that such vessels are bound by a provision prohibiting the diversion of any money, property, or other thing of value, used in foreign-trade operations, for which a subsidy is paid by the United States, into any coastwise or intercoastal operations. Authorizes the Secretary of the department in which the Coast Guard is operating to issue a coastwise certificate of documentation to a vessel which meets certain requirements, provided the certificate is endorsed to restrict the use of the vessel to the transportation of valueless material in the coastwise trade, and to the transportation of dredged material, whether or not of value, between specified types of points.</summary>
</bill>
