<bill session="100" type="s" number="1997" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to authorize the stretching out of the $1,200 basic-pay reduction of Montgomery GI Bill participants, and to provide for a payment to the survivors of certain participants who die on active duty.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-12-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-12-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Military pay"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/22/1987--Introduced.
Amends Federal veterans' benefits provisions to authorize the Secretary of Defense, after consultation with the Secretaries of the military departments, the Secretary of Transportation, and the Administrator of Veterans Affairs, to adjust certain individuals' reduction in basic pay (reduced for the purpose of the provision of basic educational assistance for members of the armed forces serving on active duty during a specified period) so that such reduction is no more than $100 and no less than $60 for the first 20 months (with a $1,200 total reduction limit) that the individual is entitled to such pay. Makes identical changes to the reduction in such pay for members of the Selected Reserve component of the armed forces. Provides that, in the event of the service-connected death of an individual whose basic pay has been reduced for the provision of basic educational assistance and who had not received such educational assistance, the Administrator shall pay to the living survivors (in a specified order of priority) the amount by which the individual's basic pay had been so reduced exceeds the total amount of educational assistance paid to such individual.</summary>
</bill>
