<bill session="100" type="s" number="1996" updated="2016-06-29T08:46:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-12-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 28, United States Code, with respect to United States District Court jurisdiction regarding certain actions involving citizens of the United States and foreign persons.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405310"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-12-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-12-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-01-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/21/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Federal judicial code to grant U.S. district courts personal jurisdiction over citizens and subjects of foreign states in actions relating to the purchase or use of a product manufactured outside of the United States (provided such citizen or subject knew or should have known that the product would be imported for sale or use in the United States). Permits removal of such actions (without regard to whether all interested parties were properly joined and served) to an appropriate Federal district court. States that the law of the place of injury shall govern all issues concerning liability and damages in such actions.</summary>
</bill>
