<bill session="100" type="s" number="2028" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Oil Pipeline Regulatory Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reform the regulation of oil pipelines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300012"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2734"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2734"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Energy Regulatory Commission"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/2/1988--Introduced.
Oil Pipeline Regulatory Reform Act - Amends the Interstate Commerce Act (regarding oil pipeline transportation rates) to declare that oil pipelines are common carriers obligated to: (1) provide transportation service without undue discrimination; and (2) provide reasonable routes and facilities. Prohibits an oil pipeline from: (1) charging shippers different compensation for like services; or (2) subjecting a person, place, port, or type of traffic to undue discrimination. Cites circumstances under which differences between rates, classification, rules, and practices do not constitute a violation of the discrimination prohibition. Declares that the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission (the Commission) may only initiate an investigation upon the complaint of an interested person (not upon its own motion). Prescribes guidelines for complaint processing. Directs the Commission to investigate any complaint upon State request. Prescribes enforcement guidelines. Authorizes the Commission to establish through routes for oil pipeline transportation. Prescribes guidelines under which the Commission is authorized to investigate new pipeline rates, classifications, or practices upon the complaint of an interested person. (Prohibits the Commission from initiating such an investigation upon its own motion.) Amends the Department of Energy Organization Act to transfer from the Secretary of Energy to the Commission certain functions relating to oil pipeline transportation. Prohibits State regulation of oil pipeline rates or practices. Continues the applicability of antitrust laws to oil pipelines.</summary>
</bill>
