<bill session="100" type="s" number="2020" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate above ground storage tanks having the capacity to store at least one million gallons of petroleum, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1988-02-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1988-02-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability for oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution"/>
    <term name="Oil pollution control"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum storage"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Storage"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/1/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to regulate above ground petroleum storage tanks. Requires tank owners to notify State or local authorities of the existence of such tank, specifying the age, size, type, location, assembly history, and uses of the tank. Requires each State to inventory above ground petroleum storage tanks in such State, aggregate the data derived from tank owners, and submit such data to the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency within two years of this Act's enactment. Directs the Administrator to promulgate petroleum spill prevention, correction, and financial responsibility regulations applicable to tanks which are 30 or more years old, have been reassembled in whole or in part, or have been relocated from their original site. Includes within such regulations requirements for: (1) the granting of operating permits pursuant to periodic tank inspections; (2) immediate reporting of a release and corrective action taken in response to a release; and (3) maintaining evidence of financial responsibility. Requires the Administrator, in promulgating financial responsibility regulations, to conduct a study to determine the appropriate amounts of coverage for the costs and damages of a spill. Permits the assertion of claims against guarantors providing evidence of financial responsibility for claims against insolvent tank owners or operators. Allow the Administrator to waive financial responsibility requirements upon the owner's or operator's demonstration of a secondary containment adequate to hold any release. Permits corrective actions by the Administrator or States to protect human health or the environment, but makes tank owners or operators liable for costs. Authorizes a State to submit for the Administrator's review and approval a program under which such State would assume primary responsibility for the enforcement of regulations pertaining to above-ground storage tanks. Requires that the State program be at least as stringent as the Federal program. Sets forth authorized actions when a facility owner or operator has not complied with or cannot meet financial responsibility requirements. Requires owners or operators of tanks to furnish the relevant government employees with all necessary information, including submitting their facilities to inspection and monitoring. Provides for confidentiality of such information and criminal penalties for prohibited disclosure. Authorizes the use of compliance orders to enforce this Act, providing daily civil penalties for noncompliance. Includes tanks under Federal jurisdiction under this Act, permitting exemptions of up to one year upon the President's specific request. Requires that all exemptions be reported annually to the Congress Directs the Administrator to study above ground petroleum storage tanks and above ground tanks used for the storage of regulated substances and report to the Congress and the President on the results of such studies within one year of this Act's enactment. Requires the Administrator to conduct a study and report to the Congress on the cause and environmental effects of the petroleum spill into the Monongahela River on January 2, 1988. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992.</summary>
</bill>
