<bill session="100" type="s" number="2024" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:33-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Asbestos in Schools Amendment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Asbestos in Schools Amendment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Asbestos Hazard Emergency Response Act of 1986, Public Law 99-519, to extend certain deadlines.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1988-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1988-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-04-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1988-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300159" joined="1988-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1988-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300154" joined="1988-04-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1988-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1988-02-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1988-02-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1988-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-04-13" withdrawn="1988-04-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-09">
      <text>Subcommittee on Hazardous Wastes and Toxic. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Burdick with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-405.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="769">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 769.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSEV03" subcommittee="Hazardous Wastes and Toxic Substances" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Asbestos"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government publicity"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Schools"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Environment and Public Works with amendment, S. Rept. 100-405) Asbestos in School's Amendment Act of 1988 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to permit local education agencies (LEAs) to request their State Governor, by September 22, 1988, for a deferral to June 9, 1989, of the October 12, 1988, deadline for the submission of school asbestos management plans to such Governor. Requires that such requests include either a statement that the State has requested, before June 1988, a waiver of the Act's school asbestos management requirement so as to operate its own asbestos and management program, and has not received a response to such request or: (1) an explanation as to why the LEA, despite good faith efforts, will be unable to meet the original deadline; (2) a proposed schedule of activities leading to the submission of the management plan; and (3) an assurance that the LEA has given the public notice of certain of its asbestos-related activities. Requires that such deferral requests be made available for public inspection. Directs that a LEA, before filing a deferral request, notify affected parents, teachers, and educational organizations and, in the case of a request pertaining to a public school, discuss the request at a public meeting of the school board. Prohibits a Governor from denying a deferral request when a LEA satisfies such information and notification requirements. Requires each Governor to submit a report to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) by November 12, 1988, listing the status of LEAs within the State regarding management plan submissions and deferral requests. Requires that such report be made available to LEAs within the State. Maintains the current requirement that LEAs begin implementation of management plans by July 9, 1989. Directs the EPA to publish a monthly list of approved asbestos training courses and each laboratory accredited. Prohibits LEAs which do not have an approved asbestos management plan for a school from undertaking routine renovations or removal of building materials in such school unless a thorough inspection has been conducted in the school and shown that such material does not contain asbestos. Directs such LEAs to follow specified regulations governing operations, maintenance, training, and surveillance to protect school employees from asbestos exposure. Requires that school employees who are directed to conduct emergency repairs involving actual or suspected asbestos-containing materials, or to conduct operations and maintenance activities in a school, be provided with proper equipment and training and be allowed to follow safe work practices. Establishes civil penalties against LEAs which knowingly submit false information to their Governor regarding deferral requests. Amends the Asbestos School Hazard Abatement Act of 1984 to extend the authorization of appropriations for the asbestos abatement program through FY 1992.</summary>
</bill>
