<bill session="100" type="s" number="2066" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill relating to the ocean dumping of municipal sludge.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1988-05-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage sludge"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to prohibit the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency from granting a permit to a municipality to dump sewage sludge into the ocean after 1988, unless it enters into a compliance agreement with the Administrator before 1989 containing a schedule for the full implementation of an alternative sludge disposal system within five years of such agreement. Prohibits continued ocean dumping, unless the Administrator is notified of such dumping and the municipality is in compliance with its schedule for the implementation of an alternative sludge disposal system. Directs the Administrator to make biannual reports to the Congress regarding schedule compliance. Fines municipalities which violate compliance or notification requirements or dump sludge at unauthorized ocean sites. Places such fines in a newly created Clean Ocean Fund for enforcement, monitoring, and research activities related to ocean dumping.</summary>
</bill>
