<bill session="100" type="s" number="2079" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Organ Transplant Contributions Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a mechanism for taxpayers to designate any portion of any overpayment of income tax, and to contribute other amounts, for payment to the National Organ Transplant Trust Fund.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-04-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immunosuppressive drugs"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/22/1988--Introduced.
Organ Transplant Contributions Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow taxpayers to designate on their income tax returns that any portion of their income tax refund or any cash donation included with the return be paid to the National Organ Transplant Trust Fund. Establishes in the Treasury the National Organ Transplant Trust Fund and appropriates to it amounts equal to those designated on tax returns. Establishes a program through which Trust Fund monies will be used to pay the costs of organ transplantation procedures and immunosuppressive drugs for individuals deemed unable to pay for a reasonably medically necessary transplant procedure. Authorizes, in addition, the use of Fund monies to pay the costs of notifying potential beneficiaries about the Trust Fund, and for other administrative expenses, including the solicitation of contributions.</summary>
</bill>
