<bill session="100" type="s" number="2073" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Thrift Charter Enhancement Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Thrift Charter Enhancement Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "Thrift Charter Enhancement Act of 1988".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406183"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27">
      <text>Committee on Banking. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-715.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Committee on Banking. Reported to Senate by Senator Proxmire with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-483.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-11" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="905">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 905.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Bank capital"/>
    <term name="Bank directors"/>
    <term name="Bank failures"/>
    <term name="Bank holding companies"/>
    <term name="Bank loans"/>
    <term name="Bank mergers"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Investments"/>
    <term name="Savings and loan associations"/>
    <term name="Savings banks"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Stocks"/>
    <term name="Subsidiary corporations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/11/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs with amendment, S. Rept. 100-483) Thrift Charter Enhancement Act of 1988 - Amends the National Housing Act to increase the limit on the aggregate amount of transactions or service agreements allowed between federally insured thrift institutions and their affiliates without the prior approval of the Federal Savings and Loan Insurance Corporation (FSLIC) in cases of GAAP-qualified insured institutions. Increases such limit from the lesser of to the greater of $100,000 or 0.1 percent of the thrift institution's total assets, up to a maximum of $2,000,000 for transactions and $1,000,000 for service agreements. Defines a "GAAP-qualified insured institution" as an insured institution: (1) whose capital equals or exceeds the greater of five percent of total assets or the minimum capital level prescribed by the FSLIC; and (2) that is not affiliated with an insured institution whose capital is less than three percent of total assets. Exempts an institution from the three percent capital requirement if it: (1) is affiliated due to the acquisition of a failed or failing institution; (2) has capital of not less than zero; (3) has submitted a plan to the FSLIC for increasing capital to at least three percent within four years and the FSLIC has determined such plan to be feasible; and (4) is in compliance with such plan. Allows a savings and loan holding company to acquire up to five percent of the voting shares of an unaffiliated thrift institution or savings and loan holding company. (Present law prohibits the acquisition of any voting shares of an unaffiliated institution unless the holding company has, or is acquiring, control of such thrift institution.) Repeals requirements under the National Housing Act for prior FSLIC approval for interlocking directors of savings and loan holding companies (leaving the Depository Institution Management Interlocks Act of 1978 as the governing statute.) Allows a savings and loan holding company or any nonthrift subsidiary thereof to assume or incur debt without the prior approval of the FSLIC if each of the holding company's insured institution subsidiaries is a GAAP-qualified insured institution.</summary>
</bill>
