<bill session="100" type="s" number="2070" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Limit America's Runaway Defense Dollars Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to revise and repeal certain labor standards laws applicable to the Department of Defense; to revise the authority of the President to prescribe and modify stockpile goals for strategic and critical materials in the National Defense Stockpile; and to establish the Bipartisan Commission on the Consolidation of Military Bases.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400565"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Readiness, Sustainability, Support.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-02-29">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services requested executive comment from Defense Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSAS04" subcommittee="Readiness, Sustainability and Support" name="Senate Armed Services"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Construction workers"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Defense contracts"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/18/1988--Introduced.
Limit America's Runaway Defense Dollars Act of 1988 - Makes inapplicable to contracts awarded by the Department of Defense: (1) the Davis-Bacon Act; and (2) all provisions of the Service Contract Act of 1965. Amends the Strategic and Critical Materials Stock Piling Act to direct the President, no later than 60 days after the enactment of this Act, to prescribe a goal for each material to be stockpiled, and to report such goals to the Senate and House Armed Services Committees. States that such goals shall become effective 45 days after the Committees receive such report. Authorizes the President to reduce such goals by up to 30 percent or to increase such goals. Requires the President to notify the Committees of any revised goal and the reasons therefore. States that such revised goals shall become effective 45 days after the Committees receive such notification. Provides a minimum total quantity of such stockpiled materials. Establishes the Bipartisan Commission on the Consolidation of Military Bases to: (1) review the military importance of all major military installations; and (2) identify which such installations can be closed or realigned without impairing the security of the United States. Outlines administrative procedures concerning membership, staff, meetings, and powers of the Commission. Directs the Commission, within 180 days after the enactment of this Act, to submit to the President, the Secretary of Defense, and the Congress a final report on the findings and conclusions of the Commission. Terminates the Commission 30 days after the submission of such report. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to take specified action with respect to the implementation of the Commission's recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
