<bill session="100" type="s" number="2092" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-02-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Ground Water Revenue Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 38 of the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to establish new environmental taxes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-02-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water resources development"/>
    <term name="Fertilizers"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gardening"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Hazardous wastes"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Pesticide regulation"/>
    <term name="Pesticides"/>
    <term name="Recycling of waste products"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water districts"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/25/1988--Introduced.
Ground Water Revenue Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to impose a per ton tax on: (1) the exportation of hazardous waste from the United States (liability for the tax is on the exporter); and (2) the receipt of hazardous waste at a qualified hazardous waste management unit (liability is on the owner or operator of the unit) or for transport from the United States for ocean disposal (liability is on permittee). Sets the initial (1989) rate of the tax at $27.00 for land disposal (increasing annually to a maximum of $43.00 for 1993 and thereafter), and $2.70 ($3.00 in 1993) for any other taxable event. Establishes exceptions to the tax, including hazardous waste received at a U.S.-owned facility or at any waste treatment unit, unless the unit requires corrective action that has not been completed. Provides for reduced tax liability when the waste has already been subjected to the waste management tax or to the tax on waste generation. Permits as a credit or refund any waste management tax paid in connection with: (1) hazardous waste incinerated on land or a battery recycled within 90 days after the receipt subjected to the tax; or (2) waste used by a producer of a qualified chemical fuel or solvent to be sold for industrial or commercial use. Imposes a per ton waste generation tax on hazardous waste that has been neither received for proper disposal nor exported within 270 days of being generated. Applies the same rates as those of the hazardous waste management tax. Places liability for the tax on the producer of the waste. Permits some of the same exemptions established in connection with the waste management tax, as well as exemptions for generators of small amounts of waste and waste legally disposed of in publicly owned treatment works. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury to provide for other exemptions. Describes reporting requirements with respect to the hazardous waste management tax. Imposes penalties on persons who fail to report or who underpay environmental excise taxes because of negligence or disregard of rules and regulations. Imposes a $1.00 per ton tax on the receipt of solid waste at a solid waste management facility (liability is on the owner or operator) and on its exportation from the United States (liability is on exporter). Establishes exemptions generally corresponding to those under the hazardous waste management tax. Describes reporting requirements with respect to the tax and imposes penalties on persons failing to report. Imposes a tax of two cents per thousand gallons on the sale or delivery of water piped by any public water system. Exempts small systems (those supplying up to 500 service connections) and sales of water already subjected to the tax. Imposes a two percent excise tax on chemical products sold as pesticide or fertilizer packaged for retail distribution in quantities of less than 100 pounds. Places liability on the manufacturer, producer, or importer. Permits as a credit or refund any tax paid in connection with a fertilizer or pesticide used to produce either another product subject to this tax or an agricultural commodity. Establishes in the Treasury the Ground Water Protection Trust Fund to receive revenue generated by the hazardous waste management tax and by the excise tax on fertilizers and pesticides. Describes permissible Fund expenditures. Provides for State entitlements (based on the nationwide proportion of residents dependent on groundwater for household needs) to be paid whenever the fiscal year ending balance of the Fund exceeds $300,000,000. Earmarks these monies for State groundwater protection programs. Appropriates amounts to fund these entitlements for FY 1989 through 1993. Establishes in the Treasury the Well Water Replacement Trust Fund to receive revenue generated by the tax on the sale or delivery of water and other specified amounts. Describes permissible Fund expenditures. Establishes in the Treasury the Community Water Supply Management Trust Fund to receive revenue generated by the solid waste disposal tax. Makes Fund monies available, with express exceptions, only to make grants to local groundwater management districts. Provides for district entitlements to be paid whenever the Fund's fiscal year ending balance exceeds $20,000,000. Appropriates amounts to fund these entitlements for FY 1989 through 1993. Authorizes FY 1989 through 1993 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
