<bill session="100" type="s" number="2122" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicaid Infant Mortality Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Social Security Act to reduce infant mortality through improvement of coverage of services to pregnant women and infants under the medicaid program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1988-03-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1988-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-03-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-03-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1988-04-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1988-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Ambulatory care"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/2/1988--Introduced.
Medicaid Infant Mortality Amendments of 1988 - Title I: Medicaid Coverage of Pregnant Women, Infants and Young Children - Amends title XIX (Medicaid) of the Social Security Act to require States to cover pregnant women and children under age four who were born after 1987 if their family income is below the Federal poverty level. Authorizes States to provide Medicaid coverage to children from the age of four through seven who were born after 1987. Prohibits States from: (1) imposing a resource eligibility test on pregnant women and children under age four which is more restrictive than a resource eligibility test imposed under title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) of the Act; or (2) reducing payment levels under part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Act below the levels in effect on July 1, 1987. Requires that eligible pregnant women continue to receive Medicaid coverage through the month in which the 60th day following the end of pregnancy falls without regard to changes in family income. Title II: Promoting Medicaid Coverage of Pregnant Women, Infants and Young Children - Reimburses States, at the Federal Medicaid assistance percentage, for outreach services identifying Medicaid-eligible pregnant women and children and assisting them in applying for Medicaid coverage. Requires that States make ambulatory prenatal care available to pregnant women during a presumptive eligibility period. Alters the rules for determining when such period ends. Makes clarification amendments regarding the qualifications of providers of covered ambulatory prenatal care. Title III: Assuring Provison of Necessary Services for Pregnant Women and Infants - Requires States to submit information to the Secretary of Health and Human Services, by April 1 of each year, pertaining to the supply of and demand for obstetrical services and proposed Medicaid payment rates for such services so that the Secretary may determine whether such rates are sufficient to ensure that obstetrical services will be at least as available to Medicaid beneficiaries as they are to the general population. Requires States to immediately revise rates determined to be insufficient. Directs States to: (1) establish exceptions to durational limits on Medicaid coverage of medically necessary inpatient hospital services furnished to infants in disproportionate share hospitals; and (2) adjust payments to such hospitals to take into account exceptionally costly and lengthy inpatient hospital services for infants. Title IV: Medicaid Relationship with Special Supplemental Food Program for Women, Infants, and Children (WIC) - Requires States to: (1) coordinate Medicaid services with WIC program services under the Child Nutrition Act of 1966; and (2) notify Medicaid-eligible pregnant, breastfeeding, or postpartum women, and children under age five of WIC program benefits. Allows States to provide Medicaid coverage of supplemental foods furnished by the WIC program to Medicaid beneficiaries who are certified to participate in the WIC program. Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to permit States to cover Medicaid recipients under the WIC program without regard to WIC income eligibility standards.</summary>
</bill>
