<bill session="100" type="s" number="2131" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide lawful temporary resident status for certain aliens based upon petitions submitted to the Attorney General on behalf of such aliens by sponsoring employers and lobor unions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403142"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-14">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Immigration and Refugee Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU04" subcommittee="Immigration and Refugee Affairs" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4079"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4079"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Labor supply"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to provide annual lawful temporary resident status, or adjustment to such status, for up to 10,000 aliens sponsored by employers and labor organizations. Limits such status to a period of not more than five years. Requires the petition for such an alien to be: (1) submitted to the Secretary of Labor (Secretary) by a sponsoring employer or labor organization; (2) certified by the Secretary; and (3) approved by the Attorney General. Prohibits the Attorney General from approving a petition unless the Secretary certifies that: (1) there are not sufficient U.S. workers available at the time and place to perform the necessary services; and (2) the alien's employment will not adversely affect similarly employed U.S. workers. Sets forth conditions for petition denial, including: (1) a strike or lockout in the course of a labor dispute; (2) employer or labor organization failure to regionally recruit qualified U.S. workers; and (3) substantial labor certification violations by an employer or labor organization within the previous two-year period. Limits per country fiscal year admissions to not more than 15 percent of total admissions. Provides for: (1) renewal (up to five years) or termination of temporary resident status; and (2) adjustment to permanent resident status. Provides for the admission for lawful temporary resident status, or adjustment to such status, of up to 30,000 aliens: (1) who have been employed in the United States illegally since before October 1, 1988; and (2) who are sponsored by an employer or labor organization. Limits such status to a period of not more than five years. Prohibits the issuance of a visa or the adjustment of status unless an alien's petition has been: (1) submitted to the Secretary of Labor by its sponsor; and (2) approved by the Attorney General. Directs the Attorney General, in consultation with the Secretary of Labor, to issue implementing regulations.</summary>
</bill>
