<bill session="100" type="s" number="2148" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-28">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Omnibus Oregon Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Omnibus Oregon Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">Umatilla Basin Project Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Omnibus Oregon Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted" partial="1">Umatilla Basin Project Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1968, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408420" joined="1988-03-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department, Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held at Oregon City, Oregon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held at Bend, Oregon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-01">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held at Grants Pass, Oregon.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Agriculture Department. Favorable.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-22" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Johnston with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-570.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-30" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1034">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1034.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-12" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-28" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-557" type="public" datetime="1988-10-28">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-557.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4093"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4164"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4259"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4259"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1613"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Irrigation"/>
    <term name="Oregon"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Rivers"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water conservation"/>
    <term name="Water resources development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
    <term name="Wild rivers"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3625"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/7/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Title I: Omnibus Oregon Wild and Scenic Rivers Act of 1988 - Amends the Wild and Scenic Rivers Act to designate the following river segments in Oregon as scenic, wild, or recreational rivers: (1) Big Marsh Creek; (2) Chetco; (3) Clackamas; (4) Crescent Creek; (5) Crooked; (6) Deschutes; (7) Donner and Blitzen; (8) Eagle Creek; (9) Elk; (10) Grande Ronde; (11) Imnaha; (12) John Day; (13) Joseph Creek; (14) Little Deschutes; (15) Lostine; (16) Malheur; (17) McKenzie; (18) Metolius; (19) Minam; (20) North Fort Crooked; (21) North Fork John Day; (22) North Fork Malheur; (23) North Fork of the Middle Fork of the Williamette; (24) North Fork Owyhee; (25) North Fork Smith; (26) North Fork Sprague; (27) North Powder; (28) North Umpqua; (29) Powder; (30) Quartzville Creek; (31) Roaring; (32) Salmon; (33) Sandy; (34) South Fork Imnaha; (35) South Fork John Day; (36) Squaw; (37) Sycan; (38) Upper Rogue; (39) Wenaha; (40) West Little Owyhee; and (41) White. Designates the following river segments in Oregon for potential addition to the National Wild and Scenic Rivers System: (1) Blue; (2) Chewaucan; (3) North Fork Malheur; (4) South Fork Mckenzie; (5) Steamboat Creek; and (6) Wallowa. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to complete a study on the eligibility of a specified segment of the Upper Klamath River for potential addition to such System. Requires such study to be completed and a report on its results submitted to the Congress by April 1, 1990. Prohibits lands held in trust by the United States for the benefit of an Indian tribe or individual Indian from being included within the boundaries of the Deschutes or Metolius Rivers without the consent of the applicable tribal council. Requires the Secretaries of the Interior and of Agriculture to consult and enter into cooperative management agreements with Indian tribes for planning, administration, and management of Indian treaty lands that are included within System lands. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Umatilla Basin Project, Oregon - Umatilla Basin Project Act - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to construct, operate, and maintain the Umatilla Basin Project, Oregon, in accordance with the report of the Secretary dated February 12, 1988. Declares the purpose of such project to mitigate losses to anadromous fishery resources and continuing water service to the Hermiston, West Extension, Westland, and Stanfield Irrigation Districts, for the project water exchange. Declares the principal works of such project to consist of: (1) lands, water rights, or interests therein acquired for the benefit of fishery resources; (2) measures to conserve water and improve the drainage systems of the project; (3) pumping plants and related conveyance and distribution features; (4) works incidental to existing irrigation system necessary to accomplish a water exchange; (5) fishery resources mitigation measures; and (6) programs to monitor and regulate project operations and evaluate fishery resource mitigation measures. Requires project features to be integrated and coordinated with the existing Umatilla Project. Requires the Administrator of the Bonneville Power Administration to provide for project power needed to effect the water exchange with irrigation districts in accordance with the Columbia River Basin Fish and Wildlife Program established under the Pacific Northwest Electric Power Planning and Conservation Act. Requires the cost of project power to be credited to fishery restoration goals of the Program. Makes non-Federal interests responsible for the cost of operating and maintaining the project, except for those costs associated with the project water exchange and mitigation of losses to anadromous fisheries resources. Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary for the operation and maintenance of the existing pumping facilities as an interim measure to provide flow augmentation in the Umatilla River. Provides for the crediting of non-Federal costs for fishery resource improvements. Provides that when project pumping capacity is available in excess of that needed for fishery resource benefits, such capacity shall be available to eligible irrigation districts participating in the project. Requires the irrigation districts to pay the costs of such power which shall be provided from the Federal Columbia River power system. Authorizes appropriations for the Secretary to purchase land, water rights, or other interests for the benefit of fishery resources consistent with the purposes of this Act. Authorizes construction appropriations. Declares that nothing in this Act alters existing water rights. Declares irrigation districts participating in the project eligible for financial assistance under the Rehabilitation and Betterment Act for water conservation purposes and improvements to water supply systems. Requires the Secretary of the Interior, within one year after enactment of this title, to complete a review of the current operations of the project. Directs the Secretary, within 90 days of the completion of such review, to transmit a report to the House Committee on the Interior and Insular Affairs and the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</summary>
</bill>
