<bill session="100" type="s" number="2141" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Food Security Act of 1985 to permit the enrollment of cropland containing agricultural drainage wells and naturally occurring sinkholes in the conservation reserve program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Conservation and Forestry.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSAF07" subcommittee="Conservation and Forestry" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Drainage"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Soil conservation"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/4/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to carry out a ground water pilot program in conjunction with the conservation reserve program to assist owners and operators of land: (1) containing agricultural drainage wells or naturally occurring sinkholes; or (2) affected by water quality problems resulting from agricultural and water management practices. Requires participating owners or operators to: (1) retire permanently from the base and allotment history applicable to acreage placed in the reserve a number of acres equal to the number of acres placed in the reserve; and (2) not use for agricultural purposes other land drawing from the same water supply as land placed in the reserve.</summary>
</bill>
