<bill session="100" type="s" number="2162" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-20">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-15"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park Establishment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park Establishment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park Establishment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of the Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park in the State of New Mexico, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-03-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-15" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-24">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Hearings held jointly with the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources' Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks and Forests.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Inouye with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-354.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-23" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="683">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 683.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-09-20" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-23">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Recreation and Recreational Facilities"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Trails"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s3169"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>9/20/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park Establishment Act of 1988 - Establishes the Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park in New Mexico. Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to approve a leasehold interest in and to trust lands of the Zuni Indian Reservation which are necessary for the establishment of such park. Provides that any lease shall not become effective until 30 days after it has been transmitted to the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources, the Senate Select Committee on Indian Affairs, and the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs. Provides for the management of the park by the Secretary. Authorizes the Secretary to accept concurrent jurisdiction from the Zuni Tribe with respect to law enforcement within the park. Requires the Secretary to exempt all enrolled members of the Tribe from the payment of fees for admission into the park. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into cooperative agreements with the Tribe for the purpose of providing training to Zuni members in the management and preservation of historical properties and needed public services on the Reservation. Sets forth requirements with respect to Federal agency activities affecting the park. Establishes the Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park Advisory Commission within the Department of the Interior. Provides that such Commission shall advise the Director of the National Park Service in the planning, management, and administration of the park. Authorizes the Commission to employ an administrative director. Directs the Secretary to develop and transmit to the House Committee on Interior and Insular Affairs and the Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources a management plan for the park. Includes the Zuni-Cibola National Historical Park as an area to be accessed by the Masau Trail. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
