<bill session="100" type="s" number="2180" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-12">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Firearms Detection Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Undetectable Firearms Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend chapter 44, title 18, United States Code, to prohibit the manufacture, importation, sale or possession of firearms, not detectable by metal detection and x-ray systems.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1988-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1988-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1988-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1988-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1988-03-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1988-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1988-05-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on Constitution. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-12" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Reported to Senate by Senator Byrd for Senator Biden with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="668">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 668.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-18">
      <text>Star Print ordered S.2180.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 4445 as an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 4445 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting" code="SSJU03" subcommittee="Constitution" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4445"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Air piracy"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Arson"/>
    <term name="Assault"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Firearms control"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Sentences (Criminal procedure)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2126"/>
    <amendment number="s2127"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>5/25/1988--Indefinitely postponed in Senate.
(Measure indefinitely postponed in Senate, H.R. 4445 passed in lieu) Undetectable Firearms Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal criminal code to make it unlawful to manufacture, assemble, import, sell, ship, or deliver (or knowingly possess, transfer, or receive) any firearm which is not: (1) as detectable as the Minimum Security Standard Exemplar (after the removal of grips, stocks, and magazines) by walk-through metal detectors calibrated to detect the Exemplar; or (2) detectable by airport cabinet x-ray systems. States that nothing in this Act shall require the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to utilize the Minimum Security Standard Exemplar as an FAA detection standard. Defines the term "Minimum Security Standard Exemplar" to mean a firearm substitute used for testing that resembles a revolver, is made of stainless steel, and weighs 3.7 ounces. Prohibits the Secretary of the Treasury from authorizing the importation of undetectable firearms. Directs the Administrator of the FAA to conduct research to improve the effectiveness of airport security metal detectors and airport security x-ray systems. Allows the Secretary, when appropriate because of changed technology, to promulgate regulations to amend the definition of Minimum Security Standard Exemplar. Prohibits the Secretary from amending such definition so as to increase the weight of the Exemplar as set forth in this Act. Permits the conditional importation of firearms for the purpose of examiniation and testing to determine whether the importation of such firearms will be allowed under this Act. Directs the Attorney General, the Secretary, and the Secretary of Transportation to conduct studies to identify available equipment capable of detecting the Minimum Security Standard Exemplar while distinguishing innocuous metal objects. Provides increased criminal penalties for using or carrying an undetectable firearm during the commission of a crime of violence or a drug trafficking crime. Provides for the imposition of mandatory criminal penalties for using or carrying a firearm while assaulting a Federal officer. Makes it unlawful to knowingly possess, or attempt to possess, a firearm or dangerous weapon in a Federal courthouse. Makes it a Federal criminal offense to possess explosives in FAA regulated airports. Increases the criminal penalties for possessing explosives in Government buildings. Increases the criminal penalties for using fire or explosives to commit, or carrying an explosive during the commission of, a Federal felony. Prohibits the transfer of firearms to any person who does not reside in the State in which the transferor resides. Makes it unlawful to traffic in stolen firearms (or firearms which have had their serial numbers altered) which have been shipped or transported in interstate or foreign commerce. Makes it unlawful to manufacture, enter into commerce, ship, transfer, or receive any toy or imitation firearm which does not have markings which make it readily identifiable.</summary>
</bill>
