<bill session="100" type="s" number="2186" updated="2014-12-10T13:16:05-05:00">
  <state datetime="1988-11-17">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-11-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Public Buildings Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed house">Public Buildings Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Public Buildings Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Public Buildings Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Public Buildings Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the efficiency and effectiveness of management of public buildings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-03-29" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Burdick with amendments. With written report No. 100-322.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="631">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 631.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-18">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-05-18" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with amendments by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-19" where="h" result="pass" state="PASS_BACK:HOUSE">
      <text>Passed House (Amended) by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-20">
      <text>Message on House action received in Senate and held at desk: House amendment to Senate bill.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="pingpong" datetime="1988-10-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Senate agreed to the House amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-11-08">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-11-08">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-11-17" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-678" type="public" datetime="1988-11-17">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-678.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3817"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="5281"/>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2799"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Burglary protection"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Construction costs"/>
    <term name="Courthouses"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Indexing (Economic policy)"/>
    <term name="Inflation"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Names"/>
    <term name="Police"/>
    <term name="Rent"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2105"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/19/1988--Passed House amended.
(Measure passed House, amended) Public Buildings Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Public Buildings Act of 1959 to require congressional approval for any alteration or acquisition which exceeds the estimated maximum cost of $1,500,000 (currently, $500,000). Requires congressional approval for any alteration to leased space which exceeds a specified amount. Requires the Administrator of General Services, prior to leasing certain space, to certify in writing to specified congressional committees that the leasing of such space is necessary to meet requirements which cannot be met in public buildings. Describes such space as any space to accommodate: (1) computer and telecommunications operations; (2) secure or sensitive activities related to national defense or security (except where inappropriate); or (3) a permanent courtroom, judicial chamber, or administrative office for any U.S. court. Authorizes the Administrator to adjust amounts for any alteration or acquisition annually to reflect a percentage increase or decrease in construction costs during the preceding calendar year, as determined by the composite index of construction costs of the Department of Commerce. Requires that any adjustment be reported to specified congressional committees. Authorizes the Administrator to assign to a State, commonwealth, territory, or U.S. possession all or part of the authority of the United States to administer criminal, health, and safety laws with respect to lands or interests under the control of the Administrator in such State, commonwealth, territory, or possession. Prohibits the Administrator from making any agreement or undertaking any commitment which will result in the construction of any building for lease to, and for predominant use by, the United States until the Administrator has by regulation established detailed specification requirements for such building. Requires the Administrator to procure the construction of any such building only by soliciting competitive bids. Directs the Administrator to inspect such building during construction to ensure compliance with specifications. Requires the contract for construction of such building to contain provisions permitting a reduction of rent during any period when such building is not in compliance with specifications. Requires that buildings constructed or altered by a Federal agency comply with nationally recognized model building codes and with local zoning laws and other local requirements. Provides for State and local government consultation, review, and inspection. Requires the Administrator or appropriate agency to give due consideration to State and local government recommendations. Declares that no action may be brought against the United States for failure to meet requirements with respect to nationally recognized codes and recommendations. Provides that such requirements apply to projects for which funds are appropriated after FY 1989. Repeals the provision of Federal law which limits the maximum rental rate on leased buildings. Revises current provisions relating to the protection of Federal property by special police officers under the jurisdiction of the Administrator to state that the Administrator may provide such protection on property owned or occupied by the United States and under the charge and control of the Administrator. Designates the Federal building to be constructed in Lakeland, Florida, that will replace the existing Federal building as the Lawton Chiles, Jr. Federal Building. Designates the Federal building at 405 South Tucker Boulevard, St. Louis, Missouri, as the Robert A. Young Federal Building.</summary>
</bill>
