<bill session="100" type="s" number="2191" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize a Western Center for Nuclear and Groundwater Research.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-03-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Groundwater"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution"/>
    <term name="Radioactive pollution of water"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to establish the Western Center for Nuclear and Groundwater Research (Center) in Nevada which shall be directed by a nine-member board of directors chosen by Federal, State, and University of Nevada officials. Requires the Center to: (1) conduct, promote, and coordinate research into nuclear and hazardous waste containment and disposal; (2) study and evaluate the availability, usage, and management of groundwater in arid regions; (3) study and evaluate ways of increasing and coordinating research in monitoring the movement and concentration of contaminants in groundwater; and (4) serve as a forum for the consideration of problems involving the protection of groundwater from nuclear and hazardous substances. Directs the Center to report its findings and activities to the Congress, the President, and the Governor of Nevada within one year of this Act's enactment and thereafter upon the request of the Congress. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
