<bill session="100" type="s" number="2190" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Terrorism Sanctions Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Act of September 13, 1961, relating to the destruction or injury of property moving in interstate or foreign commerce, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2489"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="2489"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Most favored nation principle"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff agreements"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1988--Introduced.
Anti-Terrorism Sanctions Act of 1988 - Provides certain sanctions against countries determined by the Department of State, under provisions of the Export Administration Act of 1979, as countries that repeatedly provide support for international terrorism. Specifies such sanctions as: (1) the termination, withdrawal, or suspension of any portion of any trade agreement or treaty that relates to the provision of nondiscriminatory (most-favored-nation) trade treatment to such country; (2) the denial of nondiscriminatory (most-favored-nation) trade treatment by the United States; (3) the nonapplication of the Generalized System of Preferences with respect to the products of such country; (4) the nonapplication of the provisions of the Caribbean Basin Economic Recovery Act with respect to the products of such country; and (5) the nonapplication of the provisions of the International Travel and Tourism Act of 1961 instructing the Secretary of Commerce to consult with other nations regarding international travel and tourism. Authorizes the President to waive any or all of such sanctions with respect to any foreign country if the President determines that such a waiver would be in the best interests of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
