<bill session="100" type="s" number="2198" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nonintervention Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to limit the introduction of United States Armed Forces into or over Honduras or Nicaragua.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405212"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Federal receipts and expenditures"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military maneuvers"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1988--Introduced.
Nonintervention Act of 1988 - Prohibits the use of Government funds for the purpose of introducing U.S. armed forces into or over the territory or waters of Honduras or Nicaragua for combat unless: (1) the Congress has declared war or enacted specific authorization for such introduction; or (2) such introduction is necessary to meet a clear and present danger of attack upon the United States to protect the U.S. embassy, or to protect and evacuate U.S. citizens. Prohibits the use of Government funds to introduce U.S. armed forces into Honduras for purposes other than military exercises in a number exceeding the total number of such forces in Honduras as of March 15, 1988, unless such conditions have been met. Prohibits the use of Government funds to involve U.S. armed forces in military exercises in Honduras unless the Congress has been notified in writing at least 30 days in advance. Defines "combat" as delivering weapons fire upon an enemy. Sets forth procedures for considering legislation authorizing the introduction of U.S. armed forces for combat.</summary>
</bill>
