<bill session="100" type="s" number="2202" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recreation and Public Purposes Amendment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 3 of the Act of June 14, 1926, as amended (43 U.S.C. 869-2), to authorize the issuance of patents with a limited reverter provision for lands devoted to solid waste disposal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1988-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-03-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1988-03-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4362"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4362"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1988--Introduced.
Recreation and Public Purposes Amendment Act of 1988 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to convey title, with a limited reverter provision, to lands to be used for solid waste disposal or purposes which may include, or result in the release of, hazardous substances. Provides for reversion of conveyed lands not used for the stated purposes within five years of their conveyance. Requires pricing for such conveyances to be determined in accordance with current Federal law, except that no compensation shall be required for the inclusion of only a limited reverter in the patent (conveyance agreement). Requires such document to include a provision that the lands shall not revert to the United States by operation of law if the lands are used for the stated purposes. Authorizes the Secretary to release (for a patent holder or on the Secretary's own initiative) the reverter provision contained in such patent on a finding that the lands have been or are being used for solid waste disposal or for purposes which may result in the release of hazardous substances. Provides that, upon such reverter release, such lands shall not revert to the United States by operation of law, or be subject to current Federal provisions concerning permissible uses of such properties. Authorizes the Secretary, with regard to lands leased for the above-stated purposes, to issue a patent to such lessee without compensation, on a finding that the lands have been or are being used for solid waste disposal or for purposes which may result in the release of hazardous substances. Provides the same non-reverter protection to such lessees as is provided to patent holders of such lands under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
