<bill session="100" type="s" number="2213" updated="2016-06-29T08:46:06-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Telemarketing Fraud Prevention Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Trade Commission Act to strengthen the authority of the Federal Trade Commission respecting fraud committed in connection with sales made with a telephone.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404679"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1988-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Consumer. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM03" subcommittee="Consumer" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4101"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4101"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Citizen lawsuits"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Unfair or deceptive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1988--Introduced.
Telemarketing Fraud Prevention Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to authorize both citizen suits and civil actions on behalf of a State for relief against entities engaging in telemarketing fraud or dishonest acts or practices. Prescribes the general framework to govern such suits. Directs the Federal Trade Commission (FTC) to promulgate rules to govern telemarketing activities. Describes required contents of such rules, including mandatory notice to telemarketing recipients concerning refunds for untimely delivery of the product or service. Provides for rescission of a sale within three days after a sales agreement. Requires that the rules include a rebuttable presumption that a telemarketing entity that does not keep adequate records illustrating compliance will be considered in violation. Declares that violators shall be considered to have engaged in an unfair or deceptive trade practice. Prohibits telemarketing conduct whose natural consequence is to harass, oppress, or abuse, and considers violators to have engaged in an unfair or deceptive trade practice. Directs the FTC to establish a clearinghouse for inquiries made to Federal agencies concerning telemarketing.</summary>
</bill>
