<bill session="100" type="s" number="2219" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Mental Health Centers Construction Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XIX of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the construction of community mental health centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental care facilities"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mentally ill"/>
    <term name="Psychiatric personnel"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public health personnel"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/1988--Introduced.
Community Mental Health Centers Construction Act of 1988 - Amends title XIX (Block Grants) of the Public Health Service Act to create a new part on mental health construction block grants. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services, for each of FY 1989 through 1993, to make allotments to States to assist in constructing community mental health facilities. Requires funds to be used for: (1) building and renovating; and (2) providing staffing and maintenance of centers which have been built or renovated. Requires at least 75 percent of the funds to be used to provide services for the homeless mentally ill and chronically mentally ill. Requires matching State funds. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993. Prohibits States from using more than ten percent of their allotments for administrative expenses.</summary>
</bill>
