<bill session="100" type="s" number="2220" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to preserve the independence of the scientific evaluation group for the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant in New Mexico.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-03-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear research"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Radioactive wastes"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/28/1988--Introduced.
Reestablishes the Environmental Evaluation Group (EEG) as an independent scientific review group for the Waste Isolation Pilot Plant (WIPP) in New Mexico, to be exclusively administered through the New Mexico Institute of Mining and Technology. Sets forth EEG membership and administrative parameters. Declares that the EEG shall be the primary responsible party for evaluating technical information on WIPP on behalf of the State of New Mexico. Provides that the EEG shall disseminate its findings and analyses through professional publications and that no approvals from outside sources will be required prior to publication. Directs the EEG to evaluate the scientific and technical status of the WIPP project in an objective manner in order to protect the health and environmental interests of New Mexico residents. Declares that the EEG shall be funded for a minimum of five years by the Department of Energy.</summary>
</bill>
