<bill session="100" type="s" number="2239" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the provision of trauma care for victims of the Nicaraguan civil war.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405212"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Emergency medical services"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Rehabilitation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1988--Introduced.
Directs the Agency for International Development to provide trauma care for victims of the Nicaraguan civil war through a contract with the Brown University Medical School's International Health Institute. Specifies that such care shall include: (1) a medical evacuation system; (2) a trauma care hospital center; and (3) a rehabilitation capability. Directs that such care be provided: (1) in accordance with guidelines specified by the American College of Surgeons; (2) on a nondiscriminatory basis; and (3) consistent with the requirements of the 1977 Protocols to the Geneva Conventions of 1949, the Esquipulas II Accord of August 1987, and the March 23, 1988, Nicaraguan ceasefire agreement. Makes assistance under this Act contingent upon the approval of the Government of Nicaragua and the Nicaraguan resistance and upon assurance that no reprisals will be taken against wounded persons and that the trauma center established would not be subject to any harassment. Recommends a hospital in La Trinidad, Nicaragua, as the site of the trauma center. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
