<bill session="100" type="s" number="2246" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Lower Mississippi Delta Development Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Lower Mississippi Delta Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Lower Mississippi Delta Development Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-09-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409580" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1988-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-28">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Burdick with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-557.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1014">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1014.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arkansas"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Depressed areas"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Kentucky"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Louisiana"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Missouri"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Regional economic disparities"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Tennessee"/>
    <term name="Transportation planning"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/28/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Environment and Public Works with amendment, S. Rept. 100-557) Lower Mississippi Delta Development Act - Establishes the Lower Mississippi Delta Development Commission to study and make recommendations concerning the economic needs and economic development of the Lower Mississippi Delta, defined to include areas in Arkansas, Illinois, Kentucky, Louisiana, Mississippi, Missouri, and Tennessee. Directs the Commission to: (1) identify and study the economic development, infrastructure, employment, transportation, resource development, education, health care, housing and recreation needs of the Lower Mississippi region; and (2) develop a ten-year plan describing recommendations and priorities for alleviating these needs. Enumerates Commission duties in connection with plan development, including: (1) to review existing Federal, State, local, and private programs for business development and financing; (2) to develop inventories of the region's business resources and natural resources; (3) to study the role of small business in creating jobs in the region; (4) to evaluate the proper roles of the public and private sectors in fostering the economic development of the region; and (5) to assess the area's health, educational, job training, housing, and poverty relief needs. Requires the Commission, no later than one year after its first meeting, to present an interim report to specified congressional leadership and committees, the President, and the Governors of the affected States. Requires a final report of required findings and recommendations within 18 months of the first meeting. Terminates the Commission within 180 days after submission of its final report. Authorizes FY 1989 through 1990 appropriations. Requires member States to contribute to Commission costs.</summary>
</bill>
