<bill session="100" type="s" number="2240" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Act to reauthorize the State Mining and Mineral Resources Research Institute program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406084"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-04-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1988-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1988-05-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-07-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-06-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1988-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1988-05-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-04-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-27">
      <text>Subcommittee on Mineral Resources and Development. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-27">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered favorably reported H.R. 3977 in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG05" subcommittee="Mineral Resources Development and Production" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="3977"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development facilities"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Research grants"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1988--Introduced.
Amends Federal law establishing the State Mining and Mineral Resources Research Institute Program to authorize appropriations for FY 1990. Mandates that appropriated funds be made available for grants matched on a basis of no less than two non-Federal dollars for each Federal dollar. Authorizes State mining and mineral resources research institutes to include the production of fuel and nonfuel mineral resources as a research and training area. Authorizes appropriations for research funds to institutes for FY 1990, and for four additional fiscal years thereafter. Increases from six to seven persons the non-Federal membership of the Committee on Mining and Mineral Resources Research. Requires the Committee to submit the annual updated national plan for mining and mineral resources research by January 15 of each calendar year. Amends the eligibility criteria for school participation as a mining and mineral resources research institute to provide that those institutions which on the date of enactment of this Act had eligible research programs in place shall retain their eligibility (subject to review during their authorized period).</summary>
</bill>
