<bill session="100" type="s" number="2252" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to encourage economic development in Central America, and to increase the sugar import quota.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1988-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-10">
      <text>Subcommittee on International Trade. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFI03" subcommittee="International Trade" name="Senate Finance"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4854"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4854"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural price supports"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Costa Rica"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="El Salvador"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Guatemala"/>
    <term name="Honduras"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Interest rates"/>
    <term name="Nicaragua"/>
    <term name="Sugar and sugar trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the President, during FY 1988 and 1989, to issue new U.S. guarantees of eligible debt obligations made or issued by the Governments of Costa Rica, El Salvador, Guatemala, or Honduras in exchange for existing debt obligations owed by such countries to private financial institutions. Requires that the United States guarantee certain debt obligations which Costa Rica and Guatemala issue in exchange for no more than 40 percent, and which El Salvador and Honduras issue in exchange for no more than 100 percent, of the existing debt obligations owed by such countries to private financial institutions. Directs specified U.S. Government lending institutions with loans outstanding to any such country to take steps to reduce the interest rate applicable to such loans to the prevailing rate minus four percentage points. Directs the Department of the Treasury and the Department of State to take steps to implement such reductions and encourage other creditor countries to such countries to make similar reductions. Increases the import quota on sugars, syrups, and molasses. Allocates additional amounts for such products of: (1) Guatemala, Honduras, El Salvador, and Costa Rica; and (2) Nicaragua, if the Nicaraguan Reconciliation Commission reaches conclusions satisfactory to all participants. Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend the sugar price support program indefinitely. (Currently such program applies through the 1990 crops of sugarcane and sugar beets).</summary>
</bill>
