<bill session="100" type="s" number="2255" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Rural Long-Term Care Demonstration Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program of demonstration projects, funded from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund under part A of title XVIII of the Social Security Act, to provide long-term care to elderly medicare beneficiaries residing in rural areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1988-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-04-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-04-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-04-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1988-04-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1988-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-05-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1988-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Long-term care"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1988--Introduced.
Medicare Rural Long-Term Care Demonstration Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to conduct 25 five-year demonstration projects testing alternative approaches for delivering long-term care to elderly Medicare (title XVIII of the Social Security Act) beneficiaries residing in rural areas. Requires that, in determining which rural health care providers will participate in such projects, the Secretary: (1) take into account the extent to which the proposed project will test the use of volunteers and paraprofessionals in the delivery of such care; and (2) ensure that approximately 75 percent of the projects are community-based while approximately 25 percent are hospital-based. Requires the Secretary to conduct an on-going evaluation of each project which includes an analysis of the quality of care provided, community and recipient acceptance of the project, and the financial impact of the project on the programs under titles XVIII (Medicare), XIX (Medicaid), and XX (Grants to States for Social Services) of the Social Security Act. Provides that such projects may include case management services and home health, day, and respite care, but prohibits the inclusion of services for which payment is otherwise made under the Medicare and Medicaid programs. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress on the results of such projects by January 1, 1994. Authorizes appropriations for such projects from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund through FY 1993.</summary>
</bill>
