<bill session="100" type="s" number="23" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make changes in the Trade Adjustment Assistance Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="Tariff negotiations"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to change the eligibility requirements for trade adjustment assistance for workers and firms. Authorizes the certification of workers and firms as eligible for such assistance if there are increases in imports of articles that are competitive with articles to which the workers (through their firms) or the firms provide essential parts or services. Requires a worker, in order to receive cash assistance, to: (1) be enrolled in a training program approved by the Secretary of Labor; (2) have completed such a program; or (3) have received a written certification from the Secretary or the relevant State or State agency that it is not feasible or appropriate to approve a training program for such worker. Prohibits payment of such assistance to such worker if the worker has failed to begin, or has ceased to participate in, such training program and there is no justifiable cause for such failure or cessation until the worker begins or resumes participation in such training program. Requires the Secretary of Labor to report annually to specified congressional committees on the number of workers who received certifications on the non-feasibility or inappropriateness of job training during the preceding year. Increases the maximum trade readjustment allowance to an amount equal to 78 (currently 52) times the amount of one week's trade readjustment allowance. Provides that such increase shall apply to a worker who receives a certification of non-feasibility of job training. Requires that, if the Secretary approves training for adversely affected workers, the training must be reasonably available. Provides that such training may be paid for directly or through a voucher system. Limits the total amount of payments for training for each adversely affected worker to $4,000. Requires each cooperating State agency (agency which provides trade adjustment assistance services) to advise adversely affected workers of training opportunities as soon as practicable. (Current law requires the agency to provide such advice within 60 days of receiving an application for training.) Terminates on September 30, 1991, trade adjustment assistance programs for workers, technical assistance for firms, and the imposition of import fees to fund such programs. Authorizes appropriations for trade adjustment assistance for workers and for firms through FY 1989. (Current law authorizes such appropriations through FY 1991.) Establishes within the Treasury a Trade Adjustment Assistance Trust Fund. Provides for funding the Trust Fund. Requires the amounts in the Trust Fund to be used to: (1) pay drawbacks and refunds of the duty imposed on all imports by this Act; and (2) carry out trade adjustment assistance for workers and firms to the extent and in such amounts as provided by appropriation Acts. Prohibits the use of the amounts in the Trust Fund to pay certain loans guaranteed under programs for trade adjustment assistance for firms. Directs the President to undertake negotiations to change the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT) to allow countries to impose a small uniform duty on all imports in order to use the revenue from such duty to fund trade adjustment assistance programs. Directs the President to report to the Congress six months after enactment of this Act on the progress of such negotiations. Directs the President to report to the Congress as soon as the GATT allows the imposition of such a duty. Imposes an additional duty on all imports into the United States, including those imports granted duty-free treatment, with specified exceptions. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exempt from tax a job training voucher received under a trade adjustment assistance program.</summary>
</bill>
