<bill session="100" type="s" number="2311" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Infrastructure Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to meet the growing challenge of America's infrastructure needs.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300036"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Accounting"/>
    <term name="Depreciation and amortization"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Infrastructure (Economics)"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Municipal services"/>
    <term name="Public works"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Sewage disposal"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment"/>
    <term name="Sewage treatment plants"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax-exempt securities"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Water treatment plants"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/22/1988--Introduced.
Environmental Infrastructure Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to provide for infrastructure bonds as a new category of tax-exempt bond. Includes within the definition of such bonds any State or local bond issued as part of an issue 95 percent or more of whose proceeds are to be used to provide public sewage facilities, solid or hazardous waste disposal facilities, water supply systems, or other facilities acquired, constructed, or renovated to achieve compliance with Federal environmental law. Amends arbitrage rebate provisions to: (1) exclude funds deposited in a reasonably required reserve or replacement fund from amounts that must be spent in order to avoid the required rebate to the United States; and (2) extend the temporary period during which unlimited arbitrage earnings are permitted with respect to governmental bonds. Classifies infrastructure facilities as seven-year property for purposes of the accelerated cost recovery system associated with the depreciation deduction. Designates a ten-year class life to such facilities under the alternative depreciation system. Exempts infrastructure facility property from restrictions relating to property leased to a tax-exempt entity.</summary>
</bill>
