<bill session="100" type="s" number="2326" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Fraud Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enhance the Federal Trade Commission's ability to prevent consumer fraud.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1988-10-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Consumer. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM03" subcommittee="Consumer" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="Jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Life care communities"/>
    <term name="Mail-order business"/>
    <term name="Marketing"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Restrictive trade practices"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Service industries"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Unfair or deceptive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/1988--Introduced.
Consumer Fraud Prevention Act - Amends the Federal Trade Commission Act to make it unlawful to disseminate any false advertisement for the purpose of inducing the purchase of services. (Current law addresses only dissemination of false advertisements regarding products.) Permits courts to join parties having common interests in false advertising suits brought under such Act. Modifies the procedures for the service of process by the Federal Trade Commission in cases involving temporary restraining orders and preliminary injunctions. Permits the FTC to use subpoenas to obtain physical evidence. Directs the United States Postal Service to amend its regulations concerning mail covers to permit the FTC the same access now permitted other law enforcement agencies. Allows the FTC to gain access to the financial records of consumer fraud suspects, after first obtaining a court order, upon a showing that the funds which are the subject of the records are likely to be dissipated, removed, or destroyed, and are subject to seizure by reason of having been obtained in violation of law. Permits the FTC to appoint State attorneys general to enforce FTC rules. Requires the FTC to extend its mail order rule to telemarketing. Requires the FTC to consider including in such final rule a requirement that telemarketers inform consumers of their rights under the rule. Directs the FTC to conduct a study of the life-care industry and, if appropriate, initiate a trade regulation rule proceeding.</summary>
</bill>
