<bill session="100" type="s" number="2330" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Women in Development Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the integration of women in the development process in developing countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1988-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1988-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-08-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409580" joined="1988-06-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-06-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-08-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-06-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="Women in business"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/27/1988--Introduced.
Women in Development Act of 1988 - Requires the Administrator of the Agency for International Development (AID) to take specific steps to strengthen the Agency's women in development policy, including: (1) incorporating and increasing the active participation of local women and local women's organizations in its development activities; (2) instructing Agency staff and contractors to collect sex-disaggregated data and to insure that country strategies, projects, and programs are designed so that the percentage of women receiving assistance in proportion to the higher of their traditional participation in the targeted activities or their proportion of the population; (3) insuring that project and program evaluations include an assessment of the extent to which the project integrates women in the development process and of the project's impact on women; (4) increasing the number and responsibility of women in professional positions within AID; and (5) establishing within AID a task force on women in development. Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to require that a minimum of $4,000,000 (currently, a maximum of $10,000,000) in funds made available for foreign assistance programs be used for programs to promote the participation and integration of women in the development process in developing countries. Requires that not less than $2,000,000 of such funds be extended as matching funds to support the efforts of AID field missions to integrate women into their programs. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress annually on the implementation of this Act. Authorizes appropriations to be made available for the United Nations Development Fund for Women and the United Nations International Research and Training Institute for the Advancement of Women.</summary>
</bill>
