<bill session="100" type="s" number="2342" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">INF Treaty Reinforcement Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reinforce the INF Treaty by restricting funding for excessive levels of MIRVed strategic nuclear forces, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-04-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1988-04-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Defense budgets"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Intercontinental ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="Missile warheads"/>
    <term name="Strategic forces"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/28/1988--Introduced.
INF Treaty Reinforcement Act of 1988 - Prohibits funding for any multiple independently-targetable reentry vehicle (MIRV) strategic nuclear weapons launcher or platform that would cause the United States to exceed the numbers of MIRVed ICBMS, ballistic missiles, and strategic systems that it had deployed on January 25, 1988. Requires the President to notify the Congress of plans for carrying out such prohibition. Requires the President to submit to the Congress, by December 1, 1988, a report (in both classified and unclassified versions) describing the numbers and types of operational strategic nuclear weapons launchers and platforms that the United States and the Soviet Union have dismantled since October 1972. Encourages the President to pursue alternative mutual restraints on offensive nuclear forces until a new strategic offensive arms agreement can be concluded. Waives the funding restriction under this Act if the President notifies the Congress in writing that: (1) a new U.S.-Soviet strategic arms agreement has entered into force; (2) the United States and the Soviet Union have agreed upon an alternative regime for interim restraint on strategic nuclear weapons; or (3) the Soviet Union has deployed strategic launchers and platforms in excess of the number of launchers of MIRVed ICBMs, ballistic missiles, or strategic systems that it had deployed on January 25, 1988, and in excess of the number of launchers and platforms of MIRVed strategic systems that the United States had deployed on that date. Requires that such notification be accompanied by a report (in both classified and unclassified versions) providing information upon which the the President bases his notification. Provides for a temporary waiver of the funding restriction for any 30-day period when the President notifies the Congress in writing that, based on the best agreed intelligence community assessments, he is unable to determine whether the Soviet Union has exceeded the levels of strategic forces specified above.</summary>
</bill>
