<bill session="100" type="s" number="2353" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:47-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pet Theft Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Pet Theft Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Laboratory Animal Welfare Act to prohibit the selling of stolen dogs and cats, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404219"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Senate Committee on Agriculture discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-08-10" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-08-11">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-25">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-28">
      <text>Subcommittee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee code="HSAG" name="House Agriculture" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="HSAG04" subcommittee="Department Operations, Research, and Foreign Agriculture" name="House Agriculture"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Dogs"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Laboratory animals"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Pets"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2843"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Pet Theft Act of 1988 - Amends the Federal Laboratory Animal Welfare Act (the Act) to prohibit, except in instances where State or local law supersedes, class B licensees (dealers) from obtaining live random source dogs and cats from: (1) a source other than a State, county, or city owned and operated pound; (2) a private entity established for the purpose of caring for animals (such as a humane society, or any other organization that is under contract with a State, county, or city that operates as a pound or shelter and that releases animals on a voluntary basis); (3) research facilities licensed by the Department of Agriculture; or (4) individuals who have bred and raised such dogs and cats on their own premises. Requires such pounds, shelters, or organizations to hold and care for dogs or cats for at least seven days before selling them to dealers (thus enabling them to be recovered by their original owners or adopted by other individuals). Prohibits dealers from selling, providing, or making available to any individual or entity a random source dog or cat without providing the recipient with a valid certification. Sets forth certification requirements. Requires the original certification to accompany the shipment of the dog or cat to the recipient, and a copy to be retained by the dealer. Requires the recipients and dealers to retain such certificates or copies for at least one year for enforcement purposes. Requires a copy of the certificate to accompany any transfer of an animal from one research facility to another. Subjects dealers who fail to act accordingly to the requirements of this Act, or who include false information in the certification, to: (1) specified penalties under the Act; (2) a fine of $5,000 per dog or cat for subsequent violations; and (3) permanent revocation of their license for violating such requirements three or more times. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to promulgate regulations to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
