<bill session="100" type="s" number="2364" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to enable certain United States flag vessels to engage temporarily in trade within the Great Lakes, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408937"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1988-05-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-05-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4562"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4562"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Cargo preference"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="National defense"/>
    <term name="Shipbuilding"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Vessel documentation"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Merchant Marine Act, 1936 to include in the term "privately owned United States-flag vessels," as used in provisions relating to cargo preference, any U.S. flag vessel designated by the Secretary of Transportation as a Great Lakes Exempt Vessel (GLEV) regardless of the number of years the vessel has been documented under U.S. laws. Authorizes the Secretary to designate each of six vessels as a GLEV to enable vessels documented less than three years to engage temporarily in trade within the Great Lakes. Prohibits any vessel engaged primarily in bulk trade from being designated as a GLEV. Prohibits any vessel from retaining its GLEV designation if it has repair, reconditioning, or maintenance work done other than in a U.S. shipyard, subject to waiver by the secretary to enable a vessel to safely sail from a foreign port. Prohibits any GLEV from serving any other U.S. seaport than the Great Lakes, subject to exception. Prohibits the Secretary from designating a vessel as a GLEV unless it has been approved by the Secretary of Defense as suitable for national defense purposes. Terminates any GLEV designation on December 31, 1990.</summary>
</bill>
