<bill session="100" type="s" number="2366" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-04-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-04-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intelligence Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal year 1989 for the Intelligence activities of the United States Government, the Intelligence Community Staff, for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401604"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Intelligence ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Committee on Intelligence. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Boren. With written report No. 100-334.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Armed Services by unanimous consent for a period not to exceed thirty calendar days, not to include days when the Senate is not in session, pursuant to the provisions of section 3(b) of S. Res. 400, 94th Congress.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Committee on Armed Services. Reported to Senate by Senator Nunn without amendment. With written report No. 100-404.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-28" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="767">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 767.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05">
      <text>Senate incorporated this measure in H.R. 4387 as an amendment.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 4387 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIN" name="Senate Intelligence (Select)" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
    <committee code="SSAS" name="Senate Armed Services" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4387"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Cryptography"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disability retirement"/>
    <term name="Disciplining of employees"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Intelligence community staff"/>
    <term name="Intelligence officers"/>
    <term name="Intermediate range ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Military attaches"/>
    <term name="Military dependents"/>
    <term name="Military intelligence"/>
    <term name="Military personnel"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="New York City"/>
    <term name="Patriotism"/>
    <term name="Retired military personnel"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="Victims of terrorism"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s2814"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>8/5/1988--Indefinitely postponed in Senate.
(Measure indefinitely postponed in Senate, H.R. 4387 passed in lieu) Intelligence Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1989 - Title I: Intelligence Activities - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 for intelligence activities in specified departments and agencies of the Government, including the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA) and the Department of Defense (DOD). Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 for the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI) to be expended for carrying out its functions relative to the implementation of the Intermediate Range Nuclear Forces Treaty. Declares that the authorized amounts and personnel ceilings for such intelligence activities are those specified in the classified Schedule of Authorizations prepared by the Select Committee on Intelligence. Authorizes the Director of Central Intelligence to employ civilian personnel in excess of the ceiling for such personnel when necessary to the performance of important intelligence functions. Title II: Intelligence Community Staff - Authorizes appropriations for the Intelligence Community Staff for FY 1989. Establishes an end strength ceiling of 244 full-time Intelligence Community Staff employees. Provides that such staff shall be administered in the same manner as the CIA. Title III: Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability System - Authorizes appropriations for the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement and Disability Fund for FY 1989. Title IV: General Provisions - Provides that the authorization of appropriations by this Act shall not constitute authority for the conduct of any intelligence activity which is not otherwise authorized by the Constitution or laws of the United States. Permits appropriations authorized by this Act for employee benefits to be increased to meet increases in such benefits authorized by law. Title V: Central Intelligence Agency Administrative Provisions - Allows the Director of Central Intelligence to grant appropriate relief to former CIA employees who unfairly had their CIA careers adversely affected as a result of allegations concerning their loyalty to the United States. Requires the Director to submit reports to specified congressional committees regarding the use of such authority. Amends the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement Act of 1964 for Certain Employees to permit certain employees who are subject to the Central Intelligence Agency Retirement System to elect to become subject to the Federal Employees Retirement System (FERS). Permits retired members of the uniformed services employed by the Director of Central Intelligence to receive compensation for serving on Central Intelligence Advisory Committees. Sets forth reporting requirements with respect to the activities of the Inspector General at the CIA. Title VI: FBI Enhanced Counterintelligence Authorities - Requires the Directors of the FBI and the Office of Personnel Management to conduct a demonstration project to ascertain the effects on the recruitment and retention of personnel, and on field operations in the New York Field Division of the FBI, of providing: (1) lump sum payments to personnel assigned to such Division; and (2) periodic payments to Division employees who are subject to directed geographic transfer or assignment. Requires the Directors to submit annual reports to the President and the Congress concerning the results of such project. Title VII: Department of Defense - Allows the Secretary of Defense, with certain restrictions, to use appropriated funds, and funds other than appropriated funds, for foreign cryptologic support. Authorizes the Secretary of Defense to pay a death gratuity benefit to the surviving dependents of any member of the armed forces or any employee of the Department of Defense who is assigned to duty with a defense attache office and who is killed as a result of hostile or terrorist activity.</summary>
</bill>
