<bill session="100" type="s" number="2368" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Main Street Fair Competition Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize the several States and the District of Columbia to collect certain taxes with respect to sales of tangible personal property by nonresident persons who solicit such sales.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-05-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-07-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental tax relations"/>
    <term name="Interstate commerce"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local taxation"/>
    <term name="Mail-order business"/>
    <term name="Retail trade"/>
    <term name="Sales promotion"/>
    <term name="Sales tax"/>
    <term name="State taxation"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/11/1988--Introduced.
Main Street Fair Competition Act of 1988 - Empowers any State and the District of Columbia to require a person to collect a State sales tax imposed with respect to the sale of tangible personal property if: (1) the destination of sale is in such State; and (2) the person engages in regular or systematic soliciting of sales in the State and has, within a specified one-year period, gross receipts from the sale of such property that exceed either $750,000 within the State or $15,000,000 nationally. Sets forth requirements under which local sales taxes may be collected as a component of State sales tax. Prohibits a State from requiring: (1) any person who collects a State sales tax to make an accounting for the receipts of such tax on the basis of the geographical location at which the taxable transaction occurs; or (2) collection of sales tax under this Act unless the State has available a toll-free telephone service to provide potential collectors with information relating to liability for and collection of State sales tax. Limits a State's authority in connection with tax return filing and payment frequency requirements. Applies relevant State law to persons required to collect State sales tax under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
