<bill session="100" type="s" number="2360" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Park System Review Board, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401709"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Department of the Interior"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/10/1988--Introduced.
Establishes the National Park System Review Board to maintain a continuing review of National Park Service programs and of existing and proposed national park system units. Requires the Board to transmit annually to the President and the Congress: (1) a report containing the results of such review, together with recommendations for the management of the national park system or any proposed additions to such system; and (2) budget recommendations for the Service and the Board. Establishes a Director of the National Park Service within the Department of the Interior, to be appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Sets forth the functions of the Director. Mandates a five-year term of office.</summary>
</bill>
