<bill session="100" type="s" number="2380" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Disaster Relief Act Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Disaster Relief Act of 1974, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-05-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-10" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Reported to Senate by Senator Burdick without amendment. With written report No. 100-524.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-22" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="959">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 959.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-21">
      <text>H.R. 2707 passed in Senate relating to this measure.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-22">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="2707"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Canal Zone"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Income"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Lumber trade"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Timber sales"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1988--Introduced.
Disaster Relief Act Amendments of 1988 - Renames the Disaster Relief Act of 1974 the Major Disaster Relief and Emergency Assistance Act. Amends such Act to establish an emergency assistance program. Sets forth procedures for State governors to request the President to determine an emergency. Describes general Federal assistance under such an emergency, including debris removal assistance. Limits the amount of emergency assistance to $5,000,000, which may be exceeded if the President finds it necessary. Requires the President to report to the Congress on the nature and extent of an emergency when such limitation is exceeded. Increases from $25,000 to $50,000 the maximum amount of grants to States for improvement, maintenance, and updating of State plans. Allows the consideration of economic status when providing disaster assistance. Requires public and private nonprofit facilities in flood hazard areas to maintain flood insurance. Declares that major disaster and emergency assistance shall not be considered income or a resource when determining benefit levels for Federal programs. Declares that major disaster and emergency assistance shall not be deemed a major Federal action under the National Environmental Policy Act of 1969. Authorizes the Federal Government to recover the cost of assistance from any person whose negligent act or omission, or whose act or omission while engaged in ultra-hazardous activity, resulted in an emergency of major disaster. Directs the President to conduct audits and investigations necessary to ensure compliance with this Act. Sets forth provisions relating to criminal and civil penalties. Sets forth procedures for State governors to request declarations by the President that a major disaster exists. Requires such request to be based on a finding that effective response to such disaster is beyond the capabilities of the State and local governments and that Federal assistance is necessary. Describes general and essential assistance that the President may provide. Decreases from 100 percent to 75 percent the Federal share of the cost to repair, restore, reconstruct, or replace public facilities and private nonprofit facilities which are damaged by a major disaster. Declares the Federal share of assistance for debris removal to be 75 percent. Provides for temporary housing assistance for up to 18 months after the date of a major disaster. Authorizes the President to extend such period due to extraordinary circumstances. Declares the Federal share of such assistance to be 100 percent of eligible costs. Declares the Federal share to be 75 percent for a group site development of mobile homes or other readily fabricated dwellings. Authorizes the President to contribute up to 50 percent of the cost of implementing hazard mitigation measures which would be cost effective and would substantially reduce the risk of future damage, hardship, loss, or suffering in the area affected by a major disaster. Declares that disaster unemployment assistance is not payable for any week for which an individual is entitled to unemployment compensation or waiting week credit. Provides for reducing disaster unemployment assistance by any amounts received from private income protection insurance compensation. Modifies the requirement that the States repay the advances on matching grants made by the Federal Government for individual and family disaster relief grants by deferring repayment (and the interest accruing thereon) for a maximum period of two years from the date of the major disaster declaration. Increases from $5,000 to $7,500 the maximum aggregate grant amount which an individual or family may receive with respect to any one major disaster. Repeals disaster relief provisions regarding purchasers of Federal timber. Removes the Canal Zone from coverage under such Act. Prohibits a State from being ruled ineligible to receive disaster assistance solely by virtue of an arithmetic formula based on income or population.</summary>
</bill>
