<bill session="100" type="s" number="2383" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Education Benefits Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to extend eligibility for education benefits under the Vietnam-era GI bill to certain service academy and Senior Reserve Officer Training Corps graduates, to permit students using Veterans' Administration education assistance one instance of course withdrawal without a requirement to repay benefits, and to provide tutorial assistance for Post-Vietnam Era Educational Assistance Program and Montgomery GI Bill participants; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-09-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-20">
      <text>Committee on Veterans requested executive comment from VA, OMB, Defense Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans received executive comment from VA.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Military education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/12/1988--Introduced.
Veterans' Education Benefits Amendments of 1988 - Makes eligible for education benefits under the Vietnam-era GI Bill individuals who: (1) before January 1, 1977, commenced the third academic year as a cadet or midshipman at one of the service academies or the third academic year as a member of the Senior Reserve Officer Training Corps (SROTC); (2) served more than 180 days as a commissioned officer, were honorably discharged, and enrolled in the Post-Vietnam Era Veterans' Educational Assistance Program; and (3) submit to the Administrator of Veterans Affairs before January 1, 1990, an irrevocable election to be so eligible. Allows students using Veterans Administration educational assistance to make a one-time course withdrawal without the requirement of repayment of benefits. Makes Montgomery GI Bill and Post-Vietnam Era Educational Assistance Program students eligible for tutorial assistance. Increases the maximum tutorial assistance payments to be paid by the Administrator.</summary>
</bill>
