<bill session="100" type="s" number="239" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Intercircuit Panel of the United States Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Intercircuit Panel, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Appellate courts"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Intercircuit Panel of the United States Act - Establishes the Intercircuit Panel of the United States Courts of Appeals. States that the Panel shall be composed of nine circuit court judges and four alternate judges designated by the Supreme Court of the United States. States that the Chief Justice shall designate the presiding judge of the Panel from among the members of the Panel. Places the principal office of the Panel in the District of Columbia. Allows the Supreme Court to refer cases to the Panel where a conflict exists between U.S. Courts of Appeals decisions. Declares that decisions of the Panel shall be binding on all U.S. courts unless modified or overruled by the Supreme Court. Directs the Panel, in consultation with the Director of the Administrative Office of the United States Courts, to submit to the Supreme Court, the Judicial Conference of the United States, the President, and the Congress a comprehensive report on Panel activities. Authorizes appropriations. Terminates the Panel upon the disposition of all cases pending five years after the date of its first referral.</summary>
</bill>
