<bill session="100" type="s" number="2392" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Homebuyer Savings Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide for the establishment of, and deduction of contributions to, homebuyer saving accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402412"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Home ownership"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Trusts and trustees"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/13/1988--Introduced.
Homebuyer Savings Act - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax deduction of contributions (cash or securities) to a savings account established for the benefit of the taxpayer (or the taxpayer and spouse) for the exclusive purpose of purchasing the taxpayer's first principal residence. Limits the maximum annual deduction to $5,000. Permits deductions only during a five-year period. Disallows the deduction to taxpayers having adjusted gross income exceeding $50,000. Provides that no individual may be a beneficiary of more than one account. Excludes account distributions from gross income if they are used exclusively for the purchase of a first principal residence. Imposes penalties in the form of additional tax when account funds or distributions are used for other than the legitimate purposes for which the account was established. Requires the account trustee to report to the Secretary of the Treasury and to the account's beneficiary on the maintenance of the account. Imposes a penalty for failure to file required reports.</summary>
</bill>
