<bill session="100" type="s" number="2409" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cooperative Organ Transplant Contributions Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to provide a mechanism for taxpayers to designate any portion of any overpayment of income tax, and to contribute other amounts, for payment to the National Organ Transplant Trust Fund, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402004"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1988-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1988-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-12">
      <text>Subcommittee on Taxation and Debt Management. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Taxation and Debt Management. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFI06" subcommittee="Taxation and Debt Management" name="Senate Finance"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Checkoff"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Immunosuppressive drugs"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Poor"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax refunds"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
    <term name="Transplantation of organs, tissues, etc."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/18/1988--Introduced.
Cooperative Organ Transplant Contributions Act of 1988 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow taxpayers to designate on their income tax returns that any portion of their income tax refund or any cash donation included with the return be paid to the National Organ Transplant Trust Fund. Establishes in the Treasury the National Organ Transplant Trust Fund and appropriates to it amounts equal to those designated on tax returns, as well as any other cash contributions made to it. Directs each State to establish a program through which Fund monies will be used to provide assistance in paying the costs of organ transplantation procedures and immunosuppressive drugs for individuals who meet certain financial need requirements and who have a medical condition for which a transplant procedure is reasonably medically necessary. Prescribes conditions to govern Fund administration. Permits payment of Fund monies to a State only if the Secretary of Health and Human Services certifies that the State is properly carrying out its program and has fully accounted for previously received monies. Requires the State's chief health officer to place monies received from the Fund into a separate interest-bearing account, to be disbursed only to eligible individuals. Limits the ways in which States may use Fund monies. Requires each State to submit an annual report concerning its organ transplant program.</summary>
</bill>
