<bill session="100" type="s" number="2415" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:48-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide that surplus dairy products should be provided to carry out the temporary emergency food assistance program before certain dairy export programs, to extend such dairy export programs and such food assistance program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407622"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1988-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1988-05-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 2560 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-14">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-27">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture. Reported to Senate by Senator Leahy without amendment. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-27" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="764">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 764.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2560"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Dairy products"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/19/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Temporary Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 to state that the dairy export incentive program and the export sales of dairy products program shall not be operated in a way that will reduce the dairy products available for the temporary emergency food assistance program (TEFAP) or any other domestic feeding program. Extends TEFAP, including storage and distribution authorizations, through FY 1991. Increases the amount of TEFAP funds for emergency feeding organizations. Extends through FY 1991 the Secretary of Agriculture's responsibility to publish a notice of anticipated available commodities in the Federal Register. Amends the Food Security Act of 1985 to extend through FY 1991: (1) the dairy export incentive program; and (2) the export sales of dairy products program. Amends the Temporary Emergency Food Assistance Act of 1983 to direct the Secretary to establish procedures for State, local, or private donations to supplement Federal food assistance programs. Authorizes States or emergency feeding organizations to use funds appropriated under this Act for facilities use and distribution costs. Authorizes States to use such funds to conduct an information program regarding available food assistance programs, including the food stamp program and the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children. Directs State and local agencies to continue to use volunteer workers and donated food stuffs in food distribution programs.</summary>
</bill>
