<bill session="100" type="s" number="2422" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foreign Aid Insurance Reciprocity Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to increase opportunities for United States insurance companies to provide insurance in connection with United States Government-assisted supplies or activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1988-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1988-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1988--Introduced.
Foreign Aid Insurance Reciprocity Act of 1988 - Requires each executive agency or military department responsible for economic or military assistance to foreign countries to take such actions as may be necessary to ensure that U.S. insurance companies have a fair and open competitive opportunity to provide insurance whenever such insurance is necessary or proper in connection with Government-assisted supplies or activities. Specifies that such actions shall include: (1) including in any contract or solicitation for procurement of such supplies or activities a clause requiring that U.S. insurance companies have a competitive opportunity; and (2) certifying to the United States Trade Representative (USTR) that all necessary and practicable actions have been taken to provide U.S. insurance companies with competitive opportunities. Provides that if the USTR determines that any foreign government or country discriminates against U.S. insurance companies in connection with U.S. economic or military assistance, insurance for such activities may be provided only: (1) by U.S. insurance companies; or (2) by insurance companies of foreign countries which have entered into agreements concerning nondiscriminatory treatment of U.S. insurance companies or which have provided assurance of such nondiscriminatory treatment. Provides exceptions to such requirements if: (1) no insurance was reasonably available from a U.S. insurance company; or (2) the USTR certifies to the Congress that negotiations concerning discriminatory treatment of U.S. insurance companies are in progress. Requires the USTR to review the actions of each executive agency and military department required by this Act and to include a report concerning such actions in the USTR's required annual report to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
