<bill session="100" type="s" number="2420" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Arizona-Florida Land Exchange Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the disposition of certain lands in Arizona under the jurisdiction of the Department of the Interior by means of an exchange of lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-08-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-23">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Senate Committee on Energy and Natural Resources discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28">
      <text>Referred jointly to the Committees on Energy and Natural Resources; Indian Affairs; Veterans by unanimous consent with instructions that if the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources orders the bill to be reported, the other committees have twenty calendar days to report or be discharged.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-25">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held. Jointly with the Select Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Indian Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Child welfare"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Education of Indians"/>
    <term name="Educational facilities"/>
    <term name="Extended care facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Florida"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="High schools"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Nursing homes"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Recreation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
    <term name="Zoning and zoning law"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/20/1988--Introduced.
Arizona-Florida Land Exchange Act of 1988 - Title I - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to dispose of the real property used for the Phoenix Indian High School in Phoenix, Arizona. Ratifies the Agreement Among the United States, Collier Enterprises, and the Barron Collier Company under which the United States agrees to exchange such property for certain lands in Florida located in the Florida Panther National Wildlife Refuge owned by Collier and specified monetary proceeds. Requires the Secretary, if such Federal property is conveyed, to convey 20 acres of such property to the city of Phoenix to provide for public open space and recreation, to transfer administrative jurisdiction of 11.5 acres of such property to the Veterans Administration (VA) for expansion of a VA hospital, and to convey 4.5 acres of such property to the State of Arizona for the construction of a nursing home for veterans, provided that each such entity elects to accept such property. Provides that such property conveyed to Phoenix and Arizona shall revert to the United States if not used for the prescribed purposes. Requires Collier to provide 90 days' advance notice of its intention to accept the offer of the United States under the exchange agreement to the Secretary, the Mayor of Phoenix, the Administrator of the VA, the Intertribal Council of Arizona (ITCA), the governing body of the Navajo Tribe, and the Governor of Arizona. Requires the Secretary, not later that 45 days after receiving such notice from Collier, to publish notice that the Secretary will consider offers by persons other than Collier for the school property. Requires any such offer to provide for: (1) a single cash payment of a minimum acceptable price; (2) an agreement to make annual payments into the Arizona Intertribal Trust Fund or the Navajo Trust Fund; and (3) an offer to enter into a planning and zoning agreement with the city of Phoenix. Provides that: (1) if no qualifying offer is received, Collier may accept the U.S. offer under the exchange agreement; (2) if a qualifying offer is received, Collier will be allowed to match that offer; and (3) if Collier declines to match the best qualifying offer, the Secretary shall accept such offer. Provides for the management of school property which is not conveyed or which reverts to the United States under this Act. Provides for the deposit of the monetary proceeds from the school property into the Arizona Intertribal Trust Fund and the Navajo Trust Fund. Allows the Secretary to elect to receive such proceeds in a lump-sum payment or in 30 annual payments. Title II - Requires the Secretary to close the Phoenix Indian High School between June 1, 1988, and September 1, 1988. Requires the Secretary to notify the tribal governing body of each affected Arizona tribe and each student, or parent or guardian of each student, enrolled at the school within 30 days after the enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary to transfer administrative jurisdiction of the school property from the Bureau of Indian Affairs to the National Park Service within 60 days after the closure of the school. Authorizes the National Park Service to manage and control the property consistent with the requirements of the exchange agreement, although the School Property will not be considered a unit of the National Park System. Provides for the establishment of the Arizona Intertribal Trust Fund and the Navajo Trust Fund. Specifies that each fund shall consist of the portion of the monetary proceeds from the school property allocable to the fund. Requires the Secretary of the Treasury to: (1) invest any lump-sum payments into the trust fund into interest-bearing securities and deposits; or (2) hold the security provided by the purchaser in trust if payment into the trust funds is made in the form of annual payments. Authorizes the Secretary of the Treasury, at the direction of the Secretary of the Interior, to invest any portion of the trust income not used. Limits use of the trust income to supplemental educational and child-welfare programs, activities, and services and the design, construction, improvement, and repair of related facilities. Authorizes the Secretary, pursuant to appropriations and with the approval of the governing body of the affected tribe, to make grants from the trust funds to public school districts on or near the reservations. Directs the Secretary to make annual payments in an amount equal to five percent of the appropriate trust income to the ITCA and the governing body of the Navajo tribe. Limits the use of such income to education, child welfare, community development, and general administrative purposes. Prohibits the use of any part of the trust income for scholarship grants for higher education. Provides for the allocation of the monetary proceeds from school property into the trust funds, with 95 percent of the payment to be deposited into the Arizona Intertribal Trust Fund, and five percent to be deposited into the Navajo Trust Fund.</summary>
</bill>
