<bill session="100" type="s" number="2442" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Television and Radio Anti-Drug Advertising Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Communications Act of 1934 to provide for a program within the National Telecommunications and Information Administration to develop television and radio advertising regarding illegal drug use and to disseminate such advertising by means of mass media.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Mass media"/>
    <term name="Public service advertising"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television advertising"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/26/1988--Introduced.
Television and Radio Anti-Drug Advertising Act - Amends the Communications Act of 1934 to direct the Administrator of the National Telecommunications and Information Administration (NTIA) to establish a nationwide program to produce and disseminate television, radio, and other mass media advertising against the illegal use of drugs and other controlled substances. Sets conditions to be met by persons receiving funds in connection with the program. Establishes the Mass Media Advertising Advisory Committee to advise the NTIA Administrator concerning the program. Authorizes appropriations. Requires broadcasting licensees to allow reasonable access to time and to limit their charges for advertising in connection with the program.</summary>
</bill>
