<bill session="100" type="s" number="2447" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hydrogen-Fueled Aircraft Research and Development Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a hydrogen-fueled aircraft research and development.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407268"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Aeronautics"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Aircraft construction"/>
    <term name="Alternative energy sources"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation fuels"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy research"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Hydrogen as fuel"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1988--Introduced.
Hydrogen-Fueled Aircraft Research and Development Act - Directs the Administrator of the National Aeronautics and Space Administration to: (1) prepare and transmit to the Congress a comprehensive five-year program management plan regarding the development of a hydrogen-fueled aircraft capability; (2) submit an annual detailed description of such plan to the Congress after the initial transmittal; and (3) establish within the National Aeronautics and Space Administration a research and development program regarding such aircraft capability. Sets forth specified implementation steps including transmission to the Congress of a comprehensive flight demonstration plan. Confers responsibility upon the Secretary of Energy for those aspects of the research and development program which are suitable for a fully integrated hydrogen fueled aircraft system but which are not specifically developed for such application. Grants the Administrator overall management responsibility for program implementation. Establishes the Hydrogen-Fueled Aircraft Advisory Committee to advise the Administrator regarding the research and development program. Requires an annual report to the Administrator of its findings and recommendations. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992.</summary>
</bill>
