<bill session="100" type="s" number="2454" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Global Poverty Reduction Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to seek the eradication of the worst aspects of poverty in developing countries by the year 2000.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-10-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-08-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1988-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1988-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-06-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1988-06-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-06-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4277"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4277"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Infant mortality"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="World health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1988--Introduced.
Global Poverty Reduction Act - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to direct the President to develop a plan to ensure that U.S. development assistance contributes measurably toward eradicating the worst aspects of absolute poverty by the year 2000. Requires that such plan include target dates for reaching specific measurable goals whose attainment would contribute to direct improvements in the living standards of the poorest 40 percent of the population. Specifies that such goals shall include reducing the mortality rate of infants under age five, increasing the female literacy rate, and reducing the percentages of populations below the absolute poverty level by specified amounts by the year 2000. Directs that primary emphasis of development activities to restore the renewable natural resource base shall be on small-scale, affordable, low-risk local projects featuring close consultation with, and involvement of, local people at all stages of project design and implementation. Requires the President to submit the plan to the Congress by July 1, 1989. Requires all U.S. development assistance to be directed at attaining plan goals between October 1, 1989, and December 31, 2000. Requires the President to submit annual reports to the Congress detailing progress toward achieving plan goals. Directs the Comptroller General to review and comment on each report issued. Directs the President to host an international development conference for heads of governments of development assistance donor and recipient countries by October 16, 1989, to conclude an international agreement on eliminating the worst aspects of absolute poverty by the year 2000.</summary>
</bill>
