<bill session="100" type="s" number="2452" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to place a moratorium on the relocation of Navajo and Hopi Indians under Public Law 93-531, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-06-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="New Mexico"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1988--Introduced.
Prohibits: (1) the relocation of Navajo and Hopi Indians for an 18-month period; (2) the expenditure of Federal funds during such period with respect to certain lands held in trust for the Navajo and Hopi Tribes; and (3) construction on such lands during such period. Establishes the Navajo and Hopi Relocation Advisory Commission to study: (1) the problems resulting from the implementation of the Navajo-Hopi Land Settlement Act of 1974; and (2) alternatives to relocations required under such Act that meet the needs of traditional members of both the Hopi and Navajo traditional governments. Directs the Commission to hold public hearings regarding the lands involved in the relocation. Requires the Commission, within one year after enactment of this Act, to submit to the President and to the Congress a report on the study, including recommendations for solutions to the implementation problems and viable alternatives to the relocations. Provides for the termination of the Commission 30 days after it submits its report. Provides for the payment of funds necessary to carry out the provisions of this Act out of amounts appropriated to the Navajo and Hopi Indian Relocation Commission.</summary>
</bill>
