<bill session="100" type="s" number="2453" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the rehiring of certain former air traffic controllers.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1988--Introduced.
Provides that former air traffic controllers shall not, as a class, be considered unsuitable or ineligible for: (1) positions as air traffic controllers in the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) or the Department of Defense; or (2) any other positions in the FAA. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to establish and have in place by September 30, 1988, a full performance level air traffic controller workforce of specified size and composition. Directs the Secretary to establish for FY 1989, and for each succeeding fiscal year, air traffic controller workforce and full performance controller levels in accordance with this Act and goals established in the annual Department of Transportation Appropriations Act. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress by April 1 of each year the status of the air traffic controller workforce and full performance controller levels. Sets forth procedures for the rehiring of former controllers if the Secretary cannot meet the staffing goals required by this Act. Provides for a waiver of the maximum-age limitation applicable to such appointments. Prescribes procedural guidelines for competitive and non-competitive appointments of such controllers. Precludes an applicant's role in the 1981 strike from being considered when making a determination of suitability for an air traffic controller position. Requires the Secretary of Transportation and the Secretary of Defense to prescribe regulations under which the appointment of a former controller to an air traffic controller position within their respective departments shall not become final unless a probationary period has been successfully completed. Sets forth guidelines for the computation of creditability of service for retirement purposes. Expresses the sense of the Congress that such reinstatements should not: (1) cause the separation or reduction in grade of any other air traffic controller; or (2) interfere with training opportunities which would otherwise be afforded to air traffic controllers seeking to become fully qualified.</summary>
</bill>
