<bill session="100" type="s" number="245" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the reimbursement of states for advance construction of highways.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-01-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-01-21" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Highway construction and repair"/>
    <term name="Highway engineering"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Amends Federal law relating to construction by States in advance of apportionment to authorize the Secretary of Transportation to pay the Federal share of a State's highway construction project costs when a State: (1) has obligated all highway substitute, urban, secondary, or bridge funds apportioned or allocated to it, or has used or demonstrates that it will use the obligation authority allocated to it; and (2) proceeds to construct a highway substitute, urban, secondary, or bridge project without the aid of Federal funds; or (3) proceeds to construct any project on the Federal-aid primary system, including the Interstate System, without the aid of Federal funds. Provides that the Federal share of a State's construction costs on the Interstate System shall include the interest earned and payable on bonds issued by the State to the extent that the bond proceeds have been expended in the construction of such projects on the System. Prohibits the Secretary from approving applications for the Federal share of construction costs if the amount of approved applications in the category of funds involved exceeds certain apportionments for the applicant State.</summary>
</bill>
