<bill session="100" type="s" number="2461" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Foster Care Independent Living Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part E of title IV of the Social Security Act to extend and make necessary improvements in the independent living program under such part, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1988-07-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Social Security and Family Policy. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFI02" subcommittee="Social Security and Family Policy" name="Senate Finance"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Foster home care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1988--Introduced.
Foster Care Independent Living Amendments of 1988 - Amends part E (Foster Care and Adoption Assistance) of title IV of the Social Security Act to extend, through FY 1989, Federal assistance to States and localities in establishing and carrying out independent living initiatives programs to assist children in making the transition from foster care to independent living. Permits the FY 1989 expenditure of unobligated independent living program payments made to a State for FY 1987. Authorizes a State to include in its independent living program: (1) foster care children for whom the State is not making foster care maintenance payments; and (2) for six months, children for whom such care or payments were discontinued on or after their 16th birthday. Requires the application of procedural safeguards to any determination regarding the services needed to assist a child in the transition from foster care to independent living. Prohibits the use of Federal funding for independent living initiatives programs on room or board.</summary>
</bill>
