<bill session="100" type="s" number="2463" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-05-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, to improve the capability of Veterans' Administration health-care facilities to provide the most effective and appropriate services possible to veterans suffering from mental illness, especially conditions which are service-related, through the designation of centers of mental illness research, education, and clinical activities at up to five of its medical centers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1988-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-05-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-05-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-17">
      <text>Committee on Veterans requested executive comment from VA, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Mental care facilities"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental illness"/>
    <term name="Psychiatric research"/>
    <term name="Psychiatry"/>
    <term name="Psychology"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
    <term name="Veterans' medical care"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/27/1988--Introduced.
Directs the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to establish and operate up to five Veterans Administration health-care facilities as centers of mental illness research, education, and clinical activities, taking into account appropriate geographic distribution of such facilities. Precludes the Administrator from designating any health-care facility as a center unless the facility has (or may reasonably be anticipated to develop): (1) an arrangement with an accredited medical school and graduate school of psychology which provide education and training in psychiatry and psychology through regular rotation through such center so as to provide training in the diagnosis and treatment of mental illness; (2) an arrangement under which nursing, social work, or other allied health personnel receive education and training in mental health care through regular rotation through such facility; (3) the ability to attract the participation of scientists who are capable of ingenuity and creativity in research into the causes, treatment, and prevention of mental illness and into models for furnishing care and treatment to veterans suffering from mental illness; (4) a policymaking advisory committee to advise the directors of such facility and center on policy matters pertaining to the activities of such center; and (5) the capability to conduct effectively evaluations of the activities of such center. Authorizes appropriations. Declares that activities of clinical and scientific investigation at each center shall be eligible to compete for the award of funding from funds appropriated for the VA medical and prosthetics research account and shall receive priority insofar as funds are awarded to projects for mental illness. Requires the Chief Medical Director to ensure that: (1) research activities carried out through such centers include an appropriate emphasis on the psychosocial dimension of mental illness and on models for furnishing care and treatment to veterans suffering from mental illness; and (2) useful information produced by the centers is disseminated throughout the Department of Medicine and Surgery. Requires the Administrator to submit to the House and Senate Committees on Veterans Affairs an annual report on the activities and effectiveness of the centers.</summary>
</bill>
