<bill session="100" type="s" number="2479" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-24">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Immigration Technical Corrections Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="enacted">Immigration Technical Corrections Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Immigration and Nationality Act to make technical correction in immigration-related laws.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-06-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1988-06-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-06-07" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-10-06" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-10-24" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-525" type="public" datetime="1988-10-24">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-525.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural labor"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Alien labor"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Cubans"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Haitians"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Illegal aliens"/>
    <term name="Illegitimacy"/>
    <term name="Immigrants"/>
    <term name="Immigration law"/>
    <term name="Immigration policy"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Migrant labor"/>
    <term name="National socialism"/>
    <term name="Passports"/>
    <term name="Right of privacy"/>
    <term name="Seasonal labor"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Tourist trade"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1988--Introduced.
Immigration Technical Corrections Act of 1988 - Makes technical amendments to provisions of the Immigration and Nationality Act (INA) as amended by the Immigration Reform and Control Act of 1986 (IRCA) with respect to: (1) employer sanctions in connection with control of unlawful employment of aliens; (2) unfair immigration-related employment practices; (3) unlawful transportation of aliens to the United States; and (4) restrictions on adjustment of status. Makes an immigration-related technical correction in the Higher Education Act of 1965 with respect to educational assistance. Makes technical corrections of the INA with respect to the legalization of alien status, including amendments to: (1) include developmentally disabled individuals as eligible for waivers from basic citizenship skill requirements; and (2) permit exceptions to confidentiality requirements for specified Government reporting purposes. Makes technical amendments to the IRCA to: (1) authorize the Attorney General to waive misrepresentation of a relevant material fact as a reason to exclude Cuban-Haitian aliens from admission into the United States; and (2) make World War II Nazis ineligible for a record of lawful admission for permanent residence. Amends provisions relating to: (1) State legalization impact-assistance grants in connection with special agricultural workers; and (2) temporary agricultural workers under the H-2A program. Amends INA provisions relating to G-1V special immigrants. Makes technical amendments of ICRA provisions concerning the visa waiver pilot program for certain visitors. Amends the IRCA to limit to one percent the portion of funds appropriated for the Commission for the Study of International Migration and Cooperative Economic Development that may be spent on official entertainment. Makes technical amendments of the INA with respect to: (1) visa waivers for nonimmigrant visitors to Guam; and (2) the nationality of certain American Samoans. Makes technical revisions and corrections of INA provisions amended by the Department of Justice Appropriation Act, 1987, the Narcotics Traffickers Deportation Act, and the Refugee Assistance Extension Act of 1986. Makes technical amendments of the Immigration Marriage Fraud Amendments of 1986, including a limitation on adjustment of status petitions of alien fiance(e)s of U.S. citizens ("K" nonimmigrants). Makes technical amendments of the Immigation and Nationality Act Amendments of 1986, including amendments in connection with effective dates of various provisions affecting the nationality of children born out of wedlock to at least one American parent. Makes various other technical amendments and corrections of the INA.</summary>
</bill>
