<bill session="100" type="s" number="2475" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:49-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-14">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Farmers' Market Nutrition Enhancement Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Child Nutrition Act of 1986 to authorize the establishment of a demonstration project to provide coupons to recipients of assistance under the special supplemental food program for women, infants, and children for use at farmers' markets.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300051"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-14" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Agriculture. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 2560 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="2560"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Child nutrition"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Farms"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Marketing of farm produce"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/7/1988--Introduced.
Farmers' Market Nutrition Enhancement Act - Amends the Child Nutrition Act of 1966 to authorize three-year demonstration project grants in seven States to provide coupons (between ten and 20 dollars' worth) to special supplemental food program (WIC) recipients for use at farmers' markets. Requires at least 30 percent State matching funds. Sets minimum and maximum grant amounts at $75,000 and $700,000, respectively. Prohibits the use of funds to construct or operate a farmers' market. Limits the use of funds for administrative costs. Requires: (1) State recipients to make annual reports to the Secretary of Agriculture; and (2) the Secretary to provide the Congress with a project evaluation report within two years after the last grant award. Authorizes FY 1989 through 1991 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
