<bill session="100" type="s" number="249" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:27-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Parental and Medical Leave Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to grant employees parental and temporary medical leave under certain circumstances, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-10-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Labor Department, Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-29">
      <text>Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR03" subcommittee="Labor" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSHR06" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Adoption"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Maternal and infant welfare"/>
    <term name="Maternity leave"/>
    <term name="Parents"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Parental and Medical Leave Act of 1987 - Title I: General Requirements for Parental and Medical Leave - Entitles employees to parental leave for specified periods in cases involving the birth, adoption, or serious health condition of a child. Entitles employees to temporary medical leave for specified periods in cases involving inability to work because of a serious health condition. Sets forth conditions for certification for such types of leave. Provides that such leave may be without pay. Allows employees to substitute other types of paid leave to cover part of such leave period. Sets forth employment and benefits protections relating to such leave. Provides for administrative enforcement of this title by the Secretary of Labor, as well as enforcement by civil action. Sets forth provisions for injunctive relief, monetary relief, and attorneys' fees. Requires employers to post notice of the pertinent provisions of this title. Title II: Parental Leave and Temporary Medical Leave for Civil Service Employees - Amends specified Federal law to entitle civil service employees to parental leave and temporary medical leave for specified periods. Provides that such leave will be without pay. Allows employees to substitute other types of paid leave for part of such leave. Sets forth protection for job position and health insurance benefits of employees using such leave. Directs the Office of Personnel Management to prescribe regulations for administration of this title which are consistent with the regulations prescribed by the Secretary of Labor under title I of this Act. Title III: Advisory Panel on Paid Parental and Medical Leave - Establishes the Advisory Panel on Paid Parental and Medical Leave. Requires the Panel to report on its study of paid parental and medical leave to the Congress within two years after the Panel first meets. Terminates the Panel within 30 days after its final report. Title IV: Miscellaneous Provisions - Sets forth the effect of this Act on existing laws and existing employment benefits. Directs the Secretary of Labor to prescribe regulations to carry out title I of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
