<bill session="100" type="s" number="2491" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans Services Improvements Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Secretary of Labor to simplify the application and problem-resolution processes relating to certain services and benefits, and to establish and carry out a job bank and job matching program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-06-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Labor Department, Education Department, VA, Defense Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-15">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Employment and Productivity.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR04" subcommittee="Employment and Productivity" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Data banks"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational counseling"/>
    <term name="Employment agencies"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Job hunting"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
    <term name="Veterans' employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/9/1988--Introduced.
Veterans Services Improvements Act of 1988 - Requires the Secretary of Labor to provide in offices in each State: (1) information concerning employment assistance under the Job Training Partnership Act and the Veterans' Job Training Act, employment assistance and unemployment compensation under the trade adjustment assistance program and any other program administered by the Employment and Training Administration, educational assistance for veterans and under the Adult Education Act, veterans' training and rehabilitation programs, and services available in connection with the job bank and job matching program established under this Act; (2) all forms necessary for applying for services, claiming benefits, and resolving questions under such programs; (3) assistance in applying for such services and benefits; and (4) administrative services for accepting and forwarding application forms for such programs to the appropriate department or agency of the Federal Government or of a State. Requires the Secretary of Labor to establish and carry out a nationwide computerized job bank and job matching program for veterans, armed forces reserve members, and individuals recently discharged or released from the armed forces. Authorizes appropriations. Authorizes the use of Job Training Partnership Act funds and other sources of funds for such program.</summary>
</bill>
