<bill session="100" type="s" number="2511" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a pilot program for providing assistance to certain veterans who have service-connected disabilities and are quadriplegic, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21">
      <text>Committee on Veterans requested executive comment from VA, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-19">
      <text>Committee on Veterans received executive comment from VA.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Deaf"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Dogs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Hearing disorders"/>
    <term name="Paraplegia"/>
    <term name="Pets"/>
    <term name="Primates"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/14/1988--Introduced.
Requires the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to conduct pilot programs during FY 1989, 1990, and 1991 under which the Administrator: (1) provides assistive monkeys to certain veterans who have service-connected disabilities and are quadriplegic and facilitates the provision of such monkeys to other veterans who are quadriplegic; and (2) provides dogs specially trained to provide hearing assistance to deaf individuals to certain veterans with service-connected hearing impairments, if the Administrator determines that the Veterans Administration is not currently authorized to provide such dogs. Requires the Administrator to: (1) determine the costs, benefits, and effectiveness of such pilot program; and (2) report to the Congress the results of such evaluation and the Administrator's views on the relationship between the provision of such a monkey and the payment of an aid and attendance allowance or an annual pension based on the need for aid and attendance.</summary>
</bill>
