<bill session="100" type="s" number="2531" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Anti-Public Corruption Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18 of the United States Code to create a criminal offense for public corruption.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300072"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1988-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4871"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4871"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Election administration"/>
    <term name="Electronic surveillance"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Misconduct in office"/>
    <term name="Organized crime"/>
    <term name="Public corruption"/>
    <term name="State officials and employees"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Voter registration"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/17/1988--Introduced.
Anti-Public Corruption Act of 1988 - Makes it a crime for any person to endeavor by scheme or artifice corruptly to deprive or defraud the inhabitants of a State or political subdivision of the honest services of a State or local official or employee or to deprive inhabitants of a fair and impartially conducted election through fraudulent ballots or voter registration forms. Specifies the jurisdictional bases for the offenses as the use of the U.S. mails, use of interstate or foreign communications, or use of or effect on interstate or foreign commerce. Imposes criminal penalties for endeavoring to deprive or defraud U.S. inhabitants of the honest services of a public official or person selected to be a public official. Amends the Racketeer Influenced and Corrupt Organizations statute (RICO) and electronic surveillance statutes to add a reference to the public corruption offenses created by this Act.</summary>
</bill>
