<bill session="100" type="s" number="254" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Tax Delinquency Amnesty Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide a one-time amnesty from criminal and civil tax penalties and 50 percent of the interest penalty owed for certain taxpayers who pay previous underpayments of Federal tax during the amnesty period, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1954 to increase by 50 percent all criminal and civil tax penalties, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403483"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Internal Revenue Service (IRS)"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Tax amnesty"/>
    <term name="Tax evasion"/>
    <term name="White collar crime"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Federal Tax Delinquency Amnesty Act of 1987 - Provides for a one-time amnesty from criminal and civil tax penalties for a taxpayer who: (1) files a written statement with specified information concerning any underpayment of tax; (2) pays the amount of such underpayment when filing the statement; and (3) within 30 days of notification, pays 50 percent of the amount of interest payable on any underpayment (and the amount of any tax delinquent amount). Permits installment payments in certain cases. Defines the amnesty period as the six-month period beginning July 1, 1987, or beginning the first July 1 after the enactment of this Act. Applies such amnesty to all payments relating to tax years ending before January 1, 1986, or taxable events occurring before January 1, 1986. Disallows such amnesty where: (1) the taxpayer was contacted before a statement was filed; (2) there was fraud in seeking amnesty; (3) a criminal investigation is pending; or (4) the income involved is illegal source income. Authorizes appropriations to administer such amnesty program and to employ 3,000 additional Internal Revenue Service agents. Increases criminal and civil tax penalties by 50 percent.</summary>
</bill>
