<bill session="100" type="s" number="2550" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 23, United States Code, to eliminate a reduction of the apportionment of Federal-aid highway funds to certain States and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410588"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1988-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="Speed limits"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/21/1988--Introduced.
Amends Federal-aid highway law to repeal the requirement that each State certify it is enforcing all speed limits on public highways as a prerequisite to obtaining the approval of the Secretary of Transportation for its plans and specifications regarding highway projects eligible for Federal-aid highway funds. Prohibits the Secretary from approving any Federal-aid highway plans in any State that fails to certify annually that: (1) any public highway posted at a maximum speed limit of 55 miles per hour or higher and constructed with Federal funds has been designed and constructed to standards appropriate for the permitted speed; and (2) it has been enforcing during the immediately preceding calendar year speed limits posted at 55 miles per hour or higher. Repeals provisions relating to the reduction of a State's Federal-aid highway funds apportionments for non-compliance with the 55 mile-per-hour speed limit. Mandates that each State report to the Secretary speed monitoring data on public highways with speed limits posted at 55 miles per hour or higher in the same manner as such data was submitted for the fiscal year immediately preceding the enactment of this Act. Prohibits the Secretary from approving plans for a proposed Federal-aid highway project on a system which is to be posted at a maximum speed limit of 55 miles per hour or higher if such plans fail to provide for a facility designed and constructed for a speed limit equal to or greater than that to be posted upon completion.</summary>
</bill>
