<bill session="100" type="s" number="2578" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Canals"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Pennsylvania"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/28/1988--Introduced.
Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Act of 1988 - Establishes the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania. Establishes the Delaware and Lehigh Navigation Canal National Heritage Corridor Commission to assist appropriate Federal, State, and local authorities in the development and implementation of an integrated resource management plan for the Corridor. Directs the Commission, within one year after a specified review by the National Park Service, to submit to the Secretary of the Interior a Cultural Heritage and Corridor Management Plan which: (1) provides an inventory of Corridor property to be preserved and restored because of its national historic or cultural significance; (2) develops a historic interpretive plan; and (3) recommends policies for resource management of the Corridor. Terminates the Commission in five years, with a possible five-year extension. Requires the Secretary to approve or disapprove the Commission's Plan within 60 days after its receipt. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
