<bill session="100" type="s" number="2572" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Medicare Graduate Nurse Training Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to recognize as an allowable cost under the medicare program the reasonable costs incurred by a provider in conducting, by contract with an educational institution, certain approved educational activities under a post-graduate nursing program, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-09-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Nurses"/>
    <term name="Nursing"/>
    <term name="Nursing education"/>
    <term name="Nursing students"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/27/1988--Introduced.
Medicare Graduate Nurse Training Act of 1988 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to cover, from FY 1989 through 1992, the reasonable costs incurred by a hospital in conducting, by agreement with an educational institution, a graduate clinical nurse training program. Reimburses hospitals for the costs of such programs on the same basis as hospitals are reimbursed for resident physician program costs. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to report to the Congress by January 1, 1992, on the effect of such coverage on the supply and characteristics of nurses. Authorizes the Secretary to conduct up to four demonstration projects under each of which a hospital tests the effects of different personnel-related activities in promoting the recruitment and retention of nurses. Requires that such projects conclude before FY 1989. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress on the results of such projects by January 1, 1992. Authorizes appropriations for the demonstration projects from FY 1989 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
