<bill session="100" type="s" number="2597" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an interdisciplinary training grant program for the benefit of rural areas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-07-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-07-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to medical education"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to, or enter into contracts with, eligible applicants for interdisciplinary training projects relating to health care in rural areas. Declares that allowed uses for funds include stipends to students, post-doctoral fellowships, enhancement of faculty, or purchase or rental of transportation and telecommunication equipment. Requires applications to: (1) be jointly submitted by at least two eligible applicants with the purpose of assisting individuals in academic institutions in establishing long-term collaborative relationships with health care providers in rural areas; and (2) designate one or more rural health care agencies for clinical treatment or training. Directs the Secretary to contract for a study of manpower training needs in rural areas: (1) paying particular attention to the needs of the rural elderly and the rural population that is not eligible for Medicare; and (2) evaluating existing models for health care training and service delivery and proposing innovative alternative models. Sets forth reporting requirements. Authorizes appropriations to carry out the study and reporting for FY 1990. Authorizes appropriations to carry out this Act for FY 1988 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
