<bill session="100" type="s" number="2598" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-29">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-06-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Waste Export Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to ensure that waste exported from the United States to foreign countries is managed in a manner so as to protect human health and the environment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1988-06-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-06-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-06-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/29/1988--Introduced.
Waste Export Control Act - Prohibits the exportation of waste from the United States, except as provided for by this Act. Sets forth the required content of applications to the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) for waste export permits, including information demonstrating that exported waste will be transported, treated, stored, and disposed of in a manner providing environmental protection no less strict than that required in this country. Gives the public notice and an opportunity to comment on an application before the issuance of a permit. Sets a maximum term of five years for such permits. Requires that permit terms and conditions, at a minimum, be equivalent to and consistent with the standards and requirements applicable to waste management in this country under the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act and regulations promulgated thereunder. Directs the EPA to impose fees on permitees and permit applicants to cover all the costs of such permit program. Subjects individuals who violate any provision of this Act to monetary penalties, and individuals who export waste without a permit or in knowing violation of a material condition of a permit to a fine and/or imprisonment. Exempts certain waste from this Act's provisions on the basis of national security considerations or its exportation for recycling or reuse.</summary>
</bill>
