<bill session="100" type="s" number="2628" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">New Jersey-New York Medical Waste Tracking Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Solid Waste Disposal Act to establish a pilot program for the tracking of medical wastes in the States of New York and New Jersey.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-07-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-07-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="New Jersey"/>
    <term name="New York State"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/11/1988--Introduced.
New Jersey-New York Medical Waste Tracking Act of 1988 - Amends the Solid Waste Disposal Act to require the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a demonstration program to track, by the use of a manifest system, medical waste generated and disposed of in New York and New Jersey. Makes such program applicable to generators of medical waste and owners and operators of facilities for the treatment, storage, transport, and disposal of medical waste. Requires such parties to permit access to and provide copies of all records relating to such wastes to any designated EPA representative. Provides for the enforcement of program requirements by use of the Act's hazardous waste management enforcement mechanisms. Prohibits the interpretation of this Act as precluding any State or locality from imposing more stringent requirements for the control or monitoring of medical waste. Requires the EPA to report to the Congress on the progress of the demonstration program. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 and 1991.</summary>
</bill>
