<bill session="100" type="s" number="263" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Tennessee Valley Authority Fiscal Responsibility and Accountability Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tennessee Valley Authority Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405795"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bonds"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Inspectors general"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Tennessee Valley Authority"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Tennessee Valley Authority Fiscal Responsibility and Accountability Act of 1987 - Amends the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 to limit members of the board of directors of the Tennessee Valley Authority (the Corporation) to two three-year terms. Reduces the Corporation's bond ceiling from $30,000,000,000 to $18,000,000,000. Prohibits the Federal Financing Bank from purchasing obligations issued or guaranteed by the Corporation after enactment of this Act. Requires the Corporation to pay the principal and interest on bonds on a timely basis. Amends the Inspector General Act of 1978 to establish a permanent Office of Inspector General for the Corporation. Amends the Tennessee Valley Authority Act of 1933 to make the Corporation subject to State regulation as if it were a private utility, except that a State may not interfere with the obligations of the Corporation imposed by law. Repeals the permanent authorization of appropriations for the Corporation.</summary>
</bill>
