<bill session="100" type="s" number="2644" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Health Payment Reform Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to make certain payment reforms in the Medicare Program to ensure the adequate provision of health care in rural areas, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1988-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1988-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-07-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Capital"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical education"/>
    <term name="Medical personnel"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Obstetrics"/>
    <term name="Physicians"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1988--Introduced.
Rural Health Payment Reform Act of 1988 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to guarantee at least a 3.8 percent increase in payments for rural hospital services in FY 1989. Sets such increase for sole community hospitals at the market basket percentage increase. Exempts hospitals that meet the criteria for sole community hospital status, regardless of whether they elect to be paid on that basis, from reductions in Medicare payments for capital costs. Amends part B (Supplementary Medical Insurance) of the Medicare Program to increase, beginning in FY 1990, the incentive payment for physician services in rural health manpower shortage areas from five to ten percent of the regular payment for such services. Requires the Secretary of Health and Human Services to enter into agreements with from five to ten hospitals to conduct three-year demonstration projects providing instruction and consultation to physicians in rural areas that are designated as either class one or two health manpower shortage areas under the Public Health Service Act. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress by July 1, 1990, and March 1, 1992, regarding such projects. Authorizes appropriations for the projects. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with States to conduct demonstration projects to improve the access of pregnant women and children who are eligible for Medicaid (title XIX of the Act) benefits to obstetrical and pediatric services. Requires that the Secretary give priority to States that emphasize improving such access in rural communities experiencing a decline in essential services for pregnant women and children. Increases the Federal matching for such demonstration project services by the lesser of ten percent or the percentage necessary to raise such rate to 90 percent. Terminates such projects before 1993. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress by March 1, 1993, regarding such projects.</summary>
</bill>
