<bill session="100" type="s" number="2646" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-07-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">American Partnership for Our Children's Future Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow for a refundable credit against tax for dependents who have not attained the age of compulsory school attendance, to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow an employer who implements a child care and/or comprehensive parental and medical leave program(s) for employees to exclude from gross taxable income any amount spent implementing and executing these programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405305"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-07-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Employer incentives"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Leave of absence"/>
    <term name="Parental leave"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/14/1988--Introduced.
American Partnership for Our Children's Future Act of 1988 - Title I: Income Tax Provisions - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an individual taxpayer a refundable income tax credit, in an amount based on adjusted gross income (minimum credit of $150), for each dependent below the age of compulsory school attendance in the State where the taxpayer resides. Sets the maximum credit amount as the total employee tax withheld from the taxpayer's wages during the year under the Federal Insurance Contributions Act. Disallows application of the nonrefundable dependent care income tax credit with respect to a taxpayer's dependents under age 15, unless the child is physically or mentally incapable of self-care. Title II: Employer Income Tax Incentives - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to exclude from gross income amounts spent by an employer in providing employee child care, comprehensive parental and medical leave programs, or both.</summary>
</bill>
