<bill session="100" type="s" number="266" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Service Contract Reform Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Service Contract Act to reform the administration of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300159" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-01-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300154" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-01-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="412006" joined="1987-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Labor Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR03" subcommittee="Labor" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Fringe benefits"/>
    <term name="Government service contracts"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Service Contract Reform Act of 1987 - Amends the Service Contract Act of 1965 to raise from $2,500 to $200,000 the minimum size of a private service contract with the Federal Government subject to such Act. Declares that such Act applies only to contracts whose principal purpose is to furnish services. Revises provisions regarding predecessor contracts. Provides that a successor contractor shall not be required to pay the wages and fringe benefits of a predecessor contractor unless the Secretary of Labor establishes that wages and fringe benefits under the successor contract are less than prevailing wages and fringe benefits in the locality in which the work is to be performed. Directs the Secretary to make wage and fringe benefit determinations for service contracts under which 25 or more service employees are to be employed. (Current law requires such determinations for five or more service employees.)</summary>
</bill>
