<bill session="100" type="s" number="2689" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Calumet National Historical Park Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the Calumet National Historical Park in the State of Michigan, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-08-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Michigan"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1988--Introduced.
Calumet National Historical Park Act of 1988 - Establishes the Calumet National Historical Park, including the C and H Mining Company properties, the Quincy Mining Company Historic District, and the Calumet Historic Preservation District, in Michigan. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to acquire by donation or purchase historic structures, mine ruins, and other properties representing the copper industry and its association with the cultural development of Calumet. Authorizes the Secretary to enter into agreements with other Federal, State, and local agencies to provide for the preservation of historic sites within the Park. Establishes the Calumet Historic Preservation Commission. Provides that the Commission shall terminate ten years from enactment of this Act. Directs the Secretary and the Commission to prepare a park preservation plan which meets specified requirements. Requires the Secretary to forward such plan to the Congress. Prohibits the Secretary from providing funds to the Commission until such plan has been prepared and submitted to the Congress. Authorizes the Commission to make loans and grants and provide technical assistance to corporations and to owners of property within the Park for the preservation or development of property within the Park and preservation district. Sets forth the powers of the Commission. Authorizes appropriations. Declares it is Congress' intent that a visitor and interpretive facility be established by the National Park Service to promote the Park.</summary>
</bill>
