<bill session="100" type="s" number="2686" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the use and distribution of certain funds awarded the Sioux Nation of Indians.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408898"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Federal-Indian relations"/>
    <term name="Indian claims"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="South Dakota"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1988--Introduced.
States that the funds appropriated in satisfaction of the judgment awarded the Sioux Nation in Sioux Nation of Indians, et al. v. United States shall be used and distributed as provided in this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Interior to invest the funds until distribution, compile a roll of eligible individuals, publish notices, and determine per capita shares. Requires the Secretary to conduct an election of roll individuals asking for a vote on whether the individual wants to accept payment of the per capita share. Provides for confidentiality in the voting. States that if a majority of voters accept payment of the per capita share, the funds shall be distributed, but that if a majority vote to reject such payment, no funds may be distributed under this Act. Provides that a vote to accept payments shall constitute full and complete satisfaction of the judgment in the civil action and shall confirm that all claims arising out of the taking of the Black Hills by the United States are extinguished.</summary>
</bill>
