<bill session="100" type="s" number="2684" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title II of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide personal earnings and benefits statements to individuals covered by Social Security, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Tax administration"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/4/1988--Introduced.
Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to provide, upon request, beginning on October 1, 1989, a personal earnings and benefits statement to individuals who have a social security number, have wages or self-employment earnings, and have attained age 25 (hereinafter referred to as "eligible individuals"). Directs the Secretary to assure that eligible individuals are informed of the availability of the statement. Makes the provision of such statement to each eligible individual who has attained age 60 mandatory by October 1, 1991, if his or her mailing address can be determined. Requires the provision of such statement at least once every three years by October 1, 2000, to each eligible individual for whom a mailing address can be determined. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress by October 1, 1991, on plans to provide statements to all eligible individuals by 2000. Requires the Comptroller General to conduct a study and report to the Secretary by October 1, 1990, on improving the coordination between, and the accuracy of, the wage-reporting systems used by the Social Security Administration, the Internal Revenue Service, and the States. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to authorize the Internal Revenue Service to disclose the mailing address of an eligible individual to the Social Security Administration.</summary>
</bill>
