<bill session="100" type="s" number="2698" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide Federal assistance to the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1988-10-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1988-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1988-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-09-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1988-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1988-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1988-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1988-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-09-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1988-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-08-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-10-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-23">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, GAO.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational associations"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Rating of teachers"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/9/1988--Introduced.
National Board for Professional Teaching Standards Act of 1988 - Directs the Secretary of Education to provide financial assistance to the National Board for Professional Teaching Standards (a private non-profit organization) for research and development relating to teacher assessment and certification procedures. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 for such purpose. Sets forth terms and conditions for such assistance. Requires the Board to: (1) establish a Research and Development Advisory Committee; and (2) consult with the Secretary and other specified entities in appointing the ten Committee members (with the Secretary selecting two of those). Requires funds under this Act to be used only for research and development of teacher assessment and certification procedures for elementary and secondary school teachers. Requires that priority be given to activities relating to teaching: (1) the subject areas of mathematics, the sciences, foreign languages, and literacy (including reading, writing, and analytical ability); and (2) special educational populations, including limited English proficient children, gifted and talented children, handicapped children, and economically and educationally disadvantaged children. Sets forth application requirements. Sets the Federal share of the cost of such Board activities at 50 percent. Requires the Board to report annually to the appropriate committees of Congress. Requires the Department of Education, the National Science Foundation, and the National Research Council to review and comment on the Board's report and to report to such committees on the Board's compliance with this Act. Sets forth auditing provisions. Sets forth limitations on the ways this Act may be construed.</summary>
</bill>
