<bill session="100" type="s" number="2693" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">PCB Control Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "PCB Control Act of 1988".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1988-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13">
      <text>Subcommittee on Hazardous Wastes and Toxic. Approved for full committee consideration with an amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Markup, Reporting" code="SSEV03" subcommittee="Hazardous Wastes and Toxic Substances" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Polychlorinated biphenyls"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1988--Introduced.
PCB Control Act of 1988 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to require those who intend to deal in the transportation, storage, or disposal of polychlorinated biphenyls (PCBs) to notify the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency of such intent and receive an identification number from the Administrator before engaging in such activities. Directs such individuals to comply with the requirements of a manifest system set forth in rules to be promulgated by the Administrator within 60 days of this Act's enactment. Directs the Administrator to promulgate rules, within 60 days of this Act's enactment, for the transportation of PCBs and the implementation of a PCB storage approval process. Conditions the Administrator's approval of the storage or disposal of PCBs on the applicant's compliance with financial responsibility, contingency plan, and closure and post-closure requirements. Requires that each approval for PCB disposal or storage be reviewed and, if necessary, modified within five years of its issuance or reissuance. Authorizes the Administrator to revoke such approval for an individual's noncompliance with this Act's requirements. Directs the Administrator to thoroughly inspect PCB storage and disposal facilities at least once every two years. Requires the Administrator to publish notice, by June 30 of each year, of the identify of, and the amount of civil penalty assessed from, each person against whom the Administrator has concluded an enforcement action for noncompliance with this Act's requirements during the previous calendar year. Amends the Resource Conservation and Recovery Act (RCRA) to designate PCBs as a hazardous waste to be regulated under such Act six months after this Act's enactment. Directs the Administrator, within two years of this Act's enactment, to revise Toxic Substances Control Act requirements where necessary to protect human health and the environment or satisfy RCRA requirements</summary>
</bill>
