<bill session="100" type="s" number="2695" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Civil Service Retirees' Interest on Delayed Payments Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 5, United States Code, to provide for the payment of interest on delayed initial payments under the Civil Service Retirement System and the Federal Employees' Retirement System and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401391"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Annuities"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Interest"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1988--Introduced.
Civil Service Retirees' Interest on Delayed Payments Act - Requires the initial payment of an annuity under the Civil Service Retirement System to be made: (1) in the case of immediate retirement, not more than 75 days after the date on which the employee is separated from service; or (2) in the case of deferred retirement or a survivors' annuity, not more than 75 days after the date on which the Office of Personnel Management (OPM) receives a completed application from the individual. Requires the initial payment of an annuity under the Federal Employees' Retirement System to be made: (1) in the case of immediate retirement or early retirement, not more than 75 days after the date on which the employee is separated from service; or (2) in the case of deferred retirement, not more than 45 days after the date on which OPM receives a completed application from the individual. Requires OPM to pay interest to the individual entitled to such an annuity for each day the initial payment of such annuity is delayed. Makes the applicable Federal agency liable for any interest amounts caused by its delay in forwarding retirement records to OPM.</summary>
</bill>
