<bill session="100" type="s" number="2697" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Atlantic Marine Fisheries Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend certain marine fisheries laws to promote effective fishery conservation and management, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-08-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1988-08-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Ordered, that if and when reported, the bill be referred to the Committee on Envirnment and Public Works for a period not to exceed 14 calendar days for consideration of sections four and five of the bill.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Anadromous fishes"/>
    <term name="Atlantic Ocean"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/8/1988--Introduced.
Atlantic Marine Fisheries Act of 1988 - Amends the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act to direct the Secretary of Commerce, when State regulations or a Federal moratorium on fishing for Atlantic striped bass within the coastal waters of a coastal State are in effect, to promulgate regulations governing fishing for such fish in the exclusive economic zone. Authorizes the appropriate Regional Fishery Management Councils to prepare a fishery management plan on Atlantic striped bass. Provides that such plan, if approved and implemented by the Secretary, shall supersede any regulations promulgated under this Act. Terminates provisions of this Act relating to fishing regulations and authorization of a fishery management plan on September 30, 1991. Amends the Atlantic Striped Bass Conservation Act to authorize appropriations for 1988 through 1991. Extends the termination date for such Act to September 30, 1991. Amends the Anadromous Fish Conservation Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
