<bill session="100" type="s" number="2692" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the initiation of trade negotiations with Japan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Balance of payments"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Dumping"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Tariff preferences"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/5/1988--Introduced.
Directs the President to initiate multilateral trade negotiations with Japan by June 30, 1990, that meet the following objectives: (1) to establish numerical goals for increased trade between the United States and Japan and control of the bilateral balance of trade between such countries; (2) to address specific trade problems, including the establishment of stronger rules for recidivist dumping and the establishment of trade preferences to encourage the export to Japan of the products of least developed countries; (3) to increase the degree of coordination between U.S. and Japanese macroeconomic policies through the establishment of minimum and maximum rates of exchange between the currency of such countries and the coordination of consumer and government expenditures to achieve balance in the current account; and (4) to increase the amount of funds expended by Japan for foreign assistance, debt relief of less developed countries, and compensation to the United States for U.S. military expenditures for the defense of Japan. Requires the President to consult with specified congressional committees. Provides for implementation of such agreement.</summary>
</bill>
