<bill session="100" type="s" number="2702" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide OPIC insurance, reinsurance, and financing to eligible projects in Poland.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1988-10-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1988-08-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-08-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign license agreements"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Poland"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/9/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the Overseas Private Investment Corporation (OPIC) to issue insurance or reinsurance, guarantee loans, or extend financing for eligible investors with respect to projects in Poland only if such projects are undertaken in conjunction with the nongovernmental sector in Poland. Requires OPIC to annually certify to the Congress that businesses in Poland with respect to which OPIC has undertaken any such activities do not violate any internationally recognized workers' rights. Prohibits OPIC from undertaking any such activities with respect to any project in Poland: (1) which fosters unfair competition with import-sensitive U.S. industries or leads to significantly adverse impacts on U.S. employment; or (2) until the Secretary of State has certified that the Government of Poland has enacted laws which significantly improve the operating conditions for private enterprises in Poland, including the reform of present laws governing joint ventures and the licensing of new businesses.</summary>
</bill>
