<bill session="100" type="s" number="2709" updated="2016-06-29T08:46:15-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the United States' obligation to observe occupational safety and health standards and to clarify the United States' responsibility for harm caused by negligence at any workplace owned by, operated by, or under contract with the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409562"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1988-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1988-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-10-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-09-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1988-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1988-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative law and regulatory procedures"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts of special jurisdiction"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government litigation"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Occupational health and safety"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Makes the legal defense of discretionary function provided under specified Federal law and the legal doctrine of foreseeability of damages inapplicable to any legal or administrative proceeding for damages arising out of U.S. violation of occupational safety or health standards or U.S. negligence at any workplace owned or operated by or under contract with the United States. Prohibits the foreseeability doctrine from being used to limit the amount or kind of damages otherwise available to the plaintiff. Sets forth a statute of limitations of two years after the date of enactment of this Act or after the date of the harm. Establishes a National Registry of Government Litigants, within the U.S. Claims Court, to collect and maintain data regarding claims against the United States predicated (in whole or in part) upon U.S. violation of safety and health standards. Allows any person seeking damages from the United States on the basis (in whole or part) of harm resulting from U.S. violation of safety and health standards to file a notice of such fact with the U.S. Claims Court, within 30 days after commencement of such action (whether administrative or judicial in character). Directs the chief judge of the U.S. Claims Court to report annually to the Congress on the number of, and relevant facts and common characteristics underlying, such notices filed within the Registry.</summary>
</bill>
