<bill session="100" type="s" number="2701" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:53-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-28">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Bureau of Standards Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1989</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">National Technical Information Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize appropriations for the National Bureau of Standards for fiscal year 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1988-06-28" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-08-09">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Hollings. With written report No. 100-466.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-08-09" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="882">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 882.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Awards, medals, prizes"/>
    <term name="Books"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Communication in science"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Depository libraries"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Engineering"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to research"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government publications"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Industrial productivity"/>
    <term name="Industrial standards"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Intellectual property"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Inventions"/>
    <term name="Inventors"/>
    <term name="Iron and steel industry"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Laboratories"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Manufacturing industries"/>
    <term name="Materials research"/>
    <term name="Newspapers and Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
    <term name="Periodicals"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Regional economic development"/>
    <term name="Research"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Research and development contracts"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Steel"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Technology policy"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Weights and measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/9/1988--Introduced.
National Bureau of Standards Authorization Act for Fiscal Year 1989 - Title I: National Bureau of Standards Authorization Authorizations for Program Activities - Authorizes appropriations to the Secretary of Commerce for FY 1989 to carry out the following activities of the National Bureau of Standards (NBS) (now the National Institute of Standards and Technology (NIST)) (1) measurement research and standards; (2) materials science and engineering; (3) engineering measurements and standards; (4) computer science and technology; (5) technology services; and (6) research support activities. Permits transfers of funds among such activities under specified conditions. Authorizes specified amounts from such funds solely for: (1) steel technology; (2) the Center for Building Technology; (3) the Center for Fire Research; (4) support of Regional Centers for the Transfer of Manufacturing Technology; (5) the evaluation of non-energy related inventions and related technology extension activities; and (6) technical competence programs. Prohibits the merger of the Center for Building Technology and the Center for Fire Research. Authorizes additional appropriations for FY 1989 for: (1) activities of the Office of Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology; (2) activities of the Office of Technology Policy; (3) implementation of the purposes of the Japanese Technical Literature Act of 1986; and (4) salary adjustments. Mandates that the Research Information Center of the NBS be maintained as a governmental activity. Instructs the Director of the NBS (NIST) to undertake, as appropriate, a variety of activities in the interest of extending and transferring technical services and other expertise to the States and to businesses, including improving access to Federal laboratories and evaluating inventions from small businesses or individuals that have significant potential for improving competitiveness. Directs the Director of the NBS (NIST) to study public and private sector needs for evaluated engineering data and to report to the Congress, recommending appropriate roles for the NBS (NIST) other relevant government and professional entities in collecting, evaluating, and disseminating such data. Instructs the Director to report to specified congressional committees on post-1986 domestic technology transfer accomplishments, trends, and plans of the agency. Describes required report contents. Title II: National Technology Administration in Department of Commerce Technology Administration - Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to establish in the Department of Commerce a Technology Administration comprising: (1) the National Bureau of Standards (National Institute of Standards and Technology); (2) the National Technical Information Service; (3) such other agencies, programs, and activities of the Department of Commerce as the Secretary of Commerce determines should be transferred to the entity; and (4) an Office of Technology Policy, a policy analysis entity. Describes duties of the Administration, including assuming the functions currently assigned to the Office of Productivity, Technology, and Innovation. Directs the President to appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, an Under Secretary of Commerce for Technology and an Assistant Secretary of Commerce for Technology Policy. Describes the duties of these officials. Title III: National Technical Information Service - National Technical Information Act of 1988 - Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to establish the National Technical Information Service (NTIS) as a Government corporation. Assigns to it the duties performed by the existing National Technical Information Service, as well as additional functions, including making its products available to depository libraries as part of the Government Printing Office Depository Library Program and making available in English unclassified foreign technical information. Directs the President to appoint, with the advice and consent of the Senate, an Administrator to manage the NTIS. Establishes an NTIS Advisory Board. Requires annual reporting and auditing in connection with NTIS activities. Title IV: Miscellaneous Amendments to Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 - Amends the Stevenson-Wydler Technology Innovation Act of 1980 to: (1) make specific provision for intellectual property within the context of cooperative research and development agreements; (2) authorize cash awards to scientific, engineering, and technical personnel for computer software; and (3) revise provisions regarding the distribution to inventors of royalties received by Federal agencies. Makes this final amendment retroactive to October 20, 1986.</summary>
</bill>
