<bill session="100" type="s" number="2713" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 18, United States Code, to provide procedural safeguards with respect to the issuance of lawyer-client subpoenas.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409917"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-08-22">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Courts and Administrative Practice.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU02" subcommittee="Courts and Administrative Practice" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Attorney-client privilege"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Pretrial procedure"/>
    <term name="Subpoena"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to prohibit the issuance of a lawyer-client subpoena in any proceeding in which the Government is a party, except upon a judicial determination made after a hearing at which the Government shall prove by clear and convincing evidence that: (1) the subpoena lists the specific testimony, documents, or tangible objects sought; (2) there is probable cause to believe that each item sought is related to, or is evidence of, criminal activity; (3) each item sought is necessary to the continued viability of a legitimate Government investigation or prosecution, and all alternative nonattorney souces for the item have been exhausted; (4) no item sought is protected from disclosure by any statutory, common law, or constitutional privilege of the lawyer or client; and (5) if the lawyer is currently representing the client in connection with an ongoing Government investigation or a judicial or administrative proceeding in which the Government is a party, the subpoena does not seek testimony concerning information relating to such representation or items relating to fees paid to the lawyer. Permits the issuance of a subpoena for documents transferred to a lawyer for a purpose other than seeking legal advice. Prohibits the issuance of a subpoena if a judicial determination is made that other grounds to quash such subpoena exist, irrespective of such requirements being met. Provides a right of appeal with respect to the granting or denial of a lawyer-client subpoena.</summary>
</bill>
