<bill session="100" type="s" number="2720" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill requiring the use by the Federal Government of certain vehicles capable of operating on alcohol or natural gas fuels or on electricity in areas not in compliance with the Clean Air Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4968"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4968"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol as fuel"/>
    <term name="Carbon monoxide"/>
    <term name="Electric vehicles"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Requires a certain percentage of Federal fleets of passenger automobiles and light-duty trucks to be alternative fuel vehicles by specified deadlines if such vehicles are being operated in an area designated under the Clean Air Act as an area of serious health endangerment for ozone and/or carbon monoxide. Requires the Administrator of General Services and the Secretary of Defense, with the concurrence of the Secretary of Energy, to issue regulations ensuring that such vehicles shall: (1) be supplied with alcohol, natural gas, or electricity in the primary area of operation; and (2) be operated exclusively on such fuel (except when it is impracticable to obtain it). Requires funds appropriated to implement this Act to be expended first in those areas determined by the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (the Administrator) to have the most severe air pollution problems. Prescribes circumstances under which such alternative fuels shall be offered for sale to the public. Mandates that the funds appropriated for alternative fuel vehicle acquisition apply only to the portion of costs which exceeds the cost for comparable conventional fuel vehicles. Directs the Secretary of Energy to ensure that the cost to any Federal agency receiving an alternative fuel vehicle under this Act not exceed the cost to such agency of a comparable conventional fueled vehicle. Mandates that gasoline powered Federal vehicles, with specified exceptions, which are operated in an area designated as seriously endangering health for carbon monoxide, and which are not dual energy (or natural gas dual energy), be operated exclusively with fuel which blends oxygenates with gasoline at their primary fueling facility. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress the results of a comprehensive analysis regarding the public health risk associated with the use of significant amounts of alcohols or natural gas as transportation fuels as compared to diesel and gasoline fuels. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1990. Sets forth criteria for alternative fuel vehicles. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1993 through 1996.</summary>
</bill>
