<bill session="100" type="s" number="2721" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-08-10">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-08-10"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Advisory Committee Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404598"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1988-08-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-08-10"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-08-10" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>8/10/1988--Introduced.
Federal Advisory Committee Act Amendments of 1988 - Amends the Federal Advisory Committee Act to include among congressional findings that: (1) advisory committees should only be established when the information to be obtained is not already available through another advisory committee or source within the Federal Government; (2) the composition of such committees should be balanced in membership in terms of the points of view represented and the functions to be performed; (3) all matters to be considered should be clearly delineated in the committee charter; and (4) the business of an advisory committee should be conducted through meetings. Limits the functions of advisory committees to advice only, unless otherwise specifically provided with operational functions. Revises procedures and requirements for establishing advisory committees by the President or an agency. Requires the President to establish such committees by presidential directive and agencies to publish notice in the Federal Register of the establishment of such committees. Revises provisions for chartering of advisory committees. Requires a charter for each advisory committee to be filed with: (1) the Administrator of General Services; (2) the head of the agency which establishes or provides support services for such committee; and (3) the congressional committees having jurisdiction over such committee. Revises requirements regarding the President's annual report to the Congress on advisory committees. Requires the report to be a summary of information contained in the annual report of each agency which established or utilized an advisory committee. Sets forth additional responsibilities of the Administrator of General Services with respect to advisory committees. Provides that the President or the agency head has the final authority regarding the establishment, management, or termination of an advisory committee, if there is a disagreement with the Administrator. Revises provisions with respect to advisory committee procedures. Authorizes the President or an agency head to terminate an advisory committee before the statutory termination date, after giving 90 days notice to the appropriate congressional committee. Authorizes the Congress to reauthorize such advisory committee if the Congress determines such committee to be necessary.</summary>
</bill>
