<bill session="100" type="s" number="2757" updated="2016-06-29T08:46:16-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-07-27">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-07-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Miscellaneous International Affairs Authorizations Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Diplomatic Immunity Abuse Prevention Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Overseas Private Investment Corporation Amendments Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to amend the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 with respect to the activities of the Overseas Private Investment Corporation, to make supplemental authorizations of appropriations for the Board for International Broadcasting, to prevent the abuse of diplomatic immunity, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1988-07-27" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-09-07">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Pell. With written report No. 100-500.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="921">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 921.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Africa"/>
    <term name="Aliens"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Board for International Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Caribbean area"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Consular agreements"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Deportation"/>
    <term name="Developing countries"/>
    <term name="Diplomatic privileges and immunities"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="Exchange of persons programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Freedom of speech"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Israel"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority business enterprises"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Overseas Private Investment Corporation"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Romania"/>
    <term name="Small business"/>
    <term name="Smuggling"/>
    <term name="Subsaharan Africa"/>
    <term name="Terrorism"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="United Nations officials and employees"/>
    <term name="Visas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/7/1988--Introduced.
Miscellaneous International Affairs Authorizations Act of 1988 - Title I: Overseas Private Investment Corporation - Overseas Private Investment Corporation Amendments Act of 1988 - Amends the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 to update and increase the per capita income levels established for countries with respect to which the Overseas Private Investment Corporation is required to either give preferential consideration (the least developed countries) or restrict its activities (the higher income developing countries). Authorizes the Corporation to designate up to 25 percent of any loan from the Direct Investment Fund for use by a project sponsor in the development or adaptation in the United States of new technologies or new products or services that are likely to contribute to the economic or social development of less developed countries. Authorizes the Corporation to establish a four-year pilot program in sub-Saharan Africa and the Caribbean Basin to assist eligible projects through the provision of limited equity capital. Requires the Corporation, in conducting such pilot project, to give preferential consideration to projects sponsored by or significantly involving U.S. small businesses or cooperatives. Authorizes the Corporation to establish a fund to be available solely for the purposes of such pilot project and to make a one-time transfer to such fund of a specified amount from its income and revenues. Requires the Corporation to undertake cooperative programs with the private insurance industry designed to enhance the private political risk insurance industry in the United States. Requires the Corporation to establish a group to advise the Corporation on the development and implementation of such cooperative programs. Requires the Corporation to include in its annual report to the Congress an assessment of such programs,. Specifies the types of information to be included in such assessment. Increases the ceiling on the Corporation's investment guaranty authority. Extends the authority of the Corporation to issue investment insurance and guaranties until September 30, 1992. Removes Romania from the list of countries eligible for Corporation programs upon a finding that such programs in those countries would be in the national interest. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Corporation should continue to: (1) encourage U.S. small businesses to invest in the world's developing countries; and (2) encourage minority-owned U.S. small businesses to invest in the world's developing countries as such businesses are well suited to the economic and social development needs of such countries. Specifies that prohibitions on U.S. assistance for Haiti during FY 1988 shall not be construed to apply with respect to the Corporation unless the prohibition specifically states that it does apply. Title II: Board for International Broadcasting - Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 to authorize appropriations to the Board for International Broadcasting for radio transmitter construction and modernization. Amends the Board for International Broadcasting Act of 1973 to authorize appropriations for the construction of a relay station in Israel. Title III: Au Pair Provision - Expresses the sense of the Congress that the terms and conditions previously authorized by the United States Information Agency (USIA) to implement a specified Exchange Visitor Program are in keeping with the goals and objectives of the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 (Fulbright-Hayes Act). Prohibits the use of appropriated funds for the termination or substantial alteration of the terms and conditions authorized by the USIA for the implementation of such program. Title IV: Exclusion or Deportation of Aliens - Repeals provisions of the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 limiting the time period during which the exlusion or deportation of aliens or grounds of political beliefs is prohibited. Title V: Diplomatic Immunity Abuse Prevention Act - Diplomatic Immunity Abuse Prevention Act - Amends the Foreign Missions Act (title II of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956) to require the Director of Foreign Missions to maintain records on each incident in which an individual with diplomatic immunity is reasonably believed to have committed a serious criminal offense within the United States. Amends the Diplomatic Relations Act to require the Director to report annually to the Congress on all such offenses. Requires the Director to take such steps as may be necessary to: (1) educate local law enforcement officials on the extent of the immunity from criminal jurisdiction provided to members of a foreign mission and their family members under the Vienna Convention; and (2) assure that local law enforcement officials investigate and prosecute to the extent consistent with the Vienna Convention any member of a foreign mission (or family member) who commits a serious criminal offense. Prohibits officers and employees of the Department of State from discouraging any investigation or prosecution by a Federal, State, or local government of any alien who is a member of a foreign mission or any other alien who is not immune from criminal jurisdiction under the Vienna Convention. Requires the Director to notify the members of each foreign mission of U.S. policies relating to criminal offenses committed by such members (and family members), including the policies of obtaining criminal indictments, requiring such members to leave the country, and declaring such members persona non grata. Requires the Director to develop registration and departure procedures for members of foreign missions (and family members) in order to identify those individuals in the United States with immunity from the criminal jurisdiction of the United States. Amends the Foreign Missions Act to require the Secretary of State to request a waiver of immunity when a person with diplomatic immunity is charged with a serious crime and to notify the foreign ministry of the offender's country of the U.S. Government's intention to pursue compensation for all damages resulting from the actions of the offender. Requires the Secretary to declare such a person persona non grata if such request for a waiver of immunity is denied. Requires the Secretary to notify the Attorney General of each individual who voluntarily leaves, or is asked to leave, the United States because of alleged involvement in a serious crime in order to prevent permanently that person from reentering the United States. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act to require the exclusion from the United States of any alien with respect to whom the Secretary has made such a notification. Allows such an alien to be admitted for any proceeding regarding the alleged crime or if the Attorney General determines that admitting such individual is in the national interest. Amends the Diplomatic Relations Act to revise the authority to institute and maintain criminal prosecutions to allow criminal prosecutions against an individual entitled to immunity, provided no measure is taken in derogation of an individual's diplomatic immunity. Requires the Secretary to review the U.S. policy of providing privileges and immunities to members (and their families) of foreign missions which results in treatment which is more favorable than the treatment required to be provided under the Vienna Convention and to report to the Congress concerning such review. Requires the Secretary to review and report to the Congress on any changes in procedures for issuing nonimmigrant visas to diplomats to the United States and the United Nations. Requires the Director of Foreign Missions to establish and ensure compliance with liability insurance requirements which shall afford compensation for injuries resulting from the activities of a diplomatic mission and its staff. Requires the President to: (1) review the treatment accorded to diplomatic pouches under the Vienna Convention in order to preclude the use of such pouches for the transportation of unauthorized materials, particularly those used to foster terrorism; and (2) seek in every appropriate forum the adoption of measures which will ensure that diplomatic pouches are not used to smuggle illicit narcotics, explosives, weapons, and any material used to foster terrorism.</summary>
</bill>
