<bill session="100" type="s" number="2762" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Educational Software Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a National Educational Software Corporation to promote the development and distribution of high-quality, interactive, and educationally useful computer software, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404679"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Computer software"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Educational technology"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1988--Introduced.
National Educational Software Act of 1988 - Establishes a National Educational Software Corporation (the Corporation) within the executive branch of the Federal Government. Sets forth provisions for members of the board of directors of the Corporation. Lists the principal functions of the Corporation as: (1) developing participation criteria for selecting high-quality, interactive, and educationally useful computer software; (2) securing investment capital for projects to develop such software; (3) making appropriate and reasonable investments in projects for the development of such software; (4) entering into contracts and making grants to assist in the development of such software; and (5) engaging in such other operations and activities as the board of directors determines to be necessary and appropriate to encourage the development and use of such software. Sets forth the general authorities of the Corporation. Sets forth provisions concerning investments by the Corporation. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990.</summary>
</bill>
