<bill session="100" type="s" number="2761" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-20">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Marine Sanctuaries Authorization Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations to carry out title III of the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 during fiscal years 1989, 1990, 1991, and 1992, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1988-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-09-20" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Ordered to be reported with amendments favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-07">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Reported to Senate by Senator Hollings with amendments. With written report No. 100-595.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-10-07" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="1130">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 1130.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-10-12">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-14">
      <text>H.R. 4209 passed in Senate relating to this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="4209"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Forfeiture"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Marine mammal protection"/>
    <term name="Marine parks and reserves"/>
    <term name="Marine resources conservation"/>
    <term name="Massachusetts"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Texas"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
    <term name="Washington State"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/12/1988--Indefinitely postponed in Senate.
(Measure indefinitely postponed in Senate (See H.R. 4210 as passed Senate for similar provisions)) Marine Sanctuaries Authorization Act of 1988 - Amends title III (Marine Sanctuaries) of the Marine Protection, Research, and Sanctuaries Act of 1972 to authorize appropriations through FY 1992. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to issue special use permits for the conduct of specified activities in a national marine sanctuary if it is necessary to condition access to and use of, or promote public use and understanding of, a sanctuary resource. Requires that such permits: (1) authorize only those activities which are compatible with the purposes for which the sanctuary is designated, and sanctuary resource protection; (2) last for no more than five years, unless renewed; and (3) require permittees to purchase and maintain comprehensive general liability insurance against claims arising out of permitted activities and agree to hold the Federal Government harmless against such claims. Authorizes the imposition of permit fees which, after recovering permit issuance costs and costs incurred by the Secretary as the direct result of permitted activities, provide the Federal Government with a reasonable return. Authorizes the use of collected fees for the permit program, and for designating and managing sanctuaries. Imposes penalties for the violation of permit provisions. Directs each permittee to submit an annual report to the Secretary which describes activities conducted pursuant to such permit and revenues derived from such activities during the year. Excludes fishing from this Act's permit process. Subjects anyone who destroys, causes the loss of, or injures any sanctuary resource to liability to the Federal Government for response costs and damages resulting from such destruction, loss, or injury. Subjects vessels to liability in rem for such costs or damages. Sets forth defenses to such liability. Directs the Secretary to pursue civil actions against persons or vessels who may be liable for such costs or damages. Requires the Secretary to retain recovered amounts for sanctuary restoration, management, and improvement. Authorizes specified enforcement actions against title III violators, including: (1) the imposition of a civil penalty of up to $50,000 for each day a person is guilty of a violation; (2) the forfeiture of any vessel other item used, and any sanctuary resource taken or retained in connection with or as a result of a violation; and (3) injunctive relief. Sets forth dates by which the Secretary must issue a designation notice regarding the proposed Cordell Banks, Flower Garden Banks, Monterey Bay, and Western Washington Outer Coast National Marine Sanctuaries. Requires the Secretary to submit a prospectus to specified congressional committees by March 31, 1991, regarding the Northern Puget Sound National Marine Sanctuary, and by September 30, 1990, regarding Stellwagen Bank. Directs the Secretary to conduct a study to determine whether all or any part of the Santa Monica Bay area should be designated as a national marine sanctuary. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress regarding such study within two years of this Act's enactment and commence the designation process with respect to the area or any part of it if it or any part of it is found to be appropriate for designation.</summary>
</bill>
