<bill session="100" type="s" number="2769" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Community Youth Activities Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title V of the Public Health Service Act to provide for the development of comprehensive community prevention initiatives.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-09-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1988-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1988--Introduced.
Community Youth Activities Act of 1988 - Amends title V (Administration and Coordination of the National Institute of Mental Health, the National Institute on Alcohol Abuse and Alcoholism, and the National Institute on Drug Abuse) of the Public Health Service Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to States to carry out activities as described in this Act. Sets forth a minimum grant amount. Directs the Secretary to reserve five percent of the amount appropriated for any fiscal year to carry out this Act for projects of national significance which are expected to have a significant impact in preventing use of drugs among youth. Requires, if the amount appropriated is under a specified amount, that 25 percent of the amount appropriated be allotted equally among the 50 States, with the remainder apportioned according to stated priorities. Sets forth general priorities in making the grants. Declares that the assistance received under this Act may be used for: (1) State regional substance abuse education and prevention centers designed to provide technical assistance, outreach, consultation, training, and referral services; (2) community services and partnerships designed to develop community activities targeted at substance abuse prevention through education, training, and recreation projects; and (3) other projects or proposals consistent with the intent of this Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1993. Directs the Secretary to evaluate projects conducted with assistance under this Act. Requires grant applications to include a description of the method to be used in evaluating the impact the program is having on the drug problem within the community.</summary>
</bill>
