<bill session="100" type="s" number="2772" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Public Health Service Act to improve the provision of drug treatment services for pregnant women.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-09-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and women"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Maternal health services"/>
    <term name="Pregnant women"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/9/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Public Health Service Act to create a new part on drug treatment for pregnant women. Requires any drug treatment program that receives Federal assistance to give priority to the treatment of pregnant women and afford them the first opportunity to receive treatment, notwithstanding any waiting list. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a demonstration project to make grants to provide pregnant women with various drug treatment services. Requires applicants to agree to provide: (1) outreach to pregnant women who are abusers of alcohol or illegal drugs; (2) substance abuse treatment and rehabilitation; (3) prenatal care to pregnant women who are abusers of alcohol or illegal drugs; (4) counseling; (5) coordination with other Federal, State, and local programs designed to assist pregnant women; and (6) continued assistance to women who have received assistance under this Act and their infant children. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
