<bill session="100" type="s" number="2778" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Great Lakes States Medical Waste Tracking Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a pilot program for the tracking of medical wastes in the States bordering the Great Lakes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300066"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1988-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1988-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Great Lakes"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Lakes"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in rivers, lakes, etc."/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Water pollution measurement"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/1988--Introduced.
Great Lakes States Medical Waste Tracking Act of 1988 - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to establish a demonstration program, within nine months of this Act's enactment, to track, by the use of a manifest system, medical waste generated and disposed of in the States bordering the Great Lakes. Includes in such program the monitoring of beaches in Great Lake States where there have been reported incidences of medical waste being washed up on shore. Makes such program applicable to generators of medical waste, and owners and operators of facilities for the treatment, storage, transport, and disposal of medical waste. Requires such parties to permit access to, and provide copies of, all records relating to such wastes to any designated representative of the EPA. Sets forth civil and criminal penalties for violations of program requirements. Provides that this Act does not preclude any State or locality from imposing more stringent requirements for the control or monitoring of medical waste or affect the authorities or requirements of the Solid Waste Disposal Act. Requires the Administrator to report to the Congress, within three years of this Act's enactment, on the progress and success of the demonstration program. Authorizes appropriations for such program for FY 1989 through 1991. Authorizes and directs the Administrator to use authority provided in the Solid Waste Disposal Act to immediately address and correct the improper disposal of medical waste.</summary>
</bill>
