<bill session="100" type="s" number="2775" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Commission on the American Family and Employment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a Commission on the American Family and Employment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300023"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1988-09-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1988-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-10-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-09-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, Labor Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business and social problems"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Dual-career families"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee benefit plans"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to day care centers"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Labor productivity"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Parental leave"/>
    <term name="Sick leave"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
    <term name="Working mothers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/1988--Introduced.
Commission on the American Family and Employment Act of 1988 - Establishes the Commission on the American Family and Employment. Directs the Commission to study: (1) all existing and proposed policies relating to employment benefits provided to American workers, either voluntarily by employers or as required by law; and (2) the potential costs, benefits, and impact on productivity of such policies on employers. Requires the study to include reviews of all pending congressional legislative proposals designed to require: (1) employees to provide workers with additional benefits, including parental and medical leave and minimum health benefits; and (2) the provision of child care services, including Federal funding of child care providers, incentives to employers to provide child care benefits for employees, tax benefits to working parents for child care services, and child tax credits or other tax benefits to families in which a parent may choose to stay at home to provide care for the children. Requires the study to analyze the need for additional child care services, the potential costs of such services, the benefits to be derived from such services, and the impact that proposals for such services would have on domestic productivity. Requires the Commission to report its findings to the Congress within two years after it first meets. Terminates the Commission 30 days after submission of its final report to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
