<bill session="100" type="s" number="2783" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:54-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title XVIII of the Social Security Act to provide coverage for certain screening examinations and cancer detection tests under part B, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1988-09-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1988-09-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Cervical cancer"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Medical laboratories"/>
    <term name="Medical screening"/>
    <term name="Medical tests"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Women's health"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/13/1988--Introduced.
Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to cover cancer screening examinations and detection tests which include: (1) a clinical pelvic screening examination; (2) a clinical digital rectal screening examination; (3) a stool occult blood test; (4) a papanicolau (pap) test; and (5) other examinations and tests which the Secretary of Health and Human Services authorizes and which are related to the detection of cancers to which the preceding examinations and tests relate. Prohibits coverage of each such test or examination more than once a year, except for a stool occult blood test which shall be covered biannually. Requires the Secretary to establish: (1) a relative value scale to serve as the basis for payment for such cancer detection procedures; and (2) standards to assure the safety, accuracy, and effectiveness of such procedures. Directs the Secretary to enter into an agreement with a national laboratory and agreements with regional laboratories having expertise in conducting pap tests to evaluate and report on the accuracy of a random sample of such tests from each provider. Requires the Secretary to establish standards of accuracy for such tests and deny payments to providers which do not satisfy such standards. Prohibits a regional laboratory from performing such review function with respect to a laboratory with which it has a financial relationship. Directs the Secretary to use State agencies to determine laboratory compliance with standards established pursuant to this Act.</summary>
</bill>
