<bill session="100" type="s" number="2791" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to add additional land to the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Reservation in Arizona, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-09-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Indian Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SLIA" name="Senate Indian Affairs (Permanent Select)" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Arizona"/>
    <term name="Indian lands"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/14/1988--Introduced.
Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior to exchange specified land known as Red Mountain. Revokes Secretarial orders which withdrew specified lands in aid of the Salt River Project. Reserves an easement on specified lands to the Salt River Project for electric transmission and distribution lines and access purposes. Absolves the United States and such Project from liability for damages to any land revoked under this Act which may be caused by flooding in conjunction with any of the U.S. or Project facilities or protective works. Imposes liability on any future patentee for damages caused by activities which alter drainage and adversely affect adjacent lands project facilities or protective works of the United States or Salt River Project. Reserves to the United States a right-of-way for road purposes. Requires the boundary of the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Reservation in Arizona to be modified at such time as the Salt River Pima-Maricopa Indian Community acquires title to specified lands. Provides for the addition to the reservation of such lands. Requires that such lands remain as tribal lands.</summary>
</bill>
