<bill session="100" type="s" number="2809" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Recreation and Public Purposes Amendment Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend section 3 of the Act of June 14, 1926, as amended (43 U.S.C. 869-2), to authorize the issuance of patents with a limited reverter provision for lands devoted to solid waste disposal, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411271"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400927" joined="1988-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1988-09-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-10-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-21">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Hazardous waste disposal"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Land use"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/19/1988--Introduced.
Recreation and Public Purposes Amendment Act of 1988 - Authorizes the Secretary of the Interior, upon receipt of an appropriate application, to convey land under the Secretary's jurisdiction for the express purpose of solid waste disposal or other purposes which include the disposal, placement, or release of any hazardous substance. Requires the Secretary to investigate the land covered by such an application to determine whether any hazardous substance is present on such land. Prohibits any conveyance if a hazardous substance is present. Requires applications to be provided to the Environmental Protection Agency and any Federal or State agencies responsible for the enforcement of hazardous waste disposal laws and regulations. Requires applicants to warrant that the use of such lands will be consistent with all such laws and regulations. Outlines conveyance conditions, including the right of reverter to the United States for any land not used in the authorized manner. Requires pricing for such conveyance to be determined in accordance with current Federal law, except that no compensation shall be required for the inclusion of only a limited reverter in the conveyance document. Authorizes the Secretary, upon the application or with the concurrence of any party to whom such land is so conveyed, to release the reverter provision on a finding that the lands have been used for solid waste disposal or other purposes which include the disposal, placement, or release of any hazardous substance. Provides that, upon such reverter release, such lands shall not revert to the United States by operation of law, or be subject to current Federal provisions concerning permisssible uses of such property. Authorizes the Secretary, with regard to lands leased for such purposes, to convey in fee (outright) the lands covered by such lease or any portions which have been used for such purposes. Provides the same non-reverter protection to such lessees as is provided to patent holders of such lands under this Act.</summary>
</bill>
