<bill session="100" type="s" number="2805" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VII of the Social Security Act to authorize appropriations for the Office of Rural Health Policy and to establish a National Advisory Committee on Rural Health, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-10-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1988-10-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Medical research"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/16/1988--Introduced.
Amends title VII (Administration) of the Social Security Act to require the Director of the Office of Rural Health Policy to implement a grant program to establish and support rural health research centers located at public and nonprofit entities which will provide an information base and policy analysis capacity on issues of rural health. Authorizes appropriations for such program and for the Office of Rural Health Policy for FY 1989 through 1991. Establishes the National Advisory Committee on Rural Health to advise the Secretary of Health and Human Services and the Congress concerning the provision and financing of health care services in rural areas. Requires the Committee to submit a report to the Secretary and the Congress by October 10 of each year summarizing the Committee's activities and recommendations during the previous year. Authorizes appropriations for such Committee.</summary>
</bill>
