<bill session="100" type="s" number="2814" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Consumer Products Safe Testing Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the modernization of testing of consumer products which contain hazardous or toxic substances.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1988-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-10-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1635"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1635"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Animals"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Laboratory animals"/>
    <term name="Product development"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Protection of animals"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/1988--Introduced.
Consumer Products Safe Testing Act - Expresses congressional findings that: (1) the Federal Government has encouraged the use of the LD50 test through regulations which mandate or encourage its use or do not prescribe other less costly, more accurate, and more humane alternatives; and (2) private industry is reluctant to use these other tests without Federal Government encouragement. (LD50 is a procedure whereby toxicity is measured in terms of the median dose that will kill 50 percent of the test animals within a specified time.) Prohibits Federal department or agency heads from considering LD50 test results when determining product safety, labeling, or transportation requirements for purposes of Federal regulation. Requires Federal department and agency heads to: (1) review and evaluate directives that call for the use of an animal toxicity test; and (2) promulgate regulations specifying the use of nonanimal alternatives. Permits the use of animal toxicity tests under certain conditions. Requires that animal toxicity testing regulations be subject to periodic agency review and to public comment in certain cases.</summary>
</bill>
