<bill session="100" type="s" number="2819" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Chemical Warfare Control Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Export Administration Act of 1979 to impose sanctions against firms involved in the transfer of chemical agents or their related production equipment or technical assistance to Iran, Iraq, Libya, and Syria, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404444" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300154" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="409456" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1988-09-23"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="5396"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="5396"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Debarment of government contractors"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Libya"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Syria"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/22/1988--Introduced.
Chemical Warfare Control Act - Amends the Export Administration Act of 1979 to set forth as U.S. policy the use of export controls to curtail transfers of material and technology used in producing chemical weapons. Requires the President to prepare a list of materials and technology which would assist a country's chemical warfare capability. Prohibits the export of such materials and technology to Iran, Iraq, Libya, or Syria or, at the President's discretion and upon notification to the Congress, to additional countries. Authorizes the President to waive such prohibition upon determining that an export will not assist a country's chemical warfare capability. Authorizes the exclusion of any country from such prohibition beginning 30 days after the President submits the name of such country to the Congress. Requires the President, no later than 90 days after enactment of this Act and every 180 days thereafter, to submit to specified House and Senate members and committees a report on: (1) the efforts by Iran, Iraq, Libya, and Syria to acquire the materials to produce chemical weapons; and (2) the present and future capability of such countries to produce such weapons. Requires the report to: (1) assess whether Communist-bloc countries have aided such countries in acquiring such materials; (2) list companies in non-Communist countries which have exported items on the President's list to such countries; and (3) provide credible information that any non-Communist country has aided such countries. Directs the President to apply sanctions to any foreign person who exports any item on the list to any such country. Provides that such sanctions prohibit: (1) contracting with and procuring products and services from a sanctioned person by the U.S. Government; and (2) importing products produced by such person into the United States. Declares that the President shall not apply sanctions in the case of procurement of defense articles and services if: (1) the articles and services are under existing contracts; (2) the President determines that the person to whom sanctions would apply is the sole supplier of essential defense articles or services; or (3) the President determines that such articles or services are essential to national security. Prohibits the application of sanctions to: (1) contracts entered into before the President notifies the Congress of the intention to impose sanctions; (2) spare parts; (3) component parts; (4) routine servicing and maintenance of products; or (5) information and technology.</summary>
</bill>
