<bill session="100" type="s" number="281" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:50-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aid to Families and Employment Transition Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to promote the transition of severely economically disadvantaged individuals to unsubsidized employment.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300092"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-01-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social security eligibility"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Aid to Families and Employment Transition Act of 1987 - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Social Security Act to provide that AFDC beneficiaries making the transition to unsubsidized employment by participating in employment preparation programs established pursuant to the Opportunities for Employment Preparation Act of 1987 shall have their salaries excluded from the AFDC eligibility determination for one year following the initial placement. Continues Medicaid (title XIX of the Act) coverage of individuals making such a transition to unsubsidized employment until either the individual becomes eligible for an employer health plan, or 15 months elapse since his or her placement in unsubsidized employment. Provides AFDC benefits to two-parent families if at least one parent participates in an employment preparation program.</summary>
</bill>
