<bill session="100" type="s" number="2829" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Uniform Federal Crime Reporting Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require Federal departments and agencies to participate in the Federal Uniform Crime Reports program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-09-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-09-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal justice information"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/26/1988--Introduced.
Uniform Federal Crime Reporting Act of 1988 - Requires the Attorney General to collect and preserve national data on Federal criminal offenses as part of the Uniform Crime Reports. Directs all Federal agencies which routinely investigate complaints of criminal activity to report details about such crimes to the Attorney General in a uniform manner and on a form prescribed by the Attorney General. Requires the Attorney General to distribute such details in the form of annual Uniform Crime Reports for the United States to the President, the Congress, State governments, and officials of localities and institutions participating in the Uniform Crime Reports program. Authorizes the Attorney General to designate the Federal Bureau of Investigation as the lead agency for performing the functions authorized by this Act and to establish such advisory boards as may be necessary to assist the Bureau. Requires the Director of the Bureau to classify offenses involving illegal drugs and drug trafficking as a part I crime in the Uniform Crime Reports. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
