<bill session="100" type="s" number="2837" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make nonmailable any plant, fruit, vegetable, or other matter, the movement of which in interstate commerce has been prohibited or restricted by the Secretary of Agriculture in order to prevent the dissemination of dangerous plant diseases or pests, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="5199"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="5199"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Postal service"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Counterfeiting"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Forgery"/>
    <term name="Fruit and fruit trade"/>
    <term name="Nurseries (Horticulture)"/>
    <term name="Pest control"/>
    <term name="Plant diseases"/>
    <term name="Plant quarantine"/>
    <term name="Postal Services and Facilities"/>
    <term name="Vegetables and vegetable trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/27/1988--Introduced.
Declares as nonmailable matter any plant, fruit, vegetable, root, bulb, seed, or other plant product subject to interstate quarantine under the Plant Quarantine Act. Directs the Postal Service to prescribe rules and regulations permitting the mailing of such plants consistent with procedures relating to the inspection, disinfection, and certification of, and other conditions for, the delivery and shipment of plants otherwise subject to quarantine. Sets forth criminal penalties for: (1) whoever knowingly mails or causes to be mailed a nonmailable plant; or (2) whoever forges or counterfeits agricultural certifications. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the Postal Service and the Department of Agriculture should engage in a joint effort to educate the public to the types of harm which can result from the transmission to different parts of the country of plants, fruits, vegetables, and other matter which may be carrying dangerous plant diseases or pests.</summary>
</bill>
