<bill session="100" type="s" number="2847" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to transfer certain real property to the City of North Las Vegas, Nevada.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300082"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Nevada"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Introduced.
Withdraws all public lands within the city limits of North Las Vegas, Nevada, from all forms of entry and appropriation under the public land and mining laws, and from operation of the mineral and geothermal leasing laws. Terminates such withdrawal ten years after the enactment of this Act. Sets forth notification and sale periods for the exclusive purchase of such lands by the city of North Las Vegas. Subjects the sale of such lands to a determination by the Secretary of the Interior that disposition of such lands is compatible with proper management by the Bureau of Land Management of any lands within the city limits which remain in Federal ownership. Requires the city to purchase such lands in compact and contiguous parcels. Authorizes the Secretary, after the expiration of the exclusive right to purchase provided to the city, to sell such public lands. Allows the city to meet the highest bid. Authorizes the Secretary to: (1) retain such lands within the city limits which are determined to best serve the public interest in Federal ownership; and (2) attach such conditions to any sale which are determined to be appropriate.</summary>
</bill>
