<bill session="100" type="s" number="2848" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Sanctions Against Iraqi Chemical Weapons Use Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled "Sanctions Against Iraqi Chemical Weapons Use Act".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Arms sales"/>
    <term name="Chemical warfare"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Development credit institutions"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign loans"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Genocide"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Inspection (Arms control)"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Kurds"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Multilateral development banks"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Refugee policy"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Turkey"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Introduced.
Sanctions Against Iraqi Chemical Weapons Use Act - Sets forth congressional findings concerning Iraq's use of chemical weapons and the treatment of the Kurdish people in Iraq. Prohibits: (1) the sale to Iraq of any item on the U.S. Munitions list; (2) the issuance of any license for the export to Iraq of any item on the U.S. Munitions list; (3) the export to Iraq of any goods or technology on the Export Administration Act control list; and (4) the issuance of licenses for the export to Iraq of any chemical, facility, or technology that the President determines may be used primarily in the production of chemical weapons or devoted to chemical warfare purposes. Requires the United States to oppose any loan or financial or technical assistance to Iraq by all international financial institutions. Requires the President to impose at least one of the following additional sanctions against Iraq: (1) prohibiting or restricting the importation of oil, petroleum products, or other goods from Iraq; (2) prohibiting or restricting the export to Iraq of nonagricultural commodities and other goods and technology under authority of the Export Administration Act; or (3) denying credit, guarantees of credit, and Government insurance to Iraq. Specifies that contract sanctity shall apply for contracts signed before September 15, 1988, with an exception. Requires the President to report to the Congress periodically on any such actions taken. Allows the President to lift any sanctions imposed pursuant to this Act if the President determines and certifies to the Congress that Iraq: (1) is not using chemical weapons; (2) has provided reliable assurances that it will not use chemical weapons in the future; (3) is willing to allow on-site inspections by the United Nations or other impartial observers, or other means exist to ensure that Iraq is not using chemical weapons; and (4) is not engaged in a consistent pattern of gross violations of human rights of its Kurdish population. Urges Turkey to cooperate with any United Nations or other appropriate investigation of Iraqi use of chemical weapons. Commends Turkey for its humanitarian decision to accept Kurdish refugees. Calls upon the President to: (1) bring before the United Nations the matter of Iraq's use of poison gas against its own nationals; and (2) demand that appropriate and effective measures be taken against Iraq for its repeated use of chemical weapons. Calls upon the President to: (1) seek multinational cooperation in: (1) imposing sanctions and otherwise bringing pressure on Iraq in order to obtain a cessation of Iraq's use of chemical weapons; and (2) obtaining Iraqi respect for the internationally recognized human rights of the Kurdish minority in Iraq. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States should cooperate with and participate in multilateral efforts to assist Kurdish refugees who are in need of medical treatment and other humanitarian aid. States that it is the policy of the United States to prohibit the export of goods and technology to Iraq that would significantly contribute to its military potential. Urges the President to review any proposed export to Iraq of goods or technology valued at over $50,000,000. Requires the Secretary of State to report to the Congress as to whether Iraq is engaged in a consistent pattern of gross violations of internationally recognized human rights.</summary>
</bill>
