<bill session="100" type="s" number="2858" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "Rural Development Amendments of 1988".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404277"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Agriculture and food"/>
    <term name="Agricultural credit"/>
    <term name="Agricultural economics"/>
    <term name="Agricultural innovations"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federally-guaranteed loans"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Revolving funds"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural economic development"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1988--Introduced.
Title I: Capacity Building - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture to make grants to public and private nonprofit organizations to stimulate rural economic growth and diversification. Limits grants to 75 percent of project costs, with exceptions for small, poor, or minority communities. Title II: State Incentive Grants - Authorizes the Secretary to make grants to States and State departments of agriculture to promote rural development and agricultural diversification. Limits fiscal year assistance to any one State or department of agriculture to not more than ten percent of total fiscal year assistance. Title III: Rural Development Loan Fund - Includes agricultural diversification among the purposes of the Rural Development Loan Fund. Title IV: Definitions - Defines "agricultural diversification" for purposes of this Act. Title V: Programs to Promote Agricultural Diversification - Subtitle A: Agricultural Diversification Loan Fund - Authorizes the Secretary to make and insure loans to States and State departments of agriculture to establish revolving loan funds to promote agricultural diversification. Directs States and departments of agriculture to make loans to private business ventures, including family farms, to diversify the local agricultural economy. Authorizes specified appropriations. Subtitle B: Guaranteed Loans for Alternative Crops - Authorizes the Secretary to guarantee loans for alternative crop production. Authorizes FY 1989 through 1991 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
