<bill session="100" type="s" number="2851" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-30">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-30"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Forest Ecosystems and Atmospheric Pollution Research Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for study and research on the decline in United States forest productivity and to determine the effects of atmospheric pollutants on forest environments, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1988-09-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-09-30"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-30" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Ecological research"/>
    <term name="Environmental assessment"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Forest conservation"/>
    <term name="Forest ecology"/>
    <term name="Forestry research"/>
    <term name="Forests and forest products"/>
    <term name="Forests and forestry"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/30/1988--Introduced.
Forest Ecosystems and Atmospheric Pollution Research Act of 1988 - Amends the Forest and Rangeland Renewable Resources Research Act of 1978 to direct the Secretary of Agriculture to establish a ten-year program to evaluate and research the effects of atmospheric pollutants on forest ecosystems, including recommendations for solving problems affecting health and productivity. Calls for the enlargement of the Eastern Hardwood Cooperative. Requires the Secretary to appoint an advisory committee to assist in developing the program, which shall be coordinated with other governmental and private efforts. Directs the Secretary to report to the President and the Congress initially and annually on the status of the forest ecosystems, the program, and the costs of implementing the program. Requires the Secretary to submit a final report within ten years.</summary>
</bill>
