<bill session="100" type="s" number="2860" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bangladesh Disaster Assistance Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill concerning disaster assistance for Bangladesh.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300154"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1988-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1988-10-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-10-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Bangladesh"/>
    <term name="Disaster relief"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Flood control"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Water supply"/>
    <term name="Watersheds"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/4/1988--Introduced.
Bangladesh Disaster Assistance Act of 1988 - Expresses support for assistance programs for the people of Bangladesh in response to the 1988 floods. Amends the Agricultural Trade Development and Assistance Act of 1954 to permit funds generated from the sale of U.S. agricultural commodities to be used, with U.S. approval, for disaster relief, rehabilitation, and reconstruction assistance in any area of a country participating in the Food for Development Program that is affected by a serious natural disaster. Provides for the retroactive application of this Act. Calls for: (1) a specified amount of the local currencies generated under Food for Development agreements with Bangladesh to be used for assistance for victims of the 1988 floods; and (2) an extension of the period during which such currencies must be used. Requires the President, with the assistance of the Office of Technology Assessment, to report to the Congress on efforts by the international community to develop regional programs for the Ganges and Brahmaputra basins that are designed to ensure a predictable water supply in the dry season and to promote flood control.</summary>
</bill>
