<bill session="100" type="s" number="2866" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to strengthen the registration and enforcement requirements of that Act.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign agents"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/6/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Foreign Agents Registration Act of 1938 to declare that a foreign principal shall be considered to control a person in major part if: (1) such principal holds 50 percent or more of equitable ownership in such person; or (2) such principal, subject to rebuttal evidence, holds at least 20 percent but less than 50 percent of equitable ownership in such person. Requires agents of foreign principals who have filed registration statements to file supplements to such statements with the Attorney General on January 15 and July 15 of each year. Repeals a provision exempting agents of foreign principals who are qualified to practice law from filing registration statements. Imposes civil penalties upon persons who: (1) have failed to file such registration statements; or (2) have omitted a material fact or made false statements on such registration statements.</summary>
</bill>
