<bill session="100" type="s" number="2880" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-11">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-11"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-11"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Health Promotion Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote state-wide health promotion campaigns, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-11" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Preventive medicine"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/11/1988--Introduced.
National Health Promotion Act of 1988 - Authorizes the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to pay the Federal share of the cost of health promotion campaigns. Provides for allotment to each State of any sums appropriated. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide for the collection of data that measure and evaluate the impact of the campaigns; (2) publish an annual report on the activities under this Act; and (3) submit the report to the appropriate committees of the Congress. Sets forth application requirements. Mandates the creation of an Advisory Board by each State. Directs the Secretary to pay to each State with an approved application the Federal share of the cost of the activities described in the application. Sets forth the Federal share for each year of participation. Declares that each State shall be eligible for Federal funding for any three consecutive years of the five-year period during which the Federal program shall operate. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991.</summary>
</bill>
