<bill session="100" type="s" number="2893" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Coast Guard Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the establishment of the United States Coast Guard as an independent agency for certain purposes, to transfer certain functions of the Secretary of Transportation to the Commandant of the Coast Guard, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Coast guard"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/13/1988--Introduced.
United States Coast Guard Act of 1988 - Amends Federal law to declare that the Coast Guard shall be: (1) a military service and a branch of the U.S. armed forces at all times; and (2) treated as an independent establishment for purposes of all Federal laws. Requires the Coast Guard to operate as a service in the Navy upon the declaration of war or when the President directs. Transfers to the Commandant of the Coast Guard all functions which the Secretary of Transportation exercised before enactment of this Act. Authorizes the Commandant to take certain personnel actions, delegate authority, reorganize functions within the Coast Guard, and prescribe rules. Provides for transfer and allocations of appropriations and personnel. Terminates, on the effective date of this Act, the positions of individuals appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Sets forth savings and separability provisions. Authorizes the Commandant, with the consent of the Secretary of Transportation, to use: (1) personnel of the Department of Transportation; and (2) for a reasonable time, funds appropriated to transferred functions.</summary>
</bill>
