<bill session="100" type="s" number="2901" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 to permit industrial homework except with respect to an individual employer to be in violation of such Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400927"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1988-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1988-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300154" joined="1988-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1988-10-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1988-10-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Economic impact statements"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Home labor"/>
    <term name="Hours of labor"/>
    <term name="Minimum wages"/>
    <term name="Overtime"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/14/1988--Introduced.
Amends the Fair Labor Standards Act of 1938 (the Act) to permit industrial homework, except with respect to an individual employer violating minimum wage and maximum hour requirements of such Act. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor (current law authorizes the Administrator of the Wage and Hour Division of the Department of Labor) to make regulations and orders regulating and restricting industrial homework. Provides that the Secretary may not make any regulation or order under the Act that would prohibit an individual from engaging in homework as an employee of an employer subject to the Act, except that the Secretary may make such an order with respect to an individual employer found to be in violation of the Act. Directs the Secretary, within one year after enactment of this Act and each year thereafter, to report to the Congress on: (1) the impact on industries and employers of the Secretary's regulations and restrictions on industrial homework; and (2) the economic effect on industries and employees of permitting industrial homework.</summary>
</bill>
