<bill session="100" type="s" number="2917" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:58-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fire Safe Cigarette Implementation Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the recommendations of the Interagency Committee and the Technical Study Group on Cigarette and Little Cigar Fire Safety, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404679"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1988-10-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4497"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="4497"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Fires"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Cigarettes"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Flammable materials"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Product safety"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Smoking"/>
    <term name="Tobacco"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/19/1988--Introduced.
Fire Safe Cigarette Implementation Act of 1988 - Reestablishes the Interagency Committee on Cigarette and Little Cigar Fire Safety to oversee the work of the Implementation Task Force. Establishes an Implementation Task Force to continue the work specified by the Cigarette Safety Act of 1984, including: (1) development of a validated test method to determine the ignition propensity of cigarettes and little cigars when in contact with upholstered furniture or mattresses; (2) development of performance data for current cigarettes, using the validated test method, so as to compare future cigarette performance; (3) study and computer modeling of ignition physics relating to cigarettes, little cigars, soft furnishings, and fabrics; (4) collection of data regarding the characteristics of cigarettes and little cigars, products ignited, and smokers involved in smoking-related fires as well as changes in the composition of smoke from modified cigarettes and little cigars, and societal costs from smoking-related fire injuries; and (5) commercial feasibility and economic impact of cigarettes and little cigars having reduced ignition propensity. Protects the confidentiality of trade secrets and confidential information provided to the Interagency Committee or the Task Force. Sets forth reporting requirements. Terminates the Task Force within three years and three months of this Act's enactment.</summary>
</bill>
