<bill session="100" type="s" number="303" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jacob K. Javits Gifted and Talented Children and Youth Education Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Federal program to strengthen and improve the capability of State and local educational agencies and private nonprofit schools to identify gifted and talented children and youth and to provide those children and youth with appropriate educational opportunities, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401709"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-10-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-01-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-08-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-04-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-09-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="409580" joined="1987-07-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB, GAO.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-18">
      <text>Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Department of Education"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Gifted children"/>
    <term name="Private schools"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/1987--Introduced.
Jacob K. Javits Gifted and Talented Children and Youth Education Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants and contracts for programs or projects designed to meet the educational needs of gifted and talented children and youth, including the training of teachers or their supervisors. Sets forth authorized uses of such funds. Directs the Secretary to establish a National Center for Research and Development in the Education of Gifted and Talented Children and Youth through grants to or contracts with one or more institutions of higher education or State educational agencies, or a combination or consortium of such institutions and agencies. Sets forth program priorities, including the identification and inclusion of gifted and talented children and youth who may not be identified through traditional assessment methods. Sets forth provisions for participation of private school children and teachers. Directs the Secretary to appoint an advisory committee to advise on the administration of this Act. Directs the Secretary to establish or designate an administrative unit within the Department of Education to administer the programs authorized by this Act, coordinate all programs for gifted and talented children and youth administered by the Department, and serve as a focal point of national leadership and information on the educational needs of gifted and talented children and youth and the availability of educational services and programs designed to meet those needs. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 through 1991 to carry out this Act.</summary>
</bill>
