<bill session="100" type="s" number="304" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Cargo Preference Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the fair and proper implementation of the cargo preference laws of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300056"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Cargo preference"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Merchant ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/12/1987--Introduced.
Cargo Preference Amendments of 1987 - Requires the Comptroller General of the United States (the Comptroller General), within 60 days after the enactment of this Act and every six months thereafter, to: (1) review every Federal program involving the ocean transportation of any item; (2) identify each program which is subject to U.S. cargo preference laws; and (3) notify each Federal department or agency of its responsibilities under such laws. Requires the officer or employee in charge of every department or agency having responsibility under the cargo preference laws, within 15 days after the end of each month, to submit to the Comptroller General a report containing specified information relating to compliance or noncompliance with such cargo preference laws. Authorizes the Comptroller General to take specified action after a determination of noncompliance. Directs the Comptroller General, within 30 days after the end of each fiscal year, to report to the Congress concerning compliance with cargo preference laws during the previous fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
