<bill session="100" type="s" number="315" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-14">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-14"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-14"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urban Mass Transportation Authorization Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend and extend the authorization for the Urban Mass Transporation Act of 1964.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403483"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-01-14"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-14" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21">
      <text>Committee on Banking. Ordered favorably reported an original bill (S. 382) in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="382"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Advertising"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Concessions"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid highway program"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Highway finance"/>
    <term name="Industry-university relations"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Interstate highway system"/>
    <term name="Lease and rental services"/>
    <term name="Mass rapid transit"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor buses"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Railroad finance"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Research centers"/>
    <term name="Roads and highways"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Subways"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
    <term name="Urban transportation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/14/1987--Introduced.
Urban Mass Transportation Authorization Act of 1987 - Amends the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 to authorize appropriations for FY 1986 through 1990 for substitute mass transportation projects under the Federal-aid highway program. Sets forth availability guidelines for Federal grants for: (1) rail modernization; (2) fixed guideway systems; and (3) bus service facilities. Permits block grants to be made to implement an urban mass transportation program of projects in whole or in part. Excludes certain advertising and concession revenues from consideration as a revenue source for purposes of the Federal block grant program for urban mass transportation. Requires Federal block grant recipients to submit an annual report to the Secretary of Transportation regarding revenues derived from the sale of advertising and concessions relating to the operation of a public mass transportation system. Declares that apportionments for small urbanized areas shall be made available to the Governor for expenditure in such areas. Revises the guidelines under which a State may transfer apportioned funds among small urbanized areas. Requires that block grant funds be apportioned by the tenth day following the date on which the funds are appropriated (or as of October 1 of such fiscal year, whichever is later). Precludes the making of any grants in any fiscal year unless the Governor has accepted a certification for such fiscal year by the recipient. Makes block grants for construction projects available to finance the leasing of mass transportation facilities and equipment. Directs the Secretary to publish in the Federal Register proposed regulations regarding such leasing availability. Amends the Urban Mass Transit Act of 1964 to vest in the Secretary the responsibility for the overall implementation and administration of apportioned funds made available to small urbanized areas. Amends the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 to set forth reapportionment guidelines for transit account funds. Amends the Urban Mass Transit Act of 1964 to require each fund recipient to certify to the Secretary by the close of the fiscal year succeeding the first fiscal year for which funds are appropriated that it is such recipient's intent to use any funds not obligated as of the certification date. Declares that apportionments not subject to such certification shall lapse as of the close of such fiscal year. Requires the Secretary to report annually to the Congress on the effects of certain incentive tiers upon the apportionment of funds to formula grant recipients. Amends the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 to prescribe guidelines under which the Secretary may approve advance construction of certain urban mass transportation projects implemented without Federal aid if the Secretary has approved an applicant's plans and specifications. Directs the Secretary to make grants to nonprofit institutions of higher learning to establish and operate one regional transportation center in each of the ten Federal regions. Sets forth criteria to be met by grant recipients. Establishes in the Department of Transportation a national advisory council to: (1) coordinate the research and training to be carried out by grant recipients; (2) disseminate the results of such research; (3) act as a clearinghouse between such centers and the transportation industry; and (4) review and evaluate programs carried out by such centers. Authorizes appropriations for such centers for FY 1987 through 1991. Authorizes certain grant recipients under the Urban Mass Transportation Act of 1964 to contract directly with the original manufacturer or supplier of an associated capital maintenance item to replace it if such recipient certifies that: (1) such manufacturer or supplier is the only source for such item; and (2) the price of the item is no higher than the price paid by like customers. Makes eligible for construction assistance: (1) any bus remanufacturing project which extends the economic life of a bus eight years or more; and (2) any project for the overhaul of rolling stock, whether or not such overhaul increases the useful life of the rolling stock. Lowers the expense threshold for associated capital maintenance items which are eligible for certain mass transportation block grants. Makes the Federal grant for any mass transportation construction project 80 percent of the net project cost. Declares that it is the continuing intent of the Congress, in authorizing Federal assistance under this Act, that the Federal Government should remain neutral on the question of public versus private operation of mass transportation services. Prohibits the Secretary from conditioning Federal assistance upon the particular type of mass transportation service provider selected by local officials. Authorizes the Secretary to use funds to contract with any person for project management oversight activities. States that as a condition of Federal financial assistance for a major capital project under this Act (or the National Capital Transportation Act of 1969), a recipient must implement a project management plan which has been approved by the Secretary and meets certain prescribed criteria. Requires the Secretary to promulgate certain regulations regarding such project management plans, and to submit such regulations to specified congressional committees for review. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 and thereafter for the Federal share of either public mass transit projects or the purchase of passenger equipment. Restricts such appropriation to projects substituted for interstate route segments whose approval was withdrawn before January 1, 1986.</summary>
</bill>
