<bill session="100" type="s" number="318" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senate Confirmation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to insure that all relevant information bearing upon a nominee's fitness and qualifications is made available to the United States Senate in cases where the Senate is required to give its advice and consent, and to require reappointment and reconfirmation of certain senior officials of the Executive Branch during a President's second consecutive term.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Arms Control and Disarmament Agency"/>
    <term name="Central Intelligence Agency"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Defense"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Department of the Air Force"/>
    <term name="Department of the Army"/>
    <term name="Department of the Navy"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Judges"/>
    <term name="Office of Management and Budget"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court"/>
    <term name="Supreme Court justices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/16/1987--Introduced.
Senate Confirmation Act of 1987 - Directs the Federal Bureau of Investigation to conduct a background investigation with respect to the fitness and qualifications of all persons nominated to be officers of the United States who are required to be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Requires the transfer to the Senate or appropriate Senate committee of all information that is transferred to the President in the course of such investigation relating to any person nominated to be: (1) the head of certain departments; (2) Chief Justice, associate justice, circuit judge, or district judge; and (3) an officer of the United States who is required to be appointed by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Provides that this Act does not apply to any person nominated to be an ambassador or an officer in the military or foreign service. Prohibits cabinet-level officials, the Secretaries of the Air Force, Army, or Navy and the Directors of the Office of Management and Budget, the Central Intelligence Agency, or the Arms Control and Disarmament Agency from continuing service during a succeeding presidential term unless such persons are reappointed to such positions by the President by and with the advice and consent of the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
