<bill session="100" type="s" number="321" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:51-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Acid Deposition Control Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to better protect interstate transport of pollutants, to control existing and new sources of acid deposition, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407786"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-02-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-05-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409456" joined="1987-01-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-01-16"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environmental Protection. Hearings concluded. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-187, PT. 1.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environmental Protection. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-22">
      <text>Committee on Environment and Public Works. Ordered favorably reported an original bill (S. 1894) in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEV02" subcommittee="Environmental Protection" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1894"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid precipitation (Meteorology)"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Air pollution measurement"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Copper"/>
    <term name="Diesel motor"/>
    <term name="Electric power conservation"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Gasoline"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Mexico"/>
    <term name="Mineral industries"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sulphur oxides"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s78"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/16/1987--Introduced.
Acid Deposition Control Act of 1987 - Amends the Clean Air Act to establish an interstate transport and acid precursor reduction program. Requires by 1996 a reduction below 1980 levels in annual emissions of sulfur dioxide of 12,000,000 tons and of oxides of nitrogen of 4,000,000 tons. Requires each State to achieve by 1996 an annual Statewide average emissions rate of 0.9 pounds per million British thermal units (Btus) for sulfur dioxide and 0.6 pounds per million Btu's for oxides of nitrogen for all major stationary sources in operation in 1980. Requires each State to adopt, within two years, enforceable measures for reductions from these and other stationary sources sufficient to meet its share of the overall required national reduction. Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA) to approve such measures if certain conditions are met. Requires owners and operators of stationary sources to certify to the State within three years the chosen means of compliance. Requires noncertified sources and sources using fuel substitution to be in compliance within five years. Requires certified sources to enter into binding contracts within five years for the installation and implementation of energy conservation measures. Requires all covered stationary sources to be in compliance by 1996. Prohibits the increase of emissions from a source unless a simultaneous net reduction in emissions in excess of the increase is occurring. Establishes a 0.9 pounds per million Btus emissions rate for sulfur dioxide for fossil fuel fired steam generating units which are major stationary sources of emissions in a State without enforceable measures. Requires compliance for all covered units by 1996. Permits the use of the following measures to reduce emissions in addition to enforceable continuous emission reduction measures if such measures are enforceable by entities and persons other than the State in which the emissions occur: (1) programs in energy conservation where emission reductions can be identified with such programs; (2) least emissions dispatch to meet electric generating demand at existing generating capacity; (3) retirement of major stationary sources at an earlier than provided for date; (4) trading of emission reduction requirements and actual reductions through emission reduction banks or brokerage institutions; and (5) precombustion cleaning of fuels. Makes it a priority to achieve emissions reductions through conservation of electricity. Permits emissions reductions achieved by this means to substitute for emissions reductions attributable to required emissions rate limitations. Requires State implementation plans to prohibit stationary sources from emitting any air pollutant which would contribute to atmospheric loadings of pollutants or their transformation products which might be adverse to public health or the environment. Requires primary nonferrous smelters to be in compliance with applicable emission limitations or standards by 1988, terminating previous exceptions (orders). Establishes emissions of oxides of nitrogen standards for light-duty vehicles, trucks, and engines for model years 1990 and after and for heavy-duty vehicles and engines for model years 1991 and after. Increases the required useful life of emissions control components. Requires at least 90 percent of any new vehicle or engine tested to comply with emissions control requirements to retain a certificate of conformity. Requires vehicle emission control inspection and maintenance programs to test or inspect components of vehicle emissions control systems and to replace inoperative parts. Prohibits the sale of diesel fuel with sulfur content above a specified level after July 1, 1988. Requires the President, by 1988, to institute negotiations with Canada and Mexico to cooperate in reducing air pollution. Directs the President to negotiate treaties or other international agreements to apply uniform standards of performance for the control of air pollutant emissions. Requires the President to seek comparable reductions in sulfur dioxide emissions from Canada. Requires the Secretary of State to give special emphasis to ensuring that the Nacozari smelter in Mexico meets pollution control standards under the Clean Air Act when negotiating with Mexico an Annex concerning transboundary air pollution to the 1983 Border Environmental Agreement. Requires such Annex to address pollution control and monitoring at other smelters within the United States and Mexico. Requires the EPA to perform atmospheric field experiments to determine the effects of pollution controls on the Nacozari smelter. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to study and report on a system of tariffs on emissions adequate to encourage emissions reductions of precursors of acid deposition and other environmental pollution.</summary>
</bill>
