<bill session="100" type="s" number="326" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles 18 and 29 of the United States Code to eliminate, and establish an alternative to the exclusionary rule in Federal criminal proceedings.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU03" subcommittee="Constitution" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Exclusionary rule (Evidence)"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Torts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/20/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Federal criminal code to provide that evidence shall not be excluded from a criminal proceeding because it was obtained in violation of the fourth amendment to the United States Constitution. Makes the United States liable for damages resulting from a search or seizure conducted by a law enforcement officer acting within the scope of employment in violation of the fourth amendment. Permits recovery of actual and punitive damages not exceeding $25,000. Authorizes the court to award reasonable attorney fees. Limits recovery of a person convicted of an offense for which evidence was illegally seized to actual physical personal injury and property damages. Makes such remedy the exclusive civil remedy for a violation of the fourth amendment to the Constitution. Authorizes a Federal agency to discipline an officer who conducts an illegal search or seizure upon a determination, after notice and hearing, that the officer lacked a good faith belief that the search or seizure was constitutional.</summary>
</bill>
