<bill session="100" type="s" number="33" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Social Security Trust Funds Management Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "Social Security Trust Funds Management Act of 1987".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1987-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Old age, survivors and disability insurance"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
    <term name="Social security finance"/>
    <term name="Social security taxes"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Social Security Trust Funds Management Act of 1987 - Amends title II (Old Age, Survivors and Disability Insurance) of the Social Security Act to require that amounts in the Federal Old-Age and Survivors Insurance Trust Fund and the Federal Disability Insurance Trust Fund (OASDI trust funds) be invested by the Managing Trustee of such trust funds as soon as such investments can be made without exceeding the public debt limit or jeopardizing OASDI benefit payments. Directs the Managing Trustee, upon the expiration of a debt limit impact period, to issue and pay to the OASDI trust funds those obligations the trust funds would have held and the interest they would have earned but for the debt limit. Requires that the tax receipts earmarked for the OASDI program be immediately transferred (currently, monthly transfers are made) from the general fund of the Treasury to the OASDI trust funds. Requires members of the OASDI trust funds' Board of Trustees to faithfully execute their duties, but does not impose a fiduciary duty. Directs the Board of Trustees of the OASDI trust funds to meet at least twice a year. (Currently, they must meet at least once a year.) Sets forth provisions requiring reports by the Board of Trustees and the Managing Trustee to the Congress regarding the operation and status of the OASDI trust funds. Prohibits the sale and redemption of OASDI trust fund assets or the expenditure of OASDI trust fund amounts for purposes other than making payments under title II or provisions of law directly related to OASDI programs.</summary>
</bill>
