<bill session="100" type="s" number="356" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote safety in the operation of railroads and aircraft through testing for the use, without lawful authorization, of alcohol and controlled substances by the operators of railroads and aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403171"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-01-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300159" joined="1987-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-13.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to direct the Secretary of Transportation to review existing regulations governing alcohol and drug use in railroad operations for the purpose of determining whether they are adequate to ensure safety. Sets forth the criteria for such review. Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to prescribe regulations establishing a program which requires air carriers, contract carriers, and foreign air carriers to conduct pre-employment testing (as well as periodic recurring and post-accident testing) of airmen and crewmembers upon a reasonable suspicion that they have used alcohol or a controlled substance without lawful authorization. Requires the Administrator to establish such a program applicable to FAA employees whose duties include direct responsibility for flight safety operations. Directs the Administrator to require random testing as part of the testing program for air carriers. Prohibits any air carrier from permitting any individual determined to have used alcohol or a controlled substance without lawful authorization from serving as an airman or crewmember unless such individual has completed a substance abuse rehabilitation program. Requires air carriers to establish and maintain such a rehabilitation program for the identification and opportunity for treatment of airmen and crewmembers who need assistance in resolving substance abuse problems. Requires the Administrator to establish and maintain such a rehabilitation program for FAA employees whose duties include direct responsibility for flight safety operations, and who need assistance in resolving substance abuse problems.</summary>
</bill>
