<bill session="100" type="s" number="362" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airline and Rail Passenger Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 and the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to provide for testing for the use, without lawful authorization, of alcohol or controlled substances by the operators of aircraft and railroads, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-20">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-13.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Airline employees"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and Alcoholic Beverages"/>
    <term name="Alcoholism"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drug testing"/>
    <term name="Drugs and employment"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroad safety"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Airline and Rail Passenger Protection Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 to direct the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration (FAA) to prescribe regulations establishing a program requiring air carriers, contract carriers and foreign air carriers to conduct pre-employment testing (as well as periodic recurring, random, and post-accident testing) of airmen, crewmembers,and airport security screening contract personnel upon a reasonable suspicion that they have used alcohol or a controlled substance without lawful authorization. Requires the Administrator to establish such a program applicable to FAA employees whose duties include direct responsibility for flight safety operations. Sets forth guidelines for such program. Prohibits any individual who has used alcohol or a controlled substance without lawful authorization from serving as an airman, crewmember, airport security screening contract personnel, or employee of the FAA with direct responsibility for flight safety operations unless such individual has completed a rehabilitation program established under FAA auspices. Requires air carriers to establish and maintain a rehabilitation program for the identification and opportunity for treatment of airmen, crewmembers, and airport security screening contract personnel who need assistance in resolving substance abuse problems. Requires the Administrator to establish and maintain such a rehabilitation program for FAA employees whose duties include direct responsibility for flight safety operations, and who need assistance in resolving substance abuse problems. Amends the Federal Railroad Safety Act of 1970 to direct the Secretary of Transportation to review existing regulations governing alcohol and drug use in railroad operations to determine whether they are adequate to ensure safety. Sets forth the criteria for such review.</summary>
</bill>
