<bill session="100" type="s" number="369" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Emergency Planning Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to require an emergency planning and preparedness plan for an emergency planning zone of at least 10 miles in radius for each nuclear facility.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405795"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-07-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-06-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Nuclear Emergency Planning Act of 1987 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from granting an operating license to any nuclear power reactor applicant who has not been granted a full power operating license on or before January 1, 1987, unless: (1) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has reviewed and found adequate off-site emergency response plans which encompass a ten-mile radius; and (2) the NRC determines that the off-site emergency plans comply with federally prescribed standards and provide reasonable assurance that adequate protective measures will be taken in the event of a radiological emergency. Prohibits the NRC from reducing the existing emergency planning zone for a nuclear power reactor which was issued an operating license before January 1, 1987. Mandates that the standards of the NRC and FEMA for off-site and onsite emergency response plans for nuclear power reactors shall be at least as protective of public health and safety as those which are in effect as of January 1, 1987.</summary>
</bill>
