<bill session="100" type="s" number="37" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:44-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Permanent Housing for Homeless Families Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part A of title IV of the Social Security Act to reduce the need for emergency assistance payments to provide temporary housing for destitute families and homeless AFDC families, and the expense of such payments, by authorizing grants to States for the construction or rehabilitation of permanent housing that such families can afford with their regular AFDC payments.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Low-income housing"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="State-local relations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Permanent Housing for Homeless Families Act - Amends part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) of title IV of the Social Security Act to authorize the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to States for the construction and rehabilitation of permanent housing for rental to AFDC recipients who would otherwise require AFDC emergency assistance in the form of temporary housing. Requires that such grants be used to provide permanent housing which is: (1) owned by the State, an instrumentality of the State, or a nonprofit organization; (2) available to families who have been unable to find decent, nontemporary housing at rents that can be paid with AFDC aid for shelter; and (3) located in jurisdictions experiencing a critical shortage of such housing. Requires that: (1) the costs of providing permanent housing be lower than costs which would be incurred if, instead, the State made AFDC emergency assistance payments providing temporary housing; and (2) the most costly temporary housing be retired from use in the emergency assistance program as permanent housing becomes available for occupancy, unless temporary housing is demonstrably needed. Sets the State contribution to the cost of constructing or rehabilitating such housing at at least the current State AFDC share increased by ten percent. Prohibits States from requiring their political subdivisions to pay a higher percentage of such costs than such subdivisions otherwise pay under the State AFDC plan.</summary>
</bill>
