<bill session="100" type="s" number="370" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:30-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Environmental Closure Workers Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide job training benefits for dislocated workers who are unemployed due to the closure of facilities as a result of failure to comply with environmental laws, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-01-21"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Environmental law and legislation"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Liability for environmental damages"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Plant shutdowns"/>
    <term name="Relocation of employees"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Unemployment insurance"/>
    <term name="Vocational and technical education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/21/1987--Introduced.
Environmental Closure Workers Assistance Act - Requires the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to provide benefits for dislocated workers out of monies received as penalties for violations of the environmental laws by such workers' employers if such employers' operations were terminated or curtailed as a result of such violations. Authorizes the Administrator to credit violators for any environmentally beneficial projects when negotiating consent decrees. Includes job training, basic and adult education, relocation expenses, unemployment benefits, and other educational assistance whose basic purpose is to train such dislocated workers among the allowable benefits which may be paid out of employment offices established under the Wagner Peyser Act and the private industry councils established under the Job Training Partnership Act.</summary>
</bill>
