<bill session="100" type="s" number="377" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-22">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-22"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-22"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to impose a moratorium on the ability of foreign-built vessels to qualify for certain benefits under the Magnuson Fishery Conservation and Management Act, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1987-01-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-22" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Subcommittee on National Ocean Policy Study. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-124.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-28">
      <text>Committee on Commerce. Hearings held in conjunction with the National Ocean Policy Study.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM07" subcommittee="National Ocean Policy Study" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Citizenship"/>
    <term name="Fish processing ships"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Merchant marine"/>
    <term name="Merchant seamen"/>
    <term name="Ships"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Vessel documentation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s657"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/22/1987--Introduced.
Makes it unlawful, until June 1, 1997, for foreign-built vessels that are U.S.-documented after January 1, 1987, to engage in the processing of fish for commercial use or consumption. Amends Federal shipping provisions to require all of the seamen employed on a U.S.-documented fish processing vessel to be U.S. citizens. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce to issue regulations necessary to obtain information on the transportation of fish products by vessels of the United States from foreign fish processing vessels to points in the United States. Directs the Secretary, within six months after the enactment of this Act, to report to the Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation Committee and the House Merchant Marine and Fisheries Committee concerning the transportation of such fish products and its potential impact on the development of the U.S. domestic fishing industry, together with legislative recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
