<bill session="100" type="s" number="408" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:52-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-28">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-28"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-28"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Nuclear Emergency Preparedness Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to allow full participation by State and local governments in the licensing process for nuclear power facilities and to require that emergency planning extend to a minimum of 10 miles in radius around each nuclear power facility.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-01-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1988-04-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-28" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Emergency management"/>
    <term name="Evacuation of civilians"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Nuclear energy"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plant accidents"/>
    <term name="Nuclear power plants"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Radiation safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s38"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>1/28/1987--Introduced.
Nuclear Emergency Preparedness Act of 1987 - Amends the Atomic Energy Act of 1954 to prohibit the Nuclear Regulatory Commission (NRC) from granting an operating license to any applicant authorizing operation at a greater power level than that which was authorized on January 1, 1987, unless: (1) the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) has reviewed and found adequate emergency plans which have been prepared by each State in consultation with the local governments which lie within the emergency planning zone and which have been submitted for a zone at least ten miles in radius; (2) the NRC determines that the State plans comply with federally prescribed standards and provide reasonable assurance that adequate protective measures will be taken in the event of a radiological emergency; and (3) the Chief Executive Officer of each State submitting such a plan has approved in writing the final emergency plan. Prohibits the NRC from reducing the existing emergency planning zone for a nuclear power reactor which was issued an operating license before January 1, 1987. Mandates that the standards of the NRC and the FEMA for off-site and onsite emergency response plans for nuclear power reactors shall be at least as protective of public health and safety as those which are in effect as of January 1, 1987.</summary>
</bill>
