<bill session="100" type="s" number="453" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Ionizing Radiation Compensation Improvements Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 38, United States Code, and the Veterans' Dioxin and Radiation Exposure Compensation Standards Act to improve the standards for determining whether a radiation-related disease is service-connected, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1987-02-04"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-05-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-06-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-02-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-11">
      <text>Committee on Veterans requested executive comment from VA, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-30">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Atomic bomb"/>
    <term name="Bone diseases"/>
    <term name="Cancer"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Leukemia"/>
    <term name="Liver diseases"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radiation"/>
    <term name="Veterans' benefits"/>
    <term name="Veterans' disability compensation"/>
    <term name="War casualties"/>
    <term name="World War II"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1987--Introduced.
Veterans' Ionizing Radiation Compensation Improvements Act of 1987 - Amends Federal veterans' benefits provisions to create a presumption of service-connection (for purposes of eligibility for such benefits) for veterans exposed to ionizing radiation due to the atmospheric detonation of a nuclear device or the American occupation of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, Japan, during World War II who contract, within specified periods since such exposure, leukemia, liver cancer, or bone cancer. Creates an identical presumption of service-connection for the above-qualified veterans when determining either wartime or peacetime disability or death compensation. Amends the Veterans' Dioxin and Radiation Exposure Compensation Standards Act to provide for the determination of dosage resulting from the above described exposure to ionizing radiation for the purpose of adjudicating a claim for Federal veterans' benefits on behalf of any such veteran or their survivors.</summary>
</bill>
