<bill session="100" type="s" number="476" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-04">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-04"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Young Americans Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">1990 White House Conference on Young Americans</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide assistance in the development of new or improved programs to help younger persons through grants to the States for community planning, services, and training; to establish within the Department of Health and Human Services an operating agency to be designated as the Administration on Children, Youth, and Families; and to provide for a White House Conference on Young Americans.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300034"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-07-14"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1988-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1988-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300072" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-04-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1988-03-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-05-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-04" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-17">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-17">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, Education Department, Labor Department, HUD, Transportation Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Subcommittee on Children, Family, Drugs, Alcohol. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSHR06" subcommittee="Children, Family, Drugs and Alcoholism" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1003"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1003"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Child health"/>
    <term name="Children and youth"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="White House conferences"/>
    <term name="Youth"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
    <term name="Youth services"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/4/1987--Introduced.
Young Americans Act of 1987 - Title I: Declaration of Objectives; Definitions - Sets forth the declaration of objectives and definitions under this Act. Title II: The Administration on Children, Youth, and Families - Establishes in the Office of the Secretary of Health and Human Services an Administration on Children, Youth, and Families which shall be headed by a Commissioner on Children, Youth, and Families. Sets forth the duties and functions of the Administration. Directs the Commissioner to advise, consult, and cooperate with the head of each Federal agency or department proposing or administering programs or services substantially related to the purpose of this Act. Establishes a Federal Council on Children, Youth, and Families. Directs the Council to report annually to the President. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 through 1990. Sets forth the administrative authority of the Commissioner under this Act. Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to issue regulations for the administration of this Act. Directs the Secretary to measure and evaluate the impact of all programs authorized under this Act. Directs the Commissioner to report annually to the President and the Congress on the activities carried out under this Act and other activities delegated by the Secretary to the Administration. Directs the Commissioner, within two years after the enactment of this Act, to report to the Congress on the extent to which the need for services for the prevention and treatment of the abuse of children is unmet. Provides for advance funding under this Act. Title III: Grants for State and Community Programs for Children, Youth, and Families - Part A: General Provisions - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 through 1990 for grants under part A of this title (State and community planning) and under part B of this title (supportive services). Provides for State allotments for part A based on population aged 24 or younger. Sets forth requirements for a State to be eligible to participate in programs of grants to States from allotments under this title. Requires designation of a State agency to: (1) serve as an effective and visible advocate for children and youth by reviewing and commenting on all State plans, budgets, and priorities which affect children, youth, and their families and by providing technical assistance to those representing the needs of the young; (2) develop and administer the State plan; (3) coordinate all State activities related to the purpose of this Act; and (4) divide the State into district planning and service areas and designate area agencies for children, youth, and families. Requires area agencies to develop area advocacy plans. Requires each such plan to determine for young individuals the extent of the need within the area with respect to: (1) physical and mental health; (2) physical shelter; (3) educational opportunity; (4) training and apprenticeship programs leading to employment; (5) civic, cultural, and recreational activities; and (6) opportunities for participation in decisions concerning the planning and managing of their lives. Requires the plan to evaluate the use of resources in meeting such need. Requires State plans to be based upon area plans. Requires State plans to provide assurances that the State agency will establish and operate an out-of-home placement care ombudsman program. Provides that part A State allotments may be used to make grants to States for paying up to 75 percent of the cost of administration of its State plan. Part B: Supportive Services - Directs the Commissioner to make grants to States under approved State plans to demonstrate successful program approaches to service gaps identified through State and area planning and advocacy efforts. Lists eligible services under this part. Provides that part B appropriations may be used to make grants for paying up to 85 percent of supportive services. Title IV: White House Conference on Young Americans - 1990 White House Conference on Young Americans - Directs the President to call a White House Conference on Young Americans in 1990. Provides that the Conference shall be planned and conducted under the direction of the Secretary of Health and Human Services in cooperation with the Commissioner on Children, Youth, and Families and the heads of other appropriate Federal agencies. Requires the final report of the Conference to be submitted to the President within 180 days following the date on which the Conference is adjourned. Directs the Secretary, within 90 days after submission of the report, to transmit to the President and the Congress recommendations for administrative action and legislation necessary to implement the report's recommendations. Sets forth provisions for the administration of the Conference. Directs the Secretary to establish an advisory committee to the Conference and such other committees as may be necessary to assist in planning, conducting, and reviewing the Conference. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990 to carry out this title.</summary>
</bill>
