<bill session="100" type="s" number="481" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize negotiation of reciprocal trade agreements.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407268"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign exchange"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="Import relief"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International monetary system"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="Nontariff trade barriers"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Technology transfer"/>
    <term name="Trade agreements"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1987--Introduced.
Authorizes the President, during a specified ten-year period, to enter into multilateral trade agreements to reduce or eliminate trade barriers or distortions whenever the President determines that such barriers to, or distortions of, international trade: (1) unduly burden or restrict U.S. foreign trade or adversely affect the U.S. economy; or (2) are likely to result in such a burden, restriction, or effect. Limits the amount of reduction in duty that such agreements may involve. Authorizes the President, during a specified ten-year period, to enter into bilateral trade agreements with foreign countries providing for the reduction or elimination of trade barriers or distortions. Provides that such a bilateral trade agreement may be entered into only if: (1) the foreign country requested the negotiation of such an agreement; and (2) the President provides 60 days' notice to specified congressional committees and consults with such committees. Requires the President, before entering into negotiation of such a multilateral or bilateral trade agreement, to determine: (1) whether state trading enterprises account for a significant share of the exports of such foreign country or of the goods of such country that are subject to import competition; and (2) whether such state trading enterprises unduly burden or restrict, or adversely affect U.S. foreign trade or the U.S. economy or are likely to result in such a burden, restriction, or effect. Authorizes the President, if a country's state trading enterprises meet such criteria, to enter into a multilateral or bilateral trade agreement with such country only if such agreement provides that the state trading enterprises: (1) will make non-governmental purchases and sales in international trade in accordance with commercial considerations; and (2) will give U.S. businesses adequate opportunity to compete for participation in such purchases and sales. Provides that a multilateral or bilateral trade agreement may be entered into only if the trade agreement: (1) meets at least one of the negotiating objectives described in this Act; (2) provides for the reciprocal exchange of obligations among the signatories to the agreement; (3) provides a reasonable likelihood that the United States can enforce the obligations of such agreement; and (4) complements and reinforces existing agreements with non-signatory countries and existing U.S. agreements on related economic subjects. Requires the President, before entering into such a multilateral or bilateral trade agreement, to consult with specified congressional committees. Requires the U.S. Trade Representative to consult with interested congressional committees on a continuing basis in order to inform the Congress of trade negotiations and the progress in meeting, and obstacles to achieving, U.S. trade negotiating objectives. Provides that a multilateral or bilateral trade agreement entered into under this Act shall enter into force with respect to the United States if: (1) the President has notified the Congress of the intent to enter into such an agreement; (2) after entering into the agreement the President submits the final legal text of the agreement to the Congress together with other specified materials; and (3) the implementing bill is enacted. Authorizes the President to make certain recommendations to the Congress in order to ensure that a foreign country that receives benefits under a trade agreement is subject to obligations under the agreement. Imposes limitations on the use of expedited congressional procedures for the consideration of an implementing bill or approval resolution relating to such trade agreements. Declares that the overall objectives of the United States in international trade negotiations shall be, to obtain: (1) more open, fair, and equitable market access; (2) the reduction or elimination of barriers and other trade-distorting practices; (3) an appropriate overall balance between benefits and concessions within the agricultural, manufacturing, mining, and service sectors; and (4) improved management of the new global economy. Sets forth the principal objectives in negotiating such agreements. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to declare that the principal U.S. negotiating objectives under the import relief provisions of such Act shall be to eliminate or reduce foreign barriers to equitable access by U.S. persons to foreign development technology. Requires the United States, in pursuing such objectives, to take into account U.S. policies in licensing or otherwise making available to foreign persons technology and other information developed by U.S. laboratories. Provides termination and reservation authority for trade agreements entered into under this Act. Requires the President to determine, after a specified five-year period, whether any major industrial country has failed to make reciprocal concessions under a trade agreement. Requires the President to recommend certain legislation to the Congress with respect to such a country if the country has failed to make such concessions. Provides that no political party shall dominate the membership of specified trade advisory committees. Requires the President to make the same determinations regarding state trading enterprises before a foreign country accedes to a multinational trade agreement to which the United States is a party that the President is required to make before entering into negotiation of a multilateral or bilateral trade agreement under this Act. Requires the President, if a country's state trading enterprises meet such criteria, to reserve the right of the United States to withhold extension of such agreement between the United States and such country. Provides that, if a country's state trading enterprises meet such criteria such trade agreement shall not apply between the United States and such country until: (1) such country and the United States enter into an agreement providing that the state trading enterprises will make certain purchases and sales in accordance with commercial considerations and will afford U.S. businesses an opportunity to compete for such purchases and sales; or (2) a bill which approves the extension of such agreement between the United States and such foreign country is enacted. Provides for expedited congressional consideration of such an implementing bill. Requires the President to begin bilateral negotiations on an expedited basis with each foreign country which pegs its currency to the U.S. dollar to ensure that such country regularly adjusts the exchange rate between its currency and the dollar to reflect underlying economic fundamentals. Requires the President to submit to the Congress a semi-annual report on such negotiations and developments in the exchange rates.</summary>
</bill>
