<bill session="100" type="s" number="488" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend agricultural laws of the United States to improve United States agricultural exports.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300065"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Agriculture.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-05">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Domestic and Foreign Marketing.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSAF" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSAF02" subcommittee="Domestic and Foreign Marketing and Product Promotion" name="Senate Agriculture, Nutrition, and Forestry"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Agriculture"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Export credit"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade promotion"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Quality control"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Trade fairs"/>
    <term name="Trade negotiations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1987--Introduced.
Declares that it is U.S. policy to increase agricultural exports, to recapture the U.S. market share in agricultural trade, and to support programs to make U.S. exports more competitive abroad. Sets forth other policy and negotiating objectives relating to agriculture. Authorizes the Secretary of Agriculture to make available certain commodities to cooperator organizations which shall use the commodities to establish demonstration projects designed to expand markets for U.S. agricultural commodities and products. Requires that there be at least 850 full-time employees during each of FY 1987, 1988, and 1989 in the Foreign Agricultural Service of the Department of Agriculture. Expresses the sense of the Congress that such a number of employees should make it possible for the Service to devote greater resources to developing markets for U.S. agricultural commodities and products. Requires an agricultural attache who is reassigned from abroad to counsel agricultural producers on means of increasing exports and agricultural market development and promotional activities. Requires at least 60 percent of the personnel resource time of agricultural attaches who are stationed abroad to be devoted to market development and promotional activities for U.S. agricultural commodities. Authorizes the Secretary to contract with an individual for services to be performed outside the United States as necessary in order to carry out market development activities for U.S. agricultural commodities. Establishes within the Service an Office of International Market Development and Export Promotion to coordinate all market development, promotion, export enhancement, export credit, and targeted export assistance programs. Requires the Office to report annually to specified congressional committees on the market development programs. Establishes within the Office a unit to monitor the quality of agricultural exports. Requires the unit to: (1) act as liaison with the Federal Grain Inspection Service, private U.S. exporters, foreign governments, and U.S. agricultural attaches overseas; (2) receive and respond to complaints about the quality of U.S. agricultural exports; and (3) identify problems in foreign markets concerning the quality of U.S. commodities and ensure that notice of such problems is provided to the relevant entities for quick response and follow-up. Establishes within the Office a unit to evaluate the overall effectiveness of the market development and promotional programs of the Service. Requires the unit to report annually to specified congressional committees on such programs. Earmarks at least 50 percent of the FY 1987 increase in funding of the Service to be used to create new markets for U.S. agricultural commodities in developing markets. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 for trade shows and exhibitions conducted by the Service. Sets forth the ways the increase in funding for trade shows shall be used. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 for program management and support activities of the Service and for its market promotion and trade development activities. Requires some of the increased funding to be used to provide adequate staff for: (1) the development of markets for high value-added products; and (2) the improvement of the quality of agricultural exports. Establishes within the Department of Agriculture an Export Market Development Advisory Committee to: (1) review all U.S. agricultural market development and export enhancement programs; and (2) make recommendations for the improvement of such programs.</summary>
</bill>
