<bill session="100" type="s" number="492" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-09">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-12-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Construction Industry Labor Law Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Building and Construction Industry Labor Law Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Labor Relations Act to increase the stability of collective bargaining in the building and construction industry.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1988-01-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-11">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-11">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Labor Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Labor. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Labor. Approved for full committee consideration without amendment favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-12-09" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-04-12">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. With written report No. 100-314. Minority views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-04-12" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="611">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 611.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting" code="SSHR03" subcommittee="Labor" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining agreements"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining unit"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Multiunit collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Violence"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/12/1988--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Labor and Human Resources with an amendment, S. Rept. 100-314) Building and Construction Industry Labor Law Amendments of 1987 - Amends the National Labor Relations Act to provide that any two or more business entities engaged primarily in the building and construction industry, performing work within the geographical area covered by a collective bargaining agreement to which any of the entities is a party, and performing the type of work described in such agreement, shall be deemed a single employer if they have, directly or indirectly, substantial common ownership, management, or control. Provides that the terms and provisions of a contractor-subcontractor relationship shall not be deemed to create a single employer or to be evidence of direct or indirect management or control for such purposes. Applies the terms of a collective bargaining agreement regarding employees of such business entities to all other business entities comprising the single employer and performing the work described in the collective bargaining agreement within the geographical area covered by it. States that collective bargaining agreements may only be repudiated after the National Labor Relations Board certifies election results in which a majority of the employees either selects a bargaining representative other than the representative with whom such agreement was made or chooses not to be represented by a labor organization.</summary>
</bill>
