<bill session="100" type="s" number="5" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pay Equity Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Federal Employee Compensation Study Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the executive branch to enforce applicable equal employment opportunity laws and directives so as to promote pay equity by eliminating wage-setting practices which discriminate on the basis of sex, race, ethnicity, age, or disability, and result in discriminatory wage differentials.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-01-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-28">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Federal Services, Post Office.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSGA05" subcommittee="Federal Services, Post Office, and Civil Service" name="Senate Governmental Affairs"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Equal pay for equal work"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Pay equity"/>
    <term name="Position classification"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Wages"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Pay Equity Act of 1987 - Requires the Equal Employment Opportunity Commission, after consultation with the Secretary of Labor, to publish in the Federal Register guidelines for identifying and eliminating discriminatory wage-setting practices and discriminatory wage differentials. Requires the guidelines to include recommendations for utilization of job-evaluation techniques to establish rates of compensation for employees. Requires the Commission to submit annually to the President and the Congress a detailed report of its activities in carrying out the purposes of this Act. Requires the Secretary of Labor to publish guidelines and submit an annual report to the President and the Congress for the purpose of requiring all U.S. contractors to identify and eliminate discriminatory wage-setting practices and wage differentials. Federal Employee Compensation Study Act of 1987 - Establishes the Commission on Compensation Equity to provide for a consultant to study the classification, grading, and pay-setting processes within and between the position classification system and the prevailing rate system. Requires the study to determine whether these processes result in the payment of rates of basic pay for positions: (1) in which either sex is numerically predominant or any race or ethnic group is disproportionately represented; and (2) where such differences in pay are not in proportion to the duties, difficulty, responsibility, or qualification requirements of the work performed. Provides a timetable for: (1) the Commission to report to appropriate congressional committees and the Director of the Office of Personnel Management with advisory recommendations; (2) the Director to report to the committees and the Commission with a plan to carry out any of the recommendations; and (3) additional comments from the Commission and its termination. Requires each Federal agency responsible for submitting an equal employment opportunity plan under the Civil Rights Act of 1964 to include a review and identification of any discriminatory wage-setting practices and wage differentials with respect to its labor force and a plan to eliminate such practices. Requires the Commission to submit to the President and the Congress a detailed report of its enforcement activities relating to the Equal Pay Act.</summary>
</bill>
