<bill session="100" type="s" number="50" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Senate Campaign Finance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to provide for the public financing of Senate general election campaigns, to change certain contribution limits for elections, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-05">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-23">
      <text>Committee on Rules. Hearings concluded. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-127.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Campaign funds"/>
    <term name="Congressional elections"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Members of Congress (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Political action committees"/>
    <term name="Voting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Senate Campaign Finance Act of 1987 - Amends the Federal Election Campaign Act of 1971 to increase, from $1,000 to $2,000, the amount a person may contribute to a candidate for Federal office. Decreases, from $5,000 to $3,000, the amount a multicandidate political committee may contribute to any political committee other than an individual candidate's committee or a national political party committee. Revises the definition of independent expenditure. Establishes provisions for public financing of Senate general election campaigns. Requires candidates to make certain certifications to the Federal Election Commission regarding compliance with provisions of this Act. Limits personal expenditures of such candidates to $20,000. Entitles eligible candidates to aggregate payments based upon State voting-age populations and whether a candidate is of a major or minor political party. Declares that eligible candidates are entitled to such payments only to defray qualified campaign expenses. Authorizes additional entitlements to opponents of nonpublicly financed candidates to match those contributions or expenditures raised, incurred, or expended by the latter in excess of the latter's entitlement. Requires the Federal Election Commission to certify to the Secretary of the Treasury the full amount to which an eligible candidate is entitled. Requires the Secretary to maintain in the Presidential Election Campaign Fund the Senate General Election Campaign Fund for the deposit of funds for payments to eligible candidates. Directs the Commission, after each election, to audit the campaign expenses of publicly financed candidates. Requires such candidates to repay any excess amounts received. Establishes criminal penalties for violations of this Act. Directs the Commission to report to the Senate after each election on actions taken under such Act. Provides for judicial review of Commission actions. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
