<bill session="100" type="s" number="502" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:55-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Land Remote-Sensing Commercialization Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Land Remote-Sensing Commercialization Act of 1984, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="Artificial satellites"/>
    <term name="Commercialization"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Earth resources satellites"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Privatization"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Remote sensing"/>
    <term name="Research and development"/>
    <term name="Space"/>
    <term name="Space policy"/>
    <term name="Space sciences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1987--Introduced.
Land Remote-Sensing Commercialization Act Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Land Remote-Sensing Commercialization Act of 1984 (the Act) to exempt contractors from a requirement to fully reimburse the Federal Government under certain circumstances in the case of research and development agreements. Authorizes the Secretary of Commerce, following the completion of a contract under provisions for data continuity after the Landsat system, and upon 30 days' advance notice to specified congressional committees, to dispose of any Government assets (other than real property) so as to ensure continuation of the contractor's commercial activity. Revises provisions concerning the use of experimental data from Federal research and development programs. Adds provisions relating to the use of non-Federal data from the research and development activities of system operators or marketing entities. Authorizes system operators to require that unenhanced data not be reproduced or disseminated by a foreign or domestic purchaser.</summary>
</bill>
