<bill session="100" type="s" number="514" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-02">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jobs for Employable Dependent Individuals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Jobs for Employable Dependent Individuals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">AFDC/SSI and Summer Youth Employment and Training Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Jobs for Employable Dependent Individuals Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate" partial="1">AFDC/SSI and Summer Youth Employment and Training Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Job Training Act to establish an incentive bonus for the successful placement of certain employable dependent individuals, to provide targeting of assistance from certain carryover funds for such individuals, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300059"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-02-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-03-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06">
      <text>Subcommittee on Employment and Productivity. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-163.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-18" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-03-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title. With written report No. 100-20. Additional views filed.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-20" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="63">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 63.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="61" datetime="1987-04-02" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment and an amendment to the Title by Yea-Nay Vote. 99-0. Record Vote No: 61.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Referred to House Committee on Education and Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-29">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-30">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee Hearings Held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSHR04" subcommittee="Employment and Productivity" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
    <committee code="HSED" name="House Education and Labor" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Aid to dependent children"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Blind"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Families"/>
    <term name="Family planning and birth control"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to youth services"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Poverty"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Teenage pregnancy"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Vocational guidance"/>
    <term name="Youth employment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s32"/>
    <amendment number="s77"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/2/1987--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended, roll call #61 (99-0)) Jobs for Employable Dependent Individuals Act - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act (JTPA) to entitle each State to the payment of a bonus for the successful job placement of certain employable dependent individuals. Makes the following persons eligible to be counted for an incentive bonus: (1) a head of a household who has received benefits continuously under part A (Aid to Families with Dependent Children) (AFDC) of title IV of the Social Security Act or under cash and medical assistance to refugees under the Immigration and Nationality Act, or a blind or disabled person who has received benefits continuously under title XVI (Supplemental Security Income) (SSI) of the Social Security Act, for at least two years prior to participation in education, training, and support activities designed to provide jobs for such individuals, and who has no work experience for the year preceding the year for which the eligibility determination is made; or (2) a head of a household who receives benefits at the time the determination of eligibility is made under AFDC, under cash and medical assistance to refugees, or a blind or disabled individual who receives benefits under the SSI program, who has not attained 22 years of age, has not completed secondary school or its equivalent (except that this does not apply to blind or disabled persons), and has no work experience for the year preceding the year for which the eligibility determination is made. Requires that such individual: (1) participate in education, training, and support activities (other than employment-related services and activities in a program established under the Social Security Act) which are designed to provide jobs for such individuals; (2) be placed in nonsubsidized employment (or in the case of a blind or disabled individual, in employment or supported employment) for at least one year after such participation; (3) receive from such employment an income equal to or greater than the cash benefits under the relevant aid program; and (4) no longer qualify for such aid benefits. Provides that the amount of the incentive bonus paid to each State shall be equal to: (1) 75 percent of the placement bonus base for each successful placement; (2) 50 percent for the second continuous year of such employment; and (3) 25 percent for the third year. Includes in such calculation only placements in excess of those during FY 1986 or another base period agreed upon by the Governor and the Secretary of Labor (Secretary). Sets forth a formula for the determination of the placement bonus base for each category of eligible recipient. Sets forth State application requirements. Requires adequate verification of placements for approval of applications. Directs the Governor to reserve an amount equal to the amount the State receives for incentive bonuses and to: (1) set aside up to 15 percent of the amount so reserved in each fiscal year for distribution to participating State agencies to support the costs of establishing and maintaining systems necessary for the operation of the incentive bonus program; and (2) distribute the remainder of the reserved amount to participating agencies, private industry councils in service delivery areas (SDAs), and service providers, including community-based organizations, who contribute to the incentive bonus program. Limits use of these remainder funds to the following activities designed for the job preparation and job placement of participants: (1) outreach; (2) basic and remedial education, including English language training; (3) training and supportive services, including child care; and (4) transportation. Directs the Secretary to evaluate the incentive bonus program and to report the results, including an analysis of the program's costs and savings, to the Congress within three years after this Act's enactment. Reallots unexpended funds exceeding 20 percent of a State's JTPA fiscal year allocation for certain training services for the disadvantaged, plus any balance from the prior year, to States that did not have such excess funds. Requires the Secretary to reallot such monies in accordance with States' need for the ability to use the funds for the incentive bonus program. Directs the Secretary to: (1) provide improved information and technical assistance on performance standards adjustment approaches; (2) collect data that more adequately identify hard-to-serve individuals and long-term welfare dependency; (3) provide guidance on setting performance goals at the service provider level that encourages increased service to targeted persons; and (4) reexamine performance standards to ensure that they provide maximum flexibility in serving the hard-to-serve, especially long-term welfare recipients. Establishes a basic measure for performance applicable to certain adult education programs. Directs the Secretary to prescribe standards to determine whether the basic measure is being achieved. Lists factors to be included in such standards. AFDC/SSI and Summer Youth Employment and Training Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Job Training Partnership Act (JTPA) to add provisions for an AFDC/SSI Youth Employment and Training Program. Allows each service delivery area (SDA) to elect to use funds specified for such program in addition to or in lieu of services for youth available under the Summer Youth Employment and Training Program, including exemplary youth programs. Provides that the AFDC/SSI Youth program may be conducted on a year-round basis. Makes an individual eligible to participate in the AFDC/SSI Youth program if such individual: (1) is aged 16 through 21, or 14 through 21 if appropriate and set forth in the job training plan; (2) is receiving payments, or whose needs are considered in determining payments, made under the program of aid to families with dependent children under a State plan approved under part A of title IV of the Social Security Act or title XVI of the Social Security Act relating to supplement security income; and (3) is at risk of becoming a long-term welfare recipient or long-term unemployed. Provides for the following services: (1) basic and remedial education; (2) drug and alcohol abuse counseling; (3) child care classes; (4) life skills planning classes; (5) classroom training, on-the-job training, work experience, job search assistance, employment counseling, world-of-work orientation, and any other educational, employment, or job training activity designed to prepare participants for, or place them in, employment; and (6) supportive services necessary to enable such individuals to participate in the program. Subjects the new programs established under this Act to the JTPA's requirements relating to the submission of a plan, plan review and approval procedures, and performance standards. Requires the Secretary, in prescribing performance standards relating to the placement of certain employable dependent individuals, to weight the placement of such persons in accordance with the average costs of successful placement of such persons compared to the average cost of successful placement of individuals eligible for other specified services for disadvantaged persons.</summary>
</bill>
