<bill session="100" type="s" number="517" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the purpose of carrying out the activities of the Department of Justice for fiscal year 1988 and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-02-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Conferences"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA)"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI)"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to law enforcement agencies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Juvenile corrections"/>
    <term name="Juvenile delinquency"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicles"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
    <term name="Narcotics and crime"/>
    <term name="Prison administration"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="Victims of crimes"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/5/1987--Introduced.
Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Year 1988 - Title I - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 to the Department of Justice for: (1) general administration; (2) the General Administration Working Capital Fund; (3) the United States Parole Commission; (4) general legal activities; (5) the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission; (6) the United States Marshals Service; (7) the support of United States prisoners in non-Federal institutions; (8) fees and expenses of witnesses; (9) the Community Relations Service; (10) the United States Trustees System Fund; (11) the Assets Forfeiture Fund; (12) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (13) the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA); (14) the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS); and (15) the Federal Prison System. Allows up to $75,000 of the funds authorized to the Department to be made available for official reception and representation expenses. Title II - Provides general authorizations for: (1) travel expenses; (2) construction of new law enforcement facilities; (3) the treatment and care of prisoners; (4) purchasing and leasing motor vehicles; (5) purchasing firearms and ammunition; (6) leasing surveillance sites; (7) the acquisition, maintenance, and operation of aircraft; (8) miscellaneous and emergency expenses; (9) official reception and representation expenses; (10) meetings; (11) training for law enforcement personnel; (12) services of interpreters and translators; (13) the payment of rewards; (14) insurance; and (15) benefits for employees serving overseas. Authorizes the Attorney General to collect fees from State, local, and private agencies to defray the cost of services provided by the Department. Authorizes the Attorney General to accept, subject to specified restrictions, gifts for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Department. Provides guidelines for the use of appropriations by the Attorney General for: (1) the FBI; (2) the DEA; (3) the INS; (4) the Bureau of Prisons; and (5) the United States Marshals Service. Provides guidelines with respect to the authorizations and exemptions which may be utilized for undercover operations conducted by the FBI, the DEA, the INS, and the U.S. Marshals Service. Title III - Authorizes the Attorney General to make payments for assistance to individuals under the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980. Amends the Immigration and Nationality Act of 1952 to authorize INS agents and officers to: (1) carry firearms; (2) execute and serve warrants, subpoenas, or other processes issued under the authority of the United States; (3) make arrests without a warrant (under certain circumstances); and (4) perform other law enforcement duties as designated by the Attorney General. Authorizes the Attorney General to make payments for the support of United States prisoners in non-Federal institutions. Authorizes Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated, and the U.S. Parole Commission to purchase motor vehicles. Authorizes the Attorney General to host the annual meeting of the General Assembly of INTERPOL and to periodically sponsor INTERPOL conferences. Authorizes the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission to hire motor vehicles. Establishes the United States Marshals Service as a bureau within the Department of Justice. States that the Service shall be under the authority and direction of the Attorney General. Directs the President to appoint a U.S. Marshal for each judicial district of the United States. Specifies the powers and duties of the Service. Prescribes the schedule of fees that the Service may collect. Title IV - Amends the Comprehensive Crime Control Act of 1984 to require that funds in excess of a certain amount within the Crime Victims Fund be deposited in the general fund of the Treasury. Repeals the authority of: (1) the Attorney General to make grants to State and local governments to assist in suppressing the diversion of controlled substances from legitimate medical, scientific, and commercial use; (2) the Director of Justice Assistance to make grants to State and local governments for the construction of correctional facilities; (3) the Administrator of the Office of Juvenile Justice and Delinquency Prevention to make grants to State and local governments for juvenile justice programs; and (4) the Director of the Bureau of Justice Assistance to make grants to State and local governments for certain programs to improve the functioning of the criminal justice system. Title V - Makes technical changes to the United States Code.</summary>
</bill>
