<bill session="100" type="s" number="529" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 to improve the President's ability to prevent importations that impair national security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300048"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Defense industries"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/17/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Expansion Act of 1962 to grant the Secretary of Commerce (the Secretary) the responsibility for investigating, upon request, the effects of imports on national security. Requires the Secretary to report to the President on such investigation within six months of receiving the request that starts the investigation. Requires the Secretary to notify the Secretary of Defense concerning any such investigation. Requires the Secretary of Defense to conduct a separate defense needs assessment of the article affected by such imports. Requires the Secretary of Defense to report to the Secretary on such assessment within three months. Requires the Secretary's report to the President on such investigation to include a statement by the Secretary of Defense concurring or disagreeing with the Secretary's findings and explaining such concurrence or disagreement. Requires any portion of such report to be published if it is not: (1) classified as being clearly detrimental to the national security; and (2) proprietary information. Requires the President to: (1) decide whether or not to take action based on such report within 90 days of receiving it; and (2) explain the decision.</summary>
</bill>
