<bill session="100" type="s" number="556" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to prohibit investments in, and certain other activities with respect to, South Africa, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1988-04-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-03-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-11-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1988-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Apartheid"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Coins and coinage"/>
    <term name="Export controls"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="Money"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/19/1987--Introduced.
Prohibits any investments in South Africa by U.S. persons. Prohibits the importation into the United States of any article from South Africa, except for strategic minerals which the President certifies to the Congress are essential for military uses, are not sufficiently available from domestic supplies, and for which no substitutes are available. Prohibits the exportation to South Africa of any goods, technology, or other information subject to U.S. jurisdiction. Prohibits any such exportation by any person subject to U.S. jurisdiction. Exempts from the prohibition against exports to South Africa certain medical supplies and food. Directs the Secretary of Transportation to prohibit the takeoff and landing of any aircraft except for emergencies by a foreign air carrier owned by South Africa or South African nationals. Prohibits the importation into the United States of any South African gold coin. Prohibits any U.S. depository institution from accepting, receiving, or holding a deposit account from South Africa. Prohibits the United States from engaging in any military or intelligence activities in cooperation with South Africa. Provides for the enforcement of this Act. Repeals the Comprehensive Anti-Apartheid Act of 1986 and the amendments made by that Act to the Foreign Assistance Act of 1961 and to the Export-Import Bank Act of 1945.</summary>
</bill>
