<bill session="100" type="s" number="559" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Plastic Waste Reduction and Disposal Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to conduct a study of the measures available to reduce the adverse effect discarding or dumping of plastics on land and in the waters have on the environment, including the effects on fish and wildlife; to make recommendations for eliminating or lessening such adverse effects; and to require the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to control the pollution of the environment caused by the discarding of plastics on the land and in water.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402412"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-06-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-12-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-09-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environmental Protection. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environmental Protection. Approved for full committee consideration an original bill in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings, Markup" code="SSEV02" subcommittee="Environmental Protection" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="s" number="534"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Biodegradation"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Ocean"/>
    <term name="Packaging"/>
    <term name="Plastics"/>
    <term name="Refuse and refuse disposal"/>
    <term name="Waste disposal in the ocean"/>
    <term name="Water and Water Resources Development"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Wildlife conservation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/19/1987--Introduced.
Plastic Waste Reduction and Disposal Act of 1987 - Title I: Study of Plastic Pollution - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to study and report to the Congress on how to mitigate the adverse effects on the environment, including fish and wildlife, of discarding and dumping plastics. Title II: Regulation to Control Plastic Pollution - Requires packaging containers, within 18 months of this Act's enactment, to be made of a naturally degradable material which decomposes within a specified period. Permits States or subdivisions to adopt more stringent standards. Establishes criminal penalties for violations of this Act.</summary>
</bill>
