<bill session="100" type="s" number="570" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Stratosphere Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to reduce atmospheric pollution to protect the stratosphere from ozone depletion, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-07-28"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1988-07-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300082" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-02-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-02-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Climate"/>
    <term name="Climate change and greenhouse gases"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Earth sciences"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Injunctions"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Judicial review"/>
    <term name="Judicial review of administrative acts"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Weather and Climate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/19/1987--Introduced.
Stratosphere Protection Act of 1987 - Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to list manufactured substances known or reasonably anticipated to cause atmospheric modification, including stratospheric ozone depletion, and to assign an ozone depletion potential to each substance (the priority list). Requires the Administrator to list simultaneously and update annually other manufactured substances meeting the same criteria, assigning ozone depletion potentials for each. Includes specified chlorofluorocarbons on each list. Requires producers of substances on either list to report initially and annually to the Administrator on such production until it ceases. Limits production of substances on the priority list to 1986 levels after 1987. Prohibits the production, after 1994, of any substances in quantities sufficient for the ozone depletion potential to exceed five percent of the United States' portion of depletion for 1986. Sets forth a compliance schedule. Permits modifications, exceptions, and offsets as specified. Establishes phased-in penalties for violations, assessed on the degree of competitive advantage gained by using the ozone depleting substance. Prohibits imports of such substances or products manufactured using such substances unless the exporting nation has an equivalent or more stringent production reduction program. Requires the Administrator to notify each nation of this restriction and to certify national programs, such certification to be reviewed annually. Equates imports with production when determining a manufacturer's required reductions. Requires containers of listed substances to carry labeling stating the contents and potential damaging effects. Authorizes the Administrator to assess civil penalties or seek injunctive relief for violations and to revoke any permit for continued noncompliance. Establishes criminal penalties for knowing violations. Permits judicial review of final regulations and permits the taking of additional evidence as specified. Authorizes citizen suits against violators or the Administrator, subject to specified conditions. Requires that the Administrator be notified of such suits. Permits the Administrator to intervene as a matter of right. Permits others to intervene as a matter of right against alleged violators. Permits the awarding of costs and fees to the substantially prevailing party.</summary>
</bill>
