<bill session="100" type="s" number="573" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:56-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Process Patent Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect patent owners from importation into the United States of goods made overseas by use of a United States patented process.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405310" joined="1987-05-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-20">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-22">
      <text>Subcommittee on Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-148.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSJU06" subcommittee="Patents, Copyrights and Trademarks" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Patents"/>
    <term name="Patents, Trademarks, and Copyrights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/19/1987--Introduced.
Process Patent Act of 1987 - Amends the patent laws to make it an infringement of patent to use, sell, or import into the United States without authority a product produced by a process patented in the United States. Requires the infringer to know or be on notice that the product was made by a process patented in the United States before a process patent holder may recover damages. Authorizes the court to dispose of infringing products as specified. Makes this provision effective prospectively only. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to report annually to the Congress for five years on the effect of this provision on the importation of manufacturing ingredients in certain domestic industries. Places on the defendant the burden of proof in an infringement action to show that a given product was not produced by the patented process.</summary>
</bill>
