<bill session="100" type="s" number="586" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airport and Airway Enhancement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for certain categories of activities of the Federal Aviation Administration, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300053"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26">
      <text>Subcommittee on Aviation. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM01" subcommittee="Aviation" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Aviation safety"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Civil-military relations"/>
    <term name="Costs"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Explosives"/>
    <term name="Federal Aviation Administration"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal-local relations"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Liability for aircraft accidents"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Military aviation"/>
    <term name="Military bases"/>
    <term name="Planning"/>
    <term name="Police dogs"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Weather forecasting"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/1987--Introduced.
Airport and Airway Enhancement Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation (the Secretary) to publish a report on the safety and capacity of the national airport system, including: (1) its current operating characteristics and future needs; (2) civil aeronautics needs; (3) national defense requirements (as recommended by the Secretary of Defense); and (4) Postal Service needs. Requires the Administrator of the Federal Aviation Administration to submit to the Congress annually a National Airway Plan, including a status report regarding the completion of the National Airspace System Plan. Directs the Department of Defense to make domestic military airports and facilities available for civil use. Authorizes the Secretary to make grants from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund (the Fund) for airport projects. Specifies aggregate amounts available for such grants for FY 1988 and 1989. Authorizes appropriations from the Fund for FY 1987 through 1989 for an airway improvement program, and for certain costs associated with the National Airspace System Plan for 1987. Authorizes appropriations for the Secretary to implement certain research, engineering, and development demonstration projects for FY 1987 through 1989. Authorizes the Secretary to reimburse the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration for FY 1988 and 1989 for the cost of providing the Federal Aviation Administration with weather reporting services. Prohibits any appropriations from the Trust Fund to implement any program or activity under the Federal Aviation Act of 1958 (except for the airway improvement program, and the airport capacity and safety enhancement program set forth in this Act). Sets forth apportionment guidelines for large commercial service airports, the States and Territories, and Puerto Rico. Sets forth guidelines for: (1) approval of project grant applications for public-use airports; (2) the Federal share of such project costs; (3) construction work standards; (4) State block grants; (5) airport sponsorship requirements (including conditions for voluntary withdrawal from funding eligibility; and (6) the conveyance of Federal property interests determined by the Secretary to be necessary or public airport projects. Subjects persons who make false statements with intent to defraud the United States with regard to projects under this Act to a fine and or imprisonment. Directs the Secretary to take affirmative action to assure that no person shall on ground of race, creed, color, national origin, or sex be excluded from participating in any activity funded under this Act. Repeals specified portions of the Airport and Airway Improvement Act of 1982 and amends the Airport and Airway Development Act of 1970 to repeal provisions requiring local municipal approval for certain public airport construction or development. Directs the Secretary to insure that contracts permitting a State or subdivision to operate an airport facility shall include provisions relieving the United States of any liability for the acts or omissions of State employees operating such facility. Authorizes the Secretary to continue the Explosive Detection K-9 Team Training Program. Amends the Internal Revenue Code to extend for two years: (1) the imposition of certain airport excise taxes; (2) the transfer of certain amounts equivalent to specified taxes into the Airport and Airway Trust Fund; and (3) expenditures from the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for the airport and airway program. Amends the Aviation Safety and Noise Abatement Act of 1979 to make technical and conforming amendments.</summary>
</bill>
