<bill session="100" type="s" number="620" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-02-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-02-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Petroleum Security Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the petroleum security of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300079"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-02-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy security"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum reserves"/>
    <term name="Strategic materials"/>
    <term name="Tariff"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/26/1987--Introduced.
Petroleum Security Act of 1987 - Establishes in the Treasury the Petroleum Security Trust Fund to be used solely for the acquisition, transportation, and injection of crude oil for storage in the U.S. Strategic Petroleum Reserve (SPR). Requires the Secretary of Energy to purchase oil for such storage at an annualized minimum rate of not less than 100,000 barrels per day. Directs the Secretary to submit to the Congress quarterly projections of the Fund's sufficiency to fill the SPR to 750,000,000 barrels. Amends the Energy Policy and Conservation Act to: (1) require the President to carry out petroleum acquisition, transportation, and injection activities, subject to the availability of money in the Fund, until the Secretary certifies SPR storage of 750,000,000 barrels; and (2) increase from 75,000 to 100,000 barrels per day the minimum SPR fill rate required in order to permit sales or other dispositions from the Naval Petroleum Reserve Number 1 (Elk Hills) to customers other than the SPR. Increases the rate of duty on imported crude petroleum, motor fuel, kerosene, certain naphthas, and certain liquid forms of hydrocarbon mixtures as a user fee to provide revenue for the Fund. Directs the Secretary to forecast on a continuing basis the sufficiency of this surcharge to maintain adequate Fund levels.</summary>
</bill>
