<bill session="100" type="s" number="627" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Targeted Educational Assistance Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize grants to states to enable states and local educational agencies to meet priority educational needs in the areas of school dropouts, programs to combat illiteracy, programs for the gifted and talented, for basic skills instruction for secondary school students, and for school library resources, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-09-11"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Compensatory education"/>
    <term name="Dropouts"/>
    <term name="Education of socially handicapped children"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Gifted children"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="School libraries"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Textbooks"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1987--Introduced.
Targeted Educational Assistance Act - Amends the Education Consolidation and Improvement Act of 1981 to require that State and local educational agencies use funds from grants to States under Chapter 2 (Consolidation of Federal Programs for Elementary and Secondary Education) exclusively for any or all of the following critical areas: (1) school dropout prevention programs; (2) programs to combat illiteracy; (3) programs for the gifted and talented; (4) basic skills instruction programs for economically disadvantaged elementary and secondary school students; and (5) the acquisition and use of school library books and textbooks. Authorizes appropriations for the targeted assistance program for FY 1988 through 1993. Sets forth authorized uses of funds for programs in each of the critical areas.</summary>
</bill>
