<bill session="100" type="s" number="629" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">English Proficiency Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish literacy programs for individuals of limited English proficiency.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-10-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-04-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-12-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1987-09-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-09">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Adult education"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1987--Introduced.
English Proficiency Act - Directs the Secretary of Education to establish within the Office of Adult Education a program of grants for English literacy programs for individuals of limited English proficiency. Allows such grants to provide for the training of personnel to provide English language instruction and for support services including child care and transportation costs for program participants. Provides that such grants may be made to community-based organizations, local education agencies, tribally-controlled schools, institutions of higher education (including community colleges), public libraries, and prisons. Sets forth grant application requirements. Limits grants to not more than three years' duration. Requires that at least 50 percent of grant funds go to community-based organizations with the demonstrated capability to administer English proficiency programs. Requires grant recipients to report annually to the Secretary. Directs the Secretary, through the Office of Adult Education, directly and through grants and contracts, to carry out demonstration programs to: (1) develop innovative approaches and methods of literacy education for individuals of limited English proficiency; and (2) establish a nationwide clearinghouse on literacy education for individuals of limited English proficiency. Requires the Secretary, directly and through grants and contracts, to evaluate and annually audit programs funded under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary to accept grants, gifts, or bequests of money for the purposes of this Act. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1990. Limits to five percent the portion of funds available under this Act which may be used for demonstration programs.</summary>
</bill>
