<bill session="100" type="s" number="631" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:57-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-31">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Administration Procurement Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve the procedures for the procurement of medical and pharmaceutical supplies by the Veterans' Administration.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300150"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-03-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-03-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-13">
      <text>Committee on Veterans requested executive comment from VA, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-21">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-07-31" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 9 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="9"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Veterans' hospitals"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/3/1987--Introduced.
Veterans' Administration Procurement Improvement Act of 1987 - Directs the Administrator of Veterans Affairs, within three years after the enactment of this Act, to develop and implement a plan for the standardization of all medical and pharmaceutical supplies procured by the Veterans Administration (VA). Amends Federal law relating to procurement and supply within the VA to direct the VA to procure medical and pharmaceutical supplies only under national contracts awarded by the VA. Permits local contracts to be used for such procurement only in certain emergency situations and only for a specified maximum percentage of all such procurement. Requires the medical center director of each VA medical center, at the beginning of each fiscal year, to submit to the Administrator a list of all medical and pharmaceutical supplies procured by that medical center under a local contract during the preceding fiscal year.</summary>
</bill>
