<bill session="100" type="s" number="660" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Targeted Fiscal Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to create a fiscal safety net program for needy communities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1987-03-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-09-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-03-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Alaska"/>
    <term name="Alaskan natives"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to Indians"/>
    <term name="Intergovernmental relations"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Native Americans"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1987--Introduced.
Targeted Fiscal Assistance Act of 1987 - Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to repeal provisions that terminated the general revenue sharing program. Restores program provisions as they existed before enactment of such Act. Replaces the general revenue sharing program with the Targeted Fiscal Assistance (TFA) program. Authorizes appropriations for TFA for FY 1988 through 1990. Provides for special allocations of TFA funds for Indian tribes, Alaskan native villages, and the District of Columbia. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to allocate TFA funds to each State (for subsequent allocation to local governments) according to a specified formula based on the need factor, the general tax effort factor, and the relative fiscal gap factor, as defined in this Act, for each State. Entitles local governments to a portion of such State funds according to a specified formula based on the following factors, as defined in this Act, for each unit of local government relative to all units in such State: (1) the unit's population; (2) the unit's general tax effort factor; and (3) the unit's population. Eliminates provisions allowing State variation of local government allocations. Revises procedures for determining maximum and minimum limitations on local government entitlements.</summary>
</bill>
