<bill session="100" type="s" number="666" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Product Liability Reform Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to regulate interstate commerce by providing for a uniform product liability law, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406190"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-08-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-03-06"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Commercial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Defective products"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Drugs"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Federal preemption"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Negligence"/>
    <term name="Products liability"/>
    <term name="Products liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Warranties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s34"/>
    <amendment number="s35"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>3/6/1987--Introduced.
Product Liability Reform Act - Title I: States that this Act governs any civil action brought against a manufacturer or product seller for harm caused by a product. Supersedes any inconsistent State law regarding recovery in such actions. States that U.S. district courts shall not have jurisdiction over civil actions pursuant to this Act. Title II: Establishes procedures by which any party may serve upon any other party offers to settle claims. Holds any offeree who rejects a settlement offer and fails to substantially prevail in the action liable for the claimant's attorney's fees and costs. Allows the parties to pursue State established or recognized voluntary alternative dispute resolution procedures. Allows the court to assess reasonable attorney's fees and costs against any offeree who unreasonably refuses to proceed pursuant to such procedures. Title III: Allows any person seeking recovery for harm caused by a product to bring a civil action against the product's manufacturer or seller. Establishes uniform standards of product seller liability. Subjects a product seller to liability if the claimant establishes by a preponderance of the evidence that: (1) the product seller did not exercise reasonable care with respect to the product; or (2) the product failed to conform to an express warranty made by the product seller. Treats a product seller as a manufacturer where: (1) the manufacturer is not subject to service of process under the laws of any State in which the action might be brought; or (2) the court determines that the claimant would be unable to enforce a judgment against the manufacturer. Allows punitive damages to be awarded, if permitted by applicable law, where the claimant establishes by clear and convincing evidence that the harm suffered was the result of conduct manifesting the manufacturer's or seller's conscious, flagrant indifference to the safety of those who might be harmed by the product. Provides that punitive damages may not be awarded where: (1) a drug or medical device was approved or is generally recognized as safe by the Food and Drug Administration; or (2) an aircraft was certified by the Federal Aviation Administration under the Federal Aviation Act of 1958. Establishes uniform statutes of limitation and repose for product liability actions. Imposes penalties for the destruction or concealment of material relevant to product liability actions. Requires any damage award to be reduced by the amount of workers' compensation benefits paid. States that the liability of each defendant for noneconomic damages shall be several and not joint. Bars recovery where the claimant in a product liability action is under the influence of alcohol or any drug and more than 50 percent responsible for the harm. Title IV: Requires the Secretary of Commerce to provide the Congress with an annual report analyzing the impact of this Act on product liability insurance.</summary>
</bill>
