<bill session="100" type="s" number="669" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Hispanic American Affairs Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish an Office of Hispanic American Affairs in the Executive Office of the President, and various Federal departments and agencies, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Executive Office of the President"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Office of Personnel Management"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Spanish Americans (U.S.)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1987--Introduced.
Hispanic American Affairs Act of 1987 - Establishes in the Executive Office of the President the Office of Hispanic Affairs, which shall be headed by a Director appointed by the President, by and with the advice and consent of the Senate. Requires the Director, with respect to Hispanic Americans, to: (1) advise Federal departments and agencies on appropriate action to assure that Federal programs are providing needed assistance; (2) advise Federal departments and agencies on the development and implementation of comprehensive and coordinated policies, plans, and programs which focus on special problems and needs; (3) advise and assist Hispanic American groups and individuals in receiving assistance available under law; (4) establish and maintain an information clearinghouse to collect, analyze, and disseminate information concerning the social and economic conditions encountered by Hispanic individuals; (5) carry out functions relating to equal employment opportunity; and (6) report to the President and the Congress on an appraisal of the laws, policies, and performance of the Federal Government on the achievement or denial of equal opportunities for Hispanic Americans. Authorizes the Director to appoint one or more advisory task forces who are representative of and involved in the affairs of the Hispanic American community to assist the Director in functions under this Act. Transfers to the Director from the Office of Personnel Management the Hispanic Employment Program. Requires the Director to report annually to the President and the Congress concerning the activities of the Office of Hispanic Affairs. Specifies the Federal departments and agencies in which the President is directed to establish and maintain an Office of Hispanic Affairs. Declares that each office shall be headed by a Special Assistant for Hispanic Affairs to assist the Director in carrying out within each department or agency the functions of the Hispanic Employment Program. Directs the Secretary of Commerce to insure that existing information clearinghouse functions within the Department of Commerce encompass the collection and dissemination of information in easily accessible form concerning the social, economic, employment, health, and housing needs and conditions of Hispanic Americans. Prohibits the use of funds under this Act for partisan political activities. Authorizes the Director to enter into contracts to the extent provided in appropriation Acts. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989.</summary>
</bill>
