<bill session="100" type="s" number="679" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:59-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Aviation Safety and Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the safety of individuals traveling by aircraft, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403171"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Air traffic"/>
    <term name="Air traffic controllers"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Airports"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to transportation"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Noise"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1987--Introduced.
Aviation Safety and Improvement Act of 1987 - Mandates that the Federal Aviation Administration hire a minimum of 500 air traffic controllers (in addition to a specified total air traffic controller work force level) by September 30, 1988. Precludes such additional controllers from including air traffic assistants. Requires the Secretary of Transportation to promulgate a final rule within nine months after the date of enactment of this Act providing that each individual inquiring about making a reservation for scheduled airline service shall, at the time of such inquiry, receive specified verbal information about delays and cancellations. Requires the Secretary, in promulgating such rule to: (1) ensure that each air carrier makes such information available in written form; and (2) develop procedures for use by airlines in notifying passengers who have purchased tickets for scheduled airline service of the cancellation of such service. Amends the Airport and Airway Improvement Act of 1982 to specify the aggregate amounts available to the Secretary for FY 1988 through 1992 for grants regarding airport planning and development, airport noise compatibility, and capacity improvements. Extends from 1987 to FY 1992 the Secretary's obligational authority to make grants under the airport improvement program. Authorizes appropriations out of the Airport and Airway Trust Fund for FY 1988 through FY 1992 for: (1) air navigation facilities improvement under the Federal Aviation Act; (2) facilities, engineering and development, and research; (3) other expenses; and (4) weather services. Extends from 1987 to 1992 the apportionment formula to be used for primary airports. Directs the Secretary to distribute apportioned funds within 30 days after the beginning of each fiscal year to primary airport sponsors which have certified compliance with all sponsor obligations and requirements. Amends the Aviation Safety and Noise Abatement Act of 1979 to authorize the Secretary to incur obligations to make grants from specified funds for activities regarding airport noise compatibility.</summary>
</bill>
