<bill session="100" type="s" number="690" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a Commission on United States Trade in the 1990's.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Exports"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Future"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="International trade"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/6/1987--Introduced.
Establishes the Commission on United States Trade in the 1990's. Specifies that such Commission shall be composed of 18 members, six of whom shall be appointed by the President, six by the President pro tempore of the Senate, and six by the Speaker of the House of Representatives. Sets forth administrative provisions. Requires the Commission to study and make recommendations concerning U.S. international trade and export policies and practices. Requires the Commission, in conducting its study, to review and make recommendations concerning specified items, including: (1) likely impediments to exporting by U.S. industries in the 1990's; (2) the likely propensity of the United States to import goods and services in the 1990's; (3) the competitiveness of firms manufacturing products in the United States in the 1990's; (4) the likely relationships between trade and international monetary policy in the 1990's; (5) the likely state of vitality in the U.S. economy during the 1990's; (6) the role for international trade activities by State and local governments in the 1990's; and (7) the organizational structures under which other industrial nations carry out international trade activities. Requires the Commission to submit its report to the President and to the Congress by January 1, 1988. Terminates the Commission on such date. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
