<bill session="100" type="s" number="7" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:43-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">California Desert Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide for the protection of the public lands in the California desert.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1988-06-22"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department, Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-07">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Defense Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-21">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Defense Department. Unfavorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-23">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Interior Department. Unfavorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-09">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Department of Agriculture. Unfavorable.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="California"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Deserts"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="Land transfers"/>
    <term name="Monuments and memorials"/>
    <term name="National monuments"/>
    <term name="National parks"/>
    <term name="Parks"/>
    <term name="Parks and Natural Areas"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="State parks"/>
    <term name="Wilderness areas"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
California Desert Protection Act of 1987 - Title I: Wilderness Additions - Designates as additions to the National Wilderness Preservation System 81 wilderness areas within the California Desert Conservation Area (CDCA), the Yuma District, and the Bakersfield District of the Bureau of Land Management. States that non-designated areas within the CDCA have been adequately studied for inclusion in the System and are therefore released from otherwise applicable restrictions. Requires the Secretary of Agriculture to study the suitability of lands in the White Mountains Wilderness Study Area for inclusion in the System. Title II: Death Valley National Park - Establishes the Death Valley National Park which subsumes the Death Valley National Monument. Withdraws the additional lands from further exploitation under the mining laws. Requires the Secretary of the Interior (the Secretary) to determine, the validity of any unpatented mining claims within such additional lands and whether the United States should acquire any mineral rights in such lands. Title III: Joshua Tree National Park - Establishes the Joshua Tree National Park which subsumes the Joshua Tree National Monument. Withdraws the additional lands from further exploitation under the mining laws. Requires the Secretary to determine, the validity of any unpatented mining claims within such additional lands and whether the United States should acquire any mineral rights in such lands. Title IV: Mojave National Park - Establishes the Mojave National Park which subsumes the East Mojave National Scenic Area. Withdraws Federal lands within the park from further exploitation under the mining laws. Requires the Secretary to determine, the validity of any unpatented mining claims within the Park and whether the United States should acquire any mineral rights in such lands. Authorizes the Secretary to regulate mining in such Park. Allows grazing only to the extent allowed in current permits. Continues the validity of existing rights-of-way for specified activities. Directs the Secretary to prepare and report to the appropriate congressional committees, within three years, on a management plan for the Park. Authorizes the Secretary to construct a visitors' center and acquire lands. Authorizes appropriations. Title V: National Park Wilderness - Designates as wilderness the Death Valley National Park Wilderness, the Joshua Tree National Park Wilderness Additions, and the Mojave National Park Wilderness. Title VI: Miscellaneous Provisions - Directs the Secretary to transfer Red Rock Canyon State Park Additions in the CDCA to California. Establishes the Desert Lily Sanctuary within the CDCA. Establishes the Indian Canyons National Historic Site.</summary>
</bill>
