<bill session="100" type="s" number="732" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Rural Health Services Transition Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish a program of grants to assist small rural hospitals in modifying their service mixes to meet new community needs and in providing more appropriate and cost-effective health care services to medicare beneficiaries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-03-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-03-12"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to hospitals"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural public health"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/1987--Introduced.
Rural Health Services Transition Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Health and Human Services to establish a grant program, administered through the Administrator of the Health Care Financing Administration, to assist eligible small rural hospitals in modifying their services to adjust to certain demographic changes and to changing health care needs and practices in their communities. Sets forth criteria to govern grant applications and the use of grant funds. Lists the factors the Secretary must consider in determining which hospitals will receive grants. Limits grants to a maximum of $50,000 per year and to a term of no more than two years. Restricts certain capital-related expenditures of grant moneys. Requires the Secretary to report to the Congress at least every six months concerning the grant program and to submit a final report at a specified time. Authorizes appropriations from the Federal Hospital Insurance Trust Fund for FY 1988 through 1989.</summary>
</bill>
