<bill session="100" type="s" number="735" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-12">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-12"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-12"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="406084"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-12" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-12">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department, Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-14">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Animals and Animal Protection"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Revenue sharing"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Wildlife refuges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/12/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Land and Water Conservation Fund Act of 1965 to add a title III: Special Account, which sets forth the distribution of revenue from oil and gas resources in units of the National Wildlife Refuge System. Requires that 50 percent of such revenues go to the State in which the refuge is located, 25 percent to a special account in the Fund, and 25 percent to the U.S. Treasury. Requires Federal agencies eligible to receive Fund revenues to provide both Appropriations Committees with a priority list of land acquisition projects which the Committees shall finance out of the special account. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to distribute such monies according to a formula, if the Congress fails to act.</summary>
</bill>
