<bill session="100" type="s" number="749" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make changes in the Trade Adjustment Assistance Program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407786"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Occupational retraining"/>
    <term name="Trade adjustment assistance"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Trade Act of 1974 relating to eligibility and certification requirements for trade adjustment assistance to make eligible for such assistance those firms which provide essential parts or essential services of articles for which imports of like or directly competitive articles have contributed importantly to separation from work or to a serious decline in sales or production. Extends from a 26-week period to a 52-week period the time in which additional trade readjustment allowances may be paid for retraining under such Act. Revises provisions concerning such trade readjustment training to allow workers a two-week break in training and still maintain training eligibility, under certain circumstances. Directs the Secretary of Labor, in determining the appropriate period of training under trade adjustment assistance, to consider whether the training provided under each program is of suitable duration to achieve the desired skill level within a reasonable period of time.</summary>
</bill>
