<bill session="100" type="s" number="751" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Preservation Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 to provide for the deregulation of natural gas subject to a new, renegotiated, or expiring contract, and to repeal the provisions allowing reimposition of price controls and a report to Congress; to amend the Natural Gas Act to require pipeline rates for the sale of imported natural gas to be determined on the same basis as rates for domestic production; and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300009"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1987-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Antitrust actions"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Competition"/>
    <term name="Cooperative societies"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Energy prices"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Gas companies"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum prices"/>
    <term name="Price regulation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1987--Introduced.
Energy Preservation Act - Amends the Natural Gas Policy Act of 1978 to provide that wellhead price controls shall not apply to natural gas subject to any contract for the first sale of natural gas that: (1) was executed after the date of enactment of this Act; (2) was renegotiated after the date of enactment of this Act and expressly provided for the inapplicability of wellhead price controls; (3) will terminate under its own terms after the date of enactment of this Act; or (4) expired under its own terms. Repeals certain provisions pertaining to standby price control authority. Directs the Federal Energy Regulatory Commission to allocate the price charged for the resale of imported natural gas at the border to the demand charge component on the same basis that it would allocate costs to the demand charge for a natural gas company subject to Commission jurisdiction. Directs the Secretary of Energy to initiate a review and update by the Governing Board of the International Energy Agency of the Minimum Safeguard Price Decision adopted January 30, 1976, and to report to the Congress regarding such actions. Sets forth defenses to any State or Federal antitrust law regarding actions taken to develop cooperative associations of independent producers, or actions taken by such associations to market crude oil or natural gas.</summary>
</bill>
