<bill session="100" type="s" number="753" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:00-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-17">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-17"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Independent Counsel Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Ethics in Government Act of 1978 to provide a permanent authorization to the independent counsel and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402727"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-03-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-17" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1293"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Attorneys general"/>
    <term name="Conflict of interests"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Government attorneys"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Special prosecutors"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/17/1987--Introduced.
Independent Counsel Amendments Act of 1987 - Makes the statute regarding independent counsels permanent law. Authorizes the Attorney General to investigate a person subject to such statute when the Attorney General receives information that such person may have violated a Federal criminal law other than a Class B or C misdemeanor or an infraction. (Current law requires an investigation if such person has violated a criminal law other than the type described.) Authorizes the Attorney General to conduct a preliminary investigation on an additional person or matter referred from the independent counsel if such person or matter is not covered in the prosecutorial jurisdiction of the independent counsel. Authorizes the reimbursement of reasonable attorney's fees (current law simply says "attorney's fees") to certain subjects of an investigation. Requires determinations or applications for appointment of an independent counsel to be made by the Deputy Attorney General if the information or allegations involve the Attorney General or a person who has a personal or financial relationship with the Attorney General.</summary>
</bill>
