<bill session="100" type="s" number="766" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of State Authorization Act for Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1988 and 1989 for the Department of State, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered favorably reported an original bill (S. 1394) in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1394"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Arrest"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Cabinet officers"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Civil service pensions"/>
    <term name="Civil service retirement"/>
    <term name="Claims"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Diplomats"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Divorce"/>
    <term name="Divorcees"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Federal office buildings"/>
    <term name="Federal officials"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government employees' health insurance"/>
    <term name="Government liability"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health insurance"/>
    <term name="Historic sites"/>
    <term name="India"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Investment of public funds"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Liability insurance"/>
    <term name="Museums"/>
    <term name="Property insurance"/>
    <term name="Salaries"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Searches and seizures"/>
    <term name="Survivors' benefits"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
Department of State Authorization Act for fiscal years 1988 and 1989 - (Title I omitted) - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 for the Department of State for: (1) administration of foreign affairs; (2) international organizations and conferences; (3) international commissions; and (4) other activities. Title II: Miscellaneous Provisions - Authorizes the use of funds available to an agency for administrative expenses for the purchase of liability insurance for diplomatic officials abroad. Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act to revise the authority of special agents of the Department of State and the Foreign Service to allow such an agent to make felony arrests without warrant if such an agent has reasonable grounds to believe that a suspect has committed or is committing a felony violation. (Present law requires that there must be reasonable cause and that the suspect must be in or fleeing from the immediate area of such a violation.) Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to allow the carry-over into the following fiscal year of senior foreign service (SFS) performance pay. Provides that Fascell Fellows may be: (1) deemed to be Federal employees for purposes of the Foreign Service Act of 1980 and all other laws governing Federal employment; or (2) compensated through a contractual agreement under specified provisions of the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956. Requires the Secretary of State to administer and regulate specified areas of the Department of State Building in Washington, D.C., so as to preserve the museum character of such areas. Outlines certain authorities of the Secretary to acquire, sell, and lend articles of furniture, fixtures, and decorative objects of the areas which the Secretary declares to be of historic or artistic interest. Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act to authorize the Secretary of State to obtain insurance on the contents of the Diplomatic Rooms of the Department of State. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to eliminate and revise certain reporting requirements of the Department of State concerning equal employment opportunity programs and professional development programs. Amends the International Claims Settlement Act of 1949 to authorize the Secretary of the Treasury to invest amounts held in claims settlement funds in public debt securities. Requires that interest earned on such investments be used to pay claims. Requires the Secretary of State to deduct from funds received from foreign governments and other sources as a result of an international arbitration or other international dispute settlement up to five percent of moneys due a private U.S. claimant as reimbursement for expenses incurred. Authorizes the Secretary of State to accept reimbursement for certain extraordinary expenses incurred in pursuing a claim on behalf of corporations, firms, and individuals against a foreign government or other foreign entity. Amends the United States-India Fund for Cultural, Educational, and Scientific Cooperation Act to permit the use of funds appropriated for the initial capitalization of the U.S.-India Fund as well as interest earnings generated therefrom for the purposes of such Fund. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to authorize limited appointments in the Foreign Service to be extended for continued service as: (1) consular agents; (2) family members; (3) career candidates when appropriate in order to remedy a matter cognizable under the Foreign Service grievance system; or (4) career employees of another Federal agency serving in a Foreign Service position on detail from that agency. Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act to establish a pay authority for the Director of the International Communications Policy Bureau and for the Director of the Office of Foreign Missions at the Executive IV level. Amends the Foreign Service Act of 1980 to provide survivor annuities to former spouses of Foreign Service employees who were divorced from Foreign Service employees prior to February 15, 1981. Allows health insurance benefits to former spouses of Foreign Service employees who were divorced prior to May 7, 1985. Reduces the salary levels of Ambassadors at large from Executive level II to Executive level IV. Provides that such reduction shall not apply to incumbents in such positions. Amends the State Department Basic Authorities Act of 1956 to authorize the Department of State to construct, or acquire by purchase or gift, a permanent residence within the Washington, D.C. area for future Secretaries of State. Prohibits the Department from using any appropriated funds to finance such construction or acquisition. Authorizes the Department to insure such residence and its related real or personal property. Expresses the findings of the Congress that, with the adoption of United Nations General Assembly Resolution 41/213, the United Nations has taken a step toward fundamental reform of its decisionmaking procedures on program budget matters. Amends the Foreign Relations Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1986 and 1987 to urge the President to seek the adoption and implementation by the United Nations specialized agencies of decisionmaking procedures on budgetary matters which assure that sufficient attention is paid to the views of the United States and other member states who are major financial contributors to the United Nations' assessed budgets. Provides that no payment may be made for an assessed contribution to a specialized agency of the United Nations in excess of 20 percent of the total budget of the agency unless the President determines that such agency has adopted or has made substantial progress toward adopting procedures which assure that attention is paid to the views of major financial contributors. Provides that no payment may be made for assessed contributions to the United Nations in excess of 20 percent of its total annual budget unless the President determines that the consensus based on decisionmaking procedure established by General Assembly Resolution 41/213 is being implemented and its results respected by the General Assembly. Authorizes appropriations for such additional sums as may be necessary to pay the full United States assessed contributions for calendar years 1987 and 1988 to the United Nations, its specialized agencies, and other international organizations.</summary>
</bill>
