<bill session="100" type="s" number="767" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">United States Information Agency Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the United States Information Agency for fiscal years 1988 and 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Star Print ordered s.767.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-06">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-12">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-14">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration and Mark Up Session held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Ordered favorably reported an original bill (S. 1394) in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1394"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Cultural relations"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Educational exchanges"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="International broadcasting"/>
    <term name="International propaganda"/>
    <term name="Leases"/>
    <term name="Motion pictures"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Radio broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Scientific exchanges"/>
    <term name="Television"/>
    <term name="Television programs"/>
    <term name="United States Information Agency"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
United States Information Agency Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 for the United States Information Agency (Agency). Amends the United States Information and Educational Exchange Act of 1948 to authorize the Secretary of State to purchase, maintain, and operate facilities for radio transmission of information about U.S. policies, including the leasing of associated real property (either within or outside the United States) for periods not to exceed 40 years (currently not to exceed 25 years). Authorizes the Secretary, or any Government agency, in carrying out the provisions of the Act to lease, maintain, and operate aircraft. Authorizes payments received by or for the use of the Agency in connection with English-teaching, motion picture, and television programs conducted by the Agency to be credited to the Agency's applicable appropriation. Amends the Mutual Educational and Cultural Exchange Act of 1961 to authorize the Director of the United States Information Agency to facilitate the placement in the United States and other countries of educational and cultural television programs and motion pictures produced by the Agency and foreign governmental institutions, individuals, or public or private organizations. Authorizes the Director to enter into an agreement with Pakistan for the establishment of a fund for which the United States will provide a one time grant for English language training or other cultural, educational, and scientific programs of mutual interest. Requires U.S. representatives on any board created to administer such fund to be designated by the Director predominantly from U.S. agencies. Authorizes the Director to make available to the fund up to $598,176 in foreign currencies owned by the United States in Pakistan or owed to the United States by Pakistan.</summary>
</bill>
