<bill session="100" type="s" number="774" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Long-Term Care Savings Account Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code to provide for the deduction of contributions to long-term care savings accounts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300073"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-05-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Bank deposits"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Savings accounts"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax exclusion"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
Long-Term Care Savings Account Act of 1987 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow an income tax deduction for contributions made to a savings account established to pay the long-term care expenses of an individual. Defines "long-term care expenses" as expenses incurred for any item or service medically necessary or prudent for the care of the beneficiary of such an account. Limits such deduction to $2,000 (adjusted for inflation) annually. Provides that only the beneficiary, the spouse of the beneficiary, and the parents of the beneficiary may contribute to such an account. Provides that no account may have more than one beneficiary and that no individual may be the beneficiary of more than one account. Permits a tax exclusion for income accumulated in such savings accounts as long as such amounts are used exclusively for long-term care expenses. Sets forth penalties for the use of account funds for other than long-term care purposes. Extends the deduction for contributions to a long-term care savings account to taxpayers who do not otherwise itemize deductions.</summary>
</bill>
