<bill session="100" type="s" number="796" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-19">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Ambient Air Quality Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to establish revised and additional ambient air quality standards and to control interstate air pollution.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-03-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-19" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Aerosol propellants"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Ozone"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Sulphur oxides"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/19/1987--Introduced.
National Ambient Air Quality Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends the Clean Air Act to direct the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to propose national primary ambient air quality standards for sulfur dioxide and for nitrogen dioxide concentrations over a period of not more than one hour unless such standard is determined not necessary to protect public health. Establishes standards for 1990 and after should the Administrator fail to act. Requires the Administrator to propose a revised national primary ambient air quality standard for ozone concentrations over a one-hour period, unless found unnecessary to protect human health. Establishes a standard for July 1, 1991, and after should the Administrator fail to act. Directs the Administrator to propose a national primary ambient air quality standard for acid aerosols and their precursors, unless it is determined that such a standard is unnecessary to protect human health. Requires that the standard be promulgated or the determination made by 1992. Requires the Administrator to propose a national secondary ambient air quality standard for ozone concentrations unless it is determined that such standard is unnecessary to protect natural resources or other elements of the public welfare. Requires that the standard be promulgated or the determination made by 1992. Requires that such standard be different from the primary one absent a determination that the primary standard will protect the public welfare. Directs the Administrator to propose a national secondary ambient air quality standard for fine particulates, unless it is determined that such standard is unnecessary to protect natural resources or other elements of the public welfare. Requires that the standard be promulgated or the determination made by 1992. Requires States to conduct separate public hearings on the implementation of national secondary ambient air quality standards. Requires the implementation of secondary standards for ozone or fine particles to be attained within three years of an approved State plan. Permits extensions as specified. Requires State implementation plans for national primary ambient air quality standards to prohibit emissions from stationary sources which contribute to atmospheric concentrations or loadings of pollutants or transformation products which could reasonably be expected to have an adverse effect on the public health, welfare, or environment of another State or country. Requires the Administrator to promulgate implementing regulations by 1989.</summary>
</bill>
