<bill session="100" type="s" number="804" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Insurance Competition Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to clarify the antitrust exemption of the business of insurance, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409917"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Antitrust, Monopolies and Business.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU01" subcommittee="Antitrust, Monopolies and Business Rights" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Commerce"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Insurance companies"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Workers' compensation"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/20/1987--Introduced.
Insurance Competition Act of 1987 - Amends the McCarran-Ferguson Act to revise the applicability of the Federal antitrust laws to the insurance industry. Specifies limited activities that may be subject to an exempt agreement, understanding, or concert of action between or among insurers, members of an advisory organization, or other persons. Permits insurers in joint underwriting, pools, or residual market mechanisms to cooperate with each other in the following activities if the residual market mechanism is required by law or approved by a government agency, or if the joint underwriting pools do not unreasonably restrain trade: (1) making rates, rating systems, policy forms, underwriting rules, surveys, inspections, and investigations; (2) furnishing loss statistics; and (3) carrying on research on causes or the prevention of losses. Permits any State to: (1) establish or approve a residual market mechanism; and (2) require a workers' compensation and employers' liability insurer to adhere to the uniform classification system and uniform rating plan applicable to such types of insurance in such State, provided that no such insurer shall agree with any other insurer or with an advisory organization to use any rate.</summary>
</bill>
