<bill session="100" type="s" number="81" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:45-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Alzheimer's Disease and Related Dementias Home and Community Based Services Block Grant Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Older Americans Act of 1965 to establish the Alzheimer's Disease and related dementias home and community based services block grant.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-04-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-03-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-20">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Community health services"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Alzheimer's Disease and Related Dementias Home and Community Based Services Block Grant Act of 1987 - Amends the Older Americans Act of 1965 to establish a program providing States with block grants, out of appropriations authorized for FY 1988 through 1992, which are to be used by States to provide home and community based services to individuals with Alzheimer's disease and related dementias. Requires States to give priority to individuals who have attained age 60 and to those in greatest economic need. Sets the Federal share of the costs of State projects supported by such grants at no less than 60 percent of necessary costs and no more than 80 percent of such costs. Limits the percentage of Federal funds which may be used to cover State administrative expenses. Requires each State to submit a State plan to the Secretary of Health and Human Services which: (1) describes the State's intended use of its grant; (2) provides assurances that grant amounts will supplement and not supplant existing Federal and State financing for home and community based services; (3) specifies the manner in which similar services existing in the State will be coordinated with the services funded by such grant; and (4) describes the manner in which grant-funded services will be evaluated. Requires the State plan to be made available for public comment. Directs States to report annually to the Secretary regarding the extent to which the home and community based services provided pursuant to this Act prevented or delayed the institutionalization of individuals with Alzheimer's disease and related dementias. Requires the Commissioner on Aging to: (1) develop guidelines to be used by States in carrying out activities under this Act; and (2) submit an annual report to the Secretary and the Congress describing such activities.</summary>
</bill>
