<bill session="100" type="s" number="810" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize housing assistance for homeless individuals and families.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Banking. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-03">
      <text>Committee on Banking. Reported to Senate by Senator Proxmire with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="82">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 82.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 558 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Fire prevention"/>
    <term name="Fires and Fire Fighters"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing subsidies"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Smoke detectors"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/1987--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from Committee on Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs, amended (without written report)) Requires a State or urban area to submit a comprehensive homeless assistance plan for approval to the Interagency Council on the Homeless (Council) in order to receive emergency shelter grants in excess of the minimum allocation provided for under Public Law 99-500 or Public Law 99-591. Requires a comprehensive homeless assistance plan to contain: (1) an assessment of the size and characteristics of the homeless population; (2) a description of all available services for the homeless; (3) a strategy to match the needs of the homeless with such services and to meet the specific needs of such groups as the elderly, the mentally ill, veterans, and families with children; (4) an explanation of how Federal assistance will enhance such services; and (5) other additional information. Requires the Council to: (1) review and approve a submitted plan within 30 days of receipt unless the plan fails to contain the necessary requirements; and (2) inform the State, county, or city within 15 days of a disapproval the reasons for such decision and the steps necessary to make the plan acceptable. Deems a plan approved if the Council fails to follow such requirements. Requires recipients to annually monitor their plan performance and report to the Council. Makes recipients failing to follow such requirements ineligible for further assistance under this Act. Requires the Council, beginning in FY 1989, to carry out program performance evaluations and report such findings to the Congress. Authorizes additional FY 1987 and 1988 appropriations for the: (1) transitional housing demonstration program; and (2) emergency shelter grants program. Exempts such additional emergency shelter assistance from a specified planning requirement. Increases the minimum allocation amounts for the emergency shelter grants prograam. Provides for the reallocation of funds from a jurisdiction failing to have its plan approved within a specified time to a jurisdiction identified by the Council as demonstrating extraordinary need. Authorizes the Secretary of Housing and Urban Development to waive a specified limitation on the use of assistance for emergency shelter grant essential services if the local governmental recipient demonstrates that other resources are being used to provide different services. Increases available budget authority for five-year contract section 8 existing housing certificates for homeless families with children. Permits such certificates to be attached to a housing unit owned by a nonprofit organization which has agreed to provide shelter and services to the homeless. Provides for the reallocation of such funds from a jurisdiction failing to have its plan approved within a specified time to a jurisdiction identified by the Council as demonstrating extraordinary need. Increases available budget authority for ten-year (renewable) contract section 8 single room occupancy dwellings for the homeless. Gives priority to homeless persons and families. Directs the Secretary to allocate such assistance through a national competition based on need and program ability. Requires proposals to contain: (1) target population size and characteristics; (2) other potential assistance sources; (3) an inventory of housing stock; and (4) a description of the interest expressed by builders and developers in program participation. Prohibits a recipient from receiving more than ten percent of the total assistance available under such program. Requires the installation of sprinkler systems, smoke detectors, and other fire and safety requirements. Limits rehabilitation costs to $14,000 per unit, unless local conditions such as construction or acquisition costs or fire or building codes require increases.</summary>
</bill>
