<bill session="100" type="s" number="811" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-02">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Services, Mental Health Services, Job Training, and Education for the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Health Services and Mental Health Services for the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Health Services, Mental Health Services, Job Training, and Education for the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Health Services and Mental Health Services for the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide health services, mental health services, and job training for homeless individuals and education for homeless children.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-02" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-03">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="80">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 80.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 558 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to adult education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to alcoholism programs"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Illiteracy"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Local and Municipal Government"/>
    <term name="Local finance"/>
    <term name="Manpower training programs"/>
    <term name="Mental health"/>
    <term name="Mental health services"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Public health"/>
    <term name="Residence requirements"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of alcoholics"/>
    <term name="Treatment and rehabilitation of narcotic addicts"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s44"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>4/3/1987--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Labor and Human Resources with amendment (without written report)) Health Services, Mental Health Services, Job Training, and Education for the Homeless Act - Title I: Health Services and Mental Health Services for the Homeless - Health Services and Mental Health Services for the Homeless Act - Part A: Health Services - Amends title III (General Powers and Duties of Public Health Service) of the Public Health Service Act to require the Secretary of the Health and Human Services (Secretary) to make grants to public and nonprofit private entities for: (1) health services for homeless individuals; and (2) mental health services for homeless individuals who do not have a chronic mental illness. Specifies services such entities are required to provide and other requirements in order to be eligible for grants. Requires the Secretary to give preference to entities which have experience in providing comprehensive primary health care services to homeless individuals and medically underserved populations. Provides that such required services shall be provided to any homeless individual without regard to the individual's ability to pay. Specifies requirements for any fees charged by grant recipients. Places other terms and conditions on the use of funds provided under such grants. Requires the Secretary to prepare and submit to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources of the Senate and the Committee on Energy and Commerce of the House of Representatives an annual report evaluating the services provided under such grants. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 and 1988. Part B: Mental Health Services - Amends title XIX (Block Grants) of the Public Health Service Act to authorize appropriations for FY 1987 and 1988 for emergency assistance block grants for homeless mentally ill individuals. Prohibits the Secretary from using more than two percent of the amount appropriated for administration. Provides a formula for allotment of funds to States, the District of Columbia, and certain U.S. territories and possessions. Specifies how such allotments shall be used for emergency projects for homeless individuals who have chronic mental illnesses. Includes in such uses: (1) services to individuals who are homeless or who have chronic mental illness and are at risk of becoming homeless; and (2) certain training of individuals to enable them to provide services to homeless individuals. Prohibits certain uses of such allotments, including inpatient services, cash payments to recipients, and, subject to waiver by the Secretary, capital expenditures. Prohibits more than four percent of the amount paid to a State from being used to administer the funds. Requires States to apply in order to receive allocations. Requires the State chief executive officer and the chief executive officer of any metropolitan city or urban county included in the application, as a part of the application, to certify to certain terms and conditions. Requires the State chief executive officer to submit a description, open to public comment while being developed and after transmittal, of the programs, activities, and services provided through such allotments. Makes applicable to allotments under this Act provisions of existing law relating to adjustments of allotments under certain circumstances, reports and audits, withholding of funds for cause, discrimination, and criminal penalties for false statements. Part C: Alcohol and Drug Abuse Services for Homeless Individuals - Amends title XIX (Block Grants) of the Public Health Service Act to add a new subpart to Part B (Alcohol and Drug Abuse and Mental Health Services Block Grants) authorizing appropriations for FY 1987. Provides that funds appropriated under such authorization shall be allotted to the States under a formula in a specified provision of existing Federal law. Requires States receiving such allotments to use them to provide prevention, treatment, and rehabilitation services for homeless individuals who are alcoholics, alcohol abusers, or drug abusers. Title II: Assuring the Education of Homeless Children and Providing Literacy and Basic Skills Remediation for Adult Homeless Individuals - Amends the General Education Provisions Act to require the Secretary of Education to withhold a specified amount from a State which fails to comply with specified provisions of this Act in any fiscal year after September 30, 1988. Requires each State educational agency to assure that no child of a homeless person is denied for that reason access to a free, appropriate public education that would be provided to the children of a resident of the State. Requires each State to adopt a plan to provide for the education of each homeless child within the State. Sets forth requirements regarding selection of the school in which such child will be enrolled, transportation to the school selected, maintenance of the child's records, and participation in educational programs and services. Provides an exclusive administrative remedy for each local educational agency or any State which is aggrieved by the withholding of State funds under a specified provision of this Act. Requires the Secretary of Education to prepare and submit to the Congress no later than January 1, 1989, a report on the effectiveness of the State plans required by specified portions of this Act. Requires the Secretary to make grants to State and local educational agencies for exemplary programs for homeless students. Sets eligibility and application requirements. Requires the Secretary to disseminate information on such exemplary programs to other State and local educational agencies. Authorizes appropriations for such grants for FY 1987 and 1988. Directs the Secretary of Education to make grants to State educational agencies for plans and programs regarding literacy training and basic skills remediation for adult homeless individuals within the State. Sets content, coordination with other resources, and application requirements. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 and 1988. Directs the Secretary of Education to distribute funds to States on the basis of the assessments of the homeless population in the States made in the comprehensive plans submitted to the Interagency Council on the Homeless, subject to a minimum limit on such distributions. Title III: Job Training for the Homeless Demonstration Project - Requires the Secretary of Labor to make grants for the Federal share of job training demonstration projects for homeless individuals. Authorizes the Secretary of Labor to enter into contracts to carry out this title. Requires a State to describe in a comprehensive plan how the State will coordinate projects conducted within a State under this title with other services for homeless individuals assisted under this Act. Specifies elements required to be included in grant applications. Sets forth the purposes for which such demonstration grants may be used. Sets the Federal share of the cost of demonstration projects at 50 percent for each fiscal year. Allows the non-Federal share to be in cash or in kind. Limits the amount of grants to any State in each fiscal year to 15 percent of the total amount appropriated for this title. Requires the Secretary of Labor to evaluate each demonstration at the end of the first fiscal year for which funds are appropriated under this title and to submit a report to the Interagency Council on the Homeless (Interagency Council). Requires the Secretary of Labor to submit a final report to the President, the Congress, and the Interagency Council. Requires the Interagency Council to: (1) prepare and publish a report evaluating each project receiving assistance under this title; (2) make a determination of the relative effectiveness of such projects; and (3) make recommendations, including recommendations for legislation, to the Congress on job training programs for homeless individuals to be established on a national basis. Authorizes appropriations for this title for FY 1988. Terminates the provisions of this title on October 1, 1990.</summary>
</bill>
