<bill session="100" type="s" number="813" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-01">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Urgent Relief for the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Emergency Food and Shelter Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Excess Property Identification Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Interagency Council on the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Urgent Relief for the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Emergency Food and Shelter Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Excess Property Identification Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate" partial="1">Interagency Council on the Homeless Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide urgently needed assistance to protect and improve the lives and safety of the homeless.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404598" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-03-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300065" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-03-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Governmental Affairs.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-30">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-77.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-01" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-03">
      <text>Committee on Governmental Affairs. Reported to Senate by Senator Glenn with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-03" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="81">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 81.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.R. 558 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSGA" name="Senate Governmental Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="558"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Department of Health and Human Services"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Food relief"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Grants-in-aid"/>
    <term name="Homeless"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Public Welfare and Charities"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Surplus government property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/1987--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Governmental Affairs with amendment (without written report)) Urgent Relief for the Homeless Act - Title I; Interagency Council on the Homeless Act - Interagency Council on the Homeless Act - Establishes the Interagency Council on the Homeless as the successor to the Department of Health and Human Services' Federal Task Force on the homeless. Transfers all Task Force functions to the Council and terminates the Task Force. Terminates the Council three years after enactment of this Act. Sets forth Council functions, including: (1) Federal homeless program review; (2) governmental and private programs evaluation; (3) information distribution; and (4) provision of professional and technical assistance. Requires each Federal agency that is a member of the Council to report annually (the first report due within 90 days of enactment of this Act) to the Congress and the Council regarding its programs for the homeless, any impediments including statutory or regulatory restrictions affecting such programs, and efforts made to increase food, shelter, and support opportunities for the homeless. Requires the Council to report annually to the President and to the Congress regarding: (1) the Nature and extent of the homeless problem; (2) Council activities in cooperation with governmental and private entities; (3) Federal programs for the homeless, and an assessment of necessary levels of Federal assistance; and (4) appropriate recommendations. Authorizes FY 1987 and 1988 appropriations. Title II: Clarification of Use of Excess Property Under the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 - Excess Property Identification Act of 1987 - Requires: (1) each Federal agency to identify excess property under its control that would be suitable for use as a shelter or to provide services to the homeless; and (2) the Administrator of General Services to report to the Council on the availability of such property. Makes any governmental or nonprofit private entity which receives or is eligible for Federal homeless assistance eligible for donations of Federal surplus property. Amends the Federal Property and Administrative Services Act of 1949 to conform with such amendment. Title III: Shelter Program - Part A: General Provisions - Emergency Food and Shelter Act of 1987 - Establishes the Emergency Food and Shelter Program National Board, to be constituted by the Director of the Federal Emergency Management Agency (FEMA) in accordance with the provisions of this Act. Directs FEMA to act as Federal liaison and provide support services to the Board. States that each Board-designated locality shall constitute a local board for purposes of determining fund distributions. Sets forth local board responsibilities, including: (1) coordination with other governmental assistance programs; (2) selection of grant recipients; and (3) program monitoring. Sets forth Board recordkeeping and audit provisions; including authority for access by the Comptroller General of the United States. Requires the Board to report annually to the Congress. Part B: Emergency Food and Shelter Grants - Requires the Director of FEMA, within 30 days of enactment of a law providing appropriations to carry out this Part, to provide funds to the Board for grants to private nonprofit organizations and units of local government to: (1) provide shelter, food, and support services to the homeless, with attention given to homeless persons with mental and physical disabilities; (2) strengthen efforts to create more effective and innovative local programs; and (3) conduct limited rehabilitation of existing mass shelter or mass feeding facilities. Limits Board funding to only those programs carried out by nonprofit organizations and units of local government which are consistent with the purposes of this title. Prohibits the Board from carrying out programs directly. Limits administrative costs to not more than five percent of total appropriations. Requires the Board to establish written guidelines, including: (1) methods for identifying needy localities, and determining allocations; (2) eligible program costs; and (3) guidelines specifying the responsibilities and reporting requirements of the Board, its recipients, and service providers. Authorizes FY 1987 appropriations, including any amount provided under Public Law 100-6, and FY 1988 appropriations. Part C: Case Management - Requires the Director of FEMA, within 30 days of enactment of a law providing appropriations to carry out this Part, to provide grants to the Board to be given to recipient private nonprofit organizations and units of local government under Part B of the Act to provide the homeless in shelters with case management services. Requires recipients to provide or arrange for such services. Sets forth required services. States that, if feasible in certain areas, the government or private entity operating a homeless shelter shall give preference to specified Community Services Block Grant programs in arranging for the provision of case management services. Authorizes FY 1987 and 1988 appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
