<bill session="100" type="s" number="816" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-23">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-23"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title 49, United States Code, relating to the construction, acquisition, or operation of rail carriers, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-05-28"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-23" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-20">
      <text>Subcommittee on Surface Transportation. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSCM08" subcommittee="Surface Transportation" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Government and business"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Interstate Commerce Commission"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
    <term name="Railroads and state"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/23/1987--Introduced.
Amends Federal law regarding railroad lines operation and construction to direct the Interstate Commerce Commission to send a copy of a rail carrier's construction, acquisition, or operations applications (including all relevant agreements between the parties concerned) to the chief executive officer of each State (including the regulatory agencies designated by such officer) affected by such application. Grants such State officer (or designated agency) a specified time within which to submit a written protest regarding the application. Directs the Commission, upon receipt of a protest, to review the proposed transaction within a specified period to determine whether an exemption from statutory review is appropriate. Requires the Commission to determine whether the public convenience and necessity require or permit the proposed transaction if the Commission finds that such transaction does not fall under the review exemption.</summary>
</bill>
