<bill session="100" type="s" number="820" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Veterans' Education Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend titles 38 and 10, United States Code, to provide veteran's educational assistance benefits for flight training.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1988-05-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-05-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Veterans.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Committee on Veterans. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSVA" name="Senate Veterans' Affairs" activity="Referral, Hearings, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Armed forces reserves"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Flight training"/>
    <term name="Veterans' education"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1987--Introduced.
Veterans' Education Amendments of 1987 - Amends Federal law relating to veterans' educational assistance to authorize the Administrator of Veterans Affairs to approve the pursuit of flight training by an individual entitled to basic educational assistance under specified conditions, including: (1) that such training is necessary for the attainment of the individual's vocational objective; (2) that the individual possesses a valid private pilot's license and meets all medical requirements necessary for a commercial pilot's license; and (3) that the flight school courses are approved by the Federal Aviation Administration and the State. Sets forth the amount of assistance and other conditions for such flight training. Authorizes the Administrator to provide the same such assistance, under the same conditions, for members of the Selected Reserve of the armed forces found to be entitled to such basic educational assistance.</summary>
</bill>
