<bill session="100" type="s" number="821" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:01-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Independent Establishment Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to establish the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration as an independent establishment of the Government of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="411421"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Atmosphere"/>
    <term name="Department of Commerce"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Ocean policy"/>
    <term name="Presidential appointments"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/24/1987--Introduced.
National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration Independent Establishment Act of 1987 - Establishes the National Oceanic and Atmospheric Administration (NOAA) as an independent Federal agency, administered by an Administrator appointed by the President with the advice and consent of the Senate. Establishes the following positions within such Administration: (1) Deputy Administrator; (2) Assistant Administrator for Coastal Zone Management; (3) Assistant Administrator for Fisheries; (4) Chief Scientist; (5) three additional Assistant Administrators; and (6) a General Counsel. Establishes the Commissioned Officer Corps of the NOAA. Authorizes the Secretary of the Navy to detail a rear admiral to serve as the Naval Deputy to the Administrator to act as liaison. Transfers funds, functions, and personnel from the existing NOAA in the Department of Commerce. Empowers the Administrator to perform such actions as are concomitant with administering a Federal agency. Authorizes the Administrator to provide certain services for employees and dependents stationed at remote locations, including emergency medical treatment and living quarters. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
