<bill session="100" type="s" number="829" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-30">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-03-30"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">An original bill to authorize appropriations for the United States International Trade Commission, the United States Customs Service, and the Office of the United States Trade Representative for fiscal year 1988, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="401391"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-11" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Finance ordered to be reported an original measure.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25">
      <text>Committee on Finance. Original measure reported to Senate by Senator Bentsen. With written report No. 100-23.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-03-25" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="69">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 69.</text>
    </calendar>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-03-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-07-31">
      <text>Received in the Senate (Returned pursuant to the provisions of H. Res. 235.).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Origin, Reporting, Markup"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="hr" number="235"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Agricultural machinery"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Beverages"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Department of the Treasury"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Forced labor"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Fuel"/>
    <term name="Gold"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="International Trade Commission"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Motor Vehicles and Driving"/>
    <term name="Office of the U.S. Trade Representative"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Tea"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to authorize appropriations for FY 1988 for the International Trade Commission. Amends the Customs Procedural Reform and Simplification Act of 1978 to authorize appropriations for FY 1986 for the U.S. Customs Service. Earmarks specified amounts for: (1) the operation and maintenance of the air interdiction program of the Service; (2) rents incurred in connection with the provision of customs services outside the United States; (3) research; and (4) reception and representation expenses. Authorizes imposition of a limit on the total amount of payments that may be made in FY 1988 from the Customs User Fee Account for expenses incurred by the Secretary of the Treasury in providing nonreimbursable overtime customs inspectional services. Authorizes the Commissioner of Customs, during FY 1988, to: (1) purchase not more than 500 replacement motor vehicles; (2) rent passenger motor vehicles; and (3) purchase uniforms. Requires the Commissioner of Customs to notify the Senate Committee on Finance and the House Committee on Ways and Means of any action which would: (1) result in a significant reduction in force of employees (other than by attrition) or in hours of operation of any U.S. Customs Service office or port of entry; (2) eliminate or relocate an office of the Service; (3) eliminate a port of entry; or (4) reduce the number of employees assigned to an office or port of entry of the Service. Directs the Secretary to establish the Advisory Committee on Commercial Operations of the U.S. Customs Service which shall: (1) provide advice to the Secretary on matters relating to the commercial operations of the Service; and (2) submit an annual report to the Senate Committee on Finance and the House Committee on Ways and Means concerning Advisory Committee operations and recommendations regarding Service commercial operations. Amends the Trade Act of 1974 to authorize appropriations for the Office of the United States Trade Representative for FY 1988, out of which only a specified amount may be used for entertainment and representation expenses. Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to provide that user fees collected by the Service shall be deposited as offsetting receipts in the Customs User Fee Account. Authorizes and directs the Secretary to pay from such account all salaries and expenses of the Service incurred in conducting commercial operations, provided that a dollar limitation on such payments is established in the applicable appropriation act. Revises the method of calculation of fees charged by the Service for the processing of merchandise, with exceptions, imported into the United States after September 30, 1987. Prohibits, with exceptions, the importation of the following products believed to have been produced by forced labor in the Soviet Union: (1) gold ore; (2) agriculture machinery; (3) tractor generators; (4) tea; (5) crude petroleum; (6) motor fuel; and (7) kerosene. Allows the importation of such products upon Presidential certification to the Congress that: (1) such products are not being produced by forced labor; or (2) such prohibition affects U.S. security interests.</summary>
</bill>
