<bill session="100" type="s" number="838" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-25">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Computer Education Assistance Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to provide financial assistance to the States for computer education programs, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300064"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-09-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-05-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1987-03-25"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-03-25"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Education Department, OMB, National Science Foundation, GAO.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="American Samoa"/>
    <term name="Computers"/>
    <term name="Computers in education"/>
    <term name="Educational research"/>
    <term name="Elementary and secondary education"/>
    <term name="Elementary education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to private schools"/>
    <term name="Guam"/>
    <term name="Northern Mariana Islands"/>
    <term name="Puerto Rico"/>
    <term name="Science and technology"/>
    <term name="Secondary education"/>
    <term name="Teacher education"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Teaching materials"/>
    <term name="Territories (U.S.)"/>
    <term name="Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands"/>
    <term name="Virgin Islands"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Computer Education Assistance Act of 1987 - Title I: Acquisition of Computer Resources - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991 for the Secretary of Education to make grants to States to pay the Federal share of the costs of strengthening and expanding computer education resources available in elementary and secondary schools. Directs the Secretary to reserve a specified amount for the needs of the Commonwealth of Puerto Rico, Guam, American Samoa, the Virgin Islands, the Trust Territory of the Pacific Islands, and the Northern Mariana Islands. Specifies the planning activities that States must carry out in order to be eligible for grants. Authorizes the use of such grants for: (1) the acquisition and leasing of computer hardware for use in the education program in the elementary and secondary schools in the State, including operation, installation, and maintenance services; (2) teacher training programs; and (3) the acquisition of computer software. Describes the contents to be included in State and local applications for grants. Allows the participation of private elementary and secondary schools under this Act. Declares the Federal share for such grants to be 75 percent. Title II: Teacher Training Institutes - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991 for the National Science Foundation to arrange for the development and operation of short-term or regular session institutes for study to improve the qualifications of individuals for teaching, or supervising or training teachers, in the use of computers for elementary and secondary schools. Authorizes the payment of stipends for individuals who attend such institutes. Title III: Technical Assistance Information Dissemination - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991 for the Secretary of Education and the National Science Foundation to disseminate the results of research conducted on the availability of computer hardware and software for use in classrooms and to recommend improvements in implementing computer hardware and software into the curriculum of schools. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1991 for the National Science Foundation, through grants or contracts, to conduct, assist, and foster research and experimentation on, and demonstration and dissemination of, models of instruction in the operation and use of computers which can be easily replicated. Requires the Foundation to report to the Congress annually on the results of such research and experimentation.</summary>
</bill>
