<bill session="100" type="s" number="842" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-23">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-04-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-25"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Peace Corps Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Peace Corps Act to authorize appropriations for fiscal years 1988 and 1989, to authorize the encouraging of contributions to the Peace Corps, and to provide for activities to promote Americans' understanding of other peoples.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-05-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-25" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-23" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Provisions of measure incorporated into measure S. 1274 ordered to be reported.</text>
    </calendar>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="s" number="1274"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Free enterprise"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Peace Corps"/>
    <term name="Volunteer workers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/25/1987--Introduced.
Peace Corps Act Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Peace Corps Act to increase the authorization of appropriations for the Peace Corps for FY 1987. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and FY 1989. Authorizes the President to develop the commitment of private resources, through contacts with the private sector, to uses in furtherance of the purposes of the Peace Corps Act. Authorizes the Director of the Peace Corps to encourage and assist activities carried out by former volunteers and other individuals and organizations relating to the promotion of a better understanding of other peoples on the part of the American people.</summary>
</bill>
