<bill session="100" type="s" number="846" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Energy Security Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to promote the energy security of the United States by amending the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to encourage the continued exploration for and production of domestic oil and natural gas resources.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300079"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1987-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-05">
      <text>Subcommittee on Energy and Agricultural Taxation. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-143.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSFI07" subcommittee="Energy and Agricultural Taxation" name="Senate Finance"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Depletion allowances"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Excess profits tax"/>
    <term name="Excise tax"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Limitation of actions"/>
    <term name="Minimum tax"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas leases"/>
    <term name="Oil and gas royalties"/>
    <term name="Oil well drilling"/>
    <term name="Petroleum"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum industry"/>
    <term name="Prospecting"/>
    <term name="Tax deductions"/>
    <term name="Tax returns"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/26/1987--Introduced.
Energy Security Act of 1987 - Repeals provisions of the Internal Revenue Code that identify intangible drilling costs as a tax preference item for purposes of determining alternative minimum tax liability. Treats certain geological and geophysical costs as intangible drilling and development costs that a taxpayer may elect either to capitalize or to deduct for income tax purposes. Establishes a percentage depletion of 27.5 percent for new, enhanced, or stripper production of domestic oil and natural gas for purposes of calculating the deduction for depletion. Exempts the deduction attributable to such production from the taxable income limitation applicable to independent producers and royalty owners. Disallows percentage depletion for lease bonuses, advance royalties, or similar payments with respect to new, enhanced, or stripper production of oil and gas. Increases: (1) from 50 to 100 percent the net income limitation on percentage depletion applicable to oil and gas wells; and (2) from 65 to 100 percent the taxable income limitation on the percentage depletion deduction for oil and gas property. Permits a percentage depletion income tax deduction for proven oil and gas wells that have been transferred to a new owner. (Current law disallows the deduction after such a transfer.) Applies the exemption of stripper well oil from the windfall profit tax after a transfer of such a well to a new owner. (Current law disallows the exemption after such a transfer.) Revises a special windfall profit tax rule affecting the statute of limitations applicable to underpayments of the tax. (The statute of limitations on assessments for windfall profit tax liability would commence at the same time as that on the taxpayer's income tax return.) Limits the applicability of such rule revision to returns filed after February 29, 1980. Repeals the windfall profit tax on domestic crude oil.</summary>
</bill>
