<bill session="100" type="s" number="857" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-05-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-05-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Bilingual Education Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="reported to senate">Bilingual Education Act Amendments of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Bilingual Education Act to make Federal financial assistance available for children of limited English proficiency without mandating a specific method of instruction, to encourage innovation at the State and local level through greater administrative flexibility, to improve program operations at the Federal level, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408970"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-03-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-03-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-04">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Approved for reporting with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-05">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute. Without written report.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-05-05" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="110">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 110.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>The chair ruled that the bill was reported to the Senate in violation of the Rules; therefore the bill was returned to the committee.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Bilingual education"/>
    <term name="Bilingualism"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="English language"/>
    <term name="Language and languages"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>5/5/1987--Reported to Senate amended.
(Reported to Senate from the Committee on Labor and Human Resources with amendment (without written report)) Bilingual Education Act Amendments of 1987 - Amends the Bilingual Education Act (the Act) to add to the statement of policy the declaration that, regardless of the method of instruction, programs which serve children of limited English proficiency have the equally important goals of developing both academic achievement and English proficiency. Directs the Secretary of Education to reserve 25 percent of certain funds appropriated under the Act for special alternative instruction programs and related activities, including specified programs. (Current law requires that up to four percent of such funds be reserved for such activities.) States that no student may be enrolled in a bilingual program for more than three school years, but allows four or five years' enrollment under specified conditions. Sets forth conditions under which applications for grants for special alternative instructional programs for students of limited English proficiency shall receive priority.</summary>
</bill>
