<bill session="100" type="s" number="867" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Equal Access to Housing Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend title VIII of the Act commonly called the Civil Rights Act of 1968 to revise the procedures for the enforcement of fair housing, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300052"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSJU03" subcommittee="Constitution" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Architecture and the disabled"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing discrimination"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Magistrates"/>
    <term name="Racial discrimination"/>
    <term name="Real estate appraisal"/>
    <term name="Real estate business"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination"/>
    <term name="Sex discrimination against women"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/1987--Introduced.
Equal Access to Housing Act of 1987 - Entitles Public Law 90-284 the "Civil Rights Act of 1968." Entitles title VIII of such Act the "Equal Access to Housing Act." Revises the express policy of title VIII to provide for "equal access to" instead of "fair" housing. States that this policy does not mean assurance of housing for any particular proportion of individuals of a particular race, color, religion, sex, handicap, or national origin. Defines "aggrieved person" as a person whose bona fide attempt to buy, sell, lease, or finance a dwelling has been denied on a discriminatory basis. Adds the physically handicapped as a protected class of persons. Excludes from the meaning of "handicap" any impairment consisting of alcohol or drug abuse or which would be a threat to the property or safety of others. Defines discriminatory practices with respect to the handicapped. States that discrimination shall not include refusals to: (1) make alterations at the expense of sellers, landlord owners, or persons acting on their own behalf; (2) make modifications which would unreasonably inconvenience others; or (3) allow modifications which alter the marketability of a dwelling. Extends the housing financing discrimination prohibition to include real estate appraisers. States that it is not unlawful for appraisers to take into consideration all factors relevant to estimating fair market value, provided that such factors are not used for discriminatory purposes. Transfers all authority for administering title VIII from the Department of Housing and Urban Development to the Justice Department. Establishes a one-House congressional veto procedure for regulations promulgated by the Attorney General for compliance purposes. Sets forth new enforcement procedures for title VIII complaints. Permits an aggrieved person or the Attorney General on his own initiative to file a discriminatory housing practice complaint (currently, Justice Department complaints are limited to "patterns or practices" of discrimination). Requires the Attorney General to refer title VIII charges to certified State or local agencies which have jurisdiction. Prohibits the Attorney General from conditioning certification on the agency's agreement to waive its exclusive authority over housing discrimination. Requires the Attorney General to endeavor to resolve charges by conciliation. Permits the Attorney General to seek injunctive relief where preliminary investigation reveals that prompt judicial action is necessary. Continues the current authority given to private parties to seek enforcement in Federal district court. Permits the Attorney General to intervene in any such private action after personal certification that the case is of general public importance. Expresses the sense of the Congress that the use of Federal magistrates should be encouraged to the maximum extent feasible to expedite litigation. States that nothing in this Act shall be construed to prohibit: (1) landlords from establishing tenancy requirements relating to age, income, parental status, familial relationship, or maximum occupancy; (2) zoning or related land-use statutes or policies, or private agreements or contracts which may result in increased housing costs or diminished housing availability. Stipulates that such provisions shall not exempt from coverage under this Act any action taken for the purpose of discriminating on account of race, color, religion, sex, handicap, or national origin.</summary>
</bill>
