<bill session="100" type="s" number="869" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:02-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-27">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend part D of title IV of the Social Security Act to require that mandatory income withholding of court-ordered child support begin automatically when the court order is issued, to strengthen the presently-required State guidelines for child support award amounts, to require that employment security information be made available for child support enforcement purposes through Federal and State telecommunications networks, and to increase the penalties on States for failure to comply with statutorily prescribed procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403515"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-27" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Child support"/>
    <term name="Civil procedure"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Information networks"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Medicaid"/>
    <term name="Public assistance programs"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/27/1987--Introduced.
Amends part D (Child Support and Establishment of Paternity) of title IV of the Social Security Act to require the withholding of child support payments from the non-custodial parent's wages upon the issuance or modification of a child support order. (Currently, such withholding need not occur until one month of nonpayment has elapsed.) Directs States to establish binding guidelines for child support award amounts. (Currently, such guidelines need not be binding.) Creates a rebuttable presumption that the child support award resulting from the application of such guidelines in a judicial or administrative child support proceeding is correct. Requires States to review and update all child support orders at least once every two years to ensure that they continue to comply with child support award guidelines. Gives the Federal Parent Locator Service and State child support enforcement agencies access to all employment security information in the possession or control of existing data networks. Conditions a State's eligibility for payments under titles IV or XIX (Medicaid) of the Act on its compliance with federally prescribed child support enforcement procedures.</summary>
</bill>
