<bill session="100" type="s" number="885" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:03-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Airline Consumer Rights Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to make available to consumers certain information on the performance records of air carriers operating in the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="407663"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-05-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1866"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="h" number="1866"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Advertising and Marketing"/>
    <term name="Airline passenger traffic"/>
    <term name="Airlines"/>
    <term name="Aviation"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Consumer education"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Deceptive advertising"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Government paperwork"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Unfair or deceptive trade practices"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1987--Introduced.
Airline Consumer Rights Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Transportation to require commercial air carriers engaged in the transportation of passengers in the United States (including foreign air and commuter air carriers) to report to the Secretary on a monthly basis specified information regarding flight delays, cancellations, reroutings, luggage status performance, and "bumped" passengers. Requires the Secretary to make such information available to the public at all public airports in a timely fashion. Directs the Secretary to require that each such air carrier disclose to each passenger at the time of ticket purchase specified information regarding flight cancellations, overbookings, delays, liability for luggage, and food and restroom accommodations on such flight. Directs the Secretary to prohibit air carriers from advertising a fare for any flight at a particular price unless the carrier offers at least one-third of the seats for such flight at the advertised price, or unless the air carrier makes a general disclosure that fewer than one-third of such seats are available at that particular price. Prohibits any air carrier from cancelling a flight for economic reasons unless reasonable efforts are made to notify each passenger and to make similar service available within a reasonable time. Establishes a civil penalty for violations of regulations under this Act. Directs the Secretary to establish a 24-hour toll-free consumer hotline and to prominently publicize such hotline's availability at airports.</summary>
</bill>
