<bill session="100" type="s" number="888" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-31">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-31"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Pipeline Safety Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "Pipeline Safety Act of 1987".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-03-31"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-03-31"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-31" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Commerce.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSCM" name="Senate Commerce, Science, and Transportation" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Transportation and public works"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Transportation"/>
    <term name="Destruction of property"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Employee training"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fines (Penalties)"/>
    <term name="Gas pipelines"/>
    <term name="Natural gas"/>
    <term name="Petroleum and petroleum products"/>
    <term name="Petroleum pipelines"/>
    <term name="Pipelines"/>
    <term name="Safety measures"/>
    <term name="State laws"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Transportation of hazardous substances"/>
    <term name="User charges"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/31/1987--Introduced.
Pipeline Safety Act of 1987 - Amends the Hazardous Liquid Pipeline Safety Act of 1979 to direct the Secretary of Transportation (the Secretary) to promulgate regulations establishing Federal hazardous liquid pipeline safety standards, including requirements for release detection, prevention, and correction, for the transportation of hazardous liquids and for pipeline facilities. Sets forth the factors which the Secretary may consider when promulgating such regulations. Permits the States to adopt standards or requirements that are more stringent than Federal standards or requirements. Directs the Secretary to provide that the Federal safety regulations include the requirement that: (1) any pipeline facilities operator participate in any public safety program or "one-call system"; and (2) any persons engaged in demolition, excavation, tunneling, or construction near or affecting any pipeline facility shall contact the appropriate public safety program or "one-call system" prior to such activities in order to ascertain the location of underground pipeline facilities. Sets forth notification requirements for pipeline facility operators regarding such facility's location, and prescribes requirements regarding: (1) release detection; (2) shut-off valves; (3) operating pressure; (4) design requirements; (5) pipeline inventory; and (6) financial responsibility. Makes the Federal standards and requirements applicable to both interstate and intrastate pipelines. (Currently such requirements apply only to interstate facilities.) Increases from $1,000 to $25,000 the civil penalty imposed for violations of this Act. Increases from $25,000 to $250,000 the criminal penalty imposed for violations of this Act. Establishes a criminal fine and prison term for the willful defacement, damage, or removal of a federally required pipeline sign or right-of-way marker. Amends the Emergency Planning and Community Right-to-Know Act of 1986 to include within its coverage pipelines and pipeline facilities whether or not the liquids in such facilities have been included under such Act's coverage. Directs the Secretary to establish a training and certification program for personnel retained by the States to inspect and audit pipeline facilities, and for persons engaged in construction and design of such facilities. Authorizes the commencement of citizens' civil action suits against the Secretary for failure to perform a duty under this Act. Amends the Consolidated Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1985 to increase from $3,000,000 to $40,000,000 the fees assessed against hazardous liquids transported by pipelines. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992.</summary>
</bill>
