<bill session="100" type="s" number="897" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-01">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Health Care Innovation Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill entitled the "Health Care Innovation Act of 1987".</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-01" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Case mix (Medical care)"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Health maintenance organizations"/>
    <term name="Hospital care"/>
    <term name="Hospitals"/>
    <term name="Medical economics"/>
    <term name="Medical innovations"/>
    <term name="Medical supplies"/>
    <term name="Medicare"/>
    <term name="Prospective payment systems (Medical care)"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/1/1987--Introduced.
Health Care Innovation Act of 1987 - Amends title XVIII (Medicare) of the Social Security Act to require the Secretary of Health and Human Services to pay hospitals for their use of a new medical device or procedure which causes hospital operating costs to exceed 110 percent of the price of the diagnosis-related group (DRG) to which the device or procedure is applied. Funds 60 percent of the amount by which the cost of the innovative treatment exceeds 110 percent of the DRG price. Terminates such funding when the decision is made to incorporate or exclude the treatment from the DRG price, but not later than two years after the provision of such funding. Requires that new devices have premarket approval by the Food and Drug Administration and new procedures be suitable for inclusion in the DRG system before such funding is provided. Directs hospitals which receive funds pursuant to this Act to supply the financial and clinical data the Secretary needs to assess the usefulness of the treatment and establish an appropriate DRG rate for the innovative treatment. Sets forth a formula based, in part, on the percentage of total Medicare hospital payments a hospital receives, limiting payments a hospital may receive for the application of innovative treatments. Limits the aggregate payments made pursuant to this Act to one percent of the total Medicare payments made for the operating costs of inpatient hospital services. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress within one year of enactment of this Act on methods of paying health maintenance organizations and competitive medical plans for their application of innovative treatments. Requires the: (1) adjustment of DRG classifications and reweighting of weighting factors in FY 1988 and every four years thereafter; and (2) annual recalibration of weighting factors. (Recalibration, unlike reweighting, is applicable to all weighting factors simultaneously.)</summary>
</bill>
