<bill session="100" type="s" number="901" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:04-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-02">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-02"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Apprenticeship Improvement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the National Apprenticeship Act to require minimum funding for certain outreach recruitment and training programs, to restore a national information collection system, to limit the authority to conduct reductions in force within the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training of the Department of Labor, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409225"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1987-04-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-04-02"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-02" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Labor.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-06">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Labor Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR03" subcommittee="Labor" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Affirmative action programs"/>
    <term name="Apprenticeship"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Department of Labor"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Dislocated workers"/>
    <term name="Employment and training programs"/>
    <term name="Employment of the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Hard-core unemployed"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Layoffs"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Minority employment"/>
    <term name="Recruiting of employees"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Unemployment"/>
    <term name="Women's employment"/>
    <term name="Women's rights"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/2/1987--Introduced.
Apprenticeship Improvement Act of 1987 - Amends the National Apprenticeship Act to direct the Secretary of Labor to establish and maintain a national information collection system for apprenticeships and apprenticeship programs. Requires the Secretary to assure that, from the amounts appropriated to carry out such Act in each fiscal year, at least one percent shall be available to establish outreach recruitment activities to increase the participation of women and minorities, handicapped individuals, displaced workers, and disadvantaged individuals in the apprenticeship programs. Establishes the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training in the Department of Labor, under the direction of the Administrator of the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training. Transfers to the Bureau all functions of the Assistant Secretary for Employment and Training Administration with respect to the promotion of labor standards of apprenticeship, including research, information, and publications. Transfers to the Bureau all functions related to apprenticeship, including appropriate administrative and program support services, together with necessary personnel and related funds. Authorizes the Secretary to appoint necessary employees for the administration of this Act. Directs the Secretary to assure the employment of not less than a specified number of full-time employees. Limits the authority to conduct reductions in force within the Bureau of Apprenticeship and Training. Directs the Secretary to report to the Congress within six months after the enactment of this Act on whether the apprenticeship program complies with regulations governing equal opportunity. Requires such report to include: (1) a detailed description of activities carried out by the Department to ensure compliance; (2) a list of compliance reviews undertaken by the Department; and (3) a description of the sanctions imposed as a result of the compliance reviews.</summary>
</bill>
