<bill session="100" type="s" number="911" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:05-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-03">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-03"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-03"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Clean Coal Technologies Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to implement the recommendations of the Special Envoys, to authorize a program deploying clean technologies, to reduce transboundary air pollution, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403669"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-04-03"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-03" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid precipitation (Meteorology)"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Canada"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Coal research"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Sulphur oxides"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Transboundary pollution"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/3/1987--Introduced.
Clean Coal Technologies Act of 1987 - Amends the Clean Air Act to implement the recommendations of the Special Envoys concerning acid depositions and transboundary air pollution by securing near-term reductions in the movement of air pollutants from the United States into Canada. Directs the Secretary of Energy, acting jointly with the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency, to carry out a program of construction and operation of facilities to develop experience in the commercial deployment of clean coal technologies which significantly reduce air emissions of sulfur dioxide or oxides of nitrogen from the generation of electricity or industrial process steam. Includes within such program the solicitation, selection, supervision, monitoring, and dissemination of information about results of proposed projects to deploy such technologies. Requires project selection to be based on applicability to existing coal-fired sources of emission, reductions achievable, and cost-effectiveness, including the ability to use feedstock coal mined in the United States. Prohibits the application of reductions achieved through this program to reductions required under a State implementation plan. Limits Federal funds to 50 percent of costs over a two year period. Directs the Secretary and the Administrator to establish a Clean Coal Technologies Advisory Committee to select projects. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992. Allows clean coal technology project expenditures as a public utility operating expense, as part of the rate base, or as an amortizable cost, as specified. Permits exemptions from otherwise applicable requirements for participation in a project under this Act, including the prohibition against using natural gas in a major fuel burning, coal-fired installation.</summary>
</bill>
