<bill session="100" type="s" number="926" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Information System for Health Related Services Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act to provide grants for the operation of the National Information System for Health Related Services.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300157"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-05-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-06-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Handicapped (Labor and Human Res.).</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-10">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources requested executive comment from Health and Human Services Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral" code="SSHR02" subcommittee="Handicapped" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Communications and Broadcasting"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to handicapped services"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Health education"/>
    <term name="Higher education"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Information storage and retrieval systems"/>
    <term name="Social work"/>
    <term name="Telephone"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1987--Introduced.
National Information System for Health Related Services Act of 1987 - Amends the Developmental Disabilities Assistance and Bill of Rights Act to direct the Secretary of Health and Human Services to make grants to an academic institution for the operation of a National Information System for Health Related Services. Requires such system to: (1) provide information and referrals regarding services available from public and private entities for persons with developmental disabilities or chronic illnesses and their families; (2) use a central computer system accessible to the public through a toll-free telephone number; (3) train people who will receive and answer requests for information and referrals; and (4) conduct periodic followup on referrals. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 through 1992.</summary>
</bill>
