<bill session="100" type="s" number="927" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Federal Cave Resources Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to protect caves resources on Federal lands, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300031"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300009" joined="1988-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1987-12-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1988-09-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-05-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-04-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1988-08-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Energy and Natural Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Interior Department, OMB.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-10-01">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources requested executive comment from Agriculture Department.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-11-30">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources received executive comment from Agriculture Department. Favorable.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-16">
      <text>Subcommittee on Public Lands, National Parks. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-09-22">
      <text>Committee on Energy and Natural Resources. Ordered favorably reported H.R. 1975 in lieu of this measure.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEG" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSEG04" subcommittee="Public Lands, National Parks and Forests" name="Senate Energy and Natural Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="unknown" session="100" type="h" number="1975"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Conservation of natural resources"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Natural areas"/>
    <term name="Public Lands and Real Property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1987--Introduced.
Federal Cave Resources Protection Act of 1987 - Directs the Secretary of Agriculture or the Secretary of the Interior, as appropriate, to take such actions as are necessary to protect cave resources on Federal lands, including: (1) restricting the use of such resources; (2) entering into volunteer management agreements with the caving community; and (3) appointing advisory committees. Restricts the release of information concerning cave location to protect the resource, requiring the Governor of a State in which a cave resource is located or a bona fide research institution to request location information in writing along with a commitment to protect the confidentiality of such information. Establishes a permit program for the collection or removal of natural resources from caves on Federal lands. Requires a permittee to post a bond or cash deposit to offset potential damage. Revokes permits for violations of this Act or permit conditions. Excludes Federal cave resources within the National Park or Wildlife Refuge Systems from this program. Imposes criminal penalties for the alteration of a cave or interference with cave resources, including the sale or exchange of cave resources removed without permission. Establishes civil penalties for violations of this Act or permit conditions. Authorizes appropriations. Places permit fees and fines in a special fund in the Treasury for cave resource management.</summary>
</bill>
