<bill session="100" type="s" number="928" updated="2016-06-29T08:45:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-07">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Tariff Act of 1930 to make changes in the countervailing and antidumping duty provisions, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="404598"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Administrative procedure"/>
    <term name="Antidumping"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Business records"/>
    <term name="Civil actions and liability"/>
    <term name="Countervailing duties"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Customs administration"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Fraud"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government procurement"/>
    <term name="Import restrictions"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Lawyers and Legal Services"/>
    <term name="Legal fees"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/7/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Tariff Act of 1930 to apply antidumping and countervailing duties to merchandise imported by, or for the use of, the U.S. Government. Requires the Government to consider antidumping and countervailing duties when awarding procurement contracts. Establishes procedures to prevent the release of confidential information presented to, or obtained by, the U.S. International Trade Commission or other administering authority during an antidumping or countervailing duty proceeding. Requires any party submitting information to the administering authority during such a proceeding to serve the information upon all other parties to the proceeding. Requires any person submitting information to the Department of Commerce or the International Trade Commission in an antidumping or countervailing duty proceeding to certify that it is accurate and complete. Establishes a private cause of action for customs fraud. Permits recovery of actual damages for injuries sustained, equitable relief, and reasonable attorney's fees. Allows the United States to intervene in such an action as a matter of right.</summary>
</bill>
