<bill session="100" type="s" number="938" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-31">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-07-31"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-07"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989</title>
    <title type="short" as="passed senate">Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to authorize appropriations for the purpose of carrying out the activities of the Department of Justice for fiscal years 1988 and 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300008"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-04-07"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-07" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-04-08" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Ordered to be reported without amendment favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-06-16">
      <text>Committee on Judiciary. Reported to Senate by Senator Byrd for Senator Biden without amendment. With written report No. 100-72.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-06-16" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="168">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 168.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-07-31">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-07-31" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate with an amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-08-04">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Administration of criminal justice"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Aircraft"/>
    <term name="Ammunition"/>
    <term name="Antitrust law"/>
    <term name="Antitrust policy"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Civil rights and liberties, minority issues"/>
    <term name="Civil service compensation"/>
    <term name="Corporations and Stocks"/>
    <term name="Correctional institutions"/>
    <term name="Corrections and Correctional Institutions"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="Crime and law enforcement"/>
    <term name="Criminal Procedure and Sentencing"/>
    <term name="Criminal investigation"/>
    <term name="Criminal procedure"/>
    <term name="Department of Justice"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Evidence (Law)"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to education"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Fingerprints"/>
    <term name="Firearms"/>
    <term name="Freedom of information"/>
    <term name="Fugitives from justice"/>
    <term name="Gifts"/>
    <term name="Government corporations"/>
    <term name="Government liability (International law)"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Grand jury"/>
    <term name="Immigration"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="International agencies"/>
    <term name="Judicial officers"/>
    <term name="Juries"/>
    <term name="Law enforcement officers"/>
    <term name="Parole"/>
    <term name="Police training"/>
    <term name="Price fixing"/>
    <term name="Prison administration"/>
    <term name="Prisoners"/>
    <term name="Prosecution"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="Reprogramming of appropriated funds"/>
    <term name="Resale price maintenance"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
    <term name="Translating and interpreting"/>
    <term name="Transportation and Travel"/>
    <term name="Travel costs"/>
    <term name="Undercover operations"/>
    <term name="Witnesses"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s655"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>7/31/1987--Passed Senate amended.
(Measure passed Senate, amended) Department of Justice Appropriation Authorization Act, Fiscal Years 1988 and 1989 - Title I - Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 to the Department of Justice for: (1) general administration, salaries, and expenses; (2) the General Administration Working Capital Fund; (3) the United States Parole Commission; (4) general legal activities; (5) the Antitrust Division; (6) the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission; (7) the United States Marshals Service; (8) the support of United States prisoners in non-Federal institutions; (9) fees and expenses of witnesses; (10) the Community Relations Service; (11) United States Attorneys; (12) the United States Trustee System Fund; (13) the Assets Forfeiture Fund; (14) the Federal Bureau of Investigation (FBI); (15) the Drug Enforcement Administration (DEA); (16) the Immigration and Naturalization Service (INS); and (17) the Federal Prison System. Allows up to $75,000 of the funds authorized to the Department to be made available for official reception and representation expenses. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1988 and 1989 for increases in salary and employee benefits authorized by law. Allows the Administration to request increases in the amount of appropriations authorized by this Act for FY 1989. Title II - Provides general authorizations for: (1) travel expenses; (2) construction of new law enforcement facilities; (3) purchasing and leasing motor vehicles; (4) purchasing and leasing firearms and ammunition; (5) leasing surveillance sites; (6) the acquisition, maintenance, and operation of aircraft; (7) miscellaneous and emergency expenses; (8) official reception and representation expenses; (9) meetings; (10) services of experts and consultants; (11) services of interpreters and translators; (12) the payment of rewards; (13) insurance; and (14) benefits for employees serving overseas. Provides guidelines for the use of appropriations by the Attorney General for: (1) the FBI; (2) the DEA; (3) the INS; (4) the Bureau of Prisons; and (5) the United States Marshals Service. Provides guidelines with respect to the authorizations and exemptions which may be utilized for undercover operations conducted by the FBI, the DEA, the INS, and the U.S. Marshals Service. Allows the FBI to establish and collect fees for the processing of noncriminal employment and licensing fingerprint cards. Title III - Authorizes the Attorney General to make payments for assistance to individuals under the Refugee Education Assistance Act of 1980. Grants the Associate Attorney General authority to: (1) approve certain civil rights prosecutions; (2) approve prosecutions for flight to avoid service of process; (3) summon special grand juries; (4) request a judicial grant of immunity; and (5) object to the disclosure of classified information under the Classified Information Procedures Act. Grants specially designated Assistant Attorneys General authority to approve certain civil rights prosecutions. Grants the Deputy Attorney General authority to approve prosecutions for flight to avoid service of process. Authorizes the Attorney General to make payment from appropriations for the support of United States prisoners in non-Federal institutions. Authorizes appropriations for the Federal Prison Industries, Incorporated. Authorizes the Attorney General to host the annual meeting of the General Assembly of INTERPOL and to periodically sponsor INTERPOL conferences. Authorizes the Foreign Claims Settlement Commission to: (1) hire motor vehicles and purchase insurance for official motor vehicles used abroad; (2) advance funds abroad and to other Government departments and agencies; and (3) employ aliens abroad. Title IV - Allows the Attorney General to accept, subject to specified restrictions, gifts for the purpose of aiding or facilitating the work of the Department. Allows funds authorized to be appropriated under this Act to be used to: (1) train foreign law enforcement personnel; and (2) contract for the safekeeping, evaluation, treatment, care, and subsistence of persons held under legal authority. States that none of the sums authorized to be appropriated under this Act may be used to overturn or alter the per se prohibition of resale price maintenance, in effect under Federal antitrust laws, or for the obligation or expenditure through a reprogramming of funds which: (1) creates new programs; (2) eliminates a program, project, or activity; (3) increases funds or personnel for any project or activity for which funds have been denied or restricted; (4) relocates an office or employees; (5) reorganizes offices, programs, or activities; (6) contracts out functions presently performed by Federal employees; or (7) under certain circumstances, involves funds exceeding $250,0000 or ten percent of the existing program funds. Requires the Attorney General to perform periodic evaluations of the efficiency and effectiveness of Department programs and supporting activities. Sets forth certain reporting requirements. Title V - Makes technical changes to the United States Code.</summary>
</bill>
