<bill session="100" type="s" number="948" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:11-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to condition the occupation of the new Soviet embassy in Washington, D.C. on improved United States security arrangements for the embassy in Moscow.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400565"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-04-22"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-05-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-05-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Congressional veto"/>
    <term name="Consular agreements"/>
    <term name="District of Columbia"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1987--Introduced.
Prohibits the Secretary of State from allowing the Soviet Union to occupy facilities in the Washington, D.C. metropolitan area which were constructed after the date of entry into force of the agreement between the United States and the Soviet Union on Embassy sites signed on May 16, 1969, unless the President certifies to the Congress that an agreement has been reached: (1) establishing a new location for the U.S. diplomatic mission in Moscow and that the terms and conditions of construction ensure suitable security protection for that mission; or (2) providing that the Soviet Union will compensate the United States for all costs associated with establishing suitable security protection at the current U.S. diplomatic mission site in Moscow. Provides that if such certification is either disapproved or not submitted to the Congress by October 31, 1987, the Secretary of State shall require the Soviet Union to vacate, no later than December 31, 1987, all buildings and facilities at the Mount Alto site in Washington, D.C.</summary>
</bill>
