<bill session="100" type="s" number="95" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:46-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Acid Rain Control Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Clean Air Act to control certain sources of sulfur dioxide and oxides of nitrogen to reduce acid deposition, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300060"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-17">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environmental Protection. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-19">
      <text>Subcommittee on Environmental Protection. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Hearings" code="SSEV02" subcommittee="Environmental Protection" name="Senate Environment and Public Works"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Acid precipitation (Meteorology)"/>
    <term name="Acid rain"/>
    <term name="Air pollution control"/>
    <term name="Coal"/>
    <term name="Coal preparation"/>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Electric power production"/>
    <term name="Electric utilities"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy facilities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to water pollution control"/>
    <term name="Federal-state relations"/>
    <term name="Fees"/>
    <term name="Fossil fuels"/>
    <term name="Government trust funds"/>
    <term name="Industrial pollution"/>
    <term name="Mines and mineral resources"/>
    <term name="Motor vehicle pollution control"/>
    <term name="Nitrogen oxides"/>
    <term name="Public utilities"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="State finance"/>
    <term name="States"/>
    <term name="Sulphur oxides"/>
    <term name="Technological innovations"/>
    <term name="Trucks"/>
    <term name="Water pollution control"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
National Acid Rain Control Act of 1987 - Title I: Acid Deposition Control and Assistance Program - Amends the Clean Air Act to require fossil fuel fired electric utility generating plants burning coal with excessive sulfur content to clean that coal prior to combustion. Requires such plants using flue gas desulfurization units to use adipic acid treatment. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency (EPA), within 18 months after the enactment of this Act, to compute a State share for each of the 48 contiguous States of a 12,000,000 ton reduction in annual emissions of sulfur dioxide by 1995 below that of 1980. Sets forth a formula for determining State shares. Permits States to reallot shares among themselves if the required total reduction in annual emissions of sulfur dioxide is still achieved. Sets deadlines and procedures for submission and approval of State plans for such State shares. Requires the owner or operator of any fossil fuel fired facility which is a major but not new stationary source to comply with an emission limitation equivalent to an average of 1.2 pounds of sulfur dioxide per million Btu's of heat input on a rolling 30 day average, if its State has not submitted or implemented an approved plan. Requires such owners or operators to submit a compliance plan to the Administrator for approval. Establishes in the Treasury the Acid Deposition Control Fund to provide funding for emissions reductions from specified appropriations. Sets forth conditions and administrative provisions for such Fund. Imposes a fee on each kilowatt hour of electric energy generated by an electric utility in the contiguous States. Exempts electricity generated by nuclear or hydroelectric power. Directs the Administrator to make grants and contracts to accelerate research for developing other advanced industrial processes to reduce levels of sulfur dioxide and oxides of nitrogen, including limestone injected multistaged burner (LIMB) technology. Authorizes appropriations for FY 1987 through 1991. Title II: Control of Emissions of Oxides of Nitrogen - Directs the Administrator to revise nitrogen oxides emissions standards for electric utility steam generating units which burn bituminous or subbituminous coal. Sets maximum subbituminous emissions at 0.30 pounds per million Btu's and maximum bituminous coal emissions at 0.40 pounds per million Btu's, based on a 30-day rolling average. Requires the Administrator to promulgate emissions standards for new, large fossil fuel fired steam generating units. Establishes oxides of nitrogen emissions standards for light duty trucks after model year 1988. Title III: Acid Deposition Damage Mitigation Program - Establishes a grants program for States with Administrator-approved plans for mitigating water quality damage caused by acid deposition. Limits such grants to 80 percent of State-expended funds for mitigation. Apportions funds among the States upon the basis of need.</summary>
</bill>
