<bill session="100" type="s" number="962" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Family Care Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Internal Revenue Code of 1986 to allow a credit against tax for expenses incurred in the care of elderly family members.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="405321"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-06-02"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1987-06-04"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Taxation"/>
    <term name="Alzheimer's disease"/>
    <term name="Day care"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Domestic Relations and Families"/>
    <term name="Geriatrics"/>
    <term name="Health"/>
    <term name="Home care services"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Income tax"/>
    <term name="Nervous system diseases"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Support of dependents"/>
    <term name="Tax credits"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1987--Introduced.
Family Care Act of 1987 - Amends the Internal Revenue Code to allow a refundable income tax credit for qualified expenses incurred in the care of an individual who: (1) is related to the taxpayer by blood or marriage; (2) is at least 75 years of age (or diagnosed with senile dementia of the Alzheimer type); and (3) has an annual family income of $15,000 or less. Allows an income tax credit of 30 percent of the expenses incurred for taxpayers with incomes of $10,000 or less. Reduces the rate of such credit, but not below 20 percent, by one percent for each $2,000 of taxpayer income in excess of $10,000. Imposes a $3,500 limit on allowable expenses per taxable year for the care of any one qualifying individual, with a $7,000 annual maximum of total elderly care expenses subject to the credit. Includes as qualifying elderly care expenses payments for: (1) home health agency services; (2) homemaker services; (3) adult day care; (4) respite care; or (5) certain health care equipment and supplies. Prohibits the application of any other tax credit or tax deduction provisions to amounts subject to a credit under this Act. Directs the Secretary of the Treasury to prepare, over a five-year period, annual reports concerning the utilization and the fiscal effects of such credit and to submit each report to the Congress.</summary>
</bill>
