<bill session="100" type="s" number="964" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-08">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Meat Import Act of 1979 to include imports of lamb.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300005"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1987-07-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1987-07-15"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-08" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Finance.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFI" name="Senate Finance" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Agriculture in foreign trade"/>
    <term name="Food and Food Industry"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Import quotas"/>
    <term name="Imports"/>
    <term name="Livestock"/>
    <term name="Meat"/>
    <term name="Sheep"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/8/1987--Introduced.
Amends the Meat Import Act of 1979 to include lamb and the import of lamb within the provisions of such Act relating to regulations and restrictions concerning various meat imports. Limits the aggregate quantity of lamb which may be entered (imported) in any calendar year under such Act. Allows such amount to be increased or decreased in relation to an increase or decrease in the domestic production of lamb. Directs the Secretary of Agriculture, within 30 days after the enactment of this Act, to prescribe necessary regulations to convert live lamb into a poundage suitable for purposes of applying the import limitations required under this Act. Requires the Secretary to conduct a study to determine whether a disproportionate quantity of lamb meat is entered quarterly into the United States. Directs the Secretary, by the later of June 1, 1988, or 180 days after the date of enactment of this Act, to report the results of such study to the Senate Finance Committee and the House Ways and Means Committee.</summary>
</bill>
