<bill session="100" type="s" number="981" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Toxic Substances Control Act Amendments Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="short" as="introduced" partial="1">Federal Buildings Asbestos Hazard Abatement Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to amend the Toxic Substances Control Act so as to require the Environmental Protection Agency to set standards for identification and abatement of hazardous asbestos in Federal and other buildings, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="410242"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-04-09"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Environment and Public Works.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSEV" name="Senate Environment and Public Works" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Asbestos"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Building laws"/>
    <term name="Building leases"/>
    <term name="Consumer protection"/>
    <term name="Environmental Protection Agency"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Labeling"/>
    <term name="Management"/>
    <term name="Ombudsman"/>
    <term name="Public safety"/>
    <term name="Standards"/>
    <term name="Whistle blowing"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1987--Introduced.
Toxic Substances Control Act Amendments Act of 1987 - Amends the Toxic Substances Control Act to add an additional title, the Federal Building Asbestos Hazard Abatement Act of 1987. Directs the Administrator of the Environmental Protection Agency to promulgate regulations, within 360 days of enactment, for asbestos hazard abatement in Federal and other buildings. Requires such regulations to address: (1) building inspections; (2) appropriate response actions based upon potential or actual degree of significant damage; (3) the implementation of response actions; (4) an operations and maintenance program; (5) periodic surveillance needs; (6) the transportation and disposal of asbestos-containing waste material; and (7) management plans for each covered building requiring periodic inspections by accredited personnel, response actions when appropriate, and warning labels on any asbestos-containing material still in routine maintenance areas. Requires that such plans be approved by the Administrator and be available to the public. Sets forth guidelines and a compliance schedule should the Administrator fail to promulgate regulations within the prescribed period. Directs the Administrator to develop a model accreditation plan for States for individuals who inspect, manage, abate, and analyze asbestos problems. Requires asbestos contractors to be accredited by an equivalent or more stringent plan. Requires all Federal buildings to be inspected for asbestos within 180 days of the promulgation of regulations. Requires the Administrator to develop and periodically revise a schedule of non-Federal buildings to be inspected. Authorizes the Administrator to take emergency response measures where asbestos in a Federal or a covered building may be hazardous and adequate owner's actions have not been taken. Requires the building owner to be notified before emergency action is taken. Authorizes the Administrator to seek: (1) cost reimbursement; and (2) injunctive relief whenever asbestos in a covered building poses an imminent and substantial endangerment to human health or the environment. Prohibits the Federal leasing of any building not inspected for asbestos. Prohibits discrimination against whistleblowers. Sets forth the duties of an Asbestos Ombudsman, including receiving and responding to requests for information and grievances and making recommendations.</summary>
</bill>
