<bill session="100" type="s" number="993" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to require the Department of State offices involved in overseas construction projects.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Army"/>
    <term name="Building construction"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Construction industries"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Executive reorganization"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Government contractors"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Public Contracts, Procurement, and Property"/>
    <term name="Security measures"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1987--Introduced.
Provides that the Under Secretary of State for Management shall have overall management authority and responsibility for all offices and personnel of the State Department involved in the planning and implementation of State Department-managed construction projects undertaken in any foreign country, including: (1) the Bureau for Diplomatic Security; (2) the Foreign Buildings Office; and (3) the Office of Foreign Missions. Transfers direct administrative authority and responsibility over the Foreign Building Office of the Department of State from the Assistant Secretary of State for Administration to the Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security. Requires the Secretary of State to submit an annual report to the Congress concerning security-related factors and the contracting and construction plans for each Government construction project planned or underway in a foreign country. Establishes an interagency board to review and approve all such reports. Specifies that the board shall consist of representatives of the Department of State, Central Intelligence Agency, Defense Intelligence Agency, and National Security Agency and shall be headed by the Under Secretary of State for Management. Requires the Secretary to consider utilizing the Army Corps of Engineers, in lieu of other Government or private contractors, to manage the construction of any Government project in any Communist-controlled country.</summary>
</bill>
