<bill session="100" type="s" number="994" updated="2014-03-22T09:55:12-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-04-09">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-04-09"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Overseas Facilities Security Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A bill to improve security at facilities of the United States Government located in foreign countries.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403515"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-05-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400565" joined="1987-04-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-05-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-04-09" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-05-15">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Civil service employment"/>
    <term name="Communist countries"/>
    <term name="Department of State"/>
    <term name="Embassies"/>
    <term name="Espionage"/>
    <term name="Federal employees"/>
    <term name="Federal employees and officials"/>
    <term name="Federal installations"/>
    <term name="Foreign service"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Loyalty-security program"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="National security crimes"/>
    <term name="Polygraphs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/9/1987--Introduced.
Overseas Facilities Security Act of 1987 - Requires every current or prospective Government employee (including members of the Foreign Service and the Armed Forces of the United States) to take a polygraph examination prior to entering on duty in any position directly involving the security of any Government facility in a foreign country. Limits the scope of such an examination to determining the possible vulnerability of the employee to recruitment or manipulation by a foreign intelligence service for the purpose of engaging in espionage against the United States. Prohibits an employee from continuing in such a position if the results of such an examination indicate possible vulnerability to such recruitment or manipulation. Requires that each such employee have at least one such examination every 12 months. Requires each employee for whom such an examination indicates possible vulnerability to such recruitment or manipulation to be placed on administrative leave pending completion of a security investigation. Requires that a determination be made by the appropriate supervisory official regarding the fitness of such employee to continue in a security-related position. Provides that if such investigation or determination is undertaken in a foreign country, the full details must be reported to the Assistant Secretary of State for Diplomatic Security. Requires the Ambassadors to certain Communist-controlled countries to submit an annual report to the Under Secretary of State for Management concerning: (1) the security of U.S. diplomatic facilities in such countries and the integrity of personnel attached to such facilities; (2) any efforts by a foreign government to penetrate or compromise the security of U.S. diplomatic facilities or to recruit or manipulate U.S. Government employees; and (3) the security program at such facilities. Requires the Under Secretary to transmit such reports to the Congress together with an evaluation of the security programs and recommendations regarding the security of U.S. diplomatic facilities and personnel. Limits to 18 months the tour of duty of any Government employee providing physical security to U.S. diplomatic facilities in specified Communist-controlled countries, unless the Under Secretary certifies in writing to the Congress that such a tour of duty is required to protect the national security interests of the United States.</summary>
</bill>
