<bill session="100" type="sc" number="149" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:42-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-01">PASS_OVER:SENATE</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-10-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of the Congress regarding the restoration of democracy to Haiti and on conditions for the resumption of United States assistance to that country.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300046"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="401709" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="300071" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1988-10-01"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1988-10-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-10-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-10-03">
      <text>Message on Senate action sent to the House.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Called up by House Under Suspension of Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-04">
      <text>Considered by House Unfinished Business.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-10-06">
      <text>Resolution Agreed to in House by Yea-Nay Vote: 415 - 0 (Record Vote No: 435).</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="sc" number="147"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Drugs and narcotics"/>
    <term name="Economic development"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Haiti"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="International cooperation"/>
    <term name="Narcotic traffic"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/1/1988--Introduced.
Links resumption of U.S. assistance to the Government of Haiti to actions by the Haitian Government to: (1) embark upon a credible transition to democracy; (2) strictly observe human and civil rights and institute a judicial process to investigate and prosecute violations of human rights; (3) reform a corrupt bureaucracy; (4) promote economic development that will benefit the Haitian people; (5) improve cooperation with the United States in dealing with narcotics trafficking through Haiti and take steps to halt the involvement of the Haitian military in the transshipment of illicit drugs; and (6) demonstrate the willingness of the Haitian armed forces to submit to legally constituted civil authority and to respect and abide by the Haitian Constitution. States that: (1) there will be no resumption of regularized and sustained government-to-government assistance until the election of a civilian government pursuant to free, fair, and open elections; and (2) the appropriate executive branch officials should consult with the Congress before any kind of assistance is made available by the United States to the Government of Haiti. Declares support for the people of Haiti and their desire for democratic government and economic development. Directs the appropriate committees of the Congress to conduct hearings to determine appropriate and necessary legislative actions to promote free, fair, and open elections leading to civilian government in Haiti. States that the appropriate executive branch officials should examine ways that the United States can work with its allies and appropriate international organizations to develop a consistent and sustainable multilateral policy toward Haiti.</summary>
</bill>
