<bill session="100" type="sc" number="33" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-03-18">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of the Congress regarding democracy and security in the Republic of Korea.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300150"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-03-18" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Commemorations"/>
    <term name="Congressional tributes"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1987--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that the United States: (1) recognizes the close historical bonds between the American and Korean peoples and the considerable national resources South Korea contributes toward regional defense and security; (2) recognizes and supports the Korean people's desire to achieve a level of political development commensurate with their economic, social, and cultural achievements; (3) applauds President Chun Doo Hwan's pledge to initiate the transfer of executive power in South Korea; (4) commends President Chun and his party for agreeing to initiate negotiations over constitutional reform; (5) calls on such Government and the opposition to continue their dialogue; (6) hopes that such Government and the opposition will strive for democratic reform; and (7) hopes that political leaders engaged in the constitutional revision will achieve lasting reforms and popular support for the new constitution.</summary>
</bill>
