<bill session="100" type="sc" number="89" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:41-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-13">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-13"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-13"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A concurrent resolution expressing the sense of Congress regarding the continuing disregard and systematic abuse of basic human rights and freedoms by the Government of Cuba and the failure of the United Nations Human Rights Commission to address the human rights situation in Cuba.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-11-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-11-13"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-13" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="United Nations finances"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/13/1987--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Congress that: (1) the United Nations (UN) and the Human Rights Commission have acted selectively and inconsistently in addressing human rights violations in various countries; (2) the UN General Assembly and the Commission have failed to responsibly address the deplorable human rights situation in Cuba despite overwhelming evidence of abuse; (3) the President, Secretary of State, and Permanent Representative of the United States to the UN are to be commended for their efforts to place Cuba on the UN's human rights agenda and urged to continue their efforts; (4) specified countries should be commended for their votes in favor of considering such violations by Cuba; (5) the United States urges specified Commission member States to support the U.S. resolution on Cuban human rights at the next Commission session; (6) the United States should take such vote into consideration in determining U.S. assistance to all countries which are Commission members; (7) the United States should continue to emphasize how other countries vote on fundamental issues such as human rights when determining financial support for the UN and the Commission; and (8) the Commission should include Cuban human rights violations among the highest priorities of its human rights agenda at its 44th session in Geneva, Switzerland, in 1988.</summary>
</bill>
