<bill session="100" type="sj" number="179" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-24">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-07-24"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-24"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">National Economic Commission Act</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to establish a National Economic Commission.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400563"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="408252" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-07-24"/>
    <cosponsor id="410242" joined="1987-07-24"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-07-24" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Banking.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSBK" name="Senate Banking, Housing, and Urban Affairs" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Economic growth"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Fiscal policy"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade policy"/>
    <term name="International competitiveness"/>
    <term name="Monetary policy"/>
    <term name="National growth policy"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/24/1987--Introduced.
National Economic Commission Act - Establishes the National Economic Commission. Specifies the membership of such Commission. Requires the Commission to conduct a study of: (1) the elements of domestic fiscal, monetary, and trade policies and their effect on employment, real interest rates, national savings, capital formation and investment, labor productivity, the exchange rate value of the dollar, the U.S. balance of trade in goods and services, the U.S. international investment position, and the viability of economic growth in the United States and the world; (2) the elements of the fiscal, monetary, and trade policies of major U.S. trading partners and their effect on the U.S. balance of trade in goods and services and U.S. employment; and (3) the debt burden of developing countries and its effect on the U.S. balances of trade in goods and services and U.S. employment. Specifies that such study shall include consideration of recommendations regarding the coordination of domestic fiscal, monetary, and trade policies with the policies of other countries to achieve vigorous economic growth. Requires the Commission to specifically address: (1) the goal of promoting employment, low real interest rates, national savings, capital formation and investment, labor productivity, balance in U.S. trade of goods and services, and economic growth in the United States and the world; (2) a means of ensuring that the burden of achieving such goals is equitably distributed among nations; (3) the current and prospective economic factors and developments that should be taken into account in making policy to achieve these goals; and (4) the institutional arrangements required to achieve the appropriate coordination, within the United States and among foreign nations, for the making and implementation of economic policy. Requires the Commission to submit a final report concerning the results of such study to the President and the Congress no later than November 30, 1988. Sets forth administrative provisions concerning the operation of the Commission and the compensation of its members. Terminates the Commission 60 days after the day the Commission's final report is submitted. Authorizes appropriations.</summary>
</bill>
