<bill session="100" type="sj" number="209" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:23-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-05">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-27"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to provide for the extension of certain programs relating to housing and community development, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="402990"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-10-27"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1987-10-27" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="394">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate. Read twice. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 394.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-10-30">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-10-30" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Passed Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03">
      <text>Called up by House by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote2" roll="402" datetime="1987-11-03" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed House by Yea-Nay Vote: 394 - 1 (Record Vote No: 402).</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1987-11-03">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1987-11-03">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1987-11-03">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1987-11-05" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-154" type="public" datetime="1987-11-05">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-154.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="hj" number="393"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="hj" number="393"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Housing and community development"/>
    <term name="Agriculture and Rural Affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Block grants"/>
    <term name="Burglary"/>
    <term name="Burglary insurance"/>
    <term name="Business and commerce"/>
    <term name="Civilian personnel positions"/>
    <term name="Community development"/>
    <term name="Credit"/>
    <term name="Crime prevention"/>
    <term name="Department of Housing and Urban Development"/>
    <term name="Disabled"/>
    <term name="Disaster insurance"/>
    <term name="Disasters and Disaster Relief"/>
    <term name="Energy"/>
    <term name="Energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Energy policy"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to cities"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to community development"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to housing"/>
    <term name="Federal enclaves"/>
    <term name="Finance and financial sector"/>
    <term name="Flood insurance"/>
    <term name="Floods"/>
    <term name="Government securities"/>
    <term name="Group medical practice"/>
    <term name="Health facilities"/>
    <term name="Home repair and improvement"/>
    <term name="Housing and Housing Finance"/>
    <term name="Housing finance"/>
    <term name="Housing for the aged"/>
    <term name="Housing for the handicapped"/>
    <term name="Industrial energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Insurance"/>
    <term name="Medical centers"/>
    <term name="Mortgage guaranty insurance"/>
    <term name="Mortgage loans"/>
    <term name="Rental housing"/>
    <term name="Residential energy conservation"/>
    <term name="Residential rehabilitation"/>
    <term name="Robbery"/>
    <term name="Rural affairs legislation"/>
    <term name="Rural housing"/>
    <term name="Secondary mortgage market"/>
    <term name="Securities and Investments"/>
    <term name="Social welfare"/>
    <term name="Solar energy"/>
    <term name="Urban affairs"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1113"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>10/27/1987--Introduced.
Amends the National Housing Act to extend authority through November 15, 1987, for: (1) title I financial institution insurance for housing renovation and modernization; (2) general mortgage insurance; (3) low and moderate income and displaced families mortgage insurance; (4) homeownership for lower income families including mortgage insurance authority and housing stimulus authority; (5) mortgage co-insurance, including rental rehabilitation and development projects; (6) graduated payment and indexed mortgage insurance; (7) the demonstration mortgage reinsurance program; (8) mortgage insurance for armed forces' civilian employees and defense housing for impacted areas; (9) mortgage insurance for land development; and (10) mortgage insurance for medical and dental group practice facilities. Amends the Housing Act of 1964 to extend urban rehabilitation loan authority through November 15, 1987. Amends the Housing Act of 1949 to extend Farmers Home Administration Authority through November 15, 1987, for: (1) insured loans for rental and cooperative housing and related facilities for elderly persons and families in rural areas; (2) rural communities with 10,000 - 20,000 population to participate in rural housing programs; and (3) mutual and self-help housing grant and loan authority. Amends the National Flood Insurance Act of 1968 to extend authority for national flood insurance, including emergency implementation and flood-risk zones, through November 15, 1987. Amends the National Housing Act to extend authority for the national crime insurance program through November 15, 1987. Amends the Housing and Community Development Act of 1974 to extend community development block grant entitlement authority for certain metropolitan city and urban county areas through November 15, 1987. Amends the Housing and Urban-Rural Recovery Act of 1983 to extend the maximum interest rate limitation on loans for housing and related facilities for elderly or handicapped families through November 15, 1987. Extends the Home Mortgage Disclosure Act through November 15, 1987. Amends the Solar Energy and Energy Conservation Bank Act to extend the Solar Energy and Energy Conservation Bank through November 15, 1987. Amends the Federal National Mortgage Association Charter Act to extend the Federal National Mortgage Association's (Fannie Mae) authority to purchase secondary residential mortgages through November 15, 1987. Amends the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation Act to extend the Federal Home Loan Mortgage Corporation's (Freddie Mac) authority to purchase secondary residential mortgages through November 15, 1987. Amends the National Housing Act to make permanent the limitation on the principal amount of mortgages that may be insured in any fiscal year under such Act. Amends Federal law to extend the moratorium on the prepayment of certain rural rental housing loans through November 15, 1987.</summary>
</bill>
