<bill session="100" type="sj" number="213" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:29-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-11-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-11-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-11-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Persian Gulf Navigation Protection Act of 1987</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing specific authorization under the War Powers Resolution for the continued use of United States Armed Forces in the Persian Gulf, consistent with the foreign policy objectives and national security interests of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400692"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1987-11-05"/>
    <cosponsor id="411421" joined="1987-11-05"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-11-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Flags of convenience"/>
    <term name="Iran"/>
    <term name="Iran-Iraq War"/>
    <term name="Iraq"/>
    <term name="Marine transportation"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Military agreements"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="Shipping agreements"/>
    <term name="Ships and shipping"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>11/5/1987--Introduced.
Persian Gulf Navigation Protection Act of 1987 - Declares that the requirements of the War Powers Resolution became operative with respect to U.S. armed forces in the Persian Gulf on October 19, 1987. Declares that it is U.S. policy in the Gulf to: (1) keep the sea lanes open to international commerce; (2) remain neutral in the Iran-Iraq war and seek a just end to that conflict; (3) preserve the integrity of other nonbelligerent countries bordering the Gulf; (4) prevent a strategic gain by the Soviet Union in the region; (5) urge U.S. allies to participate more fully in sharing the burden of achieving and preserving peace in the region; (6) defend U.S. armed forces against aggression; and (7) pursue efforts through the United Nations to implement a cease-fire in the Iran-Iraq war. Authorizes the President, for purposes of the War Powers Resolution, to continue to deploy U.S. armed forces in the Gulf, subject to the following restrictions: (1) prohibits reregistration of vessels owned by a government or national of a country bordering the Gulf under the U.S. flag; (2) allows U.S. armed forces to escort a vessel of such a country only if the government of such country agrees to reimburse the United States for costs incurred and only for six months after the date of enactment of this Act unless reauthorized by joint resolution; and (3) requires the President to consult with the Congress before using U.S. armed forces in hostilities (other than actions necessary to repel attacks against U.S. armed forces or U.S.-flag vessels). Requires the President to report to the Congress every 30 days after enactment of this Act on the progress made in implementing the policy set forth in this Act.</summary>
</bill>
