<bill session="100" type="sj" number="26" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:19-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-08-05">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-08-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to authorize and request the President to call a White House Conference on Library and Information Services to be held not later than 1989, and for other purposes.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408597"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="400692" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1987-04-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="401611" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1987-06-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402004" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="300016" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="402412" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1987-04-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="300023" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402727" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300026" joined="1987-06-09"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1987-03-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403171" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="300031" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1987-07-21"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="403669" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="403962" joined="1987-08-07"/>
    <cosponsor id="404219" joined="1987-09-15"/>
    <cosponsor id="404277" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="404679" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1987-03-10"/>
    <cosponsor id="405212" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="405321" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300056" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="406084" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="406188" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300064" joined="1987-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="300066" joined="1987-05-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-10-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407268" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407622" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="407786" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="408252" joined="1987-06-11"/>
    <cosponsor id="408420" joined="1987-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408898" joined="1987-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408939" joined="1987-02-23"/>
    <cosponsor id="408970" joined="1987-06-19"/>
    <cosponsor id="409225" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="409562" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300086" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="409917" joined="1987-04-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-06-16"/>
    <cosponsor id="410315" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1987-03-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-06-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1987-03-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300099" joined="1987-05-13"/>
    <cosponsor id="411762" joined="1987-06-30"/>
    <cosponsor id="411801" joined="1987-02-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Labor and Human Resources.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-01-27">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-04-03">
      <text>Subcommittee on Education, Arts, Humanities. Hearings held. Hearings printed:  S.Hrg. 100-74.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-08-05" state="REPORTED">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Ordered to be reported with an amendment in the nature of a substitute favorably.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-09-15">
      <text>Committee on Labor and Human Resources. Reported to Senate by Senator Kennedy with an amendment in the nature of a substitute and an amendment to the title and with a preamble. With written report No. 100-156.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1987-09-15" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="309">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 309.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Senate passed companion measure H.J.RES. 90 in lieu of this measure by Voice Vote.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-12-15">
      <text>Indefinitely postponed by Senate by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSHR" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources" activity="Referral, Markup, Reporting"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSHR01" subcommittee="Education, Arts and Humanities" name="Senate Labor and Human Resources"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="hj" number="90"/>
    <bill relation="identical" session="100" type="hj" number="90"/>
  </relatedbills>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Libraries"/>
    <term name="Advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Alcohol and youth"/>
    <term name="Arts, culture, religion"/>
    <term name="Authorization"/>
    <term name="Bicentennial of the Constitution"/>
    <term name="Bill of Rights"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse"/>
    <term name="Drug abuse prevention"/>
    <term name="Drugs and youth"/>
    <term name="Educational policy"/>
    <term name="Federal advisory bodies"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to higher education"/>
    <term name="Federal aid to libraries"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Government records, documents, and information"/>
    <term name="Information services"/>
    <term name="Law"/>
    <term name="Law libraries"/>
    <term name="Maryland"/>
    <term name="Mississippi"/>
    <term name="Social sciences"/>
    <term name="South Carolina"/>
    <term name="Student loan funds"/>
    <term name="Teachers"/>
    <term name="Vermont"/>
    <term name="White House conferences"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments>
    <amendment number="s1360"/>
    <amendment number="s1361"/>
  </amendments>
  <summary>12/15/1987--Indefinitely postponed in Senate.
(Measure indefinitely postponed in Senate, H.J. Res. 90 passed in lieu) Title I: White House Conference on Library and Information Services - Authorizes the President to call and conduct a White House Conference on Library and Information Services to develop recommendations for improvement of such services and their public use. Requires such Conference to be held not earlier than September 1, 1989, and not later than September 30, 1991. Requires that the Conference be planned and conducted by the National Commission on Libraries and Information Sciences. Authorizes the Librarian of Congress, the Director of the National Library of Medicine, and the Director of the National Agricultural Library, upon request, to detail personnel to the Commission. Requires the Conference to submit a final report to the President within 120 days following its close. Directs that the final report be made public, and within 90 days after receipt by the President transmitted to the Congress with recommendations. Establishes an advisory committee to assist in planning and conducting the Conference. Includes among its appointed members the Secretary of Education and the Librarian of Congress. Authorizes appropriations. Title II: Constitutional Bicentennial Education Program - Amends the Arts, Humanities, and Museums Amendments of 1985 to increase the authorized appropriations for FY 1989 through 1991 to carry out the education program for the commemoration of the Bicentennial of the Constitution of the United States and the Bill of Rights. Reserves a specified amount of such appropriations for elementary and secondary teacher training and retraining programs in history, geography, and other related disciplines in the social sciences and humanities designed to enhance understanding of the Constitution. Title III: Higher Education Program - Amends the Higher Education Act of 1965 to authorize the Secretary of Education to enter into agreements with ten additional institutions of higher education for the income contingent direct loan demonstration project in any fiscal year after FY 1988 in which appropriations for such project exceed a specified amount. Allows such agreement to include a consortia of institutions if they are located in the same State. Permits such institutions to pay students' in-school interest. Allows program participation by graduate and professional students. Decreases the interest rate under such program. Requires guaranty agencies to provide information on defaults by former students to institutions who request such information. Makes students who have returned to school to obtain State teacher certification eligible for the guaranteed student loan program. Title IV: Library and Education Resource Authorizations - Authorizes appropriations for the Washington Library Consortium to construct and equip a facility in Prince George's County, Maryland, that would link by computer eight university libraries and provide central storage for the rare books of the participating institutions. (Such institutions are American University, Georgetown University, George Washington University, Catholic University, George Mason University, Gallaudet University, Marymount University, and the University of the District of Columbia.) Authorizes appropriations to the Vermont Higher Education Council in Hyde Park, Vermont, for development activities for faculty at institutions which are members of such Council designed to address and overcome professional isolation experienced by such faculty members. Authorizes appropriations for the construction of a Health and Human Resources Center at Voorhees College, in Denmark, South Carolina. Authorizes appropriations for the renovation and completion of the library facilities of the University of Mississippi Law School at Oxford, Mississippi. Title V: Drug-Free Schools - Amends the Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1986 to authorize appropriations as necessary for FY 1990 and each of the fiscal years ending prior to October 1, 1993. Requires State educational agencies to distribute funds for State and local programs for drug abuse education and prevention programs on the basis of relative enrollments in public and private, nonprofit schools (currently, on the basis of the relative number of children in the school-age population) within an area. Requires local applications for funds for a three-year period to include a description of: (1) the extent and nature of the current drug and alcohol problem in the schools of the applicant; (2) the applicant's drug and alcohol policy; and (3) how the applicant will monitor program effectiveness. Requires applicants to submit a progress report to State educational agencies for the preceding two years in order to receive funds for the third year. Requires that such report show reasonable progress toward accomplishing program objectives or a modified plan to meet such objectives. Requires States to report annually to the Secretary with specified information on programs funded under this Act. Authorizes the Secretary of Education to conduct periodic evaluations of programs authorized by the Drug-Free Schools and Communities Act of 1986.</summary>
</bill>
