<bill session="100" type="sj" number="305" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:32-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-05-25">REPORTED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-05-25"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Persian Gulf Policy Act of 1988</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution providing specific authorization under the War Powers Resolution for the continued use of United States Armed Forces in the Persian Gulf, consistent with the foreign policy objectives and national security interests of the United States.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="400692"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-13">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations. Committee consideration held.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-05-25">
      <text>Senate Committee on Foreign Relations discharged. Pursuant to section 6(a) of Public Law 93-148.</text>
    </action>
    <calendar datetime="1988-05-25" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="693">
      <text>Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 693.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Point of order sustained in Senate; determined not privileged and not in the confines of section 6(a) of Public Law 93-148 by Yea-Nay Vote. 54-31. Record Vote No: 168.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-06">
      <text>Returned to the Committee on Foreign Relations by virtue of Senate sustaining the point of order against the privileged status.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, Markup, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Americans in foreign countries"/>
    <term name="Armed forces abroad"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional-Presidential relations"/>
    <term name="Middle East"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf"/>
    <term name="Persian Gulf States"/>
    <term name="Presidential powers"/>
    <term name="Presidents and Vice Presidents"/>
    <term name="War"/>
    <term name="War and emergency powers"/>
    <term name="Warships"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/26/1988--Introduced.
Persian Gulf Policy Act of 1988 - Declares that the reporting requirements of the War Powers Resolution became operative with respect to U.S. armed forces in the Persian Gulf on April 14, 1988, and that this Act is intended to constitute statutory authorization for the continued use of U.S. armed forces under that Resolution. Authorizes the President to continue to deploy U.S. armed forces in the Persian Gulf, but allows the use of such forces to convoy or escort vessels owned by any government or national of a country bordering the Gulf as of June 1, 1987, only until three months after the expiration of the 60-day period specified in the Resolution (beyond which the specific authorization of the Congress, a declaration of war, or other extenuating circumstances are required).</summary>
</bill>
