<bill session="100" type="sj" number="374" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:34-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-09">ENACTED:SIGNED</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-09-09"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-08"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution to provide for a settlement of the labor-management dispute between the Chicago and North Western Transportation Company and the United Transportation Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="409917"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-09-08"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1988-09-08"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-09-08" where="s" result="pass" state="PASS_OVER:SENATE">
      <text>Introduced in the Senate, read twice, considered, read the third time, and passed without amendment and with a preamble by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Called up by House by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote2" datetime="1988-09-09" where="h" result="pass" state="PASSED:BILL">
      <text>Passed House by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
    <action datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Measure Signed in Senate.</text>
    </action>
    <topresident datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Cleared for White House.</text>
    </topresident>
    <topresident datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Presented to President.</text>
    </topresident>
    <signed datetime="1988-09-09" state="ENACTED:SIGNED">
      <text>Signed by President.</text>
    </signed>
    <enacted number="100-429" type="public" datetime="1988-09-09">
      <text>Became Public Law No: 100-429.</text>
    </enacted>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Collective bargaining"/>
    <term name="Courts and Civil Procedure"/>
    <term name="District courts"/>
    <term name="Illinois"/>
    <term name="Industrial arbitration"/>
    <term name="Labor disputes"/>
    <term name="Labor injunctions"/>
    <term name="Labor unions"/>
    <term name="Lockouts"/>
    <term name="Railroad employees"/>
    <term name="Railroads"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/8/1988--Introduced.
Sets forth conditions for resolving the labor-management dispute (referred to in a specified Executive Order) between the Chicago and North Western Transportation Company (a common carrier by rail in interstate commerce) and certain of its employees represented by the United Transportation Union. Requires the parties to such dispute to take all necessary steps to restore or preserve the conditions out of which the dispute arose as such conditions existed before August 4, 1988, with specified exceptions. Makes the report and recommendations of a specified Emergency Board binding on the parties, with the same effect as an agreement under the Railway Labor Act (RLA), except that nothing in this joint resolution shall prevent a mutual written agreement to any terms and conditions different from those established herein. Requires binding arbitration, on the request of either party, for unresolved issues after ten days following enactment of this joint resolution. Directs the National Mediation Board to appoint an arbitration board for such arbitration, to be conducted, enforced, and reviewed as if it were under the RLA. Designates the U.S. District Court for the Northern District of Illinois, Eastern Division, as the court in which such arbitration award is to be filed and reviewed. Requires binding arbitration to be completed within 30 days after enactment of this joint resolution.</summary>
</bill>
