<bill session="100" type="sj" number="4" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:18-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A joint resolution proposing an amendment to the Constitution relating to Federal budget procedures.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300159"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-06" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Judiciary.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-02-09">
      <text>Referred to Subcommittee on Constitution.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-03-23">
      <text>Subcommittee on Constitution. Hearings held.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSJU" name="Senate Judiciary" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
    <committee activity="Referral, Hearings" code="SSJU03" subcommittee="Constitution" name="Senate Judiciary"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Economics and public finance"/>
    <term name="Balanced budgets"/>
    <term name="Budget deficits"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional budget"/>
    <term name="Constitution and Constitutional Amendments"/>
    <term name="Constitutional amendments"/>
    <term name="Federal budgets"/>
    <term name="Legislation"/>
    <term name="National income"/>
    <term name="Public debt"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Constitutional Amendment - Requires the Congress, prior to each fiscal year, to adopt a statement of receipts and outlays for that year in which total outlays are not greater than total receipts. Permits the Congress, in such statement, to provide for a specific excess of outlays over receipts by a three-fifths vote. Requires the President and the Congress to ensure that actual outlays do not exceed the outlays set forth in such statement. Prohibits total receipts for any fiscal year set forth in such statement from increasing by a rate greater than the increase in national income in the last calendar year, unless a bill directed solely to approving specific additional receipts is enacted. Requires the President, prior to each fiscal year, to transmit to the Congress a proposed statement of receipts and outlays for that year consistent with the provisions of this article. Permits the Congress to waive the provisions of this Act with respect to any fiscal year in which a declaration of war is in effect. Declares that total receipts shall include all receipts of the United States, except those derived from borrowing, and total outlays shall include all outlays of the United States, except those for repayment of debt principal. Declares that the amount of Federal public debt as of the first day of the second fiscal year beginning after the ratification of this article shall become the permanent debt limit. Prohibits any increase in such limit unless three-fifths of the whole number of each House of the Congress pass a bill approving such increase and such bill becomes law.</summary>
</bill>
