<bill session="100" type="sr" number="241" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:36-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-06-27">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-06-27"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-06-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate concerning support for the evolution to full democracy in the Republic of Korea.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300008" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="402990" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1987-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300048" joined="1987-06-27"/>
    <cosponsor id="300051" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300059" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300060" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300070" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300073" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="300150" joined="1987-06-26"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-06-26"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-06-26">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate and held at the desk by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-27">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="165" datetime="1987-06-27" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Yea-Nay Vote. 74-0. Record Vote No: 165.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="South Korea"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>6/26/1987--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States supports the efforts of Koreans to establish fair and free elections and peacefully evolve to a full democratic government; (2) the necessary conditions for achievement of a genuine democracy in South Korea are flexibility and fairness and the renunciation of violence; (3) the necessary conditions for meaningful and free elections include specified internationally recognized human rights standards; (4) the United States recognizes President Chun Doo Hwan's commitment to initiate the first peaceful transition of executive power; (5) a peaceful transfer of power is endangered by inability to agree on timely democratic reforms; (6) the United States calls on all parties in South Korea to resume the search for a peaceful agreement on democratic reform; and (7) the President of the United States should facilitate negotiations among all parties to achieve democracy in South Korea.</summary>
</bill>
