<bill session="100" type="sr" number="243" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-07-01">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-07-01"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-07-01"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to establish the Office of Senate Security.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-07-01"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-07-01" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional officers"/>
    <term name="Internal security"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>7/1/1987--Introduced.
Establishes the Office of Senate Security within the Office of the Secretary of the Senate. Requires the Secretary to appoint a Director of Senate Security after consultation with the Majority and Minority Leaders. Requires the Director to report annually to the Majority and Minority Leaders and the Chairman and Ranking Member of the Committee on Rules and Administration on the status of security matters and the handling of classified information in the Senate, and the progress of the Office in achieving the mandates of this resolution. Sets forth various security matters for which the Office shall be responsible. Requires the Office to distribute to all Senate offices a Senate Security Manual containing policies and procedures of the Office and regulations for the handling of classified information. Requires the Director to report to the Majority and Minority Leaders and the Secretary of the Senate on the number of officers and employees who have security clearances and make recommendations regarding the feasibility of reducing the number of employees with clearances. Authorizes the Office to: (1) provide appropriate facilities in the U.S. Capitol for hearings at which restricted data or classified information is to be presented or discussed; (2) establish and operate a central repository for the safeguarding of classified information; and (3) administer and maintain oaths of secrecy and establish procedures as necessary to implement Senate Rules provisions regarding confidential or executive sessions. Transfers all records, documents, data, materials, rooms, and facilities of the Interim Office of Senate Security to the Office of Senate Security.</summary>
</bill>
