<bill session="100" type="sr" number="298" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:37-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-10-16">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-10-16"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-10-16"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate condemning violations by Japanese fishing fleets of boundaries established for ligitimate conservation purposes and the failure of the Government of Japan to adequately police its nationals' high seas fishing activities.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300150"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-10-16" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Administrative fees"/>
    <term name="Environmental protection"/>
    <term name="Fish kills"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishing boats"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Foreign trade and international finance"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Japan"/>
    <term name="Licenses"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/16/1987--Introduced.
Condemns: (1) violations by the Japanese squid gillnet fleet of fishing boundaries in the Northern Pacific Ocean; and (2) the Japanese Government's failure to provide for adequate enforcement of regulations covering the activities of such fleet. Requests the President to direct the appropriate executive agencies to achieve: (1) a negotiated settlement providing for changes to the Japanese laws and regulations governing such fleet and more active enforcement by Japanese authorities; and (2) more effective monitoring and enforcement by U.S. agencies. Urges the Secretary of State to direct the efforts of the State Department toward achieving an agreement with Japan providing for specified enforcement measures, including; (1) a guaranteed level of at-sea boardings and inspections by Japanese enforcement vessels; (2) a fisheries observer program involving U.S. observers; and (3) the right of U.S. authorities to board and inspect Japanese fishing vessels. Urges the Secretary of Transportation to direct the efforts of the Coast Guard toward increasing surveillance and enforcement efforts in connection with the squid fishery. Urges the Secretary of Commerce to invoke provisions imposing sanctions in the form of higher fees for Japanese gillnet fishing permits, for FY 1987, or provide to the Congress a full and adequate justification for failure to do so in light of Japan's failure to adequately regulate its squid fishing vessels in accordance with U.S. Japanese, and international law.</summary>
</bill>
