<bill session="100" type="sr" number="31" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-06">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-06"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate with respect to the situation in Afghanistan.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401391" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="402023" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405305" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300154" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="405795" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406190" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="407663" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="400563" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="300157" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="410936" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="412006" joined="1987-01-06"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1987-07-14" withdrawn="1987-07-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="2" datetime="1987-01-06" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Yea-Nay Vote. 92-0. Record Vote No: 2.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="Pakistan"/>
    <term name="Peace"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="Underground movements"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/6/1987--Introduced.
Declares that the Senate hereby: (1) renews its condemnation of the continued Soviet invasion and occupation of Afghanistan; (2) finds that recent Soviet representations concerning Soviet troop withdrawal have been a sham; (3) finds that recent Soviet offers of ceasefire and national reconciliation fail to provide the framework for a settlement and should be spurned by the Afghan resistance as long as Soviet troops continue to occupy Afghanistan; (4) believes that the only acceptable formula for a settlement in Afghanistan is one that results in a government representative of the Afghan people; and (5) renews its commitment to support the Afghans through the provision of material support. Urges the Secretary of State to take specified actions to encourage Soviet military withdrawal and a peaceful settlement of the situation in Afghanistan. Urges the: (1) Soviet Union to present a timetable of no more than four months for the withdrawal of its forces at the next session of U.N.-sponsored indirect negotiations in February 1987; and (2) Government of Pakistan to resist Soviet pressure to accept less than such a timetable for withdrawal of such forces.</summary>
</bill>
