<bill session="100" type="sr" number="348" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:38-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-12-19">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-12-19"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-12-19"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution establishing an Arms Control Treaty Review Support Office.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-12-19"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1987-12-19" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Advice and consent of the Senate"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Classified defense information"/>
    <term name="Intermediate range ballistic missiles"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="National Security and Intelligence Operations"/>
    <term name="Security classification (Government documents)"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate leadership"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="Treaty-making power"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>12/19/1987--Introduced.
Establishes within the Senate an Arms Control Treaty Review Support Office (Office). Requires the Office to provide the Senate with such administrative support as the Majority and Minority Leaders may direct with respect to Senate consideration of the Treaty between the United States of America and the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics on the Elimination of their Intermediate-Range and Shorter-Range Missiles and of any other arms control treaties submitted during the 100th Congress by the President to the Senate for its advice and consent to ratification. Directs that such support include the temporary storage and organization of, system of access to, and security of documents related to the negotiating records of such treaties. Directs the Majority and Minority Leaders to make arrangements with the executive branch to provide for the transmission, organization, and system of access to the negotiating record relating to such treaties submitted for advice and consent. Limits access to documents of the Office by Committee staff and consultants. Requires: (1) all staff members and consultants to agree in writing to abide by the conditions of an appropriate nondisclosure agreement promulgated by the Office of Senate Security, as a condition of employment; and (2) the Office to employ a security officer qualified to administer security procedures. Makes funds available to carry out this resolution. Terminates the Office within 30 days of the adjournment of the 100th Congress.</summary>
</bill>
