<bill session="100" type="sr" number="386" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-02-29">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-02-29"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-02-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to express the sense of the Senate on United States policy toward Afghanistan, especially toward the possibility of a Soviet troop withdrawal.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300005" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403346" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403483" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300034" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="405795" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1988-02-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="411271" joined="1988-02-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="32" datetime="1988-02-29" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate, considered, and agreed to without amendment and with a preamble by Yea-Nay Vote. 77-0. Record Vote No: 32.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Afghanistan"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Dispute settlement"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="International military forces"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Military occupation"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Refugees"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>2/29/1988--Introduced.
Declares that any settlement in Afghanistan must: (1) provide for Afghan self-determination; (2) outline a definite timetable for the complete withdrawal of Soviet troops; and (3) provide for the safe return of refugees. Urges the President to support a solution acceptable to the Afghan resistance, insist on the withdrawal of Soviet advisers with the troops, require the Soviets to terminate all forms of military assistance to the Kabul regime, and ensure continued international assistance to the Afghan refugees until all Soviet bloc forces have been withdrawn. Expresses the Senate's: (1) support for increased U.S. humanitarian assistance to the Afghan people during and following a Soviet withdrawal; (2) support for a United Nations-sponsored peacekeeping force; and (3) belief that the U.S. Government should not restrict assistance to the Afghan resistance until it is clear that the Soviets have ended their occupation and that the majahadeen can maintain its integrity during the transition period leading to new elections.</summary>
</bill>
