<bill session="100" type="sr" number="397" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-21">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-21"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate that unregulated fisheries in the international waters of the Bering Sea must be halted pending the completion of a comprehensive international agreement providing for appropriate and necessary fisheries research, management and enforcement efforts.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300150"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-03-21" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Bering Sea"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/21/1988--Introduced.
Declares that: (1) unregulated fisheries in the international waters of the Bering Sea (the donut hole area) should be halted pending a comprehensive international agreement on fisheries research, management, and enforcement; (2) the President should seek the consent of all nations having fishing fleets operating in the Bering Sea regarding a moratorium and its enforcement; (3) it is appropriate to proceed with scheduled discussions with the Soviet Union on these matters; (4) in the event any nation fishing in the Bering Sea fails to agree to the moratorium and its enforcement, the President should seek the concurrence of the Soviet Union to a bilateral agreement regarding a moratorium and its enforcement, limited to conservation and having no effect on any other rights of nations on the high seas; (5) upon cessation of fishing in the area, the Secretary of State should request interested nations to participate in multilateral negotiations on an agreement providing for research, management, and enforcement necessary to allow fisheries to resume in a manner consistent with conservation and continued productivity; and (6) the Secretary of State should present to the Congress, by June 1, 1988, a plan providing for effective fisheries enforcement in the Bering Sea.</summary>
</bill>
