<bill session="100" type="sr" number="396" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-03-21">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-03-21"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-03-18"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to express the sense of the Senate on the need to stop uncontrolled fishing in the international waters of the Bering Sea.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300094"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300012" joined="1988-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="403920" joined="1988-03-18"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1988-03-18"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1988-03-18" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="590">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 590.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1988-03-21">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="64" datetime="1988-03-21" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Yea-Nay Vote. 78-0. Record Vote No: 64.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Public lands and natural resources"/>
    <term name="Bering Sea"/>
    <term name="Fisheries"/>
    <term name="Fishery agreements"/>
    <term name="Fishery management"/>
    <term name="Foreign fishing"/>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="International environmental cooperation"/>
    <term name="International fishery management"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>3/18/1988--Introduced.
Declares that the Secretary of State should: (1) initiate negotiations with the Soviet Union on a bilateral agreement regarding establishment and enforcement of a moratorium on all fishing in the international waters of the Bering Sea known as the "Hole in the Donut" or the Donut; (2) initiate negotiations for a multilateral agreement regarding a fishery management regime and conservation and protection of the long term viability of fishery resources in the area; and (3) report to the Committee on Commerce, Science, and Transportation of the Senate regarding enforcement options for fishery management in the Bering Sea. Declares that both the bilateral and the multilateral agreements should include language indicating that their sole purpose is fishery conservation and that they in no way impose unlawful restrictions on the internationally recognized rights and freedoms of vessel transit.</summary>
</bill>
