<bill session="100" type="sr" number="425" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:39-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-06-23">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1988-06-23"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-04-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Jacob K. Javits Senate Fellowship Program Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution to establish a Jacob K. Javits Senate Fellowship program.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-04-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1988-04-29"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-04-29" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Read twice and referred to the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1988-06-23">
      <text>Senate Committee on Rules discharged by Unanimous Consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="by Voice Vote" type="vote" datetime="1988-06-23" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment by Voice Vote.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, Discharged"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Education"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Congressional fellows"/>
    <term name="Graduate students"/>
    <term name="Scholarships"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Student aid"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>4/29/1988--Introduced.
Jacob K. Javits Senate Fellowship Program Resolution - Establishes a Jacob K. Javits Senate Fellowship Program to encourage increased participation by outstanding students in a public service career. Directs the Jacob K. Javits Foundation, Incorporated, New York, New York, in consultation with the Secretary of the Senate (the Secretary), to select Senate Fellowship participants. Requires each participant to complete a program of graduate study in accordance with criteria agreed upon by the Foundation. Provides for a Senate component of the Fellowship Program. Authorizes the Secretary to appoint and fix the compensation of each eligible participant selected, for a period of employment which may not exceed one year. States that such compensation shall not supplement stipends received from the Secretary of Education under the Fellowship Program. Limits to ten the number of fellowship participants so employed for any fiscal year. Directs the Secretary, after consulting the Majority and Minority Leaders, to place eligible participants in positions in the Senate that are, within practicable considerations, supportive of their academic programs. Makes funds available to the Secretary available for five years, to be paid from the contingent fund of the Senate. Limits such funds for each of the first five years of the program. Terminates the program five years after the effective date of this resolution. Directs the Secretary, three months prior to such expiration, to report a program evaluation and recommendations to the Majority Leader and the Senate.</summary>
</bill>
