<bill session="100" type="sr" number="476" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-09-20">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-09-20"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-09-20"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding United States policy in bringing about national reconciliation and self-determination in Angola and Namibia.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="403346"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="300010" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="402495" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403142" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300046" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300052" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300053" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="406183" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="407355" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="408937" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300089" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="409923" joined="1988-09-20"/>
    <cosponsor id="300094" joined="1988-10-12"/>
    <cosponsor id="410588" joined="1988-09-20"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-09-20" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American economic assistance"/>
    <term name="American military assistance"/>
    <term name="Angola"/>
    <term name="Armistices"/>
    <term name="Civil war"/>
    <term name="Congress and Members of Congress"/>
    <term name="Congressional oversight"/>
    <term name="Cuba"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Government operations and politics"/>
    <term name="Insurgency"/>
    <term name="Military intervention"/>
    <term name="Namibia"/>
    <term name="National self-determination"/>
    <term name="Peace negotiations"/>
    <term name="Reagan Doctrine"/>
    <term name="Recognition (International law)"/>
    <term name="Sovereignty"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
    <term name="War relief"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>9/20/1988--Introduced.
Expresses the sense of the Senate that: (1) the United States should welcome an independent Namibia and ensure that the United Nations supervised transitional process assures national reconciliation and self-determination through fair and free elections and the formation of a multiparty, nonracial democracy; (2) U.S. mediators should seek the negotiation of a verifiable withdrawal of all Cuban and Soviet-bloc forces from Angola; (3) the withdrawal of all foreign forces from Angola and the implementation of the U.N.-sponsored process of independence in Namibia must be synchronized with national reconciliation and free and fair elections in Angola; (4) the presence of Soviet-bloc and Cuban military personnel and the buildup of Soviet weaponry by the Popular Movement of the Liberation of Angola (MPLA) in Angola pose a threat to peace; (5) the United States shall not cease assistance to the National Union for the Total Independence of Angola (UNITA) as long as the MPLA continues to receive foreign military assistance and until the President has certified to the Congress that all Cuban forces have been withdrawn from Angola, such forces have not been redeployed elsewhere for a later invasion of Angola, and UNITA and the MPLA have agreed to form a government of national reconciliation and to set a date for holding elections; and (6) the United States should encourage a cease-fire between Cuban and MPLA forces, respectively, and UNITA and promote direct talks between such parties to achieve national reconciliation and the settlement of the Angolan civil war. Directs appropriate Senate committees to: (1) determine what legislative actions may be necessary to promote the establishment of a multiparty, nonracial democracy in Namibia; (2) consider humanitarian assistance to help Angola reconstruct its economy and otherwise recover from the injuries of the civil war; and (3) make recommendations to the President with respect to establishing diplomatic relations with a freely elected government in Luanda and formulate plans to assist such government with economic reforms.</summary>
</bill>
