<bill session="100" type="sr" number="488" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:40-04:00">
  <state datetime="1988-10-05">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1988-10-05"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1988-10-05"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="short" as="introduced">Fair Employment Practices Resolution</title>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution providing for fair employment practices in the Senate</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300071"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1988-10-05" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Rules.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSRA" name="Senate Rules and Administration" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="Congress"/>
    <term name="Civil Rights and Liberties"/>
    <term name="Congressional agencies"/>
    <term name="Congressional committee staffing"/>
    <term name="Congressional committees (Senate)"/>
    <term name="Congressional employees"/>
    <term name="Counseling"/>
    <term name="Damages"/>
    <term name="Discrimination in employment"/>
    <term name="Employee rights"/>
    <term name="Labor and employment"/>
    <term name="Mediation"/>
    <term name="Senate"/>
    <term name="Senate rules and procedure"/>
    <term name="Wage restitution"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>10/5/1988--Introduced.
Fair Employment Practices Resolution - Requires that personnel actions affecting employment positions in the Senate be made free from discrimination based on race, color, national origin, religion, sex (including marital and parental status), handicap, or age. Provides that interpretations under such requirement shall reflect the principles of current law as generally applicable to employment. Provides that such requirement does not prohibit the taking into consideration of: (1) the domicile of an individual with respect to a position under the clerk-hire allowance; or (2) the political affiliation of an individual with respect to a position under the clerk-hire allowance or a position on a committee staff. Sets forth a three-step procedure for consideration of alleged violations under this Act: (1) counseling and mediation; (2) formal complaint, hearing, and review by the Office of Fair Employment Practices; and (3) final review by the Review Panel. Establishes the Office of Fair Employment Practices. Sets forth the membership of the Review Panel. Provides for resolution by written agreement if, after a formal complaint is filed, the parties resolve the issues. Makes such agreements effective if approved by the Office or the Panel, whichever has the matter under review. Sets forth remedies which the Office or Panel may order. Provides for reimbursement of costs of attending hearings for individuals with respect to whom a hearing is held and who reside outside the District of Columbia. Sets forth a prohibition of intimidation. Provides for closed hearings and confidentiality. Makes the procedures and remedies under this resolution exclusive, except to the extent that specified Senate rules provide for additional procedures and remedies.</summary>
</bill>
