<bill session="100" type="sr" number="82" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-01-26">REFERRED</state>
  <status>
    <introduced datetime="1987-01-26"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-26"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution expressing the sense of the Senate regarding additional actions which may be taken to end apartheid in South Africa.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="408937"/>
  <cosponsors/>
  <actions>
    <action datetime="1987-01-26" state="REFERRED">
      <text>Referred to the Committee on Foreign Relations.</text>
    </action>
    <action datetime="1987-06-03">
      <text>Committee on Foreign Relations requested executive comment from State Department.</text>
    </action>
  </actions>
  <committees>
    <committee code="SSFR" name="Senate Foreign Relations" activity="Referral, In Committee"/>
  </committees>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="American investments"/>
    <term name="Apartheid"/>
    <term name="Democracy"/>
    <term name="Foreign Trade and Investments"/>
    <term name="Human rights"/>
    <term name="Minorities"/>
    <term name="Negotiations"/>
    <term name="Political prisoners"/>
    <term name="Sanctions (International law)"/>
    <term name="Science, technology, communications"/>
    <term name="South Africa"/>
    <term name="United Nations"/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/26/1987--Introduced.
Declares that the Senate urges the Government of South Africa to: (1) release all political prisoners and begin negotiations within a specified time with black leaders of South Africa to end apartheid; (2) propose a specific plan to institute reforms in place of apartheid; and (3) abolish apartheid and install a new democratic government that guarantees equal rights to all citizens. Urges the U.S. Government, if the above-mentioned actions are not implemented, to discontinue the use of U.S. veto power to block proposed sanctions against South Africa in the United Nations, cut all telecommunications between the United States and South Africa, and continue such actions until the abolition of apartheid. Urges the U.S. Government to support white minority rights and to discourage divestment of American business in South Africa if South Africa ends the apartheid system.</summary>
</bill>
