<bill session="100" type="sr" number="94" updated="2014-03-22T09:54:35-04:00">
  <state datetime="1987-02-17">PASSED:SIMPLERES</state>
  <status>
    <unknown datetime="1987-02-17"/>
  </status>
  <introduced datetime="1987-01-29"/>
  <titles>
    <title type="official" as="introduced">A resolution concerning arms control negotiations with the Soviet Union.</title>
  </titles>
  <sponsor id="300016"/>
  <cosponsors>
    <cosponsor id="401604" joined="1987-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="403515" joined="1987-01-29"/>
    <cosponsor id="300036" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300079" joined="1987-02-03"/>
    <cosponsor id="408597" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300084" joined="1987-02-17"/>
    <cosponsor id="300092" joined="1987-02-17"/>
  </cosponsors>
  <actions>
    <calendar datetime="1987-01-29" state="REPORTED" calendar="Senate Legislative" under="General Orders" number="14">
      <text>Submitted in the Senate. Placed on Senate Legislative Calendar under General Orders. Calendar No. 14.</text>
    </calendar>
    <action datetime="1987-02-17">
      <text>Measure laid before Senate by unanimous consent.</text>
    </action>
    <vote how="roll" type="vote" roll="27" datetime="1987-02-17" where="s" result="pass" state="PASSED:SIMPLERES">
      <text>Resolution agreed to in Senate without amendment and with a preamble by Yea-Nay Vote. 93-2. Record Vote No: 27.</text>
    </vote>
  </actions>
  <committees/>
  <relatedbills/>
  <subjects>
    <term name="International affairs"/>
    <term name="Armed forces and national security"/>
    <term name="Arms control"/>
    <term name="Arms control agreements"/>
    <term name="Arms control negotiations"/>
    <term name="Arms race"/>
    <term name="Defense articles"/>
    <term name="Nuclear weapons"/>
    <term name="Radar defense networks"/>
    <term name="Space warfare"/>
    <term name="Treaties"/>
    <term name="U.S.S.R."/>
  </subjects>
  <amendments/>
  <summary>1/29/1987--Introduced.
Declares that the Senate: (1) expresses its support for the commitment by the President to achieve mutual, equitable, balanced, verifiable, and stabilizing nuclear arms reduction agreements with the Soviet Union; and (2) encourages both nations to use diplomacy at the Geneva negotiations to resolve their differences; (3) cautions the Soviet Union against pursuing strategies designed to exploit American domestic politics or to divide the United States from its allies to secure an advantage on arms reduction matters; (4) urges the Soviet Union not to condition progress on all arms control matters with issues relating to strategic defense technologies; (5) declares that an obstacle to an acceptable arms control agreement with the Soviet Union has been its violations of existing agreements, and calls upon it to rectify such violations, in particular, to dismantle the newly-constructed radar site at Krasnoyarsk, in the Soviet Union; and (6) urges the President to consult with America's allies and the Senate in the construction of sound arms reduction agreements.</summary>
</bill>
